import{_ as g,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as h,C as b,M as c,U as y,F as p,p as w,e as f,f as v,q as j}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},A={class:"poem-container"},z={class:"review"},T={class:"review-title"},N={class:"review-content"};function C(e,a,s,m,t,r){return i(),o("div",A,[n("div",z,[n("div",T,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",N,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const M=g(q,[["render",C],["__scopeId","data-v-d62ef213"]]),S=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"Doc to summarize: అదొక అరుదైన కేసు. ఆ ప్రత్యేకమైన ఆ కేసులో ఎందుకలా జరిగిందని చూస్తే, ఆ సమయంలో ఆమె పీరియడ్స్‌లో ఉంది.ఆ పరిస్థితిని ప్రత్యామ్నాయ రుతుస్రావం (Vicarious Menstruation) అంటారు. ఇలా ఎందుకు జరిగింది. కారణమేమిటి? దీనికి ఎండోమెట్రియోసిస్ అనే వ్యాధి కారణం. Endometriosis అంటే ఏమిటి?గర్భాశయం లోపల లైనింగ్‌ని ఎండోమెట్రియం (Endometrium) అంటారు. ఆ లైనింగ్‌లో ప్రత్యేకమైన కణజాలం, గ్రంధులు ఉంటాయి.అవి స్త్రీ హార్మోన్లకు అనుగుణంగా  స్పందిస్తూ, వృద్ధి చెందుతుంటాయి. పీరియడ్స్ సమయంలో ఆ గర్భాశయపు లైనింగ్ (Endometrium) రుతుస్రావంలా బయటికి వెళ్లిపోతుంది. తర్వాత ఎండోమెట్రియం యొక్క కొత్త పొర ఏర్పడుతుంది.   కొన్ని సందర్భాలలో, ఈ ప్రత్యేక కణజాలం మరియు గ్రంధులు, గర్భాశయం బయట శరీరంలో వేర్వేరు ప్రదేశాల్లో ఉండడాన్ని ఎండోమెట్రియోసిస్ అంటారు. గర్భాశయం బయట ఉన్నా సరే, ఈ గ్రంధులు స్త్రీ హార్మోన్లకు స్పందిస్తూ గర్భాశయంలోని కణాలతో సమానంగా వృద్ధి చెందుతూ తమ విధులను నిర్వర్తిస్తుంటాయి. పీరియడ్స్ సమయంలో సైతం చైతన్యవంతమవుతాయి.చండిగఢ్ యువతికి ఆ కణజాలం కంటిలో వృద్ధి చెందింది. దాని ఫలితమే ఆమెకు పీరియడ్స్ సమయంలో రక్త కన్నీరు వచ్చింది. స్త్రీలలో ఎండోమెట్రియోసిస్ లక్షణాలేమిటి?   పీరియడ్స్ సమయంలో విపరీతమైన నొప్పి కలగడం. స్త్రీ పురుషుల కలయిక బాధాకరంగా ఉండడం.పీరియడ్స్ లో వున్నపుడు, మలవిసర్జన సమయంలో బాధ.సంతానం కలగడం లేటవడం. ఏయే ప్రదేశాల్లో  దీని ప్రభావం కనబడుతుంది.. శరీరంలో కలిగే మార్పులేమిటి?ఎక్కువగా గర్భాశయం వెనుకభాగంలోనూ, అండాశయాలపైన ఎండోమెట్రియోసిస్ కనిపిస్తుంది.  ప్రతినెలా ఈ కణాలు వృద్ధి చెందడం ద్వారా శరీర నిర్మాణంలో మార్పులు జరుగుతాయి.ఫేలోపియన్ ట్యూబులు గర్భాశయం వెనుక అతుక్కుంటాయి. అండం విడుదల సమయంలో ట్యూబులు తమ చివర్ల ద్వారా స్వీకరించే సహజ గుణాన్ని పోగొట్టుకుంటాయి.   Ovaries : అండాశయాలలో ఎండోమెట్రియోసిస్ వల్ల ఆ కణాలు, అండాల వుత్పత్తికి పనికిరాకుండా పోతాయి. ఇలా శారీరిక అవయవాల్లో మార్పుల వల్ల, ఏర్పడిన అతుకుల వల్ల, కడుపులో నొప్పి, స్త్రీ పురుష సంయోగంలో బాధ, మల విసర్జన సమయంలో నొప్పి తో బాధపడతారు.  ఎండోమెట్రియోసిస్ రోగ నిర్థారణ ఎలా చేస్తారు? రోగలక్షణాలు ఈ పరిస్థితిని సూచిస్తాయి.శరీరావయవాలను పరీక్ష చేయడం ద్వారా వ్యాధిని కొంత అంచనా వేయగలం.  లాపరోస్కోపీ పరీక్ష ద్వారా వ్యాధి నిర్థారణ అవుతుంది.   in the same language as the doc:","answer":"రక్త కన్నీరు నాటకం గురించి విన్నాం. కొన్ని రోజుల క్రితం, చండీగఢ్‌లో ఒక యువతికి రక్త కన్నీరు వచ్చిన సంఘటన  ఆమెనూ, ఆమె కుటుంబాన్నే కాదు వైద్యులను సైతం కలవర పెట్టింది."},{"question":"ما هو أبرد جسم في المجموعة الشمسية ؟","answer":"قمر كوكب نبتون (ترايتون)"},{"question":"Chọn câu trả lời đúng cho câu hỏi sau: Đâu là biệt danh của Đà Nẵng?A. Thành phố của những con sôngB. Thành phố của những cây cầuC. Thành phố văn hoá","answer":"B. Thành phố của những cây cầuTheo Cổng thông tin điện tử Đà Nẵng, đây là thành phố của những cây cầu. Trong 25 năm kể từ khi chia tách Quảng Nam - Đà Nẵng thành hai đơn vị hành chính, Đà Nẵng có khoảng 20 cây cầu quy mô lớn được xây mới, gồm cả cầu vượt cạn, vượt sông. Tính riêng khu vực sông Hàn đã có 9 cây cầu, nổi tiếng phải kể tới cầu Rồng, cầu sông Hàn, cầu Thuận Phước, cầu Trần Thị Lý..."},{"question":"అబ్బూరి ఛాయాదేవి: 'ఆమె చైతన్యరూపిణి... తుళ్ళిపడే తొలకరి రోజుల గోదావరి' -అభిప్రాయంnఅబ్బూరి ఛాయాదేవి (1933 - 2019)1960, 70లలో ఆమె కథలు పత్రికలలో చదివి ఆవిడను కలవాలనుకునేదాన్ని. 80ల నుంచి ఆమె నాకు మంచి స్నేహితురాలైంది. 87లోనో 88లోనో సరిగా గుర్తులేదు కానీ, మొదటిసారి ఆమె ఇంటికి బాగ్‌లింగంపల్లికి వెళ్ళినప్పుడు భయంగానే వెళ్ళా. నాకంటే ముందు తరం రచయిత్రి కదా. రచయిత్రిగానే కాకుండా జవహర్లాల్ నెహ్రూ యూనివర్సిటీలో డిప్యూటీ లైబ్రేరియన్‌గా చాలా సంవత్సరాలు పని చేసి రాజీనామా చేసి వచ్చారు. వాళ్ళింటికి రాని ముందటి తరం సాహితీవేత్తలు లేరు. అబ్బూరి రామకృష్ణరావు కోడలు, వరదరాజేశ్వరరావు గారి భార్య ఇలా చాలా విని ఉన్నాను. ఫెమినిస్ట్ స్టడీ సర్కిల్ ప్రచురించిన ఒక పుస్తకం ఆవిష్కరించడానికి ఆహ్వానించడానికి వెళ్ళాను. ఆమెను చూసి ఆశ్చర్యపోయాను. ఎంత సామాన్యంగా, ఆప్యాయంగా, ఆత్మీయంగా ఉన్నారో చెప్పలేను. పైగా ఆ సెన్సాఫ్ హ్యూమర్. పక్కనే వరదరాజేశ్వరరావు గారి పన్‌లు (చమత్కారాలు)ను తట్టుకుంటూ ఆమె హాస్య చతురతను నిలబెట్టుకోగలిగినందుకు బోలెడు సంతోషించాను. ఫెమినిజం గురించి ఆవిడ చాలా మంచిగా మాట్లాడారు. స్టడీ సర్కిల్‌కు వచ్చి పుస్తకాన్ని ఆవిష్కరించడానికి అంగీకరించారు.ఆమె 'బోన్సాయ్ బతుకులు' కంటే మంచి ఫెమినిస్టు కథ ఉంటుందా? అతి సులువుగా జెండర్ పాఠాలనెన్నింటినో ఆమె తన కథలలో చెప్పారు. ఆమె తనకు తెలిసిన బాగా పరిచయమైన మధ్యతరగతి స్త్రీల గురించే రాశారు. తను ఎవరి కోసం రాస్తున్నానో, ఎవరు తన పాఠకులో ఆమెకు తెలుసు. ఐతే వివక్షను, అసమానతలు ఎత్తిచూపడానికి ఆమె ఎంచుకున్న జీవితాలు, ఇతివృత్తాలు ఎంతో బాగా సరిపోయాయి. స్త్రీలు చేసే చాకిరి, స్త్రీలకు పని చేసే చోట ఎదురయ్యే లైంగిక వేధింపులు, భర్తలకు నీడల్లా బతకాల్సిన పరిస్థితి, వీటన్నింటి మీదా తిరగబడాలనిపించే వారి మానసిక స్థితి- వీటిని ఛాయాదేవిగారు చాలా నేర్పుగా పట్టుకున్నారు. ఆమె కథలలో స్త్రీలు తిరుగుబాటుదార్లుగా కనిపించరు. కానీ, తిరుగుబాటుదార్లే. వారి మార్గం వేరు. తమ జీవితాలలోని అణచివేతను తప్పించుకోవడానికి వారెంచుకున్న దారులు చాలా భిన్నమైనవి. తమ జీవితాలలో పెను మార్పులు రాకుండానే మెల్లిమెల్లిగా తమకంటూ కొంత చోటు కల్పించుకుని దానిని మెల్లిగా విస్తరించుకుంటూ పోతారు. అది కుదరనపుడు కూడా 'సుఖాంతం'లో వలే నిరసన ప్రకటన చేసి నిష్క్రమిస్తారు. ఆ నిరసన ఒక తిరుగుబాటుగానే ఉంటుంది. 1991 వరకూ ఆమె కథల సంపుటి రాలేదంటే ఆశ్చర్యంగానే ఉంటుంది గానీ అది రావడానికి అది సరైన సమయం. అత్యవసర సమయం. ఏదో ఆడవాళ్ల కథలు అని పక్కన.వు0చేరా ? nntl;dr:","answer":"అబ్బూరి ఛాయాదేవిగారు ఈరోజు నుంచి కనబడరు, వినబడరు అనుకుంటే ఏమీ బాగోలేదు. కానీ, అది వాస్తవం. వాస్తవాన్ని వాస్తవంగా తీసుకోవాలని నేర్పి వెళ్ళిన మనిషి ఆమె."},{"question":"Laburtu artikulua: Irudi sinestezin hauek Falkoneria antzinako artea erakusten dute, oraindik ere Errusia, Txina eta Kazakhstanen arteko mugan dagoen mendi-eskualde gogorrean praktikatzen baita. Ehiza-metodo tradizionala Xinjiang Uygur eskualde autonomoko kulturaren zati nabarmena da, non belatz-saltzaileak urtero biltzen diren &quot;Belatzaren Herria&quot; deritzon tokian lehiatzeko. Etorkizuneko belaunaldientzako trebetasuna gordetzeko baliabide gisa, tokiko gobernuak hilero 300-500 yuaneko soldatak igortzen hasi da belatz-maisuei, haien gaitasunak transmititzera animatzeko. Joan behera bideoa ikusteko. Falconer batek bere ehiza-arranoa altxatzen du Xinjiang Uygur eskualde menditsu urrunean ospatzen den urteko jaialdian. Uygur, Kazak eta Kirgiz etniako kideek belaunaldiz belaunaldi praktikatu dute antzinako tradizioa. Urtero falkoneroak biltzen dira Akqi konderrian, Kezilesu Kirgiz prefektura autonomoan, Txinako ipar-mendebaldean. Falconer batek bere arranoa eusten dio jaialdia hasi baino lehen, non parte hartzaileak ehiza-arranoaren gaitasunak probatzeko diseinatutako hainbat lehiaketatan lehiatzen dira. Ehiztariek jantzi tradizionalak janzten dituzte, marmoka, azeri edo otso-larruz egindako larruzko berokiak eta guzti, arranoek harrapatutakoak. 2010eko azaroaz geroztik, falkoneria -gehienetan uigur, kazakia eta kirgiz etniek praktikatzen dutena- UNESCOk gizateriaren kultura-ondare immaterial gisa sartu du. Hegazti harrapari handien entrenamenduak eta manipulazioak tokiko arrano ehiztariek gordetzen saiatzen ari diren antzinako arau zorrotz bati jarraitzen diote. Arrano erraldoiekin ehizatzeko tradizioa Txina iparraldeko Mantxuriatik etorritako khitan nomadak hasi omen zuten 940. urte inguruan. Arranoak airean zehar 200 mph-ko abiaduran doaz bere atezaina lehenik heltzeko lasterketan, urteko jaialdietan. Haien ehizarako trebetasuna ere probatzen da zaldiek tiratutako haragiaren atzetik dabiltzan bitartean. Lehiaketan zehar egiten diren beste jarduera batzuk zaldi lasterketak, arku-tiroa eta Bushkashi,...","answer":"Falkoneria, ehiza-metodo tradizionala, Xinjiang Uygur eskualde autonomokoan garrantzi handiko kultura ondare gisa hartzen da. Tokiko gobernuak belatz-maisuei soldata igortzen die, antzinako trebetasuna hurrengo belaunaldiei transmititzeko. Urtero, belatz-saltzaileak \\"Belatzaren Herria\\" deritzon tokian biltzen dira lehiatzeko. Falkoneria, UNESCOk gizateriaren kultura-ondare immaterial gisa sartu du 2010etik aurrera. Arrano ehiztariek antzinako arau zorrotzak jarraitzen dituzte arrano erraldoiekin ehizatzeko. Tradizio hau 940. urte inguruan hasi zen, eta arranoak urteko jaialdietan lasterketan parte hartzen dute. Jaialdietan, zaldi lasterketak, arku-tiroa eta Bushkashi bezalako jarduera gehiago ere egiten dira."},{"question":"Напиш продолжение: В ходе Синайской кампании","answer":"«Мистэр» Бени Пеледа (к тому моменту в звании майора) был подбит египетским зенитным огнём над Рас-Назрани 29 октября 1956 года. В результате ему пришлось катапультироваться, став первым из израильских пилотов, использовавших механизм кресла-катапульты. После приземления раненый пилот несколько часов скрывался на вражеской территории, в 240 км от линии фронта, пока для его эвакуации не был прислан израильский спасательный самолёт."},{"question":"Türkiye'nin en nemli şehri neresidir?","answer":"Tunceli ili ortalama nem oranı 2013 yılı TÜİK verilerine göre 51.72 olurken, Sinop iline ait nem oranı yıllık verilere göre 86.08 olduğu görülmüştür. Karadeniz Bölgesi, en fazla yağış ve en yüksek nem oranının görüldüğü bölge konumundadır. Mutluluk düzeyi yüksek iller, genellikle bu bölgede yer almaktadır."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--जारात तुरी भट भटणीला मारी\\t","answer":"काल्पनिक गोष्टीवरुन भांडण करणे"},{"question":"Madoda! Namuhla ngithokoze kakhulu ngoba induna ayizukulalaesitokisini.Ndabezitha!Yize icala lingaphelile kodwa mina nginethemba ngoba lesi silimaesinguMbandlwa asinaye ufakazi. (iqondise kuDlamini) Awuthi qaphuqaphu ngesimo secala khona umkhandlu wami uzothola sonkeisithombe.(asukume uDlamini) Ndabezitha! Ngizoqala ngokubonga uNdabezithangokungikhokhela ibheyili. Mina bengizoyithathaphi inkulungwaneyamarandi? Ndabezitha nani bandla lenkosi, icala lokushayangiyaliphika ngima ngentaba. Ngithi, uMbandlwa ngamsikaza ngendukumaqede yena wagxuma wazishayisa echosheni lobonda lwekilasi.Okuhle kakhulu ngukuthi mina amadoda engangihamba nawoayangifakazela. Yena akanaye ufakazi ngoba ikhansela lalingaphakathiekilasini kanye nezethameli zomhlangano. Lihlehlile-ke icala. Liyozelingene emuva kwezinyanga ezintathu.(kuzwakale ukuhhomuzela kwentokozo abanye behleka)(inkosi yelule isandla sakumhlalisa phansi uDlamini) Hhayi-ke!Siyabonga Mzizi, ungahlala phansi.(ahlale phansi) Ndabezitha!Kunjalo-ke madoda. Mina ngeke ngimsole uDlamini ngoba leli khanselaliyangeyisa. Lake lakubonaphi ukuthi umfokazana angamane abizeumhlangano endaweni yenkosi engadlulanga enkosini?(ahhomuzele)Uyagcwaneka lo.Yisizwe sakho lesi Ndabezitha! Singakufela thina!(aqondise emkhandlwini) Yehlisani umoya madoda! Thulani umsindo,uNdabezitha usakhuluma!Mina ngiyasola uDuma usabambelele kulokhu okwenzekayongesikhathi sodlame. Angithi ngikhuluma nje ungomunye walabaabehla benyuka lapha endaweni yami. Begqugquzela ngenkani ukufakaleli dungabantu ababelibiza ngomzabalazo.1. Umbhali uwulandele umgomo wokubhala isingeniso. Sekela ngamaphuzuAMATHATHU. ","answer":"Uwulandele ngoba: Amaphuzu AMATHATHU kwalandelayo:• Kuvelile ukwethulwa komlingiswa oqavile esingenisweni, okunguDuma√/• Siyitholile inkinga umlingiswa oqavile abhekene nayo,okungukungemukelwa kwakhe inkosi yendawo, uShandu.√/• Isingeniso siqoqekile, sibekeke ngamagama ambalwa.√/• Isizinda siyacaca esingenisweni, okuyindawo yasemakhaya ngesikhathisanamuhla, isimo senhlalo phakathi kukaDuma nenkosi uShandu. √• Udweshu phakathi kwekhansela nenkosi luyasuka. √"},{"question":"السؤال: رمي الجمرات في الحج سنةٌ أم واجبٌ أم نسك؟","answer":"الجواب: رمي الجمرات واجبٌ في الحج."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'gayung bersambut kata berjawab'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud mengelakkan serangan musuh atau menjawab percakapan orang"},{"question":"Gịnị bụ ụfọdụ akụkọ ifo ndị a ma ama?","answer":"Ọmụmaatụ nke akụkọ ifo ndị Igbo ama ama gụnyere “Otu Mbe siri nweta Shell gbawara agbawa” na “Ihe mere eluigwe ji dị anya.”"},{"question":"स्लिष्टा क्रिया कस्यचिदात्मसंस्था संक्रान्तिरन्यस्य विशेषस्लिष्टा|यस्योभयं साधु स शिक्षकाणां धुरि प्रतीष्ठापयितव्य एव || कालिदास – मालविकाग्निमित्र","answer":"अर्थ : कोणाला [एखाद्या शिक्षकाला] स्वतःचे ज्ञान प्रशंसनीय असते. कुणाला शिकवण्याची हातोटी उत्तम असते. ज्याला या दोनही गोष्टी चांगल्या येतात त्याला निश्चितपणे अग्रस्थान दिले पाहिजे."},{"question":"અવિનાશ વ્યાસ રચિત પ્રસિદ્ધ કવિતા \\"દીકરીતો પારકી થાપણ કહેવાય\\" લખો.","answer":"બેના રે..સાસરીયે જાતાં જોજો પાંપણના ભીંજાયદીકરીતો પારકી થાપણ કહેવાયદીકરી ને ગાય, દોરે ત્યાં જાયદીકરીતો પારકી થાપણ કહેવાયબેની તારી માથે બાપનો હાથ હવે નહી ફરશેરમતી તું જે ઘરમાં એની ભીંતે-ભીંતો રડશેબેના રે.. વિદાયની આ વસમીવેળા રોકે ના રોકાયદીકરી તો પારકી થાપણ કહેવાયતારા પતિનો પડછાયો થઈ, રહેજે સદાયે સાથેસોહાગી કંકુ સેંથામાં, કંકણ શોભે હાથેબેના રે.. તારી આ વેણીનાં ફૂલો કોઈ દિ ના કરમાયદીકરી તો પારકી થાપણ કહેવાયઆમ જુઓ તો આંસુ સૌનું પાણી જેવું પાણીસુખનું છે કે દુ:ખનું એતો કોઈ શક્યું ના જાણીબેના રે.. રામ કરે સુખ તારું કોઈ દિ નજર્યું ના નજરાયદીકરી તો પારકી થાપણ કહેવાયદીકરી ને ગાય, દોરે ત્યાં જાયદીકરી તો પારકી થાપણ કહેવાય"},{"question":"C'est quoi une proposition indépendante coordonnée?","answer":" La proposition indépendante coordonnée ce sont deux propositions de même nature (indépendantes) faisant parties d’une même phrase, mais qui sont liées entre elles par une conjonction de coordination. Les conjonctions de coordination sont: mais, ou, et, donc, or, ni, car, etc. D’autres conjonctions de coordination ou locutions conjonctives sont: ainsi, aussi, cependant, en effet ensuite, par contre, pourtant, puis, soit, toutefois, néanmoins, etc. "},{"question":"Moa ve mandeha tongotra ny mpanjaka rehefa miova vohitra taloha?","answer":"Tsia, tsy mandeha tongotra ny mpanjaka taloha rehefa miova vohitra fa lanjaina."},{"question":"وضعیت جغرافیایی قاره اروپا به چه شکل است؟","answer":"پس از قارهٔ اقیانوسیه قارهٔ اروپا با ۱۰ میلیون کیلومتر مربع کوچک‌ترین قارهٔ زمین است. اروپا از شمال به اقیانوس منجمد شمالی و از جنوب به دریای مدیرانه و دریای سیاه و از طرف غرب به اقیانوس اطلس محدود شده‌ است و از سمت شرقی به قارهٔ آسیا متصل است. قارهٔ اروپا در میان مدارهای ۳۵ تا ۷۵ درجه ی جغرافیایی قرار گرفته‌ است."},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"માલણ લાવે મોગરો રે\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"માલણ લાવે મોગરો રે, કાચી કળીનો હાર;આવતાં ભીંજે ચૂંદડી,રણ મેઘ ન પડે ધાર.\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"માલણ લાવે મોગરો રે, કાચી કળીનો હાર;આવતાં ભીંજે ચૂંદડી,રણ મેઘ ન પડે ધાર.રૂપલા કેરી ઊંઢાલણી રે, સોના કેરી થાળ;પીરસે પદ્મિની પાતળી રે, તમે આરોગો નંદલાલ.ચંદ્ર વિના શી ચાંદની રે, દીવડા વિના શી રાત;હરજી વિના શી ગોઠડી, મારે જવું શામળિયા સાથ.પાંચસાત ગોપીઓ ટોળે મળી રે, ઊભી ચાંપલિયા હેઠ;છેલ કાનુડો આવશે,પેલી પાતલડીને ઘેર.આંબુડો વાવે મલગુગડો, જાંબુડો લહરે રે જાય;ભલે મળ્યો મહેતા નરસૈંનો સ્વામી, મારી હૃદયા ટાઢી થાય"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Magaalada Boosaaso Magacii Hore Ee Loo-Aqoon Jiray?","answer":"Jawaab: Magaalada Boosaaso Waxaa Loo-Aqoon Jiray Bandar Qaasim."},{"question":"Ñaata fan la jigéen di am ak dereeti mbaax ?","answer":"digante Ñett ak jurrom Ñaar"},{"question":"வினா: இந்தியாவின் முதல் 5 ஸ்டார் ஹோட்டல் எங்கு உள்ளது?","answer":"விடை:  மும்பை"},{"question":"Aşağıdaki ifadeyi tamamlayın:  Balkan Savaşı'na kendi atıyla katılan, I. Dünya Savaşı'nda","answer":"Çanakkale cephesinde çarpışan Emin Bülent Serdaroğlu cumhuriyet devrinde büyükbabası Ömer Paşa’nın unvanından hareketle “\\"Serdaroğlu\\"” soyadını aldı."},{"question":"Psikologian, nola ulertzen du pertsonalitatearen teoriak gizakien jarrera eta erreakzioak?","answer":"Pertsonalitatearen teoriak aztertzen du nola eragiten duten faktore biologikoak, sozialak eta psikologikoak gizakien jarrera eta erreakzioetan. Honek ulertzen laguntzen du gizakien portaera eta emozioen jatorria."},{"question":"Дидактика билим берүү процессин: а) начарлатат б) жакшыртат в) өзгөртпөйт г) жок кылат","answer":"Жооп: б) жакшыртат"},{"question":"تاریخي شخړو لکه د انګلیس-افغان جنګونو په پښتني ټولنه څه ډول اغیز کړی او د بهرنیو مداخلو په اړه یې د دوی مفکوره بدله کړې ده؟","answer":"پښتنه ټولنه د تاریخي شخړو، په ځانګړې توګه د انګلیس-افغان جنګونو، چې د بهرنیو مداخلو په اړه د دوی د مفکورې په جوړولو کې یې مهم رول لوبولی، د پام وړ اغیزه کړې ده. د پښتني قبایلي سیمو اکثره وخت د بهرنیو قدرتونو په وړاندې د مقاومت په سر کې وو، او جګړو د پښتنو په منځ کې د خپلواکۍ او مقاومت احساس راپاراوه. د ډیورنډ کرښه، چې په دې موده کې راښکته شوې، د روانو تاوتریخوالو سرچینه ده، چې د پښتنو هویت او د دوی تاریخي بې باوري یې د بهرنیو نفوذونو په وړاندې نوره هم اغیزمنه کړې ده. د دې شخړو د تاریخي شرایطو درک کول د پښتنو او په افغانستان کې د بهرنیو مداخلو ترمنځ د پیچلو اړیکو د پوهیدو لپاره اړین دي."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Holzapfel spelade juniorhockey för Moose Jaw Warriors i Western Hockey League (WHL). Han draftades av Atlanta Thrashers som 43:e spelare totalt i NHL Entry Draft 2006.","answer":"Den 6 september 2007 skrev Holzapfel ett treårigt ingångskontrakt med Thrashers. År 2008 spelade han för Kanada i Junior-VM där Kanada till slut vann guld efter att ha besegrat Sverige i finalen med 3-2."},{"question":"Como se chama a lei, implementada em 1871, que concedeu a liberdade a filhos de escravos nascidos no Brasil?","answer":"Lei do Ventre Livre."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina amin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Vokatra mivantana aterak'izay : miha-manan-karena ny vahôka Sinoa, mitombo ny isan’ny mpanefohefo any Chine, miakatra ny fahefa-mividy ny olona, mitombo ny filàna kanrazana Akora, mitaky farim-piainana sy fomba fiaina mifanarak amin’ny tanjan'ny firenena Sinoa.\\"","answer":"Ity ny fanambarana miaraka amin'ny hadisoana voahitsy \\"Vokatra mivantana ateraky izay : miha-manankarena ny vahoaka Sinoa, mitombo ny isan’ny mpanefoefo any Chine, miakatra ny fahefa-mividin’ny olona, mitombo ny filàna karazana Akora, mitaky fari-piainana sy fomba fiaina mifanaraka amin’ny tanjany ny firenena Sinoa.\\""},{"question":"கேள்வி: இரண்டாம் உலகப்போரின் பின்னர் தமிழ்த் திரைப்பட வரலாறு","answer":"பதில்: உலகப்போர் ஓய்ந்து இந்தியா சுதந்திரம் பெற்றபின், திரைப்படத்துறை மீண்டும் தொழில் ரீதியாக வளர ஆரம்பித்தது, திரைப்படத் தயாரிப்பு அதிகரித்தது. படங்களுக்கு வரவேற்பும் கூடியது. தமிழ்நாட்டில் கிராமப்புறங்களுக்கு மின்சார வசதி அளிக்கப்பட்டவுடன், போட்டோங் திரையரங்குகள் பெருகி, திரைப்படம் கிராமவாசிகளையும் எட்டியது. இந்த ஆண்டுகளில் சீர்திருத்தக் கருத்துக்களை உள்ளடக்கிய சில படங்கள் வெளிவந்த அதே சமயத்தில் பாதாள பைரவி (1951), கணவனே கண் கண்ட தெய்வம் (1955) போன்ற மாயாஜாலப் படங்களும் மக்களிடையே பெரும் வரவேற்பை ஏற்படுத்தின. எஸ். எஸ். வாசன் இயக்கிய சந்திரலேகா (1948) பொழுது போக்கு படங்களுக்கு சிறந்த எடுத்துக்காட்டாக விளங்கி, வியாபார ரீதியில் பெரும் வெற்றியைக் கண்டது. மாயாஜாலம், பக்தி, தமிழ்ப்பற்று இவை மூன்றும் கலந்த படைப்பாக வந்த முக்கிய படைப்புகளில் ஒன்று ஒளவையார். நாடக ஆசிரியர்களாகப் புகழ் பெற்ற சில திராவிட இயக்கத் தலைவர்கள் திரைப்படத்துறையில் ஈடுபாடுக் கொண்டனர். 1949 இல் நல்லதம்பி படத்திற்கு கதைவசனம் எழுதி சி. என். அண்ணாதுரை திரையுலகில் பிரவேசித்தார். வேலைக்காரி அவருக்கு மேலும் புகழ் சேர்த்தது. அவரைத் தொடர்ந்து மு. கருணாநிதி மந்திரி குமாரி (1950) படத்திற்கு வசனம் எழுதினார். சினிமா வரலாற்றாசிரியர்களால், திராவிட இயக்கத் திரைப்படங்கள் என்றழைக்கப்படும் திரைப்படங்கள் பலவும் இந்தக் காலகட்டத்தில் வெளிவந்தன."},{"question":"Σε ποιο σημαντικό γεγονός αναφέρεται το κείμενο: Στις 14 Ιουνίου του 2016 ημέρα κατά την οποία συμπληρώθηκαν 29 έτη από την κατάκτηση του Ευρωμπάσκετ 1987 από την εθνική Ελλάδος, το ΟΑΚΑ μετονομάστηκε σε κλειστό γυμναστήριο \\"Νίκος Γκάλης\\".","answer":"Μετονομασία του ΟΑΚΑ, σε κλειστό γυμναστήριο \\"Νίκος Γκάλης\\"."},{"question":"नेपाली हामी रहौंला कहाँ - राष्ट्रकवि माधवप्रसाद घिमिरेको रचना","answer":"नेपाली हामी रहौंला कहाँ, नेपालै न रहे।...उचाई हाम्रो चुलिन्छ कहाँ, हिमालै न रहे।...तराई हाम्रो सुनका टुक्रा, हिमाल हिरा हो।माटो र पानी पहिलो धन, धर्तीका छोरा को।ये कहाँ बाट संसार हेर्छौ, सम्झनै  नरहे।...दशैं र तिहार रमाइलो हाम्रो चुटका र ख्यालीले।हृदय हाम्रो जुर्मुराउञ्छ, जीत को जाली ले।बैशको तालमा नाचौला कहाँ, मादलै न रहे।...ये कति राम्रो बिहानी पख, घाम को रेखी हो।सभ्यता पहिलो संसारमा फैल्यो,हिमाल देखि हो।बिउझौला कहाँ पूर्वको पहिलो, उज्यालै न रहे।...नेपाली हामी रहौंला कहाँ, नेपालै न रहे।..."},{"question":"Alin sa mga numerong ito ang hindi kabilang sa grupo: 48, 30, 64, 96 o 8?","answer":"Hindi kabilang ang 30 sa grupo dahil ito lamang ang numero na hindi divisible sa 4."},{"question":"Qual filme mais ganhou oscar?","answer":"Ben-hur, Titanic e O Senhor dos Anéis: O Retorno do Rei são os filmes que mais venceram o oscar. O três filmes receberam um total de onze prêmios nos anos 1960, 1998 e 2004, respectivamente."},{"question":"प्रोटिस्टा की विशेषताएँ बताइये।","answer":"(ए) जीव एककोशिकीय और यूकेरियोटिक होते हैं।(बी) गति के लिए उपांगों का उपयोग करें जैसे सिलिया, फ्लैगेला, आदि।(सी) पोषण या तो स्वपोषी या विषमपोषी होता है।(डी) जैसे, शैवाल, प्रोटोजोआ।"},{"question":"Awọn ajinigbe ji Alaga gbe lọna oko rẹ l’Oke-Onigbin, ni Kwara","answer":"Oniṣowo pataki kan, Alhaji Alaga Ọlayẹmi, lawọn ajinigbe bii meje ji gbe l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, lọna oko rẹ niluu Oke-Onigbin, nijọba ibilẹ Isin, nipinlẹ Kwara.Alaga atawọn ọmọọṣẹ rẹ to tẹle e lawọn ajinigbe naa fibọn da lọna ni nnkan bii aago meje irọlẹ. Gbogbo akitiyan awọn to kọwọọrin pẹlu ọkunrin naa lati doola ẹmi rẹ lo ja si pabo, ṣe lawọn ajinigbe naa gbe e lọ raurau.Titi di asiko yii, ko ti i sẹni to mọ pato ibi to wa.Awọn oṣiṣẹ rẹ mejeeji to wa pẹlu rẹ lọjọ naa paapaa ko fara ire lọ, ṣe lawọn ajinigbe naa ṣa wọn lada yannayanna lasiko ti wọn n gbiyanju lati wọya ija pẹlu wọn lọna ati gba ọga wọn silẹ.ALAROYE gbọ pe awọn ọdẹ ilu pẹlu awọn agbofinro kan ti ya wọ inu igbo to wa lagbegbe tiṣẹlẹ naa ti ṣẹlẹ lati gba ọkunrin ti wọn ji gbe naa pada.Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Kwara, Ajayi Ọkasanmi, to fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ ni Ọga ọlọpaa, CP Mohammed Lawal Bagega, ti gbe ikọ kan dide lati doola Alaga, ati lati mu awọn ọdaran naa."},{"question":"Số đối của 8 là số nào trong 4 câu dưới đây?A. – 8B. 0C. 8D. 16","answer":"Ta có số đối của 8 là – 8.Chọn đáp án A."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo ranomasimbe dimy eto an-tany?","answer":"Ny ranomasimbe dimy eto an-tany dia ny Ranomasimbe Pasifika, ny Ranomasimbe Atlantika, ny Ranomasimbe Indianina, ny Ranomasimbe Arktika ary ny Ranomasimbe Atsimo (na Ranomasimbe Antarctica). Mandrakotra ny ankamaroan’ny velaran-tany ireo rano midadasika ireo ary manana anjara toerana lehibe amin’ny fandrindrana ny toetrandro."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _ \\" Lainga toahiny salaka ny tompony ihany _\\"","answer":" Lainga toahiny salaka ny tompony ihany afatony"},{"question":"ਇੰਦੌਰ, 27 ਫਰਵਰੀਸੂਚਨਾ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ (ਆਰਟੀਆਈ) ਤਹਿਤ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਸੂਚਨਾ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੇ ਕਰਜ਼ਦਾਤਾ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸਟੇਟ ਬੈਂਕ (ਐੱਸਬੀਆਈ) ਵਿਚ ਮੌਜੂਦਾ ਵਿੱਤੀ ਵਰ੍ਹੇ ਦੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਨੌ ਮਹੀਨਿਆਂ (ਅਪਰੈਲ-ਦਸੰਬਰ 2018) ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕੁੱਲ 7,951.29 ਕਰੋੜ ਰੁਪਏ ਦੀ ਬੈਂਕਿੰਗ ਧੋਖਾਧੜੀ ਦੇ 1,885 ਮਾਮਲੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਏ ਹਨ। ਮੱਧ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਨੀਮਚ ਵਾਸੀ ਆਰਟੀਆਈ ਕਾਰਕੁਨ ਚੰਦਰਸ਼ੇਖਰ ਗੌੜ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਪਾਈ ਆਰਟੀਆਈ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਤੀ ਵਰ੍ਹੇ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਤਿਮਾਹੀ (ਅਪਰੈਲ-ਜੂਨ 2018) ਵਿਚ ਬੈਂਕ ’ਚ ਕੁੱਲ 723.06 ਕਰੋੜ ਰੁਪਏ ਦੀ ਬੈਂਕਿੰਗ ਧੋਖਾਧੜੀ ਦੇ 669 ਮਾਮਲੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਏ ਹਨ। ਦੂਜੀ ਤਿਮਾਹੀ (ਜੁਲਾਈ-ਸਤੰਬਰ 2018) ਵਿਚ ਕੁੱਲ 4832.42 ਕਰੋੜ ਰੁਪਏ ਦੀ ਧੋਖਾਧੜੀ ਨਾਲ ਸਬੰਧਤ 660 ਮਾਮਲੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਏ ਹਨ। ਆਰਟੀਆਈ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲੀ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਮੌਜੂਦਾ ਵਿੱਤੀ ਵਰ੍ਹੇ ਦੀ ਤੀਸਰੀ ਤਿਮਾਹੀ (ਅਕਤੂਬਰ-ਦਸੰਬਰ 2018) ਦੌਰਾਨ ਐੱਸਬੀਆਈ ਵਿਚ 2395.81 ਕਰੋੜ ਰੁਪਏ ਦੀ ਬੈਂਕਿੰਗ ਧੋਖਾਧੜੀ ਦੇ 556 ਮਾਮਲੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਏ ਹਨ। ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਕਾਰਕੁਨ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਆਰਟੀਆਈ ਅਰਜ਼ੀ ਵਿਚ ਬੈਂਕ ਤੋਂ ਖਾਸ ਤੌਰ ’ਤੇ ਇਹ ਵੀ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਅਪਰੈਲ-ਦਸੰਬਰ 2018 ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਗਾਹਕ ਬੈਂਕਿੰਗ ਧੋਖਾਧੜੀ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਿਕਾਰ ਹੋਏ ਤੇ ਇਸ ਵਜ੍ਹਾ ਨਾਲ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਿੰਨੀ ਰਕਮ ਦਾ ਨੁਕਸਾਨ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ। ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਬੈਂਕ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨ ’ਤੇ ਆਰਟੀਆਈ ਐਕਟ ਦਾ ਹਵਾਲਾ ਦਿੰਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਵਿਸ਼ੇ ’ਤੇ ਮੰਗੀ ਗਈ ਸੂਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਖ਼ੁਲਾਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਛੋਟ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੈ।ਐੱਸਬੀਆਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੈਂਕਿੰਗ ਧੋਖਾਧੜੀ ਦੇ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਏ ਹਨ?","answer":"ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸਟੇਟ ਬੈਂਕ (ਐੱਸਬੀਆਈ) ਵਿਚ ਮੌਜੂਦਾ ਵਿੱਤੀ ਵਰ੍ਹੇ ਦੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਨੌ ਮਹੀਨਿਆਂ (ਅਪਰੈਲ-ਦਸੰਬਰ 2018) ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕੁੱਲ 7,951.29 ਕਰੋੜ ਰੁਪਏ ਦੀ ਬੈਂਕਿੰਗ ਧੋਖਾਧੜੀ ਦੇ 1,885 ਮਾਮਲੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਏ ਹਨ। "},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta ɗari biyu da hamsin a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 250"},{"question":"Ny landy hala dia nampiasaina taloha mba hanaovana tady gitara.","answer":"Tsia. Ny landy hala fanaovana tady ny lokanga."},{"question":"下文是關於什麼重大事件: 2016年6月12日約上午2:00至5:00（北美东部时区UTC-4），美国佛罗里达州奥兰多南奥兰治大道1912号，29歲阿富汗裔伊斯兰国恐怖分子奥马尔·马丁使用格洛克17（和一枝SIG MCX半自动步枪），在佛羅里達州奧蘭多「脈動」同志酒吧中開槍殺死至少49人並擊傷53人，直到他在與警方的交火中被擊殺為止。這是美國歷史上最嚴重的大規模槍擊事件，死傷人數僅次於911恐怖攻擊事件。","answer":"911恐怖攻擊事件"},{"question":"翻译下面的古文：钱金玉官松江千总，性刚果，尚廉节。道光壬寅鸦片衅起，钱方假归省亲，闻讯，即束装起行。其亲友尼之曰：“军事方急，祸福不可知。君方在假，上官又未有文檄趣君往，何急急为?”钱不听。既至吴淞，从守西炮台，与部卒同饮食卧起，以力战相勖。及东炮台陷，弹丸咸集于西炮台。钱奋勇督战，喋血数小时，左臂中三弹，曾不少却。其近卒泣陈：“公有老母在，不可死。”笑谢曰：“焉有食国之禄而逃其难者乎?幸勿为吾母虑也!”未几，一弹来，中左乳，遂仆。弥留之际，犹大呼“贼奴误国”不置。","answer":"钱金玉做松江县的千总官，性情刚毅果敢，崇尚廉洁的气节。道光壬寅年间(1842年)鸦片战争爆发。钱金玉正在休假回乡探亲，听到消息，立即收拾行装动身。他的亲友阻止他说：“战事正紧急，是祸是福不可知晓，您正在休假，上级官员又没有文件催促您前去，为什么急急忙忙地回去呢?”钱金玉不听，回到吴淞口后，就跟从军队守卫西炮台，和士兵一起吃饭睡觉，一起行动，他们用努力作战的话相互勉励。到了东炮台陷落后，枪弹炮弹全都落到西炮台。钱金玉奋勇指挥战斗，浴血奋战几个小时，左臂中了三弹，却毫不后退。他身边的士兵哭着说：“您有老母亲在，不能死。”钱金玉笑着辞谢说：“哪里有享受国家俸禄却在国家有难时逃避的道理呢?希望你不要为我母亲担心。”不久，一颗枪弹飞来，击中了左胸，他于是倒下了。在临死的时候，他还大喊“卖国贼害了国家”不停。"},{"question":"Sino ang nanalo sa FIFA Women's World Cup sa taong 2023?","answer":"Ang women's team ng Spain ang nanalo as FIFA Women's World Cup sa taong 2023. Natalo ng Spain ang koponan ng England na may final score na 1-0 sa finals ng liga  noong Agosto 20, 2023 sa Sydney, Australia."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਿਐ ਵਡੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ॥ਹਰਿ ਜੀ ਅਚਿੰਤੁ ਵਸੈ ਮਨਿ ਆਈ ॥ਹਰਿ ਜੀਉ ਸਫਲਿਓ ਬਿਰਖੁ ਹੈ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਜਿਨਿ ਪੀਤਾ ਤਿਸੁ ਤਿਖਾ ਲਹਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ਹਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਜੀਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਸਚੁ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਮੇਲਿ ਮਿਲਾਵਣਿਆ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਆਪੇ ਮੇਲੈ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੀ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵੀ ਸਬਦਿ ਸੁਹਾਇਆ ॥ਜਿਨਿ ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਮੰਨਿ ਵਸਾਇਆ ॥ਹਰਿ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਹਉਮੈ ਮੈਲੁ ਗਵਾਏ ਦਰਿ ਸਚੈ ਸੋਭਾ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੨॥ਬਿਨੁ ਗੁਰ ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾਇ ॥ਸਿਧ ਸਾਧਿਕ ਰਹੇ ਬਿਲਲਾਇ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਗੁਰ ਸੇਵੇ ਸੁਖੁ ਨ ਹੋਵੀ ਪੂਰੈ ਭਾਗਿ ਗੁਰੁ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੩॥ਇਹੁ ਮਨੁ ਆਰਸੀ ਕੋਈ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਵੇਖੈ ॥ਮੋਰਚਾ ਨ ਲਾਗੈ ਜਾ ਹਉਮੈ ਸੋਖੈ ॥ਅਨਹਤ ਬਾਣੀ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਸਬਦੁ ਵਜਾਏ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੀ ਸਚਿ ਸਮਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੪॥ਬਿਨੁ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਕਿਹੁ ਨ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਜਾਇ ॥ਗੁਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਿ ਆਪੁ ਦਿਤਾ ਦਿਖਾਇ ॥ਆਪੇ ਆਪਿ ਆਪਿ ਮਿਲਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਸਹਜੇ ਸਹਜਿ ਸਮਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੫॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਹੋਵੈ ਸੁ ਇਕਸੁ ਸਿਉ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਏ ॥ਦੂਜਾ ਭਰਮੁ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦਿ ਜਲਾਏ ॥ਕਾਇਆ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਵਣਜੁ ਕਰੇ ਵਾਪਾਰਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਨਿਧਾਨੁ ਸਚੁ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੬॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਕਰਣੀ ਹਰਿ ਕੀਰਤਿ ਸਾਰੁ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਪਾਏ ਮੋਖ ਦੁਆਰੁ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਰੰਗਿ ਰਤਾ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵੈ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਮਹਲਿ ਬੁਲਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੭॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਦਾਤਾ ਮਿਲੈ ਮਿਲਾਇਆ ॥ਪੂਰੈ ਭਾਗਿ ਮਨਿ ਸਬਦੁ ਵਸਾਇਆ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮੁ ਮਿਲੈ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਹਰਿ ਸਚੇ ਕੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੮॥੯॥੧੦॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 114 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੇ (ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦਾ) ਆਸਰਾ-ਪਰਨਾ ਬਣਾ ਲਏ, ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਭਾਰੀ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਵਾਲੀ ਕੋਈ ਚਿੰਤਾ ਪੋਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਮਾਨੋ) ਇਕ ਫਲਦਾਰ ਰੁੱਖ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਚੋਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ (ਉਹ ਰਸ) ਪੀ ਲਿਆ, ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ) ਤ੍ਰੇਹ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ ।੧।ਮੈਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਹਾਂ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਹਾਂ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਤੋਂ), ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਸਾਧ-ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਾ ਕੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਜੋੜ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਦਾ ਮੇਲ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਆਸਰਾ-ਪਰਨਾ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਮੇਰਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਸੰਵਾਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੈ, ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ ਮੈਲ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ) ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਸੋਭਾ ਖੱਟਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਗੁਰੂ (ਦੀ ਸਰਨ) ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਪਰ ਜੋਗ-ਸਾਧਨ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਤੇ ਜੋਗ-ਸਾਧਨ ਵਿਚ ਪੁੱਗੇ ਹੋਏ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਜੋਗੀ ਤਰਲੇ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਰਹਿ ਗਏ,ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਆਉਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣਦਾ, ਵੱਡੀ ਕਿਸਮਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਮਨ ਆਰਸੀ (ਲੋੋਕਨਿਗ-ਗਲੳਸਸ) ਸਮਾਨ ਹੈ (ਇਸ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਵੇਖ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ) ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਵੇਖਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਏ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਲੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਇਸ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਹਉਮੈ ਦਾ ਜੰਗਾਲ ਲੱਗਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ)ਜਦੋਂ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਹਉਮੈ ਮੁਕਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ (ਫਿਰ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਹਉਮੈ ਦਾ) ਜੰਗਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗਦਾ (ਤੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖ-ਪਰਖ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ) ।(ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਬਾਣੀ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਨੂੰ ਇਕ-ਰਸ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਪ੍ਰਬਲ ਕਰੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਕਿਸੇ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਭੀ (ਆਪਣਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ) ਵੇਖਿਆ-ਪਰਖਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ,(ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਖਾਇਆ ਹੈ) ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ (ਹੀ) ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਉਸਦਾ) ਆਪਣਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਿਖਾਇਆ ਹੈ ।(ਫਿਰ ਉਸ ਵਡਭਾਗੀ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਨਿਸਚਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਵਿਆਪਕ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ (ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪੇ ਦੀ ਵੇਖ-ਪਰਖ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਸਦਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੫।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਪਾਈ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ,ਉਹ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਮਾਇਆ ਵਾਲੀ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ (ਭਾਵ, ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਬਾਹਰ ਭਟਕਣੋਂ ਰੋਕ ਕੇ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਵਣਜ ਵਪਾਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ-ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੬।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਕਰਨ-ਜੋਗ ਕੰਮ ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੈ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਸ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਟ ਉੱਦਮ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਉਹ (ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਖ਼ਲਾਸੀ ਦਾ ਦਰਵਾਜ਼ਾ ਲੱਭ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਹ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ-ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗਿਆ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਬੁਲਾਈ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜੋੜੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ) ।ਗੁਰੂ ਹੀ (ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ, ਨਾਮ ਦੀ) ਦਾਤ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ (ਪਰ ਗੁਰੂ ਤਦੋਂ ਹੀ) ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜਦੋਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ) ਮਿਲਾਏ ।(ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ) ਪੂਰੀ ਕਿਸਮਤਿ ਨਾਲ (ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ) ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਸਾਈ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੮।੯।੧੦।\\""},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 北朝鮮の「人工衛星」　沖縄の上を通る危険がある","answer":"北朝鮮は29日、「人工衛星を5月31日から6月11日の間に打ち上げる」と日本に言いました。日本の政府は、北朝鮮が「人工衛星」と呼んでいる物はミサイルだと考えています。そして、2016年と同じように、沖縄県の先島諸島の上の空を通る可能性があると考えています。防衛省の浜田大臣は、日本に何かが落ちてきたときのために、撃つ準備をするように自衛隊に言いました。政府は、アメリカや韓国と協力して、情報を集めると言っています。そして、必要な場合は「Jアラート」を出して、危険な場所にいる人に避難するように言います。"},{"question":"ஒகேனக்கல் அருவியில் நீர் வீழ்வது _____________ உருக்கி ஊற்றுவது போல் இருந்தது.(அ) தங்கத்தை(ஆ) வெள்ளியை(இ) இரும்பை(ஈ) கற்பாறையை","answer":"(ஆ) வெள்ளியை"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండికొల్లాయిడ్ల శుద్ధి ప్రక్రియను  డయాలిసిస్ దృగ్విషయం లేదా ఘటన ద్వారా వివరించండి.","answer":"డయాలిసిస్ :ఇది అనువైన పటలం లేదా పొరను ఉపయోగించి కరిగే (ద్రావణీయ) స్థితిలో ఉండే పదార్థాలను కొల్లాయిడ్ ద్రావణం నుంచి తొలగించే ప్రక్రియ. నిజ ద్రావణంలో ఉండే అయాన్లు, లఘు అణువులు జంతుపటలం (బ్లాడర్) లేదా పార్చిమెంట్ కాగితం లేదా సెల్లోఫేస్ రేకు ద్వారా పోగల్గుతాయి. కాని కొల్లాయిడ్ కణాలు వీటిగుండా పోలేవు కాబట్టి ఈ పొరలను ఉపయోగించి డయాలిసిస్ అంటారు. కొల్లాయిడ్ ద్రావణంతో నింపిన అనువైన పటలంతో పాత్రలో ముంచి ఉంచుతారు. అణువులు అయాన్లు పటలం ద్వారా వ్యాపనం చెంది పాత్రలోని నీటిలోకి పోతాయి. సంచిలో శుద్ధ కొల్లాయిడ్ ద్రావణం మిగిలిఉంటుంది."},{"question":"竹子是","answer":"草"},{"question":"Gani Adams ni bi Akeredolu ṣe le awọn Fulani darandaran kuro ninu igbo ọba l’Ondo lo dara ju","answer":"Iba Gani Adams tí sọ pe ojuṣe ati ẹtọ Gomina Rótìmí Akeredolu ni lati le awon janduku Fulani darandaran kuro nipinlẹ Ondo.Ninu atẹjade ti Olùrànlọwọ Ààrẹ Ọnakakanfo,  Alhaji Kehinde Aderẹmi, fi sita lo ti ni Ìbá Gani Adams sọ pe ojuṣe gomina ọhun ni labẹ ofin lati pèsè ààbò tó yẹ fun awọn eeyan ipinlẹ ẹ, ati pe kaakiri ipinlẹ Ondo lawọn alejo ọran kan ti wa bayii ti wọn n ko idaamu nla ba araalu.Lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, ni Akeredolu pàṣẹ fún gbogbo àwọn Fulani darandaran ti wọn wa lawọn inu Igbo ti ijọba ti ya sọtọ ki wọn ko àwọn maaluu wọn kúrò níbẹ, bẹẹ lo fún wọn lọjọ meje pẹlu lati fi ṣe e.Bi ikede yii ti waye ni ijọba Buhari ti bẹ jade, to sì sọ pé amofin agba ni Akeredolu, ẹni tó si yẹ ko mọ òfin dáadáa ni. Buhari sọ pe igbesẹ to fẹẹ gbe ọhun ko ba oun lara mu rara. Siwaju si i, ijọba Buhari ti ni ki Akeredolu fi awọn Fulani silẹ l’Ondo, ko tete wa ọna mi-ìn gba lori bi aabo yóò ṣe wà dipo bo ṣe fẹẹ le wọn danu.Ọrọ yii lo mu Gani Adams sọ pe Buhari ko wíire, nitori ohun ti Garba Shehu sọ lorukọ rẹ, bíi ẹni to fẹẹ máa dunkooko mọ ijọba Rotimi Akeredolu ni, bẹẹ lo tun fẹẹ fọrọ ọhun yẹpẹrẹ ijọba ẹ paapaa lori ọrọ aabo.Ọkunrin naa ni bo tilẹ jẹ pé lara dukia ijọba àpapọ̀ ni awọn igbo ti wọn ya sọtọ wa, sibẹ, abẹ àkóso ijọba ipinlẹ lo wa.O ni,”Ohun to foju hàn ni pé Garba Shehu ati ọfiisi Ààrẹ paapaa ko mọ ìtumọ igbo ti ijọba ya sọtọ yìí. Iru igbo yìí kì í ṣe ibí tí ẹnikẹni le wọ, afi awọn ti wọn ba gbaṣẹ lati ṣe bẹẹ, bẹẹ lo tun jẹ aaye pàtàkì tí awọn ohun amuṣọrọ bíi igi to niye lori ati aaye pàtàkì fún àwọn eranko wa.“Iwa afojudi gbaa lawọn Fulani darandaran ti wọn n da ẹran kiri inu igbo yẹn n hu. Bi wọn ṣe n gbe inu igbo yẹn, wọn kò ní i bikita lati bẹ awọn igi olowo iyebiye to wa ninu awọn Igbo yii fi dana. Bakan naa ni wọn tun le pa awọn ẹran inu igbo ọhun paapaa.“Nibi ti wọn ba pe ni igbo ti ijọba ya sọtọ ki í ṣe ibí tó yẹ ki ẹnikẹni máa gbé, koda to fi dori awọn agbẹ ọmọ ipinlẹ Ondo paapaa.Ninu ọrọ ẹ naa lo ti sọ pe lara wahala ti awọn janduku Fulani agbebọnrin yìí ṣe naa ni bí wọn ṣe pa ọmọ Alagba Fasoranti, ti wọn tun kọ lu Alagba Falae, ti awọn ọba meji paapaa fara gba ninu iwa janduku wọn l’Ondo. Gani Adams sọ pe “Agbegbe Akoko ni mo ti wa, gbogbo igbo ti ijọba ya sọtọ ni awọn darandaran ti gba pata, ohun ti ijọba Akeredolu ṣe yíi dun mọ wa ninu daadaa.”Ni bayii, Iba ti ke sí gbogbo ọmọ Yorùbá pata lati fọwọsowọpọ pẹlu awọn gomina ilẹ Yoruba lati gbógun ti awọn janduku Fulani darandaran ti wọn n da ilẹ Yoruba laamu.Gomina Akeredolu naa ti sọ pe oun ṣì duro lori ọrọ ti oun sọ yii pe ki awọn Fulani darandaran atawọn maaluu ti wọn fi n jẹ ko kuro ni igbo ọba  l’Ondo."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"belum disuruh, sudah pergi, belum dipanggil, sudah datang\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang faham akan maksud sesuatu isyarat. Contoh ayat: Sikap Ali yang sangat rajin seperti kata pepatah belum disuruh, sudah pergi, belum dipanggil, sudah datang membuatkan dia disukai majikannya."},{"question":"¿Cuál fue el segundo sol según la mitología azteca?","answer":"Quetzalcóatl fue el sol de la segunda edad, habitada por hombres-mono, que se alimentaban de piñones. Quetzalcóatl fue el sol durante 675 años, hasta que Tezcatlipoca lo derribó y levantó un fuerte viento que se llevó a Quetzalcóatl y los hombres-mono"},{"question":"Inona no hevitra fonosin'ny « fampandroana ny maty » eo amin'ny Malagasy ?","answer":"Ny hevitra fonosin'ny « fampandroana ny maty » eo amin'ny Malagasy dia :- fahadiovana,- fampidirana azy ho amin'ny tontolon'ny maty fanesorana ny momba ny velona rehetra hiapitany amin'ny tontolon'ny razana,- fanaovana adidy farany ho an'ny maty."},{"question":"Ibo 1979 ku si dẹdẹ, n lawọn adigunjale ba ko girigiri ba awọn oloṣelu atijọba Ọbasanjọ (3)","answer":"Igba kan ti wa nilẹ yii to jẹ iṣẹ ọlọpaa a maa wuuyan i ṣe, nitori awọn ọlọpaa Naijiria ni apọnle lara pupọ. Ti kinni kan ba ṣẹlẹ to jẹ nnkan aidaa, ti wọn ba ti pe wọn si i, bii ọmọde-meji-n-ṣere ni wọn yoo ti wadii ọrọ naa, ti wọn yoo si tu aṣiri ohun gbogbo to ṣẹlẹ sita. Bi ọrọ awọn adigunjale to ja N80,000, owo ileeṣẹ Boulos, gba, ti wọn pa ọlọpaa meji, ti wọn si ri i pe ọkan to ku fara pa gidigidi, ṣe ri gan-an niyẹn. Nitori pe ọrọ naa ko jinnijinni ba gbogbo ilu, lẹsẹkẹsẹ lawọn ọlọpaa yii ti bẹ sita, nigba ti yoo si fi to ọsẹ kan bayii, aṣiri ọrọ naa ti bẹrẹ si i tu si wọn lọwọ. Bẹẹ ki i ṣe pe awọn adigunjale naa duro soju kan, wọn ko duro rara. Bi wọn ti ja owo ọhun gba ni wọn sare pade ara wọn nibi kan ti wọn ti ṣeto ni Ọgba. Nibẹ ni wọn fi ipade si, nibẹ ni gbogbo wọn si ti pin owo ti wọn ja gba naa, ti kaluku ba tirẹ lọ.Bi wọn ṣe pin owo naa ni pe Nelson Diefah ti i ṣe ọga iṣẹ yii gba ẹgbẹrun mejila Naira, Sam Dag, iyẹn Youperer Dakoru, gba ẹgbẹrun mejila, eyi ti wọn n pe ni Igun (Vulture) ninu wọn naa gba ẹgbẹrun mejila, Boniface, ti Albert naa si gba ẹgbẹrun mejila mejila, Umukoro gba ẹgbẹrun mẹwaa, William Douglas naa si gba ẹgbẹrun mẹwaa to wa fun oun ati awọn ti wọn ba wọn wa iṣẹ naa. Bi wọn ti pin owo naa tan ni kaluku da ibọn pada fẹni to ni wọn, wọn si fọnka bii ẹni ti ko tilẹ mọra ri, tabi bii ẹni to ti paayan meji laaarọ ọjọ naa, wọn gba ile wọn lọ. Bi awọn ọlọpaa ti de ibi iṣẹlẹ naa ti wọn si ko awọn oku to ku, ti wọn ṣa awọn ọta ti wọn lo nibẹ, wọn ti ri awọn ohun mẹta kan. Akọkọ ni pe ọna ti wọn gba ṣe iṣẹ naa fi han pe awọn ti wọn mọ nipa iṣẹ ologun ni wọn ṣe e, ẹẹkeji si ni pe ọta ibọn awọn ṣọja ni wọn lo.Eyi ni pe ọrọ naa ti fẹsẹ mulẹ lọna tibẹ yẹn. Awọn ọlọpaa ti mọ pe bi ko ba jẹ awọn ti wọn ṣi wa ninu iṣẹ ologun ni wọn ṣiṣẹ yii, aa jẹ awọn ti wọn ti kuro nibẹ, boya wọn le wọn tabi wọn lọ funra wọn. Ọna kẹta si ni pe ọrọ naa ko le ṣẹlẹ bi ko ba ni ọwọ araale ninu. Wọn mọ pe kinni naa ti bọ soju ẹ ju. Bawo ni wọn ṣe mọ pe wọn n gbe owo lọ? Ki lo de ti wọn ko da mọto mi-in duro to jẹ eyi to n gbowo lọ gan-an ni wọn da duro? Bawo ni wọn ṣe mọ iye ọlọpaa to wa ninu ẹ ati ibi towo wa? Awọn ọlọpaa mọ pe ko sẹni to le fun awọn adigunjale ni itọsọna yii ju araale to ti mọ bi wọn ti n gbowo kuro ni ileeṣẹ Boulos ati igba ti wọn n gbe e lọ.  Nidii eyi, awọn oṣiṣẹ ileeṣe Boulos ti wọn wa ninu mọtọ funra wọn ni wọn kọkọ mu, ti wọn si rọ wọn da sitimọle lẹsẹkẹsẹ, paapaa akauntanti ileeṣẹ naa to n gbowo ọhun lọ.Nibi ti wọn ti n tẹ akauntanti wọn yii ati dẹrẹba mi-in ti wọn tun mu ninu ni wọn ti tule kan Johnson Ibekwe. Kuku (cook) ni Ibekwe, ọdọ ọga kan ninu awọn ọga ileeṣẹ naa lo si ti n ṣiṣẹ, iṣẹ ile ni iṣẹ ẹ, ki i ṣe gbogbo igba ni i wa sinu ọgba. Ṣugbọn lọjọ iṣẹlẹ yii, wọn ri kuku naa nibi iṣẹ, koda o wa ninu awọn to ran wọn lọwọ lati gbe owo sọkọ. Nigba tawọn ọlọpaa yoo fi gbọ eyi ṣaa o, ti wọn yoo si sare pe ki wọn wa Ibekwe lọ, ẹran ti lọ! Ko dagbere to fi sa lọ si ilu wọn, ni ilẹ ibo lọhun-un. Lẹsẹkẹsẹ tawọn ọlọpaa gbọ naa ni wọn ti gbe mọto jana, nigba ti yoo si di ọjo keji, wọn kan an lara ni Uzuakoli, nipinlẹ Imo, nibẹ ni wọn ti gbe e janto. Wọn beere pe ki lo waa ṣe nile, o ni oun sare waa wo iyawo oun to loyun ni, nitori oun gbọ pe ara rẹ ko ya. Ki lo waa de ti ko dagdere, o ni ko si ọga oun nile, iyawo rẹ loun dagbere fun.Nibi yii lọrọ ti bẹrẹ si i loju o, nitori nigba ti wọn wọ Ibekwe de Eko, kia lo bẹrẹ ẹjọ ẹnu ẹ bii ẹni ti wọn ti irin gbigbona bọ labẹ, oun lo si fa wọn de ile Jimmy, nigba ti wọn ko si ri Jimmy, o mu wọn, o di ile Nelson Diefoh, ẹni to wa nidii eto gbogbo. Aarin ọsẹ kan ni wọn fi ṣe gbogbo eleyii, nigba ti wọn si ti ri Diefah, to jẹ ibi kan ti ko loluwa ninu ile Festac lo n gbe, ti wọn si mọ pe ṣọja to sa lẹnu iṣẹ ni, wọn ti mọ pe ẹni ti awọn n wa niyẹn, ki awọn mu un daadaa lo ku. Nibi yii lawọn ọlọpaa ti bẹrẹ iṣẹ wọn. Nigba ti iya dun Diefah yii, o jẹwọ fun wọn, o loun gan-an lọga ẹgbẹ adigunjale naa, ko si sohun to ṣẹlẹ lọjọ yii toun ko mọ, bi wọn ba ni suuru, oun yoo ṣalaye gbogbo rẹ fun wọn. N ni Diefah ba tẹnu bọrọ loootọ, oun lo si jẹ ki wọn mọ bi ọrọ naa ṣe lọ. O ni loootọ oun loun dari idigunale naa, ṣugbọn oun kilọ gidi fawọn eeyan oun pe wọn ko gbọdo paayan, Sam Dag ni ko gbọrọ soun lẹnu to fi ba gbogbo nnkan jẹ.Nibi yii lawọn ọlọpaa ti bẹrẹ si i wa Sam Dag, ki wọn too ṣẹṣẹ waa mọ pe ẹni ti awọn ti n wa tẹlẹ ni, orukọ rẹ gan-an si ni Youpere Dakuro. Wọn n wa a nitori o sa jade kuro ni sẹẹli Adeniji Adele ni, oun ati awọn ọdaran kan ni wọn jọ ja ilẹkun-irin ibẹ, ti wọn si sa jade lọjọ kọkanla, oṣu kẹta, ọdun naa, iyẹn ni pe bii ọsẹ kẹta to sa kuro ni sẹẹli  lo lọọ ba wọn jale, to si pa ọlọpaa meji. Ohun to jẹ ko wa ni sẹẹli ni pe wọn ti digunjale kan ni Badagiri tẹlẹ, nibẹ lo ti pa ọlọpaa kan, iyẹn ni wọn n tori ẹ ba a ṣẹjọ to fi wa ni sẹẹli, ko too di pe wọn jalẹkun jade. Nigba ti wọn beere bo ṣe sa jade lẹwọn, o ni ki i ṣe oun loun ṣeto ẹ, ọkan ninu awọn ọdaran to wa nibẹ to n jẹ Lobito ni, nigba ti oun si ri awọn ẹlẹwọn to ku ti wọn n sa jade, ko si bi oun ṣe le maa duro woran, n loun naa ṣe sa jade. O ni Ṣaṣa, nitosi Agege, loun sa lọ.Bẹẹ si ni, ni Ṣaṣa lawọn ọlọpaa ti lọọ tu u jade, Diefa lo mu wọn dele ẹ nigba tawọn ọlọpaa ṣe ṣege fun un. Ọrẹ lawọn mejeeji. Ọrẹ gidi ni wọn paapaa. Nigba  ti Dakuro jade lẹwọn to farapa rẹpẹtẹ, Dieah lo mu un lọ si ọdọ wolii kan, Pasitọ Samson Amosun, ẹni to ni ṣọọṣi rẹ si Ojule kẹrindinlọgbọn, Opopo Ọlanibi, ni Papa Ajao,  Muṣin. Diefah sọ fun Amosun pe ijamba mọto ni Dakuro ni, ko ba oun gbadura fun un ko le gbadun. Niyẹn ba bẹrẹ adura loootọ, nigba ti wọn si gbadura tan, wọn lọ. Ko pẹ ni Diefoh tun pada lọ si ọdọ pasitọ naa, to ni oun fẹ ko gbadura foun ki oun ba ojurere awọn ọlọpaa pade, nitori onimọto loun, tirela meji loun si ni lọna, oun fẹ ki wọn gbadura ki awọn mọto naa lọ daadaa, ki won bọ daadaa. Ni Pasitọ Amosun ba tun bẹrẹ adura, adura ti pasitọ yii gba, ati ogoji Naira (N40) ti wọn fun un lo sọ ọ di ero atimọle, diẹ lo si ku ki wọn mu un mọ awọn adigunjale naa.Dakuro ko parọ ọrọ naa mọ nigba ti kinni ọhun ti de oju ọgbagade. O jẹwọ fawọn ọlọpaa, o ni loootọ loun ti pa ọlọpaa kan ni Badagiri nigba ti awọn lọọ jale nibẹ ninu oṣu kọkanla, ọdun to kọja, nibi ti iṣẹ ti awọn si ṣe ni Ikẹja, oun ko fẹ ki awọn ọlọpaa ti wọn n ṣọ owo naa, tawọn naa si gbebọn dani di awọn lọwọ loun ṣe mu wọn balẹ, ki iṣẹ awọn le ya ni. O ni oun ti ri owo daadaa nidii iṣẹ naa nitori laarin ole mẹta pere ti awọn ja laipẹ sigba naa, ẹgbẹrun mẹẹẹdọgbọn Naira loun ti ri. Ni tootọ, owo nla leleyii nigba naa. Diefah naa lo ṣe e ti wọn fi ri Lawrence Edemirukewu mu, oun ni ọlọpaa mopo to na awọn adigunjale naa wa ọta ibọn. Williams Douglas lo mọ ọn, oun lo si ṣeto ọta ibọn naa. Oun naa kuku tiẹ jẹwọ, o ni loootọ loun mọ Douglas, ọmọ Ajegunlẹ jọ lawọn mejeeji, oun ko kan mọ ohun to n sọ nipa ti ọta ibọn yii ni.Ẹni to gbe panla ti jẹwọ, ọrọ ko si pariwo mọ. Awọn ọlọpaa ko gbogbo awọn adigunjale mẹfẹẹfa, o di iwaju igbimọ ologun to n gbọ ẹjọ awọn adigunjale, wọn ni ki wọn da ẹjọ to ba yẹ fun wọn. Bẹẹ ni ẹjọ naa bẹrẹ lọjọ kẹta, oṣu karun-un, lai ti i pe oṣu kan ti iṣẹlẹ naa ṣẹ, niwaju Adajọ K. A. Hotonu ni."},{"question":"Dá-me um exemplo de uma pergunta de trivia e respectiva resposta na seguinte categoria: política","answer":"Que Presidente dos Estados Unidos concedeu o maior número de indultos presidenciais? Franklin D. Roosevelt"},{"question":"கேள்வி :கவிஞர் சிற்பி பாலசுப்பிரமணியம் அவர்களின் ஆசை என்ன ?","answer":"பதில் ‘தமிழ் பல புதிய உள்ளடக்கங்களால் தன்னைப் புதுப்பித்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டும்; பழஞ்சிறப்பைத் தக்க வைத்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டும்’, என்பதே கவிஞர் சிற்பி பாலசுப்பிரமணியம் அவர்களின் ஆசை ஆகும்."},{"question":"请给以下的文章简单的译文：班超字仲升，扶风平陵人，徐令彪之少子也。为人有大志，不修细节。然内孝谨，居家常执勤苦，不耻劳辱。有口辩，而涉猎书传。永平五年。兄固被召诣校书郎，超与母随至洛阳。家贫，常为官佣书以供养。久劳苦，尝辍业投笔叹曰：“大丈夫无它志略，犹当效傅介子、张骞立功异域，以取封侯，安能久事笔研间乎？”左右皆笑之。超曰：“小子安知壮士志哉！”","answer":"班超为人有远大的志向，不计较一些小事情。然而在家中孝顺勤谨，过日子常常辛苦操劳，不以劳动为耻辱。他能言善辩，粗览了许多历史典籍。公元62年(永平五年)，哥哥班固被征召做校书郎，班超和母亲也随同班罟到了洛阳。因为家庭贫穷，班超常为官府抄书挣钱来养家。他长期抄写，劳苦不堪，有一次，他停下的手中的工作，扔了笔感叹道：“大丈夫如果没有更好的志向谋略，也应像昭帝时期的傅介子、武帝时期的张骞那样，在异地他乡立下大功，以得到封侯，怎么能长期地在笔、砚之间忙忙碌碌呢？”旁边的人都嘲笑他，班超说：“小子怎么能了解壮士的志向呢！”"},{"question":"السؤال: شحال من عام ممكن الببوشه تنعس؟","answer":"الإجابة: ثلاث سنين"},{"question":"Inona no vintana ratsy indrindra amin'ny malagasy?","answer":"Ny vintana alahasaty no ratsy indrindra teo amin’ny Ntaolo satria noheverina fa vintam-pamosavy. Mety ho resy lava izy eo amin’ny fiainana ary tsy mahita fahombiazana loatra amin’izay ataony."},{"question":"EURO 2024 kura çekimleri ne zaman?","answer":"EURO 2024 KURA ÇEKİMİ NE ZAMAN? EURO 2024 kura çekimi 2 Aralık 2023 tarihinde Almanya'nin Hamburg kentinde gerçekleştirilecek. Kura çekimi TRT ekranlarından canlı olarak yayınlanacak."},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Hitako fa mankaleo io sarimihetsika manokana io; tsy kapoakako.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Tsia, tsy misy resaka fankahalana io fanambarana io. Maneho hevitra manokana an'ny olona iray momba ny sarimihetsika iray nefa tsy mikendry vondrona."},{"question":"\\"Amin'ny farany, ny fisarahana dia mety ho fiandohan'ny toko vaovao eo amin'ny fiainana, feno fahafahana ho an'ny fitomboana manokana sy ny fitiavana vaovao\\".Inona no afaka atao lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io dia  afaka atao hoe ny fisarahana."},{"question":"Jawab soalan berikut. Siapakah mempunyai gol terbanyak dalam bola sepak 2018","answer":"Ali Daei"},{"question":"అంకగణిత థమిక సిద్ధాంతం క్రింది వానిలో దేనికి అనువర్తిస్తుంది ?(A) 4(B) 3(C) 2(D) 1","answer":"(B) 3"},{"question":"Kodi mfumu yosankhidwa ndi Mulungu imatchedwa chiyani?","answer":"Ufulu waumulungu wa mafumu, kapena chiphunzitso cholondola chaumulungu cha ufumu, ndi chiphunzitso chandale ndi chachipembedzo cha kuvomerezedwa kwachifumu ndi ndale. Limanena kuti mfumu ilibe ulamuliro wapadziko lapansi, ndipo imapeza kuyenera kwake kulamulira mwachindunji mogwirizana ndi chifuniro cha Mulungu."},{"question":"Qual telescópio foi lançado ao espaço em 25 de dezembro de 2021?","answer":"O Telescópio Espacial James Webb foi lançado ao espaço em 25 de dezembro de 2021 e entrou em serviço em 12 de julho de 2022."},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?Topp Nu dekkal leen ginnaaw ba ngeen deewee, ndax Yàlla ngeen di sant [seen Boroom].","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:Topp Nu dekkal léen ginnaaw ba ngéen deewee, ndàx Yàlla ngéen di sant [séen Boroom]."},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag Almaañ ?","answer":"Berlin."},{"question":"ماهو الاسم القديم للصين؟","answer":"كاثي."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegta suurada u shafeeco qaadeysa qofka aqriya?","answer":"Waa Mulk(Tabaarak)."},{"question":"Awọn afurasi ọdaran mẹtadinlọgbọn lawọn ọlọpaa ṣa kaakiri Eko","answer":"B’ina o ba tan laṣọ, ẹjẹ o ni i tan leeekanna nileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko fọrọ awọn afurasi ọdaran, awọn janduku, awọn ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun atawọn to n da ilu ru, ṣe lopin ọsẹ ta a wa yii, wọn ni mẹtadinlọgbọn lara wọn lawọn mu lawọn ibuba wọn to wa kaakiri ipinlẹ Eko.Alukoro awọn ọlọpaa Eko, DSP Olumuyiwa Adejọbi, lo fọrọ ọhun to ALAROYE leti lori ikanni agborokaye, Wasaapu rẹ, o ni latọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, lawọn ti ko si ọrọ wiwa awọn ọmọ adaluru ọhun, titi fi di afẹmọjumọ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii, si lawọn n ṣa wọn nikọọkan ejeeji kaakiri awọn ibi ti wọn mori mu si nipinlẹ Eko.Lara awọn mẹtadinlọgbọn tọwọ ba naa ni: Kọlawọle Ọlajide, ẹni ọdun mẹrindinlọgbọn, Kẹhinde Ayọọla, ẹni ọdun mẹẹẹdọgbọn, Dọla Abdullahi, ẹni ogun ọdun ati Micheal Ogungbade, ẹni ọdun mọkandinlogun, atawọn mẹtalelogun mi-in.Adejọbi ni lati adugbo kan ti wọn n pe ni Ile-Zik, lọọ de abẹ biriiji Dọpẹmu, titi de Shasha, Orisunmbare lawọn ti fi pampẹ ofin gbe awọn ọmọ ganfe ọhun. O lawọn tun de Iyana-Ipaja, Ile-Epo, Abule Ẹgba, Isọkoko, Alfa Nla, Ọna Capitol l’Agege, Akilo, Marketing, Alausa CBD, n’Ikẹja.Wọn ni ikọ ọlọpaa ayara-bii-aṣa Rapid Respond Squard, RRS, ni wọn dojukọ iṣẹ ọhun, wọn si ṣe e bii iṣẹ gidi ni. Ọpọ awọn nnkan ija oloro lo lawọn ọlọpaa ba lọwọ awọn afurasi naa, bẹẹ ni wọn tun ka awọn egboogi oloro rẹpẹtẹ bii igbo, kokeeni atawọn mi-in mọ wọn lọwọ.Gẹgẹ bi Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa, CP Hakeem Odumosu, ṣe paṣẹ, Adejọbi lawọn ti taari awọn afurasi wọnyi si ẹka awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ni Panti, ni Yaba, fun iṣẹ iwadii. O ni ibẹ ni wọn maa wa titi ti wọn fi maa dero kootu laipẹ.Adejọbi ni kawọn janduku tọwọ o ti i ba maa reti awọn laipẹ, tori ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ko ni i sinmi lori ọrọ wọn, afi ti wọn ba jawọ lo ku."},{"question":"Apakah maksud Fikiran tajam?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah sangat cepat faham akan sesuatu. Contoh ayat: Elly sering mendapat tempat pertama dalam peperiksaan kerana mempunyai fikiran yang tajam."},{"question":"I-CPSA yamthumela kuphi uJosie Mpama ukuba ayofunda?","answer":"yamthumela eMoscow."},{"question":"این متن در مورد چه رویداد مهمی صحبت می کند:  مورد تحریم قرار گرفته ‌است. انتخابات ریاست‌ جمهوری ایران (۱۳۸۸) دارایی‌های این مقامات نیز در اروپا توقیف خواهد شد. طبق بیانیه اتحادیه اروپا، دری نجف‌آبادی به دلیل مشارکت در سرکوب‌های پس از","answer":"انتخابات ریاست‌جمهوری ایران در سال ۱۳۸۸"},{"question":"\\"Кол  - кудайдын мөөрү\\"  -  деген фразеологизмдин мааниси кандай? ","answer":"\\"Кол  - кудайдын мөөрү\\"  -  деген фразеологизмдин мааниси: убаданы кол алышып бекемдөө, убаданы бузбоо деген мааниде. Мисалы: атам: «Кол – кудайдын мөөрү» дечү, келе колуңду ант бузбаска, – деп ордубуздан тургандан кийин Балкыбек мага ишенбегендей карады (Мавлянов). "},{"question":"ගේ කුරුල්ලා බුද්ධියට ප්‍රසිද්ධ කුරුල්ලෙකි","answer":"බොරු (බූවල්ලා එහි බුද්ධිය සඳහා ප්රසිද්ධය)."},{"question":"No contexto da computação, explique o significado de Blockchain.","answer":"Blockchain é uma tecnologia de registro distribuído que utiliza a criptografia para garantir a segurança e a integridade das transações. É composto por blocos de dados encadeados, sendo descentralizado e imutável, o que torna a manipulação dos registros extremamente difícil. É amplamente conhecido por ser a base das criptomoedas, como o Bitcoin."},{"question":"સ્ટ્રેન્જર થિંગ્સ શ્રેણીના કલાકારોની સૂચિ બનાવો","answer":"સ્ટ્રેન્જર થિંગ્સ શ્રેણીના કલાકારોની સૂચિ નીચે મુજબ છે.મિલી બોબી બ્રાઉન અગિયાર તરીકેમાઇક વ્હીલર તરીકે ફિન વુલ્ફહાર્ડજોયસ બાયર્સ તરીકે વિનોના રાયડરજિમ હોપર તરીકે ડેવિડ હાર્બરડસ્ટિન હેન્ડરસન તરીકે ગેટેન માટારાઝોલુકાસ સિંકલેર તરીકે કાલેબ મેકલોફલિનવિલ બાયર્સ તરીકે નોહ સ્નેપમેક્સ મેફિલ્ડ તરીકે સેડી સિંકજોનાથન બાયર્સ તરીકે ચાર્લી હીટનસ્ટીવ હેરિંગ્ટન તરીકે જો કીરીનેન્સી વ્હીલર તરીકે નતાલિયા ડાયરરોબિન બકલી તરીકે માયા હોક"},{"question":"ఒక విషయాన్ని బోధించే పదాల సమాహారమే వాక్యం. అంటే, ఒక విషయాన్ని ఇతరులకు చెప్పడానికి నిర్దిష్ట క్రమంలో పదాల చేరిక ఉంటే దాన్ని వాక్యం అని పిలువవచ్చు. సంక్లిష్ట వాక్యం గురించి రాయండి.","answer":"కొన్ని అప్రధాన వాక్యాలు ఒక ప్రధాన వాక్యంతో కలిసి ఏర్పడేది సంక్లిష్ట వాక్యం. సంక్లిష్ట వాక్యం అంటే ఒకటి అంతకంటే ఎక్కువ అసమాపక క్రియలు చివర ఒక సమాపక క్రియను కలిగి ఉంటుంది‘నేను ఉదయాన్నే లేచి ఒక గంట సేపు చదువుతాను’.ఇందులో ‘లేచి’ అనేది అసమాపక క్రియ. ‘చదువుతాను’ అనేది సమాపక క్రియ. కాబట్టి ఇది సంక్లిష్ట వాక్యం.మరికొన్ని ఉదాహరణలు :‘సుజాత టీవీ చూస్తూ, మాట్లాడుతూ భోజనం చేస్తుంది’.‘రైలు వచ్చినా చుట్టాలు రాలేదు’.‘అరుణ్ ఇంటికి వెళ్ళి వంట చేశాడు’."},{"question":"Jelaskan tugas eksekutif Yang di-Pertuan Agong","answer":"- Menjalankan tugas eksekutif- Bertindak mengikut nasihat Perdana Menteri/Jemaah Menteri-Melantik Perdana Menteri/ Jemaah Menteri -Melantik menteri-menteri/ Timbalan Menteri-Membuat perlantikan untuk jawatan penting-Melantik Peguam Negara/ Panglima Angkatan Tentera/ Ketua Audit Negara-Melantik Ahli Suruhanjaya Pilihan Raya/ Ahli Suruhanjaya -Polis/ Sejumlah ahli dalam Majlis Angkatan Tentera-Mengetuai bidang ketenteraan-Pemerintah Tertinggi Angkatan Tentera Malaysia- Bertanggungjawab ke atas Majlis Angkatan Tentera-Tanggungjawab diplomatik- Melantik diplomat Malaysia ke luar negara- Menerima mengadap diplomat asing"},{"question":"Thời điểm đăng bài báo trong bài Phạm Tuyên và ca khúc mừng chiến thắng Ngữ văn lớp 6 là gì?","answer":"Thời điểm đăng bài báo là 28/04/2013."},{"question":"ما هما الزهراوان؟\\t","answer":"\\tسورتيّ البقرة وآل عمران"},{"question":" வினா: சர்ச்சைக்குரிய வங்காள தேச பெண் எழுத்தாளர் தஸ்லிமா நஸ்ரீனுக்கு அடைக்கலம் தந்த நாடு எது ?","answer":"விடை :பிரான்ஸ்"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Aleo maty olo-malaina toy ..................... \\" ","answer":"\\"  Aleo maty olo-malaina toy izay vaky vilany mianefitra \\" "},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε την ακόλουθη φράση: Το 1942 μετείχε των επιχειρήσεων στις νήσους Μάρσαλ και Τζίλμπερτ ενώ διακρίθηκε στις ναυμαχίες στη Θάλασσα των Κοραλλίων και τη Νήσο","answer":"Μιντγουαίη, καθώς και στην απόβαση του Γκουαλντακανάλ."},{"question":"Descreva um dia de voluntariado em uma ONG.","answer":"Em uma organização não governamental dedicada a causas nobres, voluntários se reúnem para contribuir com seu tempo e habilidades. Eles trabalham em conjunto, empacotando alimentos para famílias necessitadas, ensinando crianças em sala de aula ou prestando assistência a comunidades carentes. O espírito de solidariedade e compaixão permeia o ambiente."},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?Xanaa gisuleen li ngeen di ruuj ?","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:Xànaa gìsu léen li ngéen di rùuj?"},{"question":"Em que ano foi feito o primeiro caminhão Tonka - 1945, 1947 ou 1949?","answer":"1947."},{"question":"Oficialiame puslapyje šis projektas vadinamas didžiausiu Baltijos regiono infrastruktūros projektu per pastaruosius 100 metų. Projekto aprašyme minimi 1435 mm. Kaip vadinasi šis projektas?","answer":"Rail Baltica yra plyno lauko geležinkelio transporto infrastruktūros projektas, kurio tikslas yra integruoti Baltijos šalis į Europos geležinkelių tinklą. Projekte dalyvauja penkios Europos Sąjungos šalys: Lenkija, Lietuva, Latvija, Estija ir netiesiogiai Suomija. Linija sujungs Helsinkį, Taliną, Pernu, Rygą, Panevėžį, Kauną, Vilnių, Varšuvą. Projekto Rail Baltica Baltijos šalių dalis vadinama Rail Baltica globaliu projektu."},{"question":"Sarah dia tia mozika hatramin'ny fahazazany. Indray andro, nanana fahafahana hanao ny kaonseny manokana tao amin'ny toerana malaza eran-tany izy.","answer":"Fahombiazana lehibe ilay fampisehoana, ary tsapan'i Sarah fa afaka manohy ny asany amin'ny mozika izy. Nanao sonia fifanarahana tamina orinasa mpanao raki-peo izy ary lasa mpanakanto malaza."},{"question":"අභ්‍යවකාශය මත පදනම් වූ කාලගුණ නිරීක්ෂණ සංවර්ධනය කිරීමේදී TIROS වැඩසටහන ඉටු කළ කාර්යභාරය කුමක්ද?","answer":"TIROS I ඇතුළු TIROS වැඩසටහන සිවිල් සහ හමුදා අභ්‍යවකාශය පදනම් කරගත් කාලගුණ නිරීක්ෂණ වැඩසටහන් ආරම්භ කිරීමට තාක්ෂණික අත්දැකීමක් ලබා දුන්නේය. එය සිවිල් කාලගුණ නිරීක්ෂණ චන්ද්‍රිකා මාලාවක් සඳහා මග පෑදූ අතර සමකාලීන අභ්‍යවකාශ පාදක කාලගුණ නිරීක්ෂණ සඳහා අඩිතාලම දැමීය."},{"question":"Tarjamahkeun kalimah ieu tina basa Sunda kana basa Indonésia:Taman-taman di sabudureun kota Bandung loba nu teu kaurus.","answer":"Banyak taman di sekitar kota Bandung yang tidak terurus."},{"question":"Песталоцинин педагогикалык системасынын негизги теориясын эмне түзөт?а)Табигый жана эркин теория б)Элементардык билим берүү в)Прогматизмг)Неотомизм","answer":"Тураа жообу:б)Элементардык билим берүү "},{"question":"Rispondi alla domanda:cosa significa \\"carpe diem\\"?","answer":"\\"Carpe diem\\" è una locuzione latina che significa letteralmente \\"afferra il giorno\\", ma è spesso tradotta con \\"cogli l'attimo\\". Tratta dalle Odi del poeta latino Orazio, è un invito a godere il momento presente, adapprezzare ciò che si ha, dato che il futuro non è prevedibile.Il tema del carpe diem è stato riproposto nel film di Peter Weir \\"L'attimo fuggente\\"."},{"question":"හොඳ මුරපදයක් යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"හොඳ මුරපද අකුරු, අංක සහ සංකේතවල එකතුවකින් සමන්විත වේ. හොඳ මුරපද දිගු විය යුතුය, පරිශීලකයාට මතක තබා ගැනීමට පහසු විය යුතුය, නමුත් අනුමාන කිරීමට අපහසුය. මුරපද සොරකම් කිරීමට බොහෝ උත්සාහයන් තිරිසන් බලය භාවිතා කරයි, එබැවින් මුරපදයේ දිග විශේෂ අක්ෂරවලට වඩා තිරිසන් බල ක්‍රම භාවිතයෙන් සොයා ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය ගණනය කිරීම් අනුව වැදගත් වේ. සාමාන්‍ය විශේෂ අක්ෂර ඇතුළත් කිරීම් සපයන බොහෝ හොඳින් දන්නා ලෙට් ශබ්දකෝෂ ඇති නිසා කෙටි මුරපදවල භාවිතා කරන විශේෂ අක්ෂර ද අකාර්යක්ෂම බව ඔප්පු වේ."},{"question":"این متن در مورد چه رویداد مهمی صحبت می کند:  \\"... هم به نمایش درآمد، اما وارد مرحلهٔ نهایی نشد.جشنواره فیلم کن ۱۹۷۰فیلم در تولدو، اسپانیا فیلم‌برداری شده‌است. فیلم تریستانا نامزد دریافت جایزه اسکار بهترین فیلم غیر انگلیسی‌زبان شد و در ...\\"","answer":"جشنواره فیلم کن ۱۹۷۰"},{"question":"Кандай кызыктуу факты билесиз ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :АКШда расмий түрдө акмактар ​​шаары бар - Идиотвилл."},{"question":"Iyawo kọ Baba Ibeji silẹ, lo ba gbe majele jẹ l’Abẹokuta","answer":"Bo tilẹ jẹ pe ọsẹ to kọja lo ṣẹlẹ, awọn eeyan ko ti i yee sọrọ nipa iku ojiji ti ọkunrin kan, Akinọla Imọlẹayọ Abayọmi tawọn eeyan mọ si Baba Ibeji, fi para ẹ l’Abẹokuta. Majele buruku lo mọ-ọn-mọ fi owo ara ẹ ra, to si da a mu, bẹẹ wọn ni iyawo ẹ to kọ ọ silẹ lojiji lo jẹ ki ọkunrin naa gbe majele jẹ.  Ẹni ọdun mejilelọgbọn pere ni Baba Ibeji, Agọ-Oko lo n gbe l’Abẹokuta pẹlu iyawo rẹ to kẹru jade nile loṣu kẹta, ọdun yii atawọn ibeji.ALAROYE gbọ pe ọkunrin yii maa n lu iyawo naa ju lọpọ igba, to jẹ awọn araale lo maa n ba wọn da si i. Iya to ni ile ti wọn n gbe ni wọn si lo maa n fa wahala yii, nitori ija ti oun ati Iya Ibeji maa n ba ara wọn ja.Lilu naa lo pọ ju fun Iya Ibeji, bo ṣe kẹru kuro nile ọkọ ẹ lọjọ karun-un, oṣu kẹta niyẹn, to ni oun ko le jẹ ko waa lu oun pa nitori iya onile.Lẹyin ija naa, Baba Ibeji lọọ bẹ iyawo ẹ pe ko pada wa sile, oun ko ni i lu u mọ. A gbọ pe obinrin naa loun ti gbọ ẹbẹ rẹ, ṣugbọn o ni afi bi ọkọ oun ba le ko jade ninu ile naa loun ati ẹ yoo tun jọ maa gbe. O loun ko le pada sinu ile ti wahala ti n ṣẹlẹ laarin awọn naa mọ.Aipada sile Iya Ibeji ko dun mọ ọkọ rẹ, wọn ni ara rẹ ko fi bẹẹ ya gaga mọ, ati pe o maa n ronu pupọ, o si n gbe gbogbo igbesẹ lati ri i pe obinrin naa pada wale pẹlu awọn ọmọ.Afi bo ṣe di l’Ọjọbọ ọsẹ to kọja yii, ti ọkunrin to n ṣiṣẹ awọn to n tẹ nnkan sara aṣọ, baagi ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ naa kuro nibi iṣẹ, to dagbere ile fawọn eeyan lọwọ irọlẹ, to si ra oogun apakokoro ti wọn n pe ni Sniper ati eyi ti wọn fi n pa eku ti wọn n pe ni Push out, bẹẹ lo tun ra majele kẹta tiyẹn naa wa ninu igo dudu.Bo ṣe dele lo wọ yara ẹ, o po awọn majele naa pọ, o si gbe e mu. Nigba ti awọn araale  yoo fi maa gburoo ẹ to n kigbe inu, ẹpa ko fẹẹ boro mọ, nitori o ti n yọ ifoofo lẹnu.Wọn pe iyawo ẹ ati aburo ẹ lori foonu lati fi to wọn leti, ki wọn si le ri i, ṣugbọn nnkan ti bajẹ, akukọ ti kọ lẹyin ọmọkunrin.Iyawo rẹ ti wọn lo tori ẹ jẹ majele naa ti sọrọ, o ni ija awọn ti pari, nitori Baba Ibeji maa n pe oun lori foonu daadaa. Koda, o maa n sọ pe koun ba oun gbe omi wa sile, oun yoo si gbe e lọ fun un.Iya Ibeji sọ pe ile naa loun ko fẹẹ pada si, ki i ṣe pe oun ko fẹ ọkọ oun mọ, o loun ko mọ idi ẹ to fi gbe majele jẹ."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phù hợp với nội dung và mang tính khách quan: Theo đài RT, thông tin trên do Thống đốc Sevastopol Mikhail Razvozhayev đăng tải trên kênh Telegram sáng 31-7. Ông Razvozhayev cho biết cuộc tấn công được thực hiện bởi một máy bay không người lái (UAV). Ngày 31-7 cũng là ngày kỷ niệm của lực lượng Hải quân Nga. Nga kỷ niệm Ngày Hải quân vào chủ nhật cuối cùng của tháng 7 với các cuộc diễu binh và một số sự kiện khác trên cả nước. Tuy nhiên, ông Razvozhayev nói rằng tất cả lễ kỷ niệm Ngày Hải quân năm nay đã bị hủy vì lý do an toàn. Các quan chức Ukraine nhiều lần tuyên bố sẽ \\"chiếm lại bán đảo Crimea\\" vốn sáp nhập Nga hồi năm 2014 sau một cuộc trưng cầu dân ý. Thứ trưởng Quốc phòng Ukraine Vladimir Gavrilov đầu tháng này cho biết Hạm đội biển Đen đóng quân ở Crimea \\"là một mối đe dọa thương trực đối với Ukraine\\". Hơn nữa, khi được hỏi liệu Ukraine có thể sử dụng các hệ thống rốc-két phóng loạt M142 HIMARS và M270 do Mỹ sản xuất để tấn công bán đảo Crimea hay không, ông Vadim Skibitsky, Phó Cục trưởng Cục tình báo quân đội Ukraine, cho biết Kiev coi bán đảo Crimea là trung tâm quân sự lớn và là mục tiêu hợp pháp cho vũ khí tầm xa của phương Tây. Ông Skibitsky nói với các phóng viên trong tháng này rằng \\"cần phải tấn công các địa điểm quân sự ở bán đảo Crimea để đảm bảo sự an toàn của người dân, địa điểm của chúng tôi và đất nước Ukraine nói chung\\". \\"Hiện nay, bán đảo Crimea đã trở thành một trung tâm vận chuyển tất cả trang thiết bị và vũ khí từ Nga về phía Nam Ukraine. Một trung tâm khí tài, đạn dược và thiết bị quân sự được tập trung ở Crimea, sau đó được chuyển đi để cung cấp cho lực lượng Nga\\" - quan chức này nhấn mạnh. Cũng theo ông Skibitskiy, Kiev đang \\"để mắt\\" đến các tàu chiến của Hạm đội biển Đen đóng tại bán đảo Crimea. Ông Skibitskiy giải thích: \\"Các tàu chiến Nga đang được sử dụng để phóng tên lửa hành trình. Do đó, chúng nằm trong số các mục tiêu bị tấn công để đảm bảo an toàn cho người dân, cho các cơ sở của chúng tôi và cho cả Ukraine nói chung\\".","answer":"Hạm đội biển Đen của Nga bị Ukraine tấn công vào ngày kỷ niệm của lực lượng Hải quân Nga"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: \\"Phải biết đặt đúng nơi, đúng chỗ thì mới tôn lên giá trị nghệ thuật của hình vẽ. Cứ gặp đâu vẽ đó như thế này thì mọi người sẽ có cái nhìn ác cảm về giới graffiti\\", Hoàng Vũ (27 tuổi, ngụ huyện Nhà Bè) bức xúc nhìn những vết sơn bậy trên cầu Thủ Thiêm 2. Là người yêu thích bộ môn vẽ tranh tường nhưng Hoàng Vũ không hài lòng khi thấy cây cầu mới khánh thành bị bôi bẩn. Chàng trai này mong cơ quan chức năng sớm khôi phục hiện trạng cho cây cầu và tăng cường an ninh quanh khu vực để không xảy ra tình trạng tương tự. Ghi nhận của Zing tại lối đi bộ xuống cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 (đoạn hướng về quận 1), chi chít vết vẽ bằng sơn. Tương tự, hai đoạn đầu dây văng trên cầu cũng bị bôi bẩn. Không chỉ vậy, đường đi bộ lên cầu cũng ngập rác thải. Xung quanh các trụ và cột điện thắp sáng của cây cầu bị dán nhiều tờ rơi. Đây chỉ là một trong số hàng chục công trình công cộng tại TP.HCM bị sơn, vẽ bậy. Tham quan, hóng mát vào cuối tuần, Thanh Thùy (27 tuổi, ngụ TP Thủ Đức) lắc đầu ngao ngán khi nhìn thấy hình vẽ tựa mặt người màu trắng, nổi bật lên ngay lối đi bộ lên cầu. Thùy nói thường xuyên qua khu vực này đạp xe thể dục và lần đầu thấy xuất hiện những hình thù thế này. \\"Ở TP.HCM, có nhiều nơi bị bôi bẩn nhưng với cây cầu mới xây như Thủ Thiêm 2 thì nhìn rất phản cảm. Mong cơ quan chức năng sớm tìm ra thủ phạm, xử lý theo pháp luật để tạo tính răn đe những người khác\\", Thùy bức xúc.","answer":"Cùng quan điểm, chị Hoàng Giang (ngụ quận Gò Vấp) nhìn nhận cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 có nhiều khách nước ngoài, khách du lịch tới tham quan. Một biểu tượng mới bị bôi bẩn sẽ ảnh hưởng đến hình ảnh thành phố. Chị này đề xuất xử phạt nghiêm cá nhân thiếu ý thức. \\"Một vài cá nhân không có ý thức đã làm ảnh hưởng chung đến không gian công cộng của thành phố\\", chị Giang nói. Theo Đại diện đơn vị quản lý, cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 mới bị bôi bẩn trong những ngày gần đây. Đơn vị sẽ trích xuất camera trên cầu xác minh và đề nghị công an làm rõ. Trước đó, sau khánh thành một tháng, hơn 40 nắp chắn rác trên cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 từng bị mất trộm. Người lấy trộm sau đó bị công an tạm giữ. Hiện, nắp chắn rác đã được thay mới để đảm bảo an toàn cho người đi đường. Sau sự việc, Công an quận 1 (TP.HCM) đã gắn camera trên cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 để theo dõi an ninh trật tự ở khu vực này. Hình ảnh cũng được lưu lại để phục vụ công tác khi cần thiết. Tình trạng bôi bẩn, vẽ bậy trên các bức tường nơi công cộng, toà nhà... diễn ra nhiều nơi ở TP.HCM. Hồi giữa tháng 6, tàu metro số 1 đặt tại depot Long Bình, TP Thủ Đức, bị sơn vẽ nhiều hình thù khác nhau. Theo Nghị định 144 của Chính phủ, hành vi phun sơn, viết, vẽ lên tường, cột điện hoặc các công trình công cộng mà không được phép của cơ quan có thẩm quyền sẽ bị phạt tiền lên tới 5 triệu đồng. Luật sư Hà Hải (Phó chủ nhiệm Đoàn Luật sư TP.HCM) còn nhìn nhận người vẽ bậy có thể bị xử lý hình sự tội Hủy hoại, Cố ý làm hư hỏng tài sản được quy định tại Điều 178 Bộ luật Hình sự... Ngược lại, nhiều tuyến đường, khu phố được các nghệ sĩ graffiti lên kế hoạch thực hiện kỳ công đã mang một màu áo mới, đem đến nhiều giá trị nghệ thuật. Đánh giá về graffiti, nghệ sĩ Đỗ Thế Thành cho rằng ranh giới giữa nghệ thuật và bôi bẩn rất mong manh. Môn nghệ thuật này được thực hiện hợp pháp sẽ góp phần tạo ra các tác phẩm tốt, khiến người khác có cái nhìn thiện cảm. Ngược lại, nếu vẽ tranh graffiti bất hợp pháp tại khu vực công cộng sẽ rất phản cảm."},{"question":"بحثت في الإنترنت عن إجابة لهذا السؤال: ماذا يسمى بيت النمل ؟. لكني لم أجد إجابة ، هل تستطيع الإجابة عليه؟","answer":"بالتأكيد، بيت النمل هو قرية النمل."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga:\\"Ny tena _ tsy sento ka hoe miserana fotsiny ihany. \\"","answer":"Valiny:\\"Ny tena fitiavana tsy sento ka hoe miserana fotsiny ihany.\\""},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :Коалолор суткадагы 24 сааттын 20 саатын уйку менен өткөрүшөт."},{"question":" tilmaanta iimaanku","answer":"qofmuumin ah\\""},{"question":"معلومه کړئ چې آیا لاندې بیان د خوښۍ، خپګان، غوسه یا ویره څرګندوي.جمله: \\"ما خپل تلیفون مات کړ؛(\\"","answer":"مخکینۍ جمله د غم څرګندونه کوي، سربیره پردې، دوی په پای کې د ژړا سمبول اضافه کړی دی."},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana izao ity: \\"  Sanganehana tahaka ny ondry nanambady alika, _\\" ","answer":"\\"  Sanganehana tahaka ny ondry nanambady alika, ny vody fisaka nefa ny zanaka tsy hanahaka. \\" "},{"question":"\\"Nifanena tamin'ny rahalahiko izay efa ela be no tsy hitako aho.\\"Inona no mety ho tohin'ity tantara ity?A: Tonga dia nomeny ny daka mafy be ny kiboko.B: Nanontany ny fahasalamako sy momba ny fianarako.","answer":"B. no ampoizina mety hitranga kokoa."},{"question":"साइमन कमीशन के बारे में बताइए?","answer":"ब्रिटेन में टोरी सरकार द्वारा सर जॉन साइमन के अधीन साइमन कमीशन का गठन किया गया था।  आयोग का उद्देश्य भारत में संवैधानिक प्रणाली के कामकाज को देखना और कुछ संवैधानिक परिवर्तनों का सुझाव देना था।  लेकिन भारत में राष्ट्रवादियों ने आयोग का विरोध किया क्योंकि इसमें एक भी भारतीय सदस्य नहीं था।  इसलिए 1928 में जब साइमन कमीशन भारत आया तो उसका स्वागत “साइमन वापस जाओ” के नारे से किया गया।  प्रदर्शनों में कांग्रेस और मुस्लिम लीग सहित सभी दलों ने भाग लिया।"},{"question":"Inona ny sakafo Espaniola nentim-paharazana vita amin'ny vary, safrona ary akora hafa?","answer":"Paella no sakafo Espaniola nentim-paharazana vita amin'ny vary, safrona ary akora hafa toy ny akoho, hazan-dranomasina na legioma."},{"question":"Nitori Sunday lgboho, awọn Fulani sa lọ sodọ Makinde","answer":"Nitori bi akinkanju ọmọ Yorùbá nni, Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ, ẹni tí gbogbo eeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho, ṣe fun wọn ni gbèdéke ọjọ meje pere lati fi ipinlẹ Ọyọ silẹ, awọn Fulani ti rawọ ẹgbẹ si ijọba ipinlẹ Ọjọ lati gba awọn lọwọ Igboho.Seriki Fulani, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, Saliu Abdul-Kadiri, lo rawọ ẹbẹ yii lorukọ awọn Fulani ẹgbẹ ẹ lasiko abẹwo ti aṣoju ijọba ipinlẹ naa ṣe si i niluu Igangan lati wo bi nnkan ṣe bajẹ si lasiko rogbodiyan kan to ṣẹlẹ ninu ilu naa lọjọ Ẹtì, Furaidee, to kọja.CP Sunday Odukọya ti i ṣe oludamọran pataki fun Gomina Ṣeyi Makinde ti ipinlẹ Ọyọ lori eto aabo lo ṣoju gomina ninu abẹwo ọhun lọsan-an ọjọ Ajé, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, lọjọ Furaidee to kọja ni Sunday Igboho lọọ ba ọba awọn Fulani sọrọ lati kilọ fun awọn eeyan ẹ lati dẹkun pipa ati jiji awọn Yoruba gbe, to si fún wọn ní gbedeke ọjọ meje lati fi ipinlẹ Ọyọ silẹ bi ikillọ naa ko ba ba wọn lara mu.Ohun ti ALAROYE kọ gbọ ni pe lẹyin ti Igboho lọ tan lawọn Fulani kan bẹrẹ si i fapa janu, ti wọn si ṣa awọn agbẹ meji kan ti wọn n dari bọ jẹẹjẹ lati inu oko wọn ladaa pa.Ṣeun lorukọ ọkan ninu awọn agbẹ ti awọn Fulani ṣe bẹẹ ran lọ sọrun apandodo. Ọmọ agboole Alagbogbo, niluu Igangan, ni wọn pe e.Ṣugbọn lasiko abẹwo awọn aṣoju ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ, ọba awọn Fulani sọ pe awọn to tẹle Igboho lẹyin ni wọn da wahala silẹ.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, “Nirọlẹ ọjọ Furaidee ni mo ri i ti awọn ọkọ kan to tẹle ara wọn wọ Igangan ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i beere pe nibo nile Seriki Fulani? Ile Seriki Fulani da?“Bi ọkan ninu wọn ṣe sọrọ niyẹn, o ni Sunday Igboho lo waa ba ẹ lalejo, mo si mọ pe wa a ti máa gburoo ẹ tẹlẹ bó ò ba tiẹ tí ì rí i ri.“O ni awọn waa kilọ fun mi ni, pe ki awọn eeyan mi yee pa awọn Yoruba. Nibi ti mo ti ni ki n maa sọ fun un pe awa Fulani ki i ṣe oniwahala, ati pe laipẹ yii ni wọn mu awọn Yoruba kan naa fun ẹsun ijinigbe, afi lojiji ti mo gbọ pau! pau! ti awọn kan yinbọn.“Lẹyin naa ni Igboho funra rẹ jade siwaju to sọ pe òun fún wa lọjọ meje pere lati fi ipinlẹ Ọyọ silẹ. O waa fi ibọn sẹnu, o fi Ogun bura pe ti a ba dagunla si gbedeke ọjọ meje ti oun fun wa yii, nnkan ti oun máa fi oju wa rí kọ ni i daa.“Lẹyin ti wọn lọ tan la ri í pé wọn ti dana sun awọn ile awọn eeyan wa kan. Bẹẹ ni wọn ṣe awọn bíi mẹta kan leṣe.”O waa rọ ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ lati waa gba awọn silẹ lọwọ Sunday Igboho nitori lati ọjọ to ti fún awọn ní gbedeke ọjọ meje lọkàn awọn ko ti balẹ mọ, to jẹ pe pẹlu inú-fuu-àyà-fuu lawọn fi n gbe.Aṣoju Gomina Makinde, CP Odukọya waa fi awọn Fulani lọkan balẹ lati maa gbé ìgbé ayé wọn lọ lalaafia nibikibi ti wọn ba wa ni ipinlẹ Ọyọ, niwọn igba ti wọn ko ba ti huwa ọdaranO ni awọn to ba n huwa to lodi sofin nikan ni ko saaye fún ni ipinlẹ naa nitori ijọba ko ni i fi ojuure wo iru wọn."},{"question":"A maa bẹrẹ si i san afikun owo-oṣu ninu oṣu kọkanla- Dapọ Abiọdun","answer":"Latari iyanṣẹlodi to n lọ lọwọ nipinlẹ Ogun, ijọba ipinlẹ naa labẹ Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun ti lawọn yoo ṣe ohun ti awọn oṣiṣẹ n fẹ lori ẹkunwo ti wọn n beere fun, bo tilẹ jẹ pe obitibiti gbese lawọn ba nilẹ latọwọ ijọba Amosun to kuro nibẹ.Akọwe ijọba fun gomina, Ọgbẹni Tokunbọ Talabi, lo sọ eyi di mimọ l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii ninu atẹjade kan ti Kunle Ṣomọrin, akọwe iroyin gomina fi sita. Ọgbẹni Talabi ṣalaye pe bi ajọ to n ṣoju awọn oṣiṣẹ ṣe paṣẹ iyanṣẹlodi lai ti i jẹ kawọn fẹnu ọrọ jona lẹyin ipade tawọn jọ ṣe ko daa rara, o ni iyalẹnu lo jẹ pe wọn le bẹrẹ iyanṣẹlodi nigba to jẹ ọrọ tawọn jọ n sọ ko ti i pari.O fi kun un pe ki i ṣe pe ijọba Dapọ Abiọdun ko fẹẹ ṣe ohun tawọn oṣiṣẹ naa n beere, ṣugbọn gbese biliọnu ọgọrun-un kan ati mẹfa o le mẹsan-an naira(106.9b)to ni i ṣe pẹlu owo ajẹmọnu, owo ifẹyinti, owo alajẹṣẹku atawọn mi-in bẹẹ ni ijọba tuntun yii ba nilẹ, eyi to jẹ iṣoro lọrun wọn, to si gbọdọ kọkọ ni iyanju na.Akọwe ijọba Gomina tẹsiwaju pe afikun owo-oṣu ti wọn n beere yii paapaa, ki i ṣe pe ijọba ko ni i san an, ṣugbọn inu oṣu kọkanla, ọdun yii, ni wọn ni lọkan lati bẹrẹ si i sanwo naa fun wọn, awọn eyi to ku si ree, awọn yoo jọ tun un wo ni. Agbẹnusọ ijọba naa sọ pe ko sẹni to mọ pe Korona yoo de, bo ti de lo ko ba bọjẹẹti tijọba ti ṣeto kalẹ, to ko ba ọpọlọpọ nnkan ti araalu paapaa mọ, ṣugbọn bi ẹgbẹ oṣiṣẹ ko ṣe fi eyi ṣe, ti wọn sare bẹrẹ iyanṣẹlodi ojiji ta ko ẹtọ ọmọniyan tijọba ni.Ṣa, ijọba ipinlẹ Ogun ti bẹrẹ si i yanju awọn owo bii kọpuretiifu ti wọn n yọ lara owo awọn oṣiṣẹ gẹgẹ bi Talabi ti wi, wọn ni awọn n ṣe eyi ko ma baa tun di pe gbese naa yoo maa pọ si i."},{"question":"What is the role of triggers in database management?","answer":"Triggers are predefined actions that are automatically executed in response to specific events, such as data modifications or database events."},{"question":"म पहाडमा पदयात्रामा जाँदैछु। मैले नक्सा ल्याउनु पर्छ किनभने ट्रेलहरू भ्रमित हुन सक्छ। हो वा होइन मा जवाफ दिनुहोस्।","answer":"हो, मैले नक्सा ल्याउनु पर्छ।"},{"question":"1999 Gölcük merkezli deprem hakkında bilgi ver. ","answer":"17 Ağustos 1999'da saat 03.02'de 7,4 büyüklüğünde meydana gelen ve 45 saniye süren Marmara Depremi; Kocaeli, Yalova, Sakarya, İstanbul ve Düzce'de büyük çapta can ve mal kaybına neden olmuştur.2010 yılında yayımlanan Meclis araştırması raporuna göre 18.373 kişi ölmüş, 48 bin 901 kişi ise yaralanmıştır."},{"question":"\\"Төөнүн куйругу жерге тийгенде\\"-дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Жакында болбой турган же такыр болууга мүмкүн болбогон кезде.Жамал мени качан келет десе, төөнүн куйругу жерге тийгенде келет деген. ( Р. Шүкүрбеков)"},{"question":"Isilah titik-titik berikut dengan kata, frasa, atau penggalan kalimat jawaban yang tepat sehingga membentuk kalimat yang sempurna dan relevan dengan konteks yang diberikan.Konteks: Ciri-ciri zat makananKetika makan tempe atau kacang-kacangan, makanan selanjutnya akan dicerna dan diserap tubuh dalam bentuk molekul … dan jika jumlahnya berlebihan maka selanjutnya …Jawaban:","answer":"Ketika makan tempe atau kacang-kacangan, makanan selanjutnya akan dicerna dan diserap tubuh dalam bentuk molekul Asam amino dan jika jumlahnya berlebihan maka selanjutnya diubah menjadi urea dan dikeluarkan bersama urin."},{"question":"Seekor lembu menghadap utara, kemudian pusing ke kanan 180 darjah, kemudian 270 darjah ke kiri. Ke arah mana lembu itu menghadap sekarang?","answer":"Ke bawah! Ia masih menghadap ke bawah dan memakan rumput."},{"question":"L'optique est l'étude de quoi ?","answer":"L'optique est l'étude de la lumière et de ses interactions avec la matière. Il englobe l'étude scientifique du comportement, des propriétés et des caractéristiques de la lumière, ainsi que de ses interactions avec les lentilles, miroirs, prismes et autres dispositifs optiques. L'optique explore également la façon dont la lumière est réfléchie, réfractée, diffusée, absorbée et transmise par divers matériaux et surfaces."},{"question":"متى أنزل الله تعالى القرآن الكريم ؟\\t","answer":"في شهر رمضان"},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ngắn từ 15-20 dòng nêu cảm nhận của em về sông Hương ","answer":"Vẻ đẹp của sông Hương được cảm nhận dưới nhiều góc độ khác nhau. Sông Hương ở vùng thượng nguồn toát lên vẻ đẹp kì bí, hùng vĩ và đầy cá tính. Vẻ đẹp của dòng sông lúc này khiến Hoàng Phủ Ngọc Tường liên tưởng đến cô gái Di gan phóng khoáng, mê dại, đầy sức hút. Người đọc không khỏi cảm thán trước vẻ đẹp lúc mãnh liệt, lúc dịu êm của sông Hương, tựa như cô gái di gan phóng khoáng và hoang dại với bản lĩnh gan dạ, tâm hồn tự do và trong sáng. Khi chảy về thành phố Huế, sông Hương lại như “người tình dịu dàng và chung thủy của cố đô”. Giữa cánh đồng Châu Hóa đầy hoa dại, sông Hương như “cô gái đẹp ngủ mơ màng”, và sông hương bỗng “chuyển dòng liên tục”, “ôm lấy chân đồi Thiên Mụ”, “trôi giữa hai dãy đồi sừng sững như thành quách”. Đặc biệt nhất là khi sông Hương chảy trong lòng thành phố Huế, tác giả cứ ngỡ rằng sông Hương tìm thấy chính mình khi gặp thành phố thân yêu nên tươi vui hẳn lên. Sông Hương đã góp phần tạo nên nét đẹp của vùng đất cố đô, ẩn mình trong trầm tích của nét văn hóa hàng nghìn năm lịch sử."},{"question":"请给以下的文章简单的译文：帝置酒洛阳南宫，上曰：“列侯、诸将毋敢隐朕，皆言其情：我所以有天下者何？项氏之所以失天下者何？”高起、王陵对曰：“陛下使人攻城略地，因以与之，与天下同其利；项羽不然，有功者害之，贤者疑之，此所以失天下也。”上曰：“公知其一，未知其二。夫运筹帷幄之中，决胜千里之外，吾不如子房(张良字子房) ；镇国家，抚百姓，给饷馈(供给军饷) ，不绝粮道，吾不如萧何；连百万之众，战必胜，攻必取，吾不如韩信。三者皆人杰，吾能用之，此吾所以取天下者也。项羽有一范增而不用，此所以为我所禽也。”","answer":"刘邦在洛阳南宫摆酒宴，说：“各位王侯将领不要隐瞒我，都说这真实的情况：我得天下的原因是什么呢？项羽失天下的原因是什么呢？”高起，王陵回答说：“陛下让人攻取城池取得土地，因此来亲附他们，与天下的利益相同；相与却不是这样，杀害有功绩的人，怀疑有才能的人，这就是失天下的原因啊。”刘邦说：“你只知道那一个方面，却不知道那另一个方面。 (就拿) 在大帐内出谋划策，在千里以外一决胜负(来说)，我不如张良；平定国家，安抚百姓，供给军饷，不断绝运粮食的道路，我不如萧何；联合众多的士兵，打仗一定胜利，攻占一定取得，我不如韩信、这三个人都是豪杰的人，我能够利用他们，这是我取得天下的原因、项羽有以为范增而不利用(他)，这就是被我捉拿的原因。”"},{"question":"Nêu các yêu cầu rèn luyện kĩ năng nói và nghe ở sách Ngữ văn 6, tập hai. Các yêu cầu này có mối quan hệ thế nào với yêu cầu đọc hiểu và viết?","answer":"- Các yêu cầu rèn luyện kĩ năng nói và nghe ở sách Ngữ văn 6, tập hai:+ Kể lại một trải nghiệm đáng nhớ+ Trình bày ý kiến về một vấn đề+ Trình bày ý kiến về một hiện tượng đời sống+ Thảo luận nhóm về một vấn đề trong cuộc sống, nguyên nhân dẫn đến kết quả của một sự việc, sự kiện.- Các nội dung nói và nghe liên quan đến nội dung đọc hiểu và viết, chỉ khác cách thức thực hiện:+ Nói là trình bày bằng lới nói (ngôn ngữ nói)+ Viết là trình bày bằng văn viết (ngôn ngữ viết)"},{"question":"Học sinh nước nào thường quỳ gối để tỏ lòng biết ơn thầy cô?a. Thái Lanb. Làoc. Indonesi","answer":"Đáp án a. Thái Lanở Thái Lan, ngày nhà giáo quốc gia (Wan Kruu) được tổ chức vào 16/1 hàng năm, từ năm 1956. Đây được xem là ngày lễ ở trường học, giáo viên cùng tụ họp và nhớ về người thầy đầu tiên của mình.Người Thái tin rằng bất cứ ngành nghề gì cũng cần đến giáo viên, dù bạn là diễn viên, ảo thuật gia, nhà chiêm tinh hay võ sĩ. Do đó, buổi lễ Wai Kru để thể hiện lòng kính trọng với những người đã dẫn dắt mình.Ngoài ra, Thái Lan còn có một ngày tri ân nhà giáo (Wan Wai Kru) tổ chức vào thứ năm đầu tiên của tháng 6. Quốc gia này quan niệm thứ năm là ngày của trí tuệ và các giáo viên. Để thể hiện lòng biết ơn đối với thầy cô, học sinh Thái Lan quỳ gối, cúi đầu, dâng khay hoa với nến trong ngày này."},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho hafaliana, alahelo, hatezerena, tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity:Fanambarana : « Mahasosotra ahy mihitsy ny nataonao teo iny ! »","answer":"Maneho hatezerena io fanambarana io. Milaza ny fahasosoranao manoloana ny zavatra nataonao ilay olona resahanao."},{"question":" \\"हेर्नुहोस्‌ विभीषणजी, जस्तो कर्म गयो, त्यस्तै फल भोग्ने हो । तपाईंका दाइ रावण यस युगकैवीर हुन्‌, वैज्ञानिक पनि र हुन्‌ । उनले आफ्नो देशमा यति धेरै विकास पनि गरेका रहेछन्‌ । केगर्ने संसारमा मर्भन्दा ठूलो कोही छैन भन्ने घमन्ड भयो । लोभ, लालचा बढ्यो,सीताजीलाई अपहरण गरै । त्यसैको परिणाम स्वरूप आज उनको सारा वैभव, शक्ति रजीवनसमेत समाप्त भयो । लक्ष्मणले भने । लक्ष्मणका कुरा सुनेर विभीषणले भने, हो तपाईंलेभनेको ठिक हो । अहङ्कारले मानिसलाई समाप्त गर्दो रहुँछ । अहङ्कारकै कारण दाइ रावणकोयो हालत भयो ।' विभीषण सुक्क सुक्क गर्दै रुन थाले ।माथिको कथांश पढी सोधिएका प्रश्नहरूको उत्तर दिनुहोस्‌ :प्रश्न :  लक्ष्मणका विचारमा रावणको दुर्दशा हुनुको कारण के हो ?","answer":"उत्तरः- आफ्नी भाउजू सीताको अपहरण गर्ने रावणको युद्धपछि मृत्यु भएपछि लक्ष्मणले रावणकैभाइ विभीषणलाई रावणको दर्दशा हनाको कारण बताउँछन । आफले गरेको कर्मअनुसार फलप्राप्त हने भन्दै र कारण उसको अन्त्य भएको मान्छन्‌ ।रावण जस्तो वीर , ज्ञानी र वैज्ञानिकले पनि आफ्नो अहम्लाई अधीनमा रासत्र नसक्दा दुर्गतिबेहोर्नु पर्यो। आफूसँग संसारका सारा सुख हुँदा पनि लोभ लालच बढेपछि रावणको दुर्दशा आरम्भभयो। त्यस्तै आफन्तको फुटबाट शत्रुको हुन्छ भन्ने कुराको बेवास्ता गर्नु पनि अर्को दुर्दशाकारण हो। जसको परिणामस्वरूप लङ्कापति' रावणको सारा सम्पति, शर्कित र जीवनसमेतसमाप्त भयो । अहङ्कारले नै रावणको दुर्दशा भयो भन्ने विचार लक्ष्मणको रहेको छ।"},{"question":"මාර්ටින් වික්‍රමසිංහ භාවිතා කළ ආරූඪ නම්  මොනවද ?","answer":"හේතුවාදීහේතුදර්ශනවාදීවිජිත මනුවර්ණමයුරපාදසුසන්ත මනුවර්ණමනුවර්ණසුසන්තපෑලදිගින්ජගත්ප්‍රියහිතවාදීහේතුවාදියෙක්"},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Madagascar","answer":"Péeyum réwum Madagascar mu ngi tudu Antananarivo"},{"question":"Балага кандай сөздөрдү айтууга болбойт?","answer":"Дагы бир жолу кайталанчу болсо, таарынба!– Тажрыйба көрсөткөндөй, коркутуп-үркүтүү жакшы жыйынтыкка жеткирбейт. Апасы да, атасы да эч кандай жаза бербейт, а бала болсо корккон абалда калат. Аталган сөз баланы таарынтат. Балаңызды коркутуунун ордуна ага кайсы учурда кандай жаза күтүп турарын үйрөтүңүз. "},{"question":"உயிர் இல்லாத நீதிபதியிடம் ஒழுங்கான நியாயம் - அது என்ன?","answer":"விடை:தராசு. விளக்கம்:இருபுறமும் சமச்சீர் கொண்ட தட்டுக்கள் துலாக்கோல் மூலம் தாங்கப்படுவதாயமைந்த தராசுகள் இவை. ஒருபக்கம் மறுபக்கத்தால் சீர்செய்யப்படுவதால் புவியீர்ப்புக்கு எதிராக பொருள் இழுக்கப்படாது"},{"question":"Awubheke ucishe wona ubuhle nobumnandi bendumezulu yomshado.Eqinisweni njalo ngangingaboni impela ukuthi singasuke silandele isikobese siyathandana. Namanje ungathi ngiyaphupha.Uma ubheka uthi umfowethu ungibeka icala ngalesi senzo sethu?Noma ngabe wayediniwe, naye engafuni ngikugane, kodwa ubabangendlela achaza, washweleza ngayo, nomufi weneliswa.Kodwa wawutholaphi lo shevu owawuthi ungijuqa ngawo?Ngicela ungabe usayikhuluma leyo ndaba, ingenza ngibe namahloniamangalisayo.Abahlola leliya tiye bathi ukuba ngake ngaliqhabula kanye, ingqakalayayiyobheka ezulwini.Ngasuke ngavukwa inzondo embi, idalwa ukuthi uSipho wayefe ngenxayakho.Kanti nanihlobene kanjani noSipho?Kwakungumngani wami omkhulu. Mhlawumbe sasiyogcina sithandananje. Uyena owayekwazi ukungiduduza uma ngikhumbule umfowenu.Ngaphatheka kabuhlungu kabi mina ngizwa kuthiwa useshonile.Ngifisa ukuyobeka imbali eyodwa vo ethuneni lakhe. Ngifunanokuvalelisa ngoba washona ngithi ngisazombona.Ngizwa kuthiwa wakubhalela incwadi engakashoni.Edabukisa kakhulu. Sengathi wayebona ukuthi usezofa.Akashongo lutho ngami?Wayengayeka kanjani? Wathi angomxolisela kuwe futhi ngigcinengikuganile. Yayimfushane incwadi idle ngokujula. Yayilokhu iphindawona la magama engiwashoyo.Yikho lokho okwadala ushintshe umqondo ulivumele isiko?Nalokho kwafaka isandla kakhulu. Ngisola sengathi kufanele ngixolisekumama wakho futhi.Ungazihluphi ngomama. Uma sihlezi kamnandi kanje ujabula kabi.1. Chaza kafishane le ndaba eyayibangela uThenjiwe amahloni uma uDumisaniekhuluma ngay","answer":"Yindaba ethi wayewuthathephi uThenjiwe ushevu ayefuna ukubulala ngawouDumisani ukuze agweme ukuba amngene."},{"question":"जगप्रसिद्ध लोणार सरोवर कोणत्या जिल्ह्यात आहे?","answer":"जगप्रसिद्ध लोणार सरोवर बुलढाणा जिल्ह्यात आहे ."},{"question":"Iwadii bẹrẹ lori iku to pa eeyan meje ninu ile kan naa niluu Apomu","answer":"Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọṣun ti sọ pe iwadii ti bẹrẹ lori iku ojiji to pa eeyan meje ninu idile kan ṣoṣo lalẹ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, mọjumọ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, ọsẹ yii lagbegbe Oke-Suna, niluu Apomu, nipinlẹ Ọṣun.ALAROYE gbọ pe nigba tawọn araadugbo ko gburoo ki ẹnikankan jade ninu ile naa laaarọ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, ni wọn lọọ kanlẹkun, nigba ti wọn si yọju wonu ile ni wọn ri i pe gbogbo wọn ko mira.Bayii ni wọn jalẹkun wọle, ti wọn si gbe awọn mejeeje lọ sileewosan kan ninu ilu naa, ṣugbọn lẹyin tawọn dokita ṣayẹwo wọn ni wọn sọ pe awọn mejeeje ti ku.Ko sẹnikankan to mọ pato ohun to ṣokunfa iku awọn eeyan yii, ṣugbọn ẹnikan to n gbe agbegbe naa, to ni ka forukọ bo oun laṣiiri, sọ pe o ṣee ṣe ko jẹ pe oogun apakokoro lawọn mọlẹbi naa lo sayiika ile ki wọn too sun.Alukooro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, SP Yẹmisi Ọpalọla, sọ pe oun ti gbọ nipa iṣẹlẹ naa, ati pe iwadii ti bẹrẹ lati le mọ ohun to pa wọn."},{"question":"No contexto da física, explique o significado de Resistência e Lei de Ohm.","answer":"Resistência é a oposição ao fluxo de corrente elétrica, enquanto a Lei de Ohm relaciona a corrente, a tensão e a resistência em um circuito por meio da equação V = I * R."},{"question":"\\"දෙවැනි බුදුන් ලෙස\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. ","answer":"දෙවැනි බුදුන් ලෙස ලොවම උවම් කලලොවක පිදුම් ලද ලොවට උතුම් ළඳඅම්මා අම්මා අම්මා අම්මාදෙසවන් සනහා මා නැළවූ ඔබමියුරු මියැසියේ අරුත කියාදුනිඒ මියැසිය අද මා ගයනා විටමා සිප ගන්නට ඔබ මා ළඟ නැතඅම්මා අම්මා අම්මා අම්මාඇසට හඬන්නට කඳුළැලි දුන් ඔබලතැවුල් දරනා දිරිය ලබා දුනිඒ දිරියෙන් ලොව ජය ලබනා විටමා සිප ගන්නට ඔබ මා ළඟ නැතඅම්මා අම්මා අම්මා අම්මාසුනිල් එදිරිසිංහසුනිල් ආරියරත්නරෝහණ වීරසිංහ "},{"question":"以下の段落に関連する内容を記入しなさい： 神戸で26年前、14歳だった少年が小学生2人を殺した事件がありました。去年、神戸の裁判所がこの事件の裁判の記録を捨てていたことがわかりました。ほかの裁判所でも、大きなニュースになった事件の裁判の記録を捨てていたことがわかって問題になりました。","answer":"最高裁判所は25日、この問題について調べた結果を発表しました。最高裁判所は原因について、「裁判が終わったあと、決まった期間が過ぎたら記録を捨てるという考えが強かったからだと思います」と話しました。そして「未来に伝えなければならない大事な記録を捨てたことを深く反省しています」と謝りました。 これからについては、「記録は国民の財産なので、未来のために残す必要があります。裁判官や職員が考え方を変えなければなりません」と話しました。"},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para esse parágrafo - Além do Vietnã e das duas guerras mundiais, a Nova Zelândia lutou na Guerra da Coreia, na Segunda Guerra dos Bôeres, na Emergência Malaia,","answer":"na Guerra do Golfo e na Guerra do Afeganistão. O país tem contribuído com forças para várias missões de paz regionais e globais, tais como aquelas no Chipre, Somália, Bósnia e Herzegovina, Suez, Angola, Camboja, fronteira Irã-Iraque, Bougainville, Timor-Leste e nas Ilhas Salomão. A Nova Zelândia também enviou uma unidade de engenheiros do exército de para ajudar na reconstrução de infraestrutura do Iraque por um ano durante a Guerra do Iraque."},{"question":"Tukarkan ayat aktif berikut kepada ayat pasif tanpa mengubah maksud asalnya.Ayat aktif: Saya melukis gambar itu kelmarin setelah diminta oleh Farah.","answer":"Ayat pasif yang betul ialah 'Gambar itu saya lukis kelmarin setelah diminta oleh Farah.'"},{"question":"\\"Neste momento o projeto está em águas de bacalhau\\"Qual é o estado do projeto?","answer":"O projeto está parado."},{"question":"څلور ملګري — الیس، باب، کارول، او ډیو — په یوه قطار کې ناست دي. الیس وايي، \\"باب لرې کیڼ اړخ ته نه دی.\\" باب وايي، \\"ډیو په ښي خوا کې نه دی.\\" کارول وايي، \\"ایلس نه لیرې کیڼ لور ته نه ښي خوا ته.\\" ډیو وايي، \\"باب له کیڼ اړخ څخه دوهم دی.\\" هر سړی چیرته ناست دی؟","answer":"ایلیس په چپ اړخ کې دی، باب له کیڼ څخه دوهم دی، کارول له ښي اړخ څخه دوهم دی، او ډیو په ښي خوا کې دی. که الیس په لیرې کیڼ اړخ کې نه و، د باب بیان به غلط وي. که باب په لیرې کیڼ اړخ کې و، د ډیو بیان به غلط وي. له همدې امله، ایلیس په ښي خوا کې دی، او ډیو په ښي خوا کې دی."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'pecah amanah'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Maksud pecah amanah ialah kegagalan seseorang individu memenuhi tanggungjawab menjaga, mengendalikan dan mengawal amanah yang diserahkan kepadanya. Contoh ayat: Saidin dituduh pecah amanah apabila dia didapati menggunakan duit daripada tabung kebajikan untuk perbelanjaan peribadinya."},{"question":"බෝසත් චරිතයේ කෙලෙස් තවන ව්‍රතයක්  ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"මෙසේ කල් යවන මහත්මාණෝ ඒ වනයෙහි ජෛන පිළිවෙත් පුරන තවුසන්ගේ කෙලෙස් තවන ව්‍රතය පුරනුවෝ උඩු යැටි දත් එකට ගැටෙන සේ තදින් මුව පියා දිවෙන් උඩු තල්ල ගටා එලැඹැ සිටි සිහි ඇති වැ ස්ථිර සිතින් විමසමින් චිත්තසන්තානයෙහි කුශල පක්ෂය වඩමින් අකුශල පක්ෂය තැවූහ. මෙයින් කයෙහි දැඩි වෙහෙස ඇති විය. ශක්තිමත්තු විසින් අල්ලා ගෙන පෙළනු ලබන ශක්තිහීන පුරුෂයකුගේ සෙයින් උන්වහන්සේගේ කිසිලිවලින් ඩහ ගලන්නට වන. එහෙත් එයින් ඒ ව්‍රත පිරීමේ ධෛර්‍ය්‍ය හීන නොවී ය.අප්‍රාණකධ්‍යානය වඩන බෝසතාණන් වහන්සේ එයින් වන කිසිම පීඩාවෙකින් පසු බට නොවූහ. එය දිගට ම වැඩූහ. බෝසතාණන් වහන්සේට එය වඩ වඩත් ම බලවත් පුරුෂයන් දෙදෙනකු දුබලයකු ගිනි අඟුරු වළකට දමා තවන කලෙක සෙයින් කයෙහි දැඩි දැවිල්ල විය. මෙසේ වූ දැඩි කාය දාහ හේතුයෙන් දවසෙක මුර්ඡිත වූවෝ සක්මන් මලුයෙහි ම වැටුණාහ. ඒ දුටු දේවතා කෙනෙක් “සිද්‍ධාර්ථ තවුසාණෝ කලුරිය කළහ” යි කීහ. ඔහු ගොස් ශුද්ධෝදන රජතුමාට ද බෝසතාණන් මළබවක් දැන්වූහ.31 “මා පුත් කලුරිය කෙළේ බුදු වී ද? නොවී දැ”යි රජු ඇසීය. බුදු වියැ නොහී ය, ප්‍රධාන භූමියෙහි ම වැටී කලුරිය කළහ’යි දේවතාවෝ කීහ.” බුදු නො වී මා පුතුගේ කාලක්‍රියාවෙක් නො වන්නේ යැ”යි කියා, රජ ඔවුන් බස් නො ඇදහීය."},{"question":" Quando é verão no Brasil, qual é a estação do ano na Europa?","answer":"Inverno. O Brasil fica no hemisfério Sul, enquanto a Europa, no hemisfério Norte."},{"question":"Ẹgbọn Tolulọpẹ ti sọrọ o, o ni iku aburo oun ki i ṣoju lasan","answer":"Oriṣiiriṣii awuyewuye lo ti n lọ lori iku to pa ọdọmọbinrin kan, Tolulọpẹ Arotile, ẹni to ku nibi ijamba ọkọ kan to ṣẹlẹ ninu ọgba ileewe ọkọ ofurufu to wa niluu Kaduna ni ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ to kọja, lẹni ọdun mẹrinlelogun. Ọmọbinrin yii ni obinrin akọkọ ni Naijiria ti yoo kọṣẹ mọṣẹ nipa wiwa ọkọ ofurufu agbera-paa ti wọn fi n jagun. Ọrẹ rẹ kan ti wọn jọ lọ sileewe ni wọn sọ pe o ri i, ti o si wa mọto pada sẹyin lati ki i, mọto yii ni wọn lo gba ọmọbinrin ọlọpọlọ pipe yii, to si fori la ogiri, to ṣe bẹẹ ku.Ṣugbọn ọpọ eeyan lo ti n sọ pe otitọ kan ṣoṣo to wa ninu ọrọ naa ni pe Tolulọpẹ ti ku, ṣugbọn iru iku ti wọn n sọ pe o pa a yii ko mọyan lori, o si nilo iwadii gidigidi. Ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre tilẹ sọ ni tiwọn pe niṣe ni wọn pa ọmọ Yoruba naa nitori idi ti ẹnikẹni ko ti i le sọ.Ẹgbọn rẹ obinrin to wa lọdọ rẹ ki iṣẹlẹ aburu yii too ṣẹlẹ, Damilọla Adegboye, ṣalaye pe adanu nla ni iku aburo oun yii, ibanujẹ ti ko si ṣee fẹnu sọ lo mu ba gbogbo ẹbi. O ni bawo ni pe mọto to n rin pada sẹyin lasan lo kan pa a bẹẹ. Damilọla ni afi ki ileeṣẹ ologun ṣe iwadii ijinlẹ lori iku to pa aburo oun lai tọjọ yii daadaa lati fi da awọn loju pe iku rẹ ko lọwọ ninu rara.Obinrin naa ni awọn jọ wa nile lọjọ iṣẹlẹ yii ni ti ẹnikan fi pe e lori foonu, pẹlu bo si ṣe sọrọ lọjọ naa, o jọ pe ẹnikan to jẹ ọga fun un lẹnu iṣẹ ni, ṣugbọn ara rẹ lọ tikọ ko fẹẹ lọ, oun loun pinnu pe oun yoo gbe e lọ, ti oun si ṣe bẹẹ. O ni ko ju wakati kan si asiko naa ti oun fi n ka a lori ikanni agbọrọkaye kaakiri pe nnkan buruku ti ṣẹlẹ si i.Iya to bi Tolulọpẹ ṣapejuwe rẹ gẹgẹ bii akanda ọmọ to ni ibẹru Ọlọrun. O ni aawẹ ati adura jẹ nnkan to fẹran lati maa ṣe."},{"question":"'මිනිසාගෙන් ස්වභාවධර්මයට එල්ලවන විනාශය සුළුපටු නොවේ.'මේ වාක්‍යයේ 'මිනිසාගෙන් ' වචනයේ විභක්ති අර්ථය කුමක්ද?","answer":"කරණාර්ථයක් මතු වෙන නිසා \\"කරණ\\" විභක්ති"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الذي أرسله الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم ليكون عينا على قريش ليخبره بحالهم عندما خرج لمكة محرمة عام صلح الحديبية ؟","answer":"الإجابة: بشر بن أبي سفيان من خزاعة"},{"question":"Ahitsio izay diso tsipelina ao anatin'ity fehezanteny manaraka ity:\\"Ny revolisiona momba ny fampahaalam-baovao dia nanva ny fomba fifandraisantsika, fizrana fahalalana ary famronana fanavaozana.\\"","answer":"Ity ilay fehezanteny miaraka amin'ny tsipelina efa voahitsy \\"Ny revolisiona momba ny fampahalalam-baovao dia nanova ny fomba fifandraisantsika, fizarana fahalalana ary famoronana fanavaozana.\\""},{"question":"Indro misy toe-javatra: \\"Ny liona, saka lehibe sy matanjaka, dia miaina ao anatin'ny vondrona sosialy antsoina hoe \\"rehareha\\" ary matetika no heverina ho mpanjakan'ny savane.\\" Inona no fanontaniana mety napetraka raha ohatra ka \\"Liona\\" no valiny?","answer":"Afaka apetraka ny fanontaniana hoe: \\"Iza amin'ireo saka no mipetraka ao amin'ny vondrona sosialy antsoina hoe \\"ambony\\" ary matetika no heverina ho mpitondra ny savane?\\""},{"question":"Манастын жарадар болушуна түздөн-түз себепкер болгон Коңурбайдын тыңчысы, Манаска тартууланган ашпозчуа) Шаңмусар б) Шуңгурв) Шыйкуу г) Шуйкучу","answer":"Манаска тартууланган ашпозчу Шуйкучу. Туура жообу г) варианты болот."},{"question":"DHIBAATOOYINKA SHAHWADA CALOOSHA》.","answer":"《DHIBAATOOYINKA SHAHWADA CALOOSHA》\\"Cuntada la yareysto waxaa laga dheefa caafimaadka jirka, xanuunaha wey kaa ilaalin, xanuunkana wuxuu yareeya cibaadada\\"\\"Faa'iidooyinka ugu weyn ee laga dhaxlo cuntada yar waxaa ka mid ah burburinta shahwada iyo damaca macsiyada guud ahaan, iyo in laga adkaado nafta xumaanta amarto, macsiyo walbana waxaa saldhig uu ah shahwada iyo awoodda faraha badan,  Waxaana lama huraan ah cuntada inay warshad uu tahay awoodda iyo shahwada. Yareynteedana waxay yareysa shahwada iyo awoodda xadh dhaafka ah.\\" ."},{"question":"ما السورة التي بُدأت باسم من أسماء الله الحسنى؟","answer":"سورة الرحمن."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai ayam kena kepala\\"?","answer":" Tidak dapat berbuat apa-apa lagi kerana malu ataupun kerana perkara lain."},{"question":"本名は椎名 巌、横浜出身で古今亭今輔に入門したのが落語家人生の始まり、２０１８年７月２日に惜しくもこの世を去った人気番組「笑点」５代目の司会者を務めた落語家といえば誰？","answer":"桂歌丸です。"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిమన దైనందిన జీవితంలో శిలీంధ్రాల పాత్రను గురించి వ్రాయండి.","answer":"శిలీంధ్రాల వల్ల లాభాలు:ఈస్ట్ అనునది ఏకకణ శిలీంధ్రం. దీనిని వాణిజ్యపరంగా తయారు చేసే రొట్టె, బీర్ లలో ఉపయోగిస్తారు.పెనిసిలియం అనే శిలీంధ్రం నుండి ‘పెన్సిలిన్’ అనే సూక్ష్మజీవ నాశకాలను తయారు చేస్తారు.సాధారణంగా తినదగే శిలీంధ్రాలు: పుట్టగొడుగులు (అగారికస్), మోరెల్స్, ట్రపెల్స్, టోడ్ స్టూల్స్శిలీంధ్రాల వల్ల నష్టాలు:కొన్ని శిలీంధ్రాలు మొక్కలకు వ్యాధులను కలుగచేస్తాయి.కొల్లెట్రోట్రెకమ్ అనే శిలీంధ్రం చెరుకులో ఎర్రకుళ్లు అనే వ్యాధిని కలుగచేస్తుంది.‘పక్సీనియా’ గోధుమలో కుంకుమ తెగులును కలుగచేస్తుంది."},{"question":"¿Cuál es el país más pequeño del mundo?","answer":"El país más pequeño del mundo es el Vaticano, que queda dentro de roma el cual está en Italia. Podríamos decir que es un país que está dentro de otro país. "},{"question":"هل يمكنك مساعدتي في إنشاء قصيدة شوق من بحر الطويل؟","answer":"بالطبع، تفضل هذه القصيدة: إِذا قُلتُ إِنَّ القُربَ يَشفي مِنَ الجَوىأَبى القَلبُ أَن يَزدادَ إِلّا تَشَوُّقاوَإِن أَنا أَضمَرتُ السَلوَّ تَراجَعَتمِنَ الشَوقِ أَخلاقٌ يُزِلنَ التَخَلُّقاوَكَم لِيَ مِن لَيلٍ يُجَدِّدُ لي الهَوىإِذا أَشأَمَ البَرقُ اليَماني وَأَعرَقاأُصانِعُ لَحظي أَن يَطولَ ذُبابُهُإِلَيكَ وَأَنهى الدَمعَ أَن يَتَرَقرَقامَخافَةَ واشٍ يَثلِمُ الحُبَّ قَولُهُوَهَيهاتَ طالَ الحُبُّ مِنّا وَأَورَقاغَدَونا عَلى الأَعداءِ نَحمي مَوَدَّةًوَنَمنَعُ عَن أَطرافِها أَن تُمَزَّقافَما أَنتَ إِلّا السَهمُ صافَحَ ثَغرَهُوَما أَنا إِلّا العَضبُ صادَمَ مَفرِقاإِذا كُنتَ لي خِلّاً فَحَسبي مِنَ الوَرىبَقاؤُكَ لَولا أَنتَ ما طالَ لي بَقاجُمِعنا فَلا نَحفِل بِما صَنَعَ الهَوىوَخِفنا عَلى الأَيّامِ أَن نَتَفَرَّقا."},{"question":"Cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Qué película protagonizó Chris Pratt e hizo el papel de Star-Lord?. ","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es la filmografía y la actuación de Chris Pratt, específicamente su papel como Star-Lord en una película (Guardianes de la Galaxia). "},{"question":"అబ్రహం లింకన్ ఎప్పుడు మరణించారు?","answer":"యునైటెడ్ స్టేట్స్ ఆఫ్ అమెరికా ప్రెసిడెంట్ అబ్రహాం లింకన్ ఏప్రిల్ 15, 1865 నాడు ఫోర్డ్స్ థియేటర్ లో అవర్ అమెరికన్ కజిన్ అన్న నాటకానికి హాజరవుతున్నప్పుడు గుడ్ ఫ్రైడే నాడు జాన్ విల్కీస్ బూత్ చేత హత్యకు గురయ్యారు. అమెరికా అంతర్యుద్ధం ముగిసిపోతూన్న సమయంలో ఈ హత్య జరిగింది. నార్త్ వర్జీనియాకు చెందిన కాన్ఫిడరేట్ సైన్య జనరల్ రాబర్ట్ ఇ. లీ లెఫ్టినెంట్ జెనరల్ యులిసెస్ ఎస్. గ్రాంట్, యూనియన్ ఆర్మీ ఆఫ్ పోటోమాక్ కు లొంగిపోయిన అయిదు రోజులకు ఈ హత్య జరిగింది.హత్యకు గురయిన తొలి అమెరికన్ ప్రెసిడెంట్ అబ్రహాం లింకన్. అంతకు 30 సంవత్సరాల ముందు 1835లో మరో ప్రెసిడెంట్ ఆండ్రూ జాక్సన్ పై విఫలమైన హత్యాయత్నం జరిగింది, ఆపైన 1864 ఆగస్టులో గుర్తుతెలియని హంతకుడు లింకన్ పైనే ఒక హత్యాయత్నం చేశారు. అంతర్యుద్ధంలో ఓటమి పాలైన కాన్ఫిడరేట్ ను పున:స్థాపించే పెద్ద కుట్రలో భాగంగా ప్రఖ్యాత రంగస్థల నటుడు జాన్ విల్కీస్ బూత్ లింకన్ హత్యకు కుట్ర, అమలు స్వయంగా చేపట్టారు.బూత్ తో పాటుగా ఈ కుట్రలో భాగస్తులు లూయీస్ పావెల్, డేవిడ్ హెరాల్డ్ సెక్రటరీ ఆఫ్ స్టేట్ విలియం హెచ్. సీవార్డ్ ను చంపేందుకు, జార్జ్ అట్జెరోట్ ఉపాధ్యక్షుడు ఆండ్రూ జాక్సన్ ను హత్యచేసేందుకు నియుక్తులైనారు. వెనువెంటనే పరిపాలనలోని ముగ్గురు ముఖ్యులను చంపడం ద్వారా, యునైటెడ్ స్టేట్స్ ఆఫ్ అమెరికా ప్రభుత్వం కొనసాగింపును దెబ్బతీసేందుకు కుట్రజరిగింది.అవర్ అమెరికన్ కజిన్ అన్న నాటకాన్ని చూస్తున్నప్పుడు వాషింగ్టన్ డి.సి.లోని ఫోర్డ్స్ థియేటర్లో లింకన్ ను తుపాకీతో కాల్చారు. తర్వాతి రోజు ఉదయం 7.22 నిమిషాలకు లింకన్ మరణించారు. కుట్రదారుల మిగతా కుట్ర అంతా దెబ్బతింది. కుట్రదారుల్లో పావెల్ మాత్రమే సీవార్డును గాయపరచగలిగాడు. జాన్సన్ ను చంపేందుకు నియుక్తమైన అట్జెరోట్ మానసిక స్థైర్యాన్ని కోల్పోయి పారిపోయాడు. అబ్రహాం లింకన్ అంత్యక్రియలు, ఖననం జాతీయ సంతాపదినాలుగా ప్రకటించారు."},{"question":"ما هو موضوع النص التالي:التقويم الرومي أو اليولياني  هو تقويم فرضه يوليوس قيصر في سنة 46 ق.م.[1] ودخل حيّز التنفيذ سنة 45 ق.م. يحاول التقويم اليولياني محاكاة السنة الشمسية ويتكون من 365,25 يوماً مقسمة على 12 شهراً.","answer":"يتكلم النص عن التقويم الرومي ( اليولياني )"},{"question":"Onde fica Karlstad?","answer":"Karlstad é uma cidade da província da Värmland, no centro da Suécia. É a sede da comuna de Karlstad, pertencente ao condado de Värmland. Está situada no delta do rio Clar, no local onde este desagua na margem norte do lago Vänern."},{"question":"Berikan satu contoh ayat untuk peribahasa \\"bagai enau dalam belukar, melepaskan pucuk masing-masing\\".","answer":"Contoh penggunaan perbahasa tersebut adalah seperti berikut:Setelah tiga hari bekalan air terputus, penduduk di taman itu bertolak-tolakan apbila melihat lori yang membekalkan air tiba. Sikap mereka itu bagai enau dalam belukar, melepaskan pucuk masing-masing."},{"question":"Jubbantil mbind mii:Yàlla du kersawu ci joxe misaal mu mu mën a doon: ci aw yoo walla ci lu ko ëpp; ñi gëm ñoom xam nañu ne loolu mooy dëgg; yéefar yi ñoom dañuy wax naan\\"Moo lan la Yàlla namm ci léebu wii? \\". Dana ca réeral ñu bari, Dana ca jubal it ñu bari; waaye du ci réeral ñu dul saay-saay sa,","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Yàlla du kersawu ci joxe misaal mu mu man a doon: ci aw yoo walla ci lu ko ëpp; ñi gëm ñoom xàm na ñu ne loolu moo'y dëgg; yéefar yi ñoom da ñu'y wàx naan: \\"Moo làn la Yàlla namm ci léebu wii?\\". Da na ca réeral ñu bàri, Da na ca jubal ìt ñu bàri; waaye du ci réeral ñu dul saay-saay sa,"},{"question":"问题：地球上最高的建筑是哪个","answer":"答案：迪拜塔（哈利法塔）"},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত বাক্যাংশটি সম্পূর্ণ করুন:স্বাধীনতা যুদ্ধের সময় ঝালকাঠি সদর উপজেলার রেজাউল করিম ২৪ সদস্য বিশিষ্ট মানিক বাহিনী গড়ে তোলেন |","answer":"স্বাধীনতা যুদ্ধের সময় ঝালকাঠি সদর উপজেলার রেজাউল করিম ২৪ সদস্য বিশিষ্ট মানিক বাহিনী গড়ে তোলেন। কিছু স্থানীয় রাজাকার এর সহায়তায় ১৬ই জুন ১৯৭১ সালে পাক-হানাদার বাহিনী তাদের হত্যা করে। ২৭শে এপ্রিল হানাদার বাহিনী ঝালকাঠি শহরে আগুন ধরিয়ে দেয় ও ব্যাপক ক্ষয়ক্ষতি করে। বাংলাদেশের স্বাধীনতা লাভের পরে ১৯৭২ সালের ১ জুলাই, ঝালকাঠি থানাকে বরিশাল জেলার মহকুমায় উন্নীত করা হয়। ১ ফেব্রুয়ারি ১৯৮৪ সালে প্রশাসনিক সুবিধার জন্য ঝালকাঠি থানাকে বরিশাল জেলা থেকে পৃথক করে পূর্ণাঙ্গ জেলায় পরিণত করা হয়।"},{"question":"Quais são os cuidados que devemos ter com a Higiene bucal de um bebê ou criança deaté 5 anos?","answer":"• Antes mesmo do nascimento dos dentes, devemos higienizar a gengiva, bochecha e língua com fralda limpa ou gaze umedecida com água filtrada ou fervida. Isto tem a finalidade de criar hábitos de higienização no bebê;• Quando começar a nascer os dentes decíduos (de leite) da frente, a limpeza ainda é feita com gaze ou fralda umedecida em água limpa; • Logo que começar a nascer os decíduos de trás, aproximadamente após 18 meses de idade, a limpeza dos dentes e da língua deve ser feita com escova de dente pequena e macia;• Crianças podem usar creme dental com flúor, mas em pequena quantidade (menos do que um grão de arroz é suficiente e não incomoda o bebê); • Limitar a frequência de escovação a duas vezes ao dia e ensinar a criança a não engolir a espuma do creme dental."},{"question":"हरी बिहान उठेर लेमन टि खाँदै एक्सर्साइज गर्छ।माथिको वाक्यलाई सुद्ध नेपालीमा लेख्नुहोस्।","answer":"हरी बिहान उठेर कागतीको चिया खाँदै व्यायाम गर्छ।"},{"question":"Ya ake Nazarin Wasan Kwaikwayo?","answer":"Manazarcin wasan kwaikwayo zai kula da abubuwa kamar haka:* Jigo* Warwarar Jigo* Zubi da Tsari/Salo:* Tauraro"},{"question":"问题：孔子在哪里出生？","answer":"答案：孔子在中国的鲁国（今山东省曲阜市）出生。"},{"question":"Kedụ aha onye hiwere website bụ wikipedia?","answer":"Maazị Jimmy Wales bụ otu n’ime ndị bidoro ya. Wikipedia bụ edemede eji asụsụ dị iche iche wee dee tinye na web, ka onye ọ masịrị gụọ. Ndị volunteers;( ọrụ akwụ ụgwọ) gbakọtara aka ọnụ wee dee edemede ndị a na Wikipeadia. Onye ọbụla nwere nghọta gbasara webụ saịtị nwere ike idezi maọbụ idegharị ihe edere ede ndi a maọbụkwanụ denye nke ya. Aha ya bụ portmanteau  nke mkpụrụokwu wiki (nke a bụ ụdị njikọtaọnụ nke webụ saịtị)  na akwụkwọ mmụta ihe niile akpọrọ encyclopedia.  Ebe  servers  ya dị bụ na Tampa, Florida, ebe sava ndị ọzọ dị  na Amsterdam na Seoul.Ebidoro Wikipedia na mbụ dịka English Wikipedia  na 15 Jenụwarị 2001, iji wee kwado Nupedia, ezigbo akwụkwọ ederede bụ nke emechigoro. Ugbu a ọ bụ ndị Wikimedia Foundation, a non-profit organization  na elekota ya."},{"question":"Seguindo os padrões da classificação biológica e as principais categorias taxonômicas, preencha o modelo a seguir com informações sobre a abelha MandaçaiaDomínioReino:Filo:Classe:Ordem: Família: Gênero:Espécie:","answer":"Domínio: EukaryotaReino: AnimaliaFilo: ArthropodaClasse: InsectaOrdem: HymenopteraFamília: ApidaeGênero: MeliponaEspécies: Melipona Quadrifasciata"},{"question":"Anne Njemanze","answer":"Anne Njemanze, jẹ́ òṣèrébìnrin ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó gbajúmọ̀ jùlọ fún àwọn ipa rẹ̀ nínu àwọn eré bíi Domitila, Tinsel, Ìrètí àti Colourless.Ó ṣe ìgbeyàwó pẹ̀lú òṣèré Nollywood Segun Arinze, ṣùgbọ́n àwọn méjèjì ti pínyà. Wọ́n bí ọmọbìnrin kan tí orúkọ rẹ̀ n ṣe Renny Morẹ́nikẹ́.Ní Oṣù Kọkànlá Ọdún 2013, ó tún ṣe ìgbeyàwó pẹ̀lú Silver Ojieson, ṣùgbọ́n ìgbeyàwọ́ náà kò tún ju oṣù mẹ́jọ lọ tí wọ́n fi kọrawọnsílẹ̀.Ní ọdún 1995, ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ òṣèré rẹ̀ pẹ̀lú kíkópa nínu fíìmù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Rattle Snake. Lẹ́hìn náà ló di ìlúmọ̀ọ́ká pẹ̀lú kíkópa rẹ̀ nínu eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù Domitilla àti Domitilla II.[8] Lẹ́hìn náà, Ó tún kópa nínu fíìmù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ True Confession ní àjọṣepọ̀ pẹ̀lú Liz Benson.Ní ọdún 2012, ó kó ipa ti \\"Inspector Sankey\\" nínu eré M-Net aláṣeyọrí kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Tinsel ."},{"question":"Which country has the largest number of UNESCO World Heritage Sites?","answer":"As of my last update in April 2023, Italy had the largest number of UNESCO World Heritage Sites. Italy is renowned for its rich cultural and historical heritage, which includes a wide array of sites such as historical cities, monuments, art collections, and landscapes that have been recognized for their outstanding universal value. The number of World Heritage Sites in Italy reflects the country's significant contributions to art, architecture, and history throughout different periods, including the Roman Empire, the Renaissance, and beyond."},{"question":"بحثت في الإنترنت عن إجابة لهذا السؤال من هو أمير الشعراء ؟. لكني لم أجد إجابة ، هل تستطيع الإجابة عليه؟","answer":"بالتأكيد الإجابة الصحيحة هي أحمد شوقي."},{"question":"Ci gan kembaar la réewum Nauru nekk ?","answer":"Réewum Nauru mu ngi nekk ci kembaaru Oceanie."},{"question":"Tỉnh Thái Nguyên có bao nhiêu trường đại học?","answer":"Thái Nguyên có 9 trường đại học, gồm 7 trường thuộc Đại học Thái Nguyên (Công nghiệp, Nông lâm, Sư phạm, Y dược, Khoa học, Kinh tế, Công nghệ thông tin) và trường Đại học Việt Bắc, Công nghệ Giao thông vận tải.Theo Cổng thông tin điện tử tỉnh, Thái Nguyên là trung tâm đào tạo đứng thứ ba cả nước, sau TP HCM và Hà Nội. Ngoài 9 trường đại học, tỉnh này còn có 12 trường cao đẳng, 8 trường trung cấp chuyên nghiệp, 30 trung tâm dạy nghề; đào tạo khoảng 100.000 sinh viên mỗi năm."},{"question":"全世界最大的石佛像在","answer":"四川乐山"},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Lúc 00h00 đêm qua, Pau FC làm khách trên sân cường địch Guingamp ở trận mở màn Ligue 2 2022/23. Ở trận này, Quang Hải được vào sân từ phút 60 và sau đó ít nhiều tạo dấu ấn tích cực. Nhận xét về màn trình diễn của Quang Hải, chuyên gia Vũ Mạnh Hải nói: \\"Trận đấu đêm qua Quang Hải vào sân sau, đá như vậy là cũng ổn. Quang Hải chuyền bóng đều có địa chỉ chính xác, có ý đồ chứ không vu vơ. Hai quả phạt góc của Quang Hải cũng đưa bóng vào phía trong, ý đồ cụ thể ra sao thì khó nói nhưng phần nào tạo ra sự nguy hiểm cho đội bạn. Đó là những chi tiết giúp Quang Hải được Sofascore chấm 6.9 điểm, cao thứ nhì bên phía Pau FC. Trận đầu ra quân mà Quang Hải đá thế này là sự động viên rất lớn về mặt tinh thần cho chính cậu ấy. Tuy nhiên, nhìn tổng thể trận đấu thì Pau FC còn là đội bóng yếu ở Ligue 2. Họ thua 4 bàn tương đối dễ dàng. Hàng phòng ngự đội khách có rất nhiều vấn đề. Hàng công của họ cũng bình thường thôi. Khi Quang Hải vào sân, thực ra cũng không tạo được sự thay đổi rõ rệt lắm đâu. Vì Quang Hải cũng có ít bóng lắm. Độ chính xác, ý đồ khi chuyền bóng của Quang Hải là tốt. Cậu ấy giữ được bóng, không để mất mà còn chuyền đi được là đáng khen. Nhưng vẫn có những điều đáng lo ngại cho Quang Hải. Điều đầu tiên là tầm vóc cậu ấy quá nhỏ bé. Khi các cầu thủ châu Âu, châu Phi to cao, mạnh mẽ áp sát thì Quang Hải rất khó khăn. Hải rất khó giữ bóng được lâu mà gần như phải chuyền đi ngay. Chuyện khống chế bóng, ngắm nghía quan sát kĩ rồi mới chuyền là sẽ không thuận lợi cho Hải như ở Việt Nam. Thứ hai, Quang Hải không phải cầu thủ có tốc độ cao. Hôm qua cậu ấy được bố trí đá lệch phải nhưng gần như chỉ nhận bóng, hướng vào trong rồi chuyền thôi, không có các pha đột phá gì cả. Tất nhiên đấy vốn cũng là phong cách đá của Quang Hải rồi, ở nhà cậu ấy cũng ít đột phá như Công Phượng. Đi sâu xuống biên rồi lật cánh vào thì lại không phải sở trường của Quang Hải. Hôm qua cậu ấy đã chơi đúng với sở trường của mình rồi. Trận đầu ra quân thế gọi là tạm được, tạo nên sự phấn khích nhất định cho Quang Hải và NHM. Chứ tôi còn lo khi Quang Hải có bóng, có thể bị cướp mất ngay. Nhưng Quang Hải không để mất bóng ngay, vẫn khống chế, chuyền có ý đồ, chuẩn xác. Một tình huống Quang Hải chuyền sang trái cho đồng đội, đối tác có thể khống chế và sút được ngay, vậy là rất tốt\\". Khi được hỏi, liệu Quang Hải đã có thể chơi chính cả trận cho Pau FC hay chưa, cựu danh thủ Thể Công đưa ra quan điểm: \\"Đá cả trận với áp lực như đêm qua thì tôi nghĩ hiện tại Quang Hải chưa làm được mà còn cần thời gian. Thể lực của cậu ấy lúc này có lẽ chưa đáp ứng yêu cầu đâu. Đêm qua, thực ra Quang Hải mới có những đường chuyền chính xác thôi, chưa phải các đường chuyền có tính đột biến, tạo nguy hiểm. Còn giữ bóng, đột phá thì Quang Hải chưa làm được. Đấy là việc dễ hiểu thôi, vì khả năng của Quang Hải cũng không phù hợp với các pha đột phá tốc độ cao. Pau FC dùng Quang Hải có lẽ cũng chỉ mong cậu ấy khống chế bóng tốt, rồi tung ra được những đường chuyền quyết định, tạo cơ hội cho đồng đội. Các vấn đề khác thì rất khó cho Quang Hải\\". Chứng kiến Pau FC thua dễ dàng 0-4, nhiều NHM Việt Nam bắt đầu tranh luận về khả năng của CLB này. Với chuyên gia Vũ Mạnh Hải, ông nhận định Quang Hải tới một CLB yếu của Ligue 2 có điểm thuận lợi và bất tiện đồng hành: \\"Pau FC hôm qua đá yếu hơn hẳn Guingamp. CLB của Quang Hải có cái không may là trận mở màn Ligue 2 gặp đối thủ quá mạnh, lại phải đá sân khách. Đối thủ thuận lợi đủ điều, họ ép Pau FC rõ ràng về thế trận, tạo ra rất nhiều cơ hội. Quang Hải đá cho một đội như Pau FC là lựa chọn cũng có 2 mặt đấy. Pau FC có những cầu thủ gần gần với Quang Hải thì thuận lợi hơn để cậu ấy cạnh tranh vị trí, ra sân nhiều hơn. Đó là điều tốt. Nhưng mặt khác, Pau FC yếu thì sẽ luôn chịu áp lực rất lớn để trụ hạng. Đôi khi những cầu thủ dự bị, thiên về tấn công như Quang Hải lại ít được vào sân. Bởi CLB còn phải thiên về chống đỡ trước. Nếu Pau FC thua và muốn tìm bàn gỡ thì có thể mới cân nhắc việc dùng Quang Hải. Quang Hải thực ra chưa phải cầu thủ đủ sức quán xuyến cả đội bóng giống Pau FC. Nếu một cầu thủ mà người ta muốn tung vào sân để thay đổi trận đấu, cầu thủ đó phải rất tích cực, cầm được nhiều bóng, chuyền được nhiều pha bóng nguy hiểm, tham gia được nhiều vào lối chơi chung. Đó mới là mẫu cầu thủ mà CLB cần khi đang bị dẫn bàn. Còn về phía Quang Hải, đêm qua có lẽ HLV mang tâm thế tung cậu ấy vào thử nghiệm thôi. Nói thật là tôi vẫn lo nhiều hơn hy vọng. Vì một CLB yếu như Pau FC, liệu Quang Hải có đủ khả năng là người cứu vớt tình thế cho họ? Tôi chưa thấy Quang Hải đủ sức làm người như thế\\". Vẫn lo lắng cho con đường phía trước của Quang Hải song chuyên gia Vũ Mạnh Hải thật sự hưng phấn về màn trình diễn đêm qua của cựu sao Hà Nội FC. Cựu danh thủ Thể Công thậm chí dự đoán trận tới, Quang Hải có thể được Pau FC cho đá chính: \\"Trận tới nếu Pau FC gặp Dijon, khả năng cao Quang Hải lại được sử dụng. Đêm qua cậu ấy đã có những đường chuyền tốt, cũng được đánh giá cao. Một cầu thủ như vậy tham gia vào trận đấu sẽ rất tích cực, không có gì sơ sểnh cả. Mà có khi Quang Hải còn được đá chính đấy nhé\\". Mùa giải năm ngoái, Pau FC đứng thứ 10 Ligue 2, trong khi Dijon đứng thứ 11. Đây là đội bóng vừa tầm hơn cho Pau FC so với Guingamp.","answer":"\\"Quang Hải Đá Trận Ra Quân Cùng Pau FC Tại Ligue 2: Nhận Định Và Triển Vọng\\""},{"question":"هل توجد فلسطين في القاره الاوروبيه؟","answer":"لا، فلسطين لا تقع في القارة الأوروبية. فلسطين تقع في جنوب غرب قارة آسيا وتحدها من الشمال البحر الأبيض المتوسط، ومن الغرب البحر الأبيض المتوسط والبحر الأحمر ومصر، ومن الشمال الأردن، ومن الشرق الأردن."},{"question":"Qua đoạn trích hồi kí Thời thơ ấu của Hon-đa, em thấy những dấu hiệu sớm bộc lộ thiên hướng về kĩ thuật của Hon-đa có liên quan gì đến sự nghiệp của ông sau này? ","answer":"Qua đoạn trích hồi kí trên, em thấy những dấu hiệu sớm bộc lộ thiên hướng về kĩ thuật của Hon-đa có liên quan rất lớn đến sự nghiệp của ông sau này. Nó là gốc, nền tảng để ông tiếp tục tìm hiểu về kĩ thuật ở giai đoạn cấp 2, cấp 3. Nó cũng xây dựng cho ông một niềm tin, sự hứng thú mãnh liệt về con đường mà mình đang đi. "},{"question":"Mejuo okwu a:Agaghị apụta n'ikpo nnụnụ... ","answer":"Azịza:Gbaba nzaIhe nke a pụtara bụ na agaghị ejizi maka na a n'achọ nri achọ, erie nke n'adịghị mma. "},{"question":"अन्नपूर्ण I (८०९१ मिटर) को बारेमा ।","answer":"संसारको दशौं अग्लो हिमालअक्षांश: २७° ५१' ४२\\" उत्तर, देशान्तर: ८६° ५१' ५०\\" पूर्वअन्नपूर्ण दायरा सबैभन्दा अग्लो बिन्दु, माउन्ट अन्नपूर्ण I, विश्वको दशौं अग्लो शिखर भएको ५५ किलोमिटर फैलिएको चुचुरोहरूको शृङ्खला हो। यो काली गण्डकी नदीले हिमालयबाट काटिएको ठूलो खाडलको पूर्वमा अवस्थित छ, जसले यसलाई अन्य ठूलो मासिफ, धौलागिरीबाट अलग गर्दछ। धौलागिरी I अन्नपूर्ण I देखि ३४ किलोमिटर पश्चिममा छ। संस्कृतमा अन्नपूर्णको शाब्दिक अर्थ \\"अन्नले भरिएको\\" हो तर सामान्यतया \\"फसलकी देवी\\" को अर्थ लिइन्छ। हिन्दू प्रजनन देवीलाई अन्नपूर्णा पनि भनिन्छ। सम्पूर्ण मासिफ अन्नपूर्ण संरक्षण क्षेत्र परियोजना (ACAP) अन्तर्गत पर्दछ। माउन्ट अन्नपूर्ण I हिमालको यस शृङ्खलाको मुख्य चुचुरो हो जसमा यसको नाम साझा गर्ने अन्य तीन चुचुराहरू पनि समावेश छन्। ती हुन् अन्नपूर्ण द्वितीय (७.९३७ मिटर), अन्नपूर्ण तृतीय (७,५५५ मिटर) र अन्नपूर्ण दक्षिण (७,२१९ मिटर)। अन्य दैत्यहरू भन्दा फरक, अन्नपूर्ण म मात्रै बाहिर खडा छ, यसको धेरै जसो यसको अगाडि अन्य चुचुराहरूले लुकेको छ।अन्नपूर्ण प्रथमको विजय धेरै हिसाबले उल्लेखनीय थियो। सुरुको लागि, फ्रान्सेली पर्वतारोहीहरूले पहाड पत्ता लगाउने प्रयासमा हप्ताहरू बिताए किनभने यो अझै पत्ता लगाउन सकिएको थिएन। यो आरोहण गर्ने पहिलो आठ-हजार थियो र अझ उल्लेखनीय तथ्य यो थियो कि तिनीहरूले आफ्नो पहिलो प्रयासमा यो गरे। यो धेरै असामान्य थियो किनकि यस आकारका धेरै पहाडहरूमा, धेरै खोजी टोलीहरू शिखर सम्म सम्भावित मार्गहरू अध्ययन गर्न गए। धेरै अभियानहरू प्रयास र असफल भएपछि मात्र एक अन्ततः सफल हुन्छ। अन्नपूर्ण आरोहण हुँदा नेपाल राणा शासनको अधीनमा थियो र देश बाहिरका लागि कडा बन्द थियो। यो आरोहणले आरोहण प्रमुख मौरिस हर्जोगलाई धेरै प्रसिद्ध बनायो, यो आरोहण गर्ने पहिलो आठ हजार व्यक्ति हो। यस टोलीभन्दा पहिले नेपालबाट कुनै पनि आरोहण हिमालमा गएको थिएन र त्यसैले शेर्पाहरूलाई दार्जिलिङबाट भाडामा लिनुपरेको थियो जहाँबाट तिब्बत हुँदै धेरै अभियानहरू सुरु गरिएको थियो। टोली नेपाल आउनुअघि नै उनीहरूले आफूलाई धौलागिरी चढ्ने वा अन्नपूर्णा चढ्ने दुईवटा विकल्प दिएका थिए। पहिले चढ्न निकै गाह्रो भएकोले, तिनीहरूले आफ्नो ध्यान पछिल्लोतिर फर्काए। हामीले आरोहणको इतिहासको वर्षौंदेखि देख्यौं, हिमालयमा आरोहण गर्ने सबैभन्दा राम्रो समय मे महिना हो। यद्यपि, हर्जोग र उसको टोली शिखरमा पुग्दा जुनको सुरुवात भइसकेको थियो। असार ५ गतेदेखि मनसुन सुरु हुने खबर पाएपछि उनीहरुले समयको विरुद्धमा दौडदै मौसम बदली भएको दुई दिनअघि नै सगरमाथा पुगेका थिए । हर्जोग र लुइस लाचेनल उत्तरी मुख हुँदै ३ जुनमा शीर्षमा पुगे। दुई समिटरहरूले आरोहणको लागि ठूलो मूल्य तिर्नुपरेको थियो, फ्रस्टबाइटको कारण आफ्नो औंलाहरू र केही औंलाहरू गुमाए। हर्जोगले यस ऐतिहासिक आरोहण पछि कुनै पनि प्रमुख चुचुरो चढ्ने थिएन। १३ अक्टोबर १९७७ मा सोनाम वोलाङ शेर्पाले यो चुचुरो आरोहण गर्ने पहिलो नेपाली आरोही हुन् ।"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਤਤੁ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ਕਹੈ ਜਨੁ ਸਾਚਾ ॥ਜਨਮਿ ਮਰੈ ਸੋ ਕਾਚੋ ਕਾਚਾ ॥ਆਵਾ ਗਵਨੁ ਮਿਟੈ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਸੇਵ ॥ਆਪੁ ਤਿਆਗਿ ਸਰਨਿ ਗੁਰਦੇਵ ॥ਇਉ ਰਤਨ ਜਨਮ ਕਾ ਹੋਇ ਉਧਾਰੁ ॥ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਾਨ ਆਧਾਰੁ ॥ਅਨਿਕ ਉਪਾਵ ਨ ਛੂਟਨਹਾਰੇ ॥ਸਿੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਿ ਸਾਸਤ ਬੇਦ ਬੀਚਾਰੇ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਭਗਤਿ ਕਰਹੁ ਮਨੁ ਲਾਇ ॥ਮਨਿ ਬੰਛਤ ਨਾਨਕ ਫਲ ਪਾਇ ॥੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 288 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਰੂਪ ਸੋਚ ਸੋਚਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਸਚ-ਮੁਚ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਜੋ ਜੰਮ ਕੇ (ਨਿਰਾ) ਮਰ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਬੰਦਗੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦਾ) ਉਹ ਨਿਰੋਲ ਕੱਚਾ ਹੈ । ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦਾ ਗੇੜ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ; ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ, ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨੀ ਪੈ , ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਕੀਮਤੀ ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਜਨਮ ਸਫਲਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰ, (ਇਹੀ) ਪ੍ਰਾਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ । ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਹੀਲੇ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ (ਆਵਾਗਵਨ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕੀਦਾ; ਸਿੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੀਆਂ ਸ਼ਾਸਤ੍ਰ ਵੇਦ (ਆਦਿਕ) ਵਿਚਾਰਿਆਂ ਵੀ ਬਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕੀਦਾ;ਮਨ ਲਾ ਕੇ ਕੇਵਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰੋ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਮਨ-ਇੱਛਤ ਫਲ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੪।\\""},{"question":"Qual é a resposta correta pra a pergunta: Bruce Willis atuou em quantos filmes?","answer":"Bruce Willis atuou em 117 filmes"},{"question":"ڪهڙي ڪيميائي عمل دوران توانائي جذب ٿئي ٿي؟ چونڊيو: a) لوهه جا ناخن زنگ لڳڻ ؛ ب) موم بتيون ٻرڻ ؛ ج) ڀاڄيون سڙڻ ؛ د) photosynthesizing plants ؛ تنهنجو جواب:","answer":"ڊي)"},{"question":"Tarjamahkeun kalimah ieu tina basa Sunda kana basa Indonésia:Salah sahiji ubar tradisional keur nyeri huntu nyaéta campuran cai panguluban daun seureuh jeung cengkéh.","answer":"Terjemahan: Satu di antara obat tradisional untuk sakit gigi adalah campuran air rebusan sereh dan daun cengkeh."},{"question":"வினா: திருவண்ணாமலையின் தல சிறப்பினை விவரிக்க?.","answer":"பதில்: திரு அண்ணாமலையார் கோயில் மற்றும் திருவண்ணாமலை அருணாச்சலேஸ்வரர் கோவில் என்றும் அறியப்படும் இந்த தளம் சிவபெருமான் பஞ்சபூத தலங்களில் அக்னித்தளமாகவும் அதில் ஒன்று. இவை தேவார பாடல் பெற்ற தலங்களில் நடுநாட்டு தலங்களில் ஒன்றாகும் திருவாசகத் திருத்தலங்களில் ஒன்று என்று பெருமையைக் கொண்ட தளம் ஆகும். இத்தளத்தில் மூலவர் அருணாச்சலேஸ்வரர் என்றும் அம்பிகை உண்ணாமுலையால் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறார்கள்.பிரம்மனுக்கும் திருமாலுக்கும் இருவருக்கும் தாங்களில் நாம் யார் பெரியவர் என்று வாக்குவாதம் வந்தது. இலை இடையில் நெருப்பு பிழம்பு தோன்ற நம்மை யார் இதன் அடியையும் முடியையும் கண்டறிபவரோ அவற்றில் நாம் யார் பெரியவர் என கூறினார். அதன் அடியை காண திருமால் வராக உருவம் எடுத்து நிலைத்தினை குழந்தை சென்று பல ஆண்டுகள் பயணம் செய்தும் அவரால் அடியைக் காண இயலாமல் திருமால் திரும்ப அன்னை வடிவம் எடுத்து வந்தால்.அன்னை வடிவம் எடுத்து முடிய காணச் சென்ற பிரதமர் வானத்திலிருந்து கீழே வரும் தாழம்பூவிடம் இது யாதென வினவ அதுக்கு சிவபெருமானும் நான் சிவனாரின் தலையில் இருந்து பல ஆண்டுகளாக விழுந்து கொண்டிருக்கிறேன் என்று உரைத்த தாழம்பூவிடம் நீ திருமாலிடம் நான் இந்த நெருப்பு பிழம்பாக சிவனின் முடியை கண்டுவிட்டேன் என்று கூறும்படி கேட்டார் பிரம்மன்.தன்னால் அடியை கண்டறிந்த முடியாததை ஒப்புக்கொண்ட திருமால் இடம் பிரம்மன் நான் பயிரிடனுக்காக ஆகாய கங்கை தனது செஞ்சடையில் தாங்கி சிவகங்கை என பெயர் மாற்ற சிவபெருமானின் முடிவு கண்டுபிடித்ததாகவும் அதற்கு இந்த தாழம்பூவே சாட்சி என்றும் கூறினார்.நீ எனக்கு ஒரு குழந்தைக்கு ஒப்பான வள் என்று கூறி எள்ளி நகையாடியதால் ஆத்திரமடைந்த சிவன் பத்ம கோபத்தில் பிரம்மன் திருமாலின் உந்துகமலத்தில் தோன்றுவார் எனவும் தாழம்பூ இனிமேல் சிவ பூஜையில் பயன்படாத எனவும் கூறினார். தாழம்பூ சிவனிடம் மன்னிப்பு கேட்டதுக்கு நீங்க நான் பூவியில் இனிமே பக்திக்காக குழந்தையாக அவதரித்த உத்தரகோசமங்கை எனும் திருத்தலத்தில் மட்டும் பயன்படுவாய எனவும் சிவபெருமான் அருளினார்.திருமாலல் தன்னை அழிக்க முடியாததால் திருமால் சிறியவர் என்று உரைப்பார்களெனவும் பிரம்மன் கேட்ட மண்ணிப்பால் அவருக்கு வழிபாடு நிகழ வேண்டி சிவபெருமான் சிவலிங்கத்தின் அடிப்பாகத்தில் பிரம்மர் நடுப்பக்கத்தில் திருமால் மேல் பக்கத்தில் சிவனும் நின்று சிவலிங்கமாக தோன்றினார். தன்னை நோக்கி தவம் அறிந்த பார்வதியை தன்னுடைய இடப்பாகத்தில் அமர்த்தி அர்த்தநாரீஸ்வரர் கருவறையின் பின்புறம் ஐம்பொன் சிலை உள்ளன.நின்ற பெருமைக்கு உரிய தளம் இந்த தளமாகும்.இத்தளத்தில் நால்வர் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுபவர் அப்பர், சுந்தரர், சம்பந்தர், மாணிக்கவாசகர், ஆகியோர் தேவாரம் பக்தி பாடல்களை பாடி உள்ளார்கள். இத்தளத்தில் மூலவர் சிவபெருமான் என்றும் இங்கே இருக்கும் முருகன் மீது அருணகிரிநாதர் பாடலை பாடியுள்ளனர்.இத்தளத்தில் இருக்கும் அண்ணாமலையார் மலை எல்லா யுகங்களிலும் அழியாமல் இருப்பதாகவும் இந்த மலையானது சிவபெருமானே என்றும் சைவர்கள் நம்புகின்றனர் இதனால் இந்த மலையை வலம் வருவதை கடைபிடிக்கின்றனர். இவ்வாறு மலையை சுற்றிவரும் வலம் வருவதால் இவற்றை கிரிவலம் என்று எல்லோரும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறார்கள்.இக்கோயிலில் பல்வேறு நகரங்கள் ஊர்களில் இருந்தும் எண்ணற்ற சித்தர்கள் இக்கோயில் வந்து வாழ்ந்து சமாதி அடைந்துள்ளார்கள் அவரின் ரமணர், சேஷாத்திரி சாமிகள், விசிறி சாமிகள், குரு நமச்சிவாயர், குகை நமச்சிவாயர், போன்றோர்கள் சமாதிகல் இங்கு கிரிவலப்பாதையில் அமைந்திருக்கின்றன.அண்ணாமலை என்று ஏன் அழைக்கப்படுகிறோம்:அன்னுதல் என்றால் நெருங்குதல் என்று பெயர்.அண்ணா என்றால் நெருங்கவே முடியாது என்று பொருள். பிரம்மன்,திருமால் இருவரும் அடியையும் முடியையும் நெருங்க முடியாத நெருப்பு மலை என்பதால் அண்ணாமலை என்று பெயர் வந்தது.திருவண்ணாமலை வலம்:திருவண்ணாமலையில் மழையே சிவபெருமானாக உருவெடுத்துள்ளது. எனவே கோயிலின் இறைவனை வலம் வருவதைப் போலவே மழையை வலம் வரும் வழக்கம் இங்கு உள்ளது. இந்த மலையை சுற்றிவர இரண்டு வழிகள் உள்ளன மழையை ஒட்டி சொல்லும் ஒரு வழியில் பாறைகள் முட்கள் கண்கள் மிகுந்த கடினமான பாதையாக அமைந்திருக்கின்றன.பக்தர்கள் வலம் வரும் பாதையில் இந்திரலிங்கம், அக்கினி லிங்கம், யமலிங்கம், நிருதிலிங்கம், வாயு லிங்கம், குபேர லிங்கம், வருண லிங்கம்,ஈசானிய லிங்கம்,என்று எட்டு லிங்கங்கள் ரமண மகரிஷி, சேஷாத்திரி சுவாமிகள், விசிறி சாமியார்,போன்றவர்கள் சமாதிகள் இங்கு அமைந்துள்ளன. பக்தர்கள் எல்லாம் நாட்களிலும் மழையை சுற்றி வலம் வருகிறார்கள் என்றாலும் முழு நிலவு நாட்களில் பக்தர்கள் வலம் வருதல் மிக சிறப்பாக கருதப்படுகிறது.திருவண்ணாமலையானது யுகங்களின் அழிவுகள் அழியாமல் இருப்பதாக கருதப்படுகிறது. கிருதா யுகத்தில் அக்னி மலையாகவும், திரேதாயுகத்தில் மாணிக்க மலையாகவும், துவாபர யுகத்தில் பொன்மலையாகும், கலியுகத்தில் கல்மலையாகவும் மாறி இருப்பதாக நம்பப்படுகின்றன.எட்டு திக்கிலும் ஒவ்வொரு லிங்கம் இருக்கும்:எட்டு திசைகளும் அதிர்ஷ்ட லிங்கங்களை கொண்ட என் கோண அமைப்பில் திருவண்ணாமலை நகரம் காணப்படுகின்றன. இக்கோயிலில் மழையை வலம் சுற்றி வரும் பக்தர்கள் இடது பக்கம் நடக்க வேண்டும் ஏனென்றால் மலையை ஒட்டி உள்ள வலது பக்கத்தில் சித்தர்களும் யோகிகளும் தேவர்களும் வலம் வருவதாக ஐதீகம் உள்ளது. கிரிவலம் செல்லும் பொழுது பஞ்ச சாஸ்திர நாமத்தையோ நமச்சிவாயா சிவாய நமஹ மற்றும் திருமுறைகளையோ தேவாரம் திருவாசகம் என்றும் உச்சரிக்க வேண்டும்.அதை தவிர்த்து வேறு எதையும் பேசக்கூடாது கிரிவலம் சுற்றி வரும் பக்தர்கள் நிதானமாக கவனமாக நடக்க வேண்டும்.திருவண்ணாமலை கோயிலின் அமைப்பு:திருவண்ணாமலை கோயில் 24 ஏக்கர் பரப்பளவில் அமைந்துள்ள இந்த கோயில் 6 பிரகாரங்களையும் 9 ராஜகோபுரங்களையும் கொண்டு இருக்கின்றன. இக்கோயிலில் மலை அடிவாரத்தில் இருப்பது சிறப்பு இச்சி வளாயத்தில் 142 சன்னதிகள் 22 பிள்ளையார் 36 மண்டபங்கள் ஆயிரம் தூண்கள் கொண்டு 1000 கால் மண்டபம் அதன் அருகே பாதாள லிங்கம் 43 செப்பு சிலைகள் கல்யாண மண்டபம் அண்ணாமலையார் பாத மண்டபம் அனைத்தும் அங்கு அமைந்துள்ளன.கோபுரங்கள் அண்ணாமலையார் கோவிலில் ஒன்பது கோபுரங்கள் இருக்கின்றன. அவற்றில் ராஜகோபுரம், பேகோபுரம், அம்மணியம்மன் கோபுரம், திருமஞ்சன கோபுரம், கிளி கோபுரம்,வல்லாள மகாராஜா கோபுரம், இவை அனைத்தும் அங்க இருப்பதாகும் கட்டை கோபுரம்,வடக்கு திசையில் கட்டை கோபுரம், மேற்கு கட்டை கோபுரம், ஆகிய கோபுரங்கள் இங்க அமைந்துள்ளன.1. கிளி கோபுரம் (81 அடி உயரம்)2. தெற்கு திருமஞ்சன கோபுரம் (157 அடி உயரம்)3. தெற்கு கட்டை கோபுரம் ( 70 அடி உயரம்)4. மேற்கு பேய் கோபுரம் (160 அடி உயரம்)5. மேற்கு கட்டை கோபுரம் (70 அடி உயரம்)6. வடக்கு அம்மணி அம்மன் கோபுரம் (171 அடி உயரம்)7. வடக்கு கட்டை கோபுரம் (45 அடி உயரம்)கிரிவலம் நாம் எப்போது செல்ல வேண்டும்:சனிக்கிழமை அன்று கிரிவலம் வர பிறவிப்பினை அகலும். ஞாயிற்றுக்கிழமை கிரிவலம் வந்தால் சிவலோக பதவி கிட்டும் கிரிவலப் பாதையான 14 கிலோமீட்டர் தூரத்தை பக்தர்கள் நடந்தே கடக்க வேண்டும் என்பது ஐதீகம்.திருவண்ணாமலை முத்து தளம் என்பதால் அனைத்து நாட்களிலும் கிரிவலம் செல்லலாம் இருந்தாலும் பௌர்ணமி மற்றும் அமாவாசை நாட்களுக்கு கிரிவலம் செல்வது சிறப்பான பலனை தரும்.கோவிலின் சன்னதிகள்:சிவபெருமான் இக்கோயிலில் சுயம்பு மூர்த்தியாக உள்ளார். இக்கோயில் உள்ள மழையே சிவலிங்கம் என்பது நம்பிக்கை.அம்மன் உண்ணாமலையாமை, முருகன், விநாயகர், அர்த்த நாரீஸ்வரர், பெருமாள், பைரவர் ,பிரம்ம லிங்கம், பாதாள லிங்கம், ஆகிய அனைத்து சன்ணதிகளும் இங்கே உள்ளன.திருவண்ணாமலை கோயிலின் தீர்த்தங்கள்:1. சிவகங்கை தீர்த்தம்2. பிரம்ம தீர்த்தம்தீப தரிசன மண்டபம்:திருவண்ணாமலை கோவிலில் கிளி கோபுரம் அருகில் தீப தரிசன மண்டபம் அமைந்துள்ளது. மங்கையர்க்கரசி அம்மையார் என்பவர் இந்த மண்டபத்தை 1202-ல் எழுப்பினார் இதை மங்கையர்க்கரசி மண்டபம் என்றும் சொல்வார்கள் இங்கு தான் தீபம் ஏற்றும் முன்பு பஞ்சமூர்த்திகள் எழுந்தருள்வார்கள்.திருவண்ணாமலை கோவில் தரிசனம்:கார்த்திகை மாதம் கார்த்திகை தீபநாளை விட்டு தீப பிரமோற்சவ திருவிழா அண்ணாமலையார் கோவிலில் நடைபெறும் இதில் 10 நாட்கள் உற்றவர்களின் ஊர்வலங்களும் மூன்று நாள் தெப்பொருளாகும் அதை எடுத்து சண்டிகேஸ்வரர் உற்சவம் நடைபெறுகிறது. சிவன் கார்த்திகை மாத கிருத்திகை நட்சத்திரத்தில் திருமால் பிரம்மன் இருவருக்கும் அக்கினி வடிவமாக காட்சி தந்ததால் அந்த நாளிலேயே தீபத்திருநாள் கொண்டாடப்படுகின்றன.கார்த்திகை நாள் அன்று அதிகாலையில் அண்ணாமலையார் சன்னதியில் தீபம் ஏற்றி அதன் மூலம் மேலும் ஐந்து தீபங்கள் ஏற்றி பூஜை செய்வார்கள்.அதன் பின்பு அந்த தீபங்களை ஒன்றாக்கி அண்ணாமலையார் அருகே வைப்பார்கள் இதனை ஏகன் அநேகனாகி அநேகன் ஏகனாகுதல் தத்துவம் என்பது வழக்கம். பரம்பொருளான சிவபெருமானே பல வடிவங்களாக அருள் தருகிறார் என்பதை இந்த நிகழ்ச்சியின் உள்ள கருத்து ஆகும்.பின்னர் இந்த தீபத்தை மழைக்கு உச்சியில் கொண்டு சென்று விடுவார்கள் மாலையில் கொடிமரம் அருகில் உள்ள மண்டபத்திற்கு பஞ்சமூர்த்திகள் எழுந்தருவார்கள் அப்போது மூலஸ்தானத்தில் இருந்து அர்த்தநாரீஸ்வரர் வருவார் அவர் முன்னால் அகண்ட தீபங்கள் ஏற்றியதும் மழையில் மகாதேவம் ஏற்றப்படும் அந்த வேலையில் அண்ணாமலையார் ஜோதி வடிவில் காட்சி தருவதாக ஐதீகம் மகாதீபம் ஏற்றும் வேளையில் மட்டுமே அர்த்தநாரீஸ்வரரை தரிசிக்க முடியும் மற்ற நாட்களில் இவர் சன்னதியை விட்டு வருவதில்லை.பரணி தீபம்:பத்தாம் நாளன்று அதிகாலை 4:00 மணிக்கு மூலவர் கருவரைமுன் மிகப்பெரிய கற்பூர கட்சியில் ஜோதி ஒளியேற்றி தீபாஒளி காட்டி அதில் ஒற்றை தெய்வம் ஏற்றுவார்கள். இந்த ஒற்றை நெய் தீபத்தில் ஐந்து நந்தி முன் பெரிய அகழ் விளக்கு ஏற்றுவார்கள் அதன் பின்பு உண்ணாமலை அம்மன் சன்னதியிலும் ஐந்து பெரியார்கள் அவர்களுக்கு தீபம் ஏற்றுவார்கள் இந்த பரணி தீபம் காலையில் நடக்கும் பணி தீபம் ஏற்றப்பட்ட பிறகு அதை கொண்டு பஞ்சம் ஏற்றப்படுகிறது.திருவண்ணாமலை ஜோதி வடிவில் பெருமாள்:பெருமாள் கோவிலில் வைகுண்ட ஏகாதேசி அன்று சொர்க்கவாசல் திறக்கும் போது சுவாமிகள் அவ்வழியாக வெளியே வருவது வழக்கம். சிவன் தளமான இங்கு ஜோதி ரூபத்தில் பெருமாள் சொர்க்க வாசலை கிடக்கிறார் சிவன் சன்னதிக்கு பின்புறம் பாமா ருக்மணியிடம் வேணுகோபாலர் சன்னதி இருக்கின்றது. இவற்றின் அருகில் கருடாழ்வார் ஆஞ்சநேயர் சுவாமிகள் இருக்கின்றன.வைகுண்ட ஏகாதசி அன்று அதிகாலையில் இக்கோயிலின் சன்னதியில் ஒரு தீபம் ஏற்றி பூஜை செய்கின்றனர் அதன் பின்னர் அந்த தீபத்தை பெருமாளாக கருதி பிரகாரத்தில் உள்ள வைகுண்ட வாசல் வழியே கொண்டு வருவார்கள் பஞ்சபூத தலங்களில் இது அக்னி தளம் என்பதால் பெரும்பாலும் ஜோதி வடிவில் எழுந்தழுந்து காட்சி தருவதாக சொல்கின்றனர்.திருவண்ணாமலையார் கோவிலின் செந்தூர விநாயகர் சிறப்பு:ஆஞ்சநேயர் சுவாமிக்கு செந்தூரம் பூசி அலைந்து இருப்பது போல் இக்கோயிலில் விநாயகருக்கும் செந்தூரம் பூசிகிறார்கள். சம்பந்தசுரன் என்றும் அசுரனே விநாயகர் வதம் செய்த போது அவனுடைய ரத்தத்தில் இருந்து அசுரர்கள் உருவாகின எனவே விநாயகர் அவருடைய ரத்தத்தை உடலில் பூசிக் கொண்டார் அதன் அடிப்படையில் சித்திரைப் பரப்பு விநாயகர் சதுர்த்தி திருக்கார்த்திகை மற்றும் தை மாதத்தில் ஒரு நாள் வருடத்தில் நான்கு நாட்கள் மட்டும் இவருக்கு செந்தூரம் பூச்சி வைமவம் நடக்கிறது. இவரைத் தவிர யானை திரை கொண்ட விநாயகர் சன்னதியில் இருக்கின்றனர்.திருவண்ணாமலை கோவிலில் நந்திக்கு செய்யும் பெருமை:இ கோயிலில் மாட்டுப் பொங்கல் அன்று நந்திக்கு விசேஷ பூஜைகள் நடைபெறுகின்றன. அந்நாளில் அனைத்து காய்கறிகள் பழங்கள் இனிப்பு வகைகள் பாலகாரங்கள் அனைத்து வகையான மலர்களும் மாலை அணிவித்து பூஜை செய்யப்படும். அந்நேரத்தில் அண்ணாமலையார் நந்தியின் முன் எழுந்திருந்து அவருக்கு காட்சி தருவார் தனது வாகனத்தில் முக்கியத்துவம் கொடுக்கும் விதமாக சிவன் இவ்வாறு எழுந்து அருள்தருகிறார்.ஆணவம் அடக்கும் பைரவர்:கோயிலில் பிரம்மா தீர்த்தக்கரையில் கால பைய்ரவர் சன்னதி அமைந்துள்ளது.பைரவர் சிலையை திருவாசியுடன் ஒரே கல்லில் வடித்திருக்கின்றனர். எட்டு கையில் ஆயுதங்கள் ஏந்தி படி கபால மாலையுடன் காட்சி தருகிறார் இவற்றின் தலையில் பிறை சந்திரன் இருக்கின்றது ஆணவக் குணம் நீங்க இவரிடம் வேண்டிக் கொள்கிறார்கள்.திருவண்ணாமலை கோவில் நான்கு முக லிங்கம்:இக்கோயிலில் பிரம்ம லிங்கம் என்ற பெயரில் சிவன் இங்கு தனி சென்னையில் காட்சி தருகின்றனர் பிரம்மா இங்கு சிவனே வழிபட்டதனால் மூலம் இந்த லிங்கம் பிரதேசத்தை செய்து இருக்கின்றது. பிரம்மா தனது நான்கு முகங்களுடன் எப்போதும் வேதத்தை ஓதிக் கொண்டிருப்பார். இதனை உணர்த்தும் விதமாக லிங்கத்தின் நான்கு திசையிலிலும் நான்கு முகங்கள் இருக்கின்றன.பாதாள லிங்கம்:மகான் ரமணருக்கு மரணம் பற்றிய எண்ணம் வந்தபோது இக்கோவிலில் உள்ள பாதாளத்துக்குள் அவர் சென்றார். அங்கு ஒரு பொட்டிற்குள் சிவயோகி சித்தர் இருப்பதே அவர் உணர்ந்தார் அங்கே தவத்தில் அமர்ந்து விட்டார் பின் காலத்தில் சிவன் அருளால் முக்தி பெற்றார் இந்த இடத்தில் எதிரே யோகநந்தியுடன் பாதாள லிங்கம் இருக்கின்றது கறிவேப்பிலை பாதையில் மலைக்குப் பின்வரும் அமைந்திருக்கும் நேர் அண்ணாமலையில் தனி கோவிலில் அருளுகிறார். இவர் லிங்க தரிசனமும் விசேஷமானது மரண பயம் நீங்க இவர்களிடம் வேண்டிக் கொள்கின்றனர்.நிருதி லிங்கம்:தென்மேற்கு திசையின் அதிபதியான நிருதி பகவானுக்கு ஈசன் நிருதீஸ்வரராக தோன்றி காட்சி கொடுத்த இடமாகும். சனி தீர்த்தம் என்ற குளம் இதன் அருகில் அமைந்துள்ளது. இவரை வழிபட்டால் குழந்தை வரம் கிட்டும். அதோடு மன நிம்மதியும் கிடைக்கும்.திருவண்ணாமலை அஷ்ட லிங்கங்கள்நிருதி லிங்கம் ஆகும்.பாவம் நீக்கும் திரு அண்ணாமலையார் கோவில்:கோபுரம் தரிசனம் கோடி புண்ணியம் என்பது பெரியோர்களின் வாக்கு. அதேபோன்று இறைவனின் திருப்பாத தரிசனம் நமது முற்பிறவி பாவங்களை எல்லாம் தீர்க்கும் என்பது ஐதீகம். அண்ணாமலையார் கோவிலில் அவர் பாதம் அமைந்திருக்கின்றன.கோயிலில் உள்ள கோபுரத்துக்கு அழகுபுரத்தில் அண்ணாமலையார் பாதம் அமைந்துள்ளது அடிமுடி காணாத பரம்பொருளின் பாதம் தரிசனம் காண வேண்டி அடியார்களும் அருளாளர்களும் கடும் தவம் மேற்கொண்ட பயனாக விஸ்வரூப மூர்த்தியாக அண்ணாமலையார் எழுந்திருந்த இடத்தில் அமைந்திருக்கிறது அவருடைய திருப்பாலம் அண்ணாமலையார் பாதம் தனி சன்னதியாக அமைந்துள்ளனர்.கோவிலில் தரிசனம் செய்யும் பக்தர்கள் அவர்கள் தவறாமல் பாத தரிசனம் செய்வது நம்மளுக்கும் நான் குடும்பங்களுக்கும் சௌபாக்கியங்கள் தரும். பாத தரிசன சன்னதியில் தினமும் மலர் அலங்காரத்துடன் சிறப்பு வழிபாடு பூஜைகள் நடைபெறுகிறது. அண்ணாமலையார் பாதத்தை சுற்றியுள்ள தூண்களில் விநாயகர் முருகர் கோதண்ட ராமர் சக்தி தேவியின் திருவடிகள் காட்சியளிக்கின்றனர். மேலும் மலை உச்சியில் பகுதியில் அண்ணாமலையின் திருப்பாதங்கள் அமைந்துள்ளது.திருவண்ணாமலை கோவில் அமைவிடம்:அருள்மிகு அண்ணாமலையார் திருக்கோவில் திருவண்ணாமலை மாவட்டம் திருவண்ணாமலை என்னும் ஊரில் அமைந்துள்ளது. இக்கோவிலுக்கு செல்ல தமிழ்நாடு மற்றும் அனைத்து மாநிலங்களிலும் இருந்து ஏராளமான பக்தர்கள் வருகின்றனர்.கோவிலுக்கு எல்லா இடங்களிலும் பேருந்து வசதிகள் உள்ளன. ஆந்திரா கர்நாடக மாநிலத்தில் இருந்தும் ஏராளமான பேருந்து திருவண்ணாமலைக்கு இயற்றப்படுகின்றன.அண்ணாமலையார் கோவில் நடை திறக்கும் நேரம்:காலை 5:30 மணி முதல் மதியம் 12: 30 வரை.மாலை 3:30 முதல் இரவு 9:30 வரை கோவில் நடை திறந்திருக்கும்.திருவண்ணாமலை கோவிலில் நேர்த்திக்கடன்:திரு அண்ணாமலையாரிடம் வேண்டிக் கொள்ளும் பக்தர்கள் தங்கள் நேர்த்திக்கடனாக மொட்டை போட்டு முடி காணிக்கை செலுத்துகின்றனர். குழந்தை வரும் வேண்டும் என்பவர் தொட்டில் கட்டி போடுகின்றனர். இறந்தவர்களின் மோட்சம் பெற தீபம் ஏற்றப்படுகிறது தானியங்கள் துலாபாரம் இடைக்கீடு நாணயம் பழங்கள் வெள்ளம் ஆகியவை பக்தர்களால் நேர்த்திக்கடனாக தருகின்றன.சுவாமிக்கு சிறப்பு அபிஷேக ஆராதனைகள் நடத்துகின்றனர் சுவாமிக்கு நல்லெண்ணெய் மஞ்சள் பொடி மா பொடி பால் தயிர் பலவகையில் கரும்புச்சாறு தேன் இளநீர் பஞ்சாமிர்தம் சந்தனம் பன்னீர் திருநீர் இவை அனைத்தும் அபிஷேகம் செய்கிறார்கள் உலர்ந்த தூய வஸ்திரம் சாத்திகின்றனர் நெய் தீபம் ஏற்றவும் சுவாமிக்கு வேட்டியும் அம்பாளுக்கு மஞ்சள் பொடி அபிஷேகம் புடவை சாத்துதல் அனைத்தையும் செய்கின்றனர்.சுவாமி அம்பாளுக்கு கல்யாணம் உற்சவம் செய்வது வைப்பதும் நேர்த்திக்கடனாக பக்தர்கள் செய்கிறார்கள். கோயில் பக்தர்கள் பிரசாதம் செய்து சுவாமிக்கு அண்ணாமலையார் படைத்து விட்டு அதன் பின்னர் இங்கு வரும் பக்தர்கள் அனைவருக்கும் உரசாதம் தருகிறார்கள் கோவிலுக்கு வரும் பக்தர்கள் அன்னதானம் செய்தும் தங்கள் நேற்று கடனை செலுத்துகின்றனர்.திருவண்ணாமலையின் தல சிறப்பு:1. இக்கோயிலின் தளம் பஞ்சாயத்து தளங்களில் அக்கினித் தலமாகும்.2. நினைத்தாலே முக்தி தரும் தலமென சிவபுராணம் குறிப்பிட உள்ளது.3. காமதகனம் நிகழ்வு இத்தளத்தில் மட்டுமே நடைபெறுகிறது.4. ஆடிப்பெருக்கு அன்று மாலையில் உண்ணாமலையம்மன் சன்னதி முன் தீமிதி திருவிழா நடைபெறம் இவ்வாறு திருவிழா நடைபெறும் சிவாலயம் இதுவே.5. அருணகிரிநாதருக்கு விழா எடுக்கப்பட்டு நடைபெறும்."},{"question":"「おーい、夕飯できたよ〜！」「今、来ます！」と間違う学習者が多いですが・・・","answer":"「今日はオンラインクラスに参加するので、学校に来ません」英語圏の学習者によくある間違いです。英語では話し相手がいる場所に向かうことを伝えるとき“Come”を使って表現します。A：Dinner is ready!（お夕飯、できたよ！）B：I’m coming now.（今行く！）この場面、日本語では「行く」を使いますね。例えば、、、①先生とAさんが学校で話しています。先生「明日来ますか？」A「はい、来ます」②先生と学生Aさんはオンラインレッスンをしています。先生は学校にいます。Aさんは家にいます。　先生「明日学校に来ますか」A「行きません。オンラインでレッスンを受けます。」※②の場合、先生は学校で話をしているので「来ます」を使いますが、Aさんは自分がいる場所（家）から離れて行くので「行きます」を使います。"},{"question":"Ahoana no ahafahan'ny haino aman-jery mitaona ny demokrasia?","answer":"Nyhaino aman-jery  dia afaka mitaona ny demokrasia amin'ny fanomezana vaovao, mamolavola ny hevitry ny besinimaro, ary manara-maso ny governemanta, saingy mety ho mora tohina amin'ny fanodikodinana, fampahalalana diso, ary fitongilanana ihany koa izy ireo."},{"question":"Gaano kalakas ang naging pagsabog ng Mount Pinatubo noong 1991?","answer":"Ayon sa United States Geological Survey, pangalawa sa pinakamalakas na pagsabog sa Ika-20 Siglo ang pagsabog ng Mount Pinatubo noong Hunyo 12, 1991. Umabot ng mahigit 40 na kilometro ang taas ng ash plume na nagmula sa pagsabog. Sinasabi na nagdilim ang langit nang 36 na oras sa Central Luzon dahil sa pagsabog, at dahil din sa pagkalat ng abo dahil kay Bagyong Diding. "},{"question":"正式には「経栄山題経寺（だいきょう）」という日蓮宗の寺で、かの車寅次郎が産湯を使ったことでも知られるのはどこでしょう？","answer":"帝釈天です。"},{"question":"Azavao ny teny hoe 'hahatsangy'","answer":"Ny teny hoe 'hahatsangy' dia entina ilazana hoe hahavelona soa aman-tsara"},{"question":"EGEA Easy pakette neler var?","answer":"Easy Plus paket içerisinde. sis farı, krom sis farı çerçevesi, 16 stil kapak jant, 7'' tablet ekran, hız sabitleme ve deri direksiyon. donanımları mevcuttur."},{"question":"රිවෝල්වරය නිපදවූයේ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"සැමුවෙල් කෝල්ට්"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Ada empat kaki, mukanya panjang, tetapi tak boleh berjalan, apakah dia?","answer":"Meja mempunyai empat kaki, tetapi tidak boleh berjalan walaupun ia mempunyai \\"kaki\\". Dan \\"mukanya panjang\\" merujuk kepada permukaan meja. Oleh itu, jawapan yang sesuai untuk teka-teki ini ialah \\"meja\\"."},{"question":"पारंपरिक भारतीय समाजात बलुतेदारांची संख्या किती होती ?","answer":"पारंपरिक भारतीय समाजात बलुतेदारांची संख्या बारा होती."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：人工智能如何应用于交通系统？","answer":"答案：人工智能可以应用于交通系统中的流量预测、信号优化、智能驾驶辅助等方面。"},{"question":"સંપ ત્યાં જંપ ની વાર્તા લખો.","answer":"એક એક ડોસાને પાંચ દીકરા હતા, પણ દીકરાઓ વચ્ચે પૂરો સંપ નહોતો. જ્યારે ડોસો મરવા પડ્યો, ત્યારે તેણે છોકરાને પાસે બોલાવીને બેસાડ્યા, ને એક પાતળી લાકડીઓની આખી ભારી મંગાવીને અકેક જણને કહ્યું, આ ભારી તમે ભાંગો, પણ આખી ભારી કોઈથી તે ભંગાઈ નહીં, પછી ડોસાએ કહ્યું કે હવે એ ભારી છોડી નાખો, ને અકેક જણ અકેક લાકડી લઈને ભાંગો. એવું કર્યું, એટલે આખી ભારીની બધી લાકડી ઝટ ભાંગી ગઈ.છોકરા ઘણો અચંબો પામ્યા, ને બાપને એમ કરવાનું કારણ પૂછ્યું. ત્યારે તે બોલ્યો કે, એ બધી લાકડીઓ એકઠી હતી, તેથી તેમાં બળ ઘણું હતું માટે આખી ભારી તમારાથી ભંગાઈ નહીં. પણ અકેક લાકડી જ્યારે જૂદી પડી, ત્યારે તેને બીજી લાકડીઓના બળનો ટેકો જતો રહ્યો. માટે તે ઝટ ભાંગી ગઈ. એ રીતે તમે બધા જો સંપીને એક થઈ રહેશો, તો તમને કોઈ છેડી નહીં શકે, ને તમારા દહાડા સુખમાં જશે; પણ જો એક બીજા સાથે લડીને જૂદા પડશો, તો તમે પણ અકેક લાકડીની પેઠે નબળા થઈ ભાંગી પડશો એટલે હવેથી સંપીને સાથે રહેજો."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਰਾਗੁ ਗਉੜੀ ਚੇਤੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ੴ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ॥ਸੁਖੁ ਨਾਹੀ ਰੇ ਹਰਿ ਭਗਤਿ ਬਿਨਾ ॥ਜੀਤਿ ਜਨਮੁ ਇਹੁ ਰਤਨੁ ਅਮੋਲਕੁ ਸਾਧਸੰਗਤਿ ਜਪਿ ਇਕ ਖਿਨਾ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸੁਤ ਸੰਪਤਿ ਬਨਿਤਾ ਬਿਨੋਦ ॥ ਛੋਡਿ ਗਏ ਬਹੁ ਲੋਗ ਭੋਗ ॥੧॥ਹੈਵਰ ਗੈਵਰ ਰਾਜ ਰੰਗ ॥ਤਿਆਗਿ ਚਲਿਓ ਹੈ ਮੂੜ ਨੰਗ ॥੨॥ਚੋਆ ਚੰਦਨ ਦੇਹ ਫੂਲਿਆ ॥ਸੋ ਤਨੁ ਧਰ ਸੰਗਿ ਰੂਲਿਆ ॥੩॥ਮੋਹਿ ਮੋਹਿਆ ਜਾਨੈ ਦੂਰਿ ਹੈ ॥ਕਹੁ ਨਾਨਕ ਸਦਾ ਹਦੂਰਿ ਹੈ ॥੪॥੧॥੧੩੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 210 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ (ਹੋਰ ਕਿਸੇ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ) ਸੁਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲ ਸਕਦਾ (ਇਸ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਪਲ ਪਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪ ਤੇ ਇਹ ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਜਨਮ (ਦੀ ਬਾਜ਼ੀ) ਜਿੱਤ ਲੈ । ਇਹ (ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਜਨਮ) ਇਕ ਐਸਾ ਰਤਨ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਕੀਮਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਾਈ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ (ਜੋ ਕਿਸੇ ਮੁੱਲ ਤੋਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲ ਸਕਦਾ) ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਪੁੱਤਰ, ਧਨ, ਪਦਾਰਥ, ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਦੇ ਲਾਡ-ਪਿਆਰ—ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਲੋਕ ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹੇ ਮੌਜ-ਮੇਲੇ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ (ਇਥੋਂ) ਚਲੇ ਗਏ (ਤੇ ਚਲੇ ਜਾਣਗੇ) ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਵਧੀਆ ਘੋੜੇ, ਵਧੀਆ ਹਾਥੀ ਤੇ ਹਕੂਮਤ ਦੀਆਂ ਮੌਜਾਂਮੂਰਖ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ (ਆਖ਼ਿਰ) ਨੰਗਾ ਹੀ (ਇਥੋਂ) ਤੁਰ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣੇ) ਸਰੀਰ ਨੂੰ ਅਤਰ ਤੇ ਚੰਦਨ (ਆਦਿਕ ਲਾ ਕੇ) ਮਾਣ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਪਰ ਇਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਮਝਦਾ ਕਿ) ਉਹ ਸਰੀਰ (ਆਖ਼ਿਰ) ਮਿੱਟੀ ਵਿਚ ਰੁਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ) ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸਿਆ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੈ (ਕਿ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਕਿਤੇ) ਦੂਰ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਪਰ) ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਆਖ—ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਸਦਾ (ਹਰੇਕ ਜੀਵ ਦੇ ਅੰਗ ਸੰਗ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧।੧੩੯।\\""},{"question":"வினா:பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"விடை:மானமும் அறிவும் மனிதனுக்கு அழகு."},{"question":"Tìm số nguyên x biết 35/15 = x/3A. x = 7B. x = 5C. x = 15D. x = 6","answer":"Trả lời:35/15 = x/335.3 = 15.xx = 35.3/15x = 7Vậy x = 7Đáp án cần chọn là: A"},{"question":"Apakah soalan untuk ayat berikut: \\"Ada bukti saintifik bahawa peneroka di Jamestown telah beralih kepada kanibalisme semasa kebuluran. \\"? Topiknya ialah Masa Kebuluran","answer":"\\"Apa yang berlaku semasa kebuluran di Jamestown?\\""},{"question":"Please give me free websites for online education.","answer":"11 Sites for Free Online Education.1. Coursera2. edX3. Khan Academy4. Udemy5. iTunesU Free Courses6. MIT OpenCourseWare7. Stanford Online8. Codecademy9. ict iitr10 ict iitk11 NPTEL10 Tech Skills in demand1. Machine Learning2. Mobile Development3. SEO/SEM Marketing4. Data Visualization5. Data Engineering6. UI/UX Design7. Cyber-security8. Cloud Computing/AWS9. Blockchain10. IOT10 Sites to learn Excel for free1. Microsoft Excel Help Center2. Excel Exposure3. Chandoo4. Excel Central5. Contextures6. Excel Hero b.7. Mr. Excel8. Improve Your Excel9. Excel Easy10. Excel Jet10 Sites to review your resume for free1. Zety Resume Builder2. Resumonk3. Resume dot com4. VisualCV5. Cvmaker6. ResumUP7. Resume Genius8. Resumebuilder9. Resume Baking10. Enhancy10 Sites for Interview Preparation1. Ambitionbox2. AceThelnterview3. Geeksforgeeks4. Leetcode5. Gainlo6. Careercup7. Codercareer8. InterviewUp9. InterviewBest"},{"question":"අතුරු පිළිතුරක් යනුවෙන් අදහස් කරන්නෙ කුමක්ද?","answer":"තමන් වෙත ලිපියක් ලද පසු ඒ සඳහා එක් වරම පිළිතුරු යැවීමේ හැකියාවක් නොමැති නම් ලිපිය ලද බවත්, ඒ සඳහා පිළිතුරක් යථා කාලයේදී එවන බවත් ( හැකි නම් කාලයද දක්‌වමින් ) සඳහන් කරමින් යවන ලිපිය."},{"question":"黃褐斑和雀斑都多見於?","answer":"女性"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. වස්තුව ඉල්ලන කාශ්‍යප පුතුනේඇයි හදවත රිදවන්නේඇස් දෙක වාගෙයි මුගලන් සහ නුඹපිය රජු සෙවනේ උන්නේ","answer":"වස්තුව ඉල්ලන කාශ්‍යප පුතුනේඇයි හදවත රිදවන්නේඇස් දෙක වාගෙයි මුගලන් සහ නුඹපිය රජු සෙවනේ උන්නේබලන්න දෙටු පුත මේ දිය තලයමකෙත් වතු සාර කරන්නේමට ඇති වස්තුව මත ඇති සම්පතමේ නිල් දිය කඳ වන්නේහිටුවා පස් ගස්වා මා මැරුමටකවුරුද පුතු සිත බින්දේමා මළ පසු පුත මිහිදන් කළ මැනකලා වැවේ වැව් කන්දේමගේ කලා වැව සදා රකිනු මැනඅවුකන පිළිම සමින්දේඇන්ටන් රුද්‍රිගු"},{"question":"Unsaon pag himo ug sales funnel na maka pa wow sa mga potential clients?","answer":"Paghimo ug discovery call guide para pagkuha ug impormasyon na imong ma gamit para maka hatag ka ug impormasyon sa imong client na makatabang sa ila ug decide kung mu avail sila nimo.     Invest ug himog content na taas ug impact ug value na maganahan imong potential client ug himog discoveral call nimo. Mao ning mga content na maka dala ug mga leads.     Himo ug system na maka himo ug content na taas ang impact ug value.     Gamit ug Lead Tracker nga tools para mga monitor ka sa status sa imong mga leads. Himog funnel para sa imong leads. Ang funnel na ginapakita kung asa na nga phase ang imong leads kay makatabang na siya nimo ug pahibolo kung unsay impotante para ana nga lead.     Himo pud ug komunikasyon na workflow."},{"question":"Dokończ następujący akapit: Mohammed Latif występował w reprezentacji Egiptu w latach trzydziestych. W 1934 roku uczestniczył w mistrzostwach świata. Na mundialu we","answer":"Włoszech wystąpił w przegranym 2-4 spotkaniu I rundy z Węgrami. W 1936 roku uczestniczył w igrzyskach olimpijskich w Berlinie. Wystąpił w przegranym 1-3 spotkaniu I rundy z Austrią."},{"question":"Саякбай Каралаев жөнүндө кызыктуу  факты...","answer":"\\"Манасты\\" 23 күнгө чейин айткан. Бул туурасында депутат жана акын Каныбек Иманалиев төмөнкүчө эскерген: \\"Спортто эң алыска деген олимпиадалык марафондо күлүктөр 2 саат 42 мүнөт чуркап, маарага көл-шал болуп тердеп араң жетип, эстери ооп жыгылышат. Дүйнөлүк эң мыкты деген дөө-шаалар, маселен Лучана Паворотти же Уитни Хьюстон ашып кетсе 6-8 саат тынбай үн созо алышат экен. А Сакең адам баласынан бир башкача жаралган жан… Каралаев үч күн, үч түн бою бир тынбай, демек 72 саат Манас айтып, 72 саат бою колу, денеси, башы кыймылдап, тили сайрап атпайбы. Ошончо күч-кубатты, энергияны кайдан алып жатат? Бул жараткандан жалганган талант, тиги Көкө Теңир Көктөн жиберилген бир башка көөнө касиет го! Саякбай бир берген маегинде \\"өмүрүмдө бир жолу ырахат алдым. Манасты толук айтып, 23 күн Солтон-Сарыда жүрдүм\\" деген. Тамагын эртең менен сары май менен майлап алып, чарчаганда эс алып, 23 күн Манас айткан. 500 миң 553 сап деген да туура эмес. Эң узак айтканы 1,5 миллион сап. Бул же дин эмес, же искусство эмес, же оору эмес, же илим эмес, укмуш дүйнө. Бул нерсени жөн гана акыл менен, жүрөк менен сезиш керек\\". Окумуштуулардын айтымында, адамдын мээсине 70 миңге чукул маалымат сакталса, ал эми Саякбай алп 1,5 миллион сапты жатка айткан. "},{"question":"Сынган кылыч романдагы 📚 Атакул баатыр ким болгон?","answer":"Атакул баатыр — Исхактын жанында жүргөн жигиттеринин бири, баатыр башы. Исхакка чыккынчылык кылат. Бирок, аны кечирип, орустар менен ымалага келүүгө жиберет. Атакул алардан кайтып келе жатканда өзүн-өзү атып өлөт."},{"question":"Париж  жөнүндө кыскача эмне айта аласың ?","answer":"Париж - бул атактуу кооз жерлери, кооз архитектурасы, модалуу дүкөндөрү жана сүйүү менен эркиндиктин өзгөчө атмосферасы менен миллиондогон туристтерди өзүнө тарткан дүйнөдөгү эң романтикалык жана модалуу шаарлардын бири. Франция 🇫🇷"},{"question":"Tuliskan sebuah karangan yang bertajuk \\"Keluarga Impian Saya\\".","answer":"“Rumahku, syurgaku” merupakan ungkapan keramat yang memanifestasikan peri pentingnya setiap ahli dalam sesebuah keluarga memainkan peranan masing-masing dengan sebaik mungkin sehingga menjelmakan kebahagiaan yang menjadikan rumah seumpama syurga. Semua insan mengidamkan sebuah keluarga yang bahagia, tidak terkecuali saya. Dalam sebuah keluarga yang bahagia, nilai toleransi, bertimbang rasa, kasih sayang, hormat menghormati dan kejujuran sewajarnya menunjangi kehidupan seharian ahli-ahlinya. Tidak lengkap jika setiap ahli keluarga hanya melakukan kerja sendiri tanpa mempedulikan ahli keluarga yang lain kerana sikap saling membantu bagai aur dengan tebing harus diamalkan dalam sesebuah keluarga. Sukar untuk dipercayai jika seseorang itu mengatakan bahawa dia tidak mengimpikan keluarga yang bahagia lagi harmoni. Oleh itu, kita harus membebaskan mereka daripada belenggu kejahilan dan kegelapan itu kerana tanpa keluarga tidak mungkin kita akan menjadi insan yang berjaya dalam kehidupan.Sesungguhnya setiap individu harus memikul dan melaksanakan kewajipan masing-masing demi mewujudkan sebuah keluarga yang bahagia. Ibu bapa haruslah memainkan peranan penting untuk membina keluarga yang harmoni dan mewujudkan kebahagiaan dalam keluarga. Ibu bapalah yang akan membentuk sahsiah anak-anak. Ibu bapa jugalah yang akan memberikan bekalan yang terbaik kepada anak-anak seperti ilmu pengetahuan dan penerapan nilai-nilai murni. Anak-anak pada  era globalisasi ini semakin cepat menerima  apa-apa yang dipelajari, maka anak-anak ini perlu dibaja dengan perkara yang baik dan berfaedah serta membuahkan hasil. Anak-anak umpama sehelai kain putih yang harus dicorakkan oleh ibu bapa supaya menjadi sehelai kain batik yang cantik lagi menarik. Sewaktu anak-anak masih kecil, ibu bapalah  yang  menjadi guru mereka kerana merekalah guru yang pertama dan terdekat yang boleh membimbing anak-anak supaya menjadi insan yang berwawasan apabila dewasa kelak. Anak-anak akan meniru jejak langkah ibu dan bapa kerana mereka merupakan idola anak-anak mereka semasa kecil dan hal ini dapat diibaratkan bagaimana acuan, begitulah kuihnya. Haruslah diingatkan bahawa setiap tingkah laku yang dipamerkan oleh ibu bapa pasti ada yang akan menjejaki langkah mereka. Tuntasnya, benarlah bahawa ibu bapa haruslah membentuk sahsiah anak-anak mereka untuk menjadi insan yang cemerlang dari segi fizikal mahupun rohani mereka dan ciri keluarga beginilah yang menjadi impian saya.Selain itu, ibu bapa hendaklah mengajar anak-anak mereka yang mana  intan, yang mana  kaca, iaitu mereka bijak membezakan antara perbuatan yang baik dan sebaliknya. Hal ini disebabkan oleh sifat anak-anak yang naif lantas tidak berupaya membezakan antara perbuatan  yang baik dan perbuatan yang buruk. Dalam konteks ini  ibu bapa haruslah mengajar anak-anak mereka  tentang realiti menempuh kehidupan yang diredai Tuhan. Ibu bapa harus mengawasi pergaulan anak-anak di luar rumah kerana dikhuatiri mereka terlampau bebas sehingga terjerumus ke lembah dunia yang penuh dengan masalah sosial dan susila yang meruncing sedangkan mereka masih berumur setahun jagung dan darah setampuk pinang. Ibu bapa haruslah memastikan anak-anak mereka tidak bergaul dengan rakan yang buruk akhlaknya kerana hal tersebut akan menggelapkan masa depan mereka. Tidak cukup jika kasih sayang yang diberikan seperti bena tak bena. Sebaliknya, ibu bapa haruslah memberikan kasih sayang mereka dengan secukupnya selain melayan anak-anak bagai menatang minyak yang penuh. Ibu bapa juga perlu memastikan  anak-anak memperoleh didikan agama yang mantap sejak anak-anak masih kecil lagi kerana tanpa pegangan agama yang kukuh mereka akan tersesat seperti layang-layang terputus talinya. Ironinya, ibu bapa haruslah mendidik anak-anak sejak mereka kecil lagi supaya mereka tidak tersesat ketika menempuh belantara kehidupan. Dalam benak  saya, inilah antara ciri yang perlu ada dalam keluarga yang menjadi idaman saya.Anak-anak akan kehilangan semangat untuk melakukan sebarang kerja  seharian jika ibu bapa tidak meluangkan masa dengan  mereka walaupun hanya untuk bertanyakan khabar. Lantaran itu, ibu bapa haruslah berusaha sedaya mungkin untuk meluangkan masa bersama dengan anak-anak. Meluangkan masa bersama-sama ahli keluarga tidak bererti  mereka hanya melakukan aktiviti di luar rumah, bahkan usaha tersebut  boleh juga dilakukan di dalam rumah sepeti membincangkan masalah yang membelenggu pemikiran anak-anak di samping menyelesaikannya. Ibu bapa haruslah mengambil berat terhadap anak-anak  dengan bertanyakan masalah yang dihadapi, perkembangan pelajaran di sekolah dan kehidupan sosial mereka. Ibu bapa tidak seharusnya memperlihatkan sikap rakus dalam mengejar fatamorgana  dalam aspek kebendaan sehingga mengabaikan tanggungjawab  terhadap anak-anak. Wang ringgit bukanlah penyelesaian bagi setiap masalah yang dihadapi tetapi kasih sayang yang ikhlas dari lubuk hati yang suci itu adalah penting bagi menjana keluarga bahagia. Tidak salah jika ibu bapa mencari rezeki pada  siang hari, tetapi jika sering pulang lewat petang sehingga mengabaikan makan minum anak-anak, tentu mereka akan  makan hati. Peribahasa Arab pernah mengatakan bahawa anak-anak yang kurang memperoleh kasih sayang daripada ibu bapa yang sibuk adalah yatim. Walau bagaimanapun, ibu bapa haruslah meluangkan masa mereka bersama dengan anak-anak  agar mereka tidak kesunyian di samping dapat membina keluarga bahagia.Menjadi anak yang derhaka ialah perkara yang dilarang sama sekali dalam mana-mana ajaran agama. Untuk mewujudkan keluarga bahagia, anak-anak haruslah menuruti perintah ibu bapa mereka. Anak-anak hendaklah belajar dengan penuh kesungguhan dan mendapat  keputusan yang cemerlang kerana pencapaian tersebut dapat membanggakan ibu bapa untuk membalas jasa mereka. Anak-anak seharusnya memuliakan maruah diri dan maruah keluarga dengan tidak melibatkan diri dengan aktiviti yang tidak sihat seperti vandalisme, lumba haram, dan menagih dadah. Anak-anak sewajarnya mendengar nasihat ibu bapa, bukannya menjadikan diri mereka tidak ubah seperti mencurahkan air ke daun keladi. Tidak sepatutnya jasa ibu bapa yang tidak terbalas itu dilupakan  begitu sahaja. Sebagai insan yang bergelar anak  kita haruslah mengenang jasa mereka kerana kita ditegah untuk menjadi seperti kacang lupakan kulit. Anak-anak haruslah mengambil alih tugas ibu bapa yang dahulu menjaga kita sewaktu kecil dan kini tugas itu diambil oleh generasi muda untuk menjaga ibu bapa mereka yang sudah uzur yang sudah tidak boleh menguruskan diri mereka lagi. Jika ibu bapa boleh menatang kita umpama anak emas, mengapa kita sebagai anak tidak boleh melakukan hal yang sama? Hal ini disebabkan oleh mereka masih tidak bijak untuk menghargai seseorang yang telah berjasa kepada diri mereka sedangkan  ibu bapalah yang telah membimbing, mendidik dan menjaga mereka sejak mereka kecil lagi. Seandainya tiada ibu bapa,siapakah kita pada hari ini? Akhir sekali,anak-anak harus mentaati perintah ibu bapa agar keluarga bahagia dapat dibina. Sejujurnya, inilah antara ciri yang perlu ada dalam sebuah keluarga yang menjadi impian saya.Haruslah menjadi kewajipan dalam institusi kekeluargaan untuk saling hormat menghormati  antara satu sama lain. Ahli keluarga sewajarnya mengelakkan daripada mencetuskan pertelingkahan, terutamanya antara ibu bapa dengan anak-anak kerana keluarga bahagia tidak seharusnya ada sikap seperti ini dan hal ini boleh mencemarkan nama baik keluarga secara tidak langsung. Ramai orang mengatakan bahawa keluarga yang bahagia ialah keluarga yang harmoni, aman dan damai. Sebagai ahli keluarga yang prihatin dan mengambil berat terhadap keluarga, mereka haruslah mewujudkan situasi ini dalam keluarga agar keluarga kita dihormati oleh masyarakat luar dan tidak dipandang serong serta dipandang hina. Ahli keluarga haruslah  bahu-membahu antara satu sama lain. Seandainya dalam keluarga itu ada seorang yang lemah dalam subjek matematik, haruslah dibantu oleh adik beradik yang lain kerana sikap bantu membantu ialah sikap yang baik dan mulia. Orang yang kedekut ilmu selalunya merupakan orang yang rugi kerana mereka tidak ingin membantu memajukan generasi akan datang, malah mereka lebih rela melihat generasi akan datang dipijak oleh penjajah. Kita haruslah mengamalkan sikap berat sama dipikul, ringan sama dijinjing dan ke gunung sama didaki, ke lurah sama dituruni. Tegasnya, saya mengimpikan ahli keluarga yang  mengamalkan nilai-nilai murni dalam kehidupan  untuk membina keluarga bahagia di samping membangunkan generasi akan datang agar sesebuah institusi keluarga itu menjadi keluarga yang dihormati.Kesimpulannya,  itulah antara ciri keluarga yang menjadi impian saya, terutamanya setelah saya dewasa dan membina keluarga sendiri. Semuanya akan menjadi kenyataan sekiranya saya berjaya dalam bidang pelajaran yang sudah pasti akan menjadikan masa hadapan saya cerah kerana kedudukan ekonomi saya yang stabil. Selain itu, saya dan pasangan yang menjadi suri kehidupan saya akan memikul tanggungjawab dengan sebaik yang mungkin agar anak-anak akan menjadikan kami sebagai rol model mereka. Dengan keizinan daripada Yang Maha Esa, mudah-mudahan impian saya akan tercapai. Lebih jauh lagi, saya mesti berusaha dengan penuh kesungguhan agar impian tidak tinggal sebagai mimpi pada siang hari kerana tanpa usaha tiadalah kejayaan. Semoga fajar yang  menyingsing pada sekurang-kurangnya sepuluh tahun akan datang  memberikan sinaran paling gemilang dalam kehidupan saya."},{"question":"Sự kiện quan trọng nào được nói tới trong văn bản này? - Vào tháng 10 năm 2017, ông được bầu làm Ủy viên Ủy ban Trung ương Đảng Cộng sản Trung Quốc khóa XIX tại Đại hội Đảng Cộng sản Trung Quốc lần thứ 19.","answer":"Văn bản nói về sự kiện quan trọng là việc một người được bầu vào chức Ủy viên Ủy ban Trung ương Đảng Cộng sản Trung Quốc khóa XIX trong Đại hội Đảng Cộng sản Trung Quốc lần thứ 19 vào tháng 10 năm 2017."},{"question":"Quem é coroado rei de Gondor após a Guerra do Anel?","answer":"Aragorn, também conhecido por Elessar, é coroado rei de Gondor após a Guerra do Anel."},{"question":"Yaya tsawon lokaci aka dauka don gina babbar ganuwa ta kasar Sin?","answer":"fiye da shekaru 2300 da suka wuce. Babbar ganuwa ita ce aikin tsaro mafi girma na tsohuwar kasar Sin, kuma daya daga cikin abubuwan al'ajabi na tarihin gine-ginen duniya. Gina Babban Katangar ya dau fiye da shekaru 2,000, daga lokacin bazara da kaka (770-476B. C.) da Jihohin Warring (475-221B."},{"question":"Zadzisa dimikara rinotevera:Kudya marasha","answer":"kupenga zvekupopota kana munhu akashatirwa"},{"question":"Explain the term \\"bag-of-words\\" in the context of NLP. ","answer":"The bag-of-words model represents text as an unordered set of words, disregarding grammar and word order. It is a basic and widely used representation in NLP."},{"question":"క్రింది గద్యాన్ని చదవండి. ప్రశ్నలకు జవాబులు వ్రాయండి.ఉర్దూ మన దేశీయుల ఉమ్మడి భాష. కాని ఏదో ఒక కులానికో, మతానికో చెందిన భాష కాదన్నారు ప్రొఫెసర్ రఫియా సుల్తానా. ఆ తరం వాళ్లందరూ అట్లాగే అనుకున్నారు. ఇప్పటికీ ఉన్న ఆ తరం వాళ్లు అట్లాగే అనుకుంటున్నారు. అందుకే నా ముచ్చట్లలో ఉర్దూతో మాకు గల సంబంధాన్ని యాది చేసుకుంటున్నాను.మా చదువు ఉర్దూ మీడియంలో జరిగింది. హెడ్మాస్టర్ అన్వరుద్దీన్ సాహెబు. ఉర్దూ చెప్పే మౌల్వీ సాహెబులు ఇద్దరో, ముగ్గురో ఉండేవాళ్లు. అయితే, పై తరగతిలో చదివే మాకు రామనాథరావుసార్ ఉర్దూ చెప్పేవారు. వారు మంథెన బ్రాహ్మణులు. ఎఫ్.ఎ. (ఇంటర్మీడియట్) చదివిన ఆ సారుకు తెలుగు, సంస్కృతం, మరాఠీ, ఇంగ్లీషు భాషల్లో మంచి పాండిత్యం వుండేదనేవాళ్లు.ఉర్దూలో ఏదో పెద్ద పరీక్ష పాసయినారు. వారు పెద్ద తరగతికి ఉర్దూ చెప్తుంటే ఉర్దూ డిగ్రీలు గల మౌల్వీ – సాహెబులెవరూ అభ్యంతరం లేవదీయలేదు. పైగా తమకు సరిగా అర్ధం కుదరని ఉర్దూ పేర్ల తాత్పర్యం మా ముందరే రామనాథరావుసార్తో చెప్పించుకునేవాళ్లు.ప్రశ్నలు:అ) రఫియా సుల్తానా తరంవాళ్ళు ఏమని అను కున్నారు ?ఆ) రచయిత తన ముచ్చట్లలో ఏ భాషా సంబంధాన్ని యాది చేసుకున్నాడు ?ఇ) రామనాథరావుసార్ ఎక్కడివారు ? ఏ విషయాన్ని బోధించేవారు ?ఈ) ఉర్దూ డిగ్రీలున్న మౌల్వీలు రామనాథరావు సార్న ఏ విషయమై సంప్రదించేవాళ్లు ?","answer":"అ) రఫియా సుల్తానా తరంవాళ్ళు ఏమని అను కున్నారు ?జవాబు:ఉర్దూ మన దేశీయుల ఉమ్మడి భాషని, ఏదో ఒక కులానికో, మతానికో చెందిన భాష కాదన్నారు.ఆ) రచయిత తన ముచ్చట్లలో ఏ భాషా సంబంధాన్ని యాది చేసుకున్నాడు ?జవాబు:ఉర్దూతో గల సంబంధాన్ని యాది చేసు కున్నాడు.ఇ) రామనాథరావుసార్ ఎక్కడివారు ? ఏ విషయాన్ని బోధించేవారు ?జవాబు:రామనాథరావు సార్ మంథెన బ్రాహ్మణులు. ఉర్దూ బోధించేవారు.ఈ) ఉర్దూ డిగ్రీలున్న మౌల్వీలు రామనాథరావు సార్న ఏ విషయమై సంప్రదించేవాళ్లు ?జవాబు:అర్థం కుదరని ఉర్దూ పేర్ల తాత్పర్యంపై సంప్రదించేవాళ్లు."},{"question":"No nosso sistema solar, qual o planeta que fica mais distante do Sol?MarteTerraUranoNetuno","answer":"O planeta mais distante do Sol é Netuno"},{"question":"යාච්ඤාවේ අරමුණ (අර්ථය) කුමක්ද?","answer":"යාච්ඤාව කිතුණු ජීවිතයේ වැදගත් අංගයකි. එය අප සමිඳාණන් වහන්සේ සමඟ සන්නිවේදනය කරන ආකාරය සහ උන්වහන්සේට ප්‍රශංසා කරන ආකාරයයි. යාච්ඤාවේ අරමුණ (අර්ථය) අවබෝධ කර ගැනීම සඳහා, යාච්ඤාව යනු කුමක්දැයි මුලින්ම තේරුම් ගැනීම වැදගත්ය. කිතුණුවන් අතර පවා යාච්ඤාව සම්බන්ධයෙන් ලෝකයේ සහ සංස්කෘතියේ බොහෝ වැරදි මත පවතින අතර, මේවාට ප්‍රථමයෙන් අවධානය යොමු කළ යුතුය."},{"question":"Inona no anaran'ny taolana miaro ny atidoha?","answer":"Ny karandoha no  anaran'ny taolana miaro ny atidoha."},{"question":"Qu'est que c'est une madoline ?","answer":"La mandoline est un instrument de musique à cordes pincées originaire d'Italie. Petit luth à manche court utilisé en musique classique, folklorique ou traditionnelle, elle est surtout répandue dans les pays méditerranéens. Elle est connue, par exemple, comme l'instrument d'accompagnement privilégié de la chanson napolitaine."},{"question":"කමත් බසෙන් පුරවන්න  යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ගෝනිය"},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para esse parágrafo - Com a Alemanha derrotada, mudou o foco para a guerra com o Japão, transferindo meio milhão de tropas para o Extremo Oriente. Foi pressionado por seus aliados a entrar na guerra e queria consolidar a posição estratégica da União Soviética na Ásia. Em 8 de agosto, entre os bombardeios atômicos dos EUA em Hiroshima e Nagasaki, o exército soviético invadiu a Manchúria ocupada pelos japoneses e derrotou o Exército de Guangdong. Esses eventos levaram à rendição japonesa","answer":"e ao fim da guerra. As forças soviéticas continuaram a crescer até ocuparem todas as concessões territoriais inimigas, mas os Estados Unidos rejeitaram o desejo de Stalin de que o Exército Vermelho participasse da ocupação aliada do Japão."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'buruk makan'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang makan dengan gelojoh; tamak makan Contoh ayat: Budak yang buruk makan itu, membedal semua kuih-muih yang dihidang di atas meja."},{"question":"Kinsa si Jose ug Mary nga magulang ni Jesus?","answer":"Sila mao ang nag-adopt kang Jesus isip iyang tinood nga mga ginikanan, si Jose mao ang iyang amahan, ug si Maria mao ang iyang inahan."},{"question":"*مدينة سورية ومنطقة في الكويت لهما نفس الإسم ؟","answer":"تدمر"},{"question":" Tìm các dấu chấm phẩy được dùng trong những câu dưới đây và chỉ ra tác dụng của chúng trong câu:a) Ai từng tiếp xúc với Nguyên Hồng đều thấy rõ điều này: ông rất dễ xúc động, rất dễ khóc. Khóc khi nhớ đến bạn bè, đồng chí từng chia bùi sẻ ngọt; khóc khi nghĩ đến đời sống khổ cực của nhân dân mình ngày trước; khóc khi nói đến công ơn của Tổ quốc, quê hương đã sinh ra mình, đền công ơn của Đảng, của Bác Hồ đã đem đến cho mình lí tưởng cao đẹp của thời đại.b) Chẳng hạn, truyện dân gian kể, lúc Lê Lợi sinh ra có ánh sáng đỏ đầy nhà, mùi hương lạ khắp xóm; còn Nguyễn Huệ, khi ra đời, có hai con hổ chầu hai bên.","answer":"a) Có hai dấu chấm phẩy dùng để ngăn các phần trong phép liệt kê.b) Có một dấu chấm phẩy dùng để ngăn hai ý trong vị ngữ."},{"question":"విశేషణ పూర్వపద కర్మాధారయం గురించి రాయండి మరియు ఉదాహరణలు రాయండి.","answer":"విశేషణ పూర్వపద కర్మాధారయం:ఈ సమాసంలోని రెండు పదాలలో మొదటి పదం విశేషణం. రెండవ పదం విశేష్యంగా ఉంటుంది.ఉదా:1. మధురోక్తులు = మధురమైన ఉక్తులు2. ఎర్రగులాబి = ఎర్రనైన గులాబి3. దివ్యాత్మ = దివ్యమైన ఆత్మపై ఉదాహరణల్లో పూర్వపదం విశేషణం. అందుకే ఈ సమాసానికి విశేషణ పూర్వపద సమాసమని పేరు."},{"question":"வினா:உ.வே.சாமிநாதையரின் ஆசிரியர் யார்?","answer":"விடை:உ.வே.சாமிநாதையரின் ஆசிரியர் மீனாட்சி சுந்தரம் பிள்ளை.குறிப்பு :மீனாட்சிசுந்தரம் பிள்ளை   சிறந்த தமிழறிஞர். உ. வே. சாமிநாதையரின் ஆசிரியர். திருவாவடுதுறை ஆதீனத் தலைவர் அம்பலவாண தேசிகர் இவருக்கு ‘மகாவித்வான்’ என்ற பட்டத்தை அளித்துச் சிறப்பித்தார். திருவாவடுதுறை மடத்தின் தலைமைப் புலவராகத் திகழ்ந்தார். சீர்காழியில் முன்சீபாகப் பணியாற்றிய தமிழில் முதல் புதினமான பிரதாப முதலியார் சரித்திரத்தை எழுதிய மாயூரம் வேதநாயகம் பிள்ளையுடன் நெருங்கிய நட்புக் கொண்டிருந்தார். அவர் மீது வைத்திருந்த பெருமதிப்பின் காரணமாக, அவரைப் பாராட்டிக் ‘குளத்துக்கோவை’ என்னும் நூலை இயற்றினார்."},{"question":"كمل الفقرة:إن هذا الموضوع -الذي تقدمه هذه المقالة- يندرج في تاريخ مؤسسات الحضارة الإسلامية، وسنُطلّ عبره على أفخمها نطاقا وأعظمها أثرا وهي مؤسسة البحرية الإسلامية التي وصلت إلى الذروة في صناعة الأساطيل البحرية الكبرى وشتى","answer":"فروع علوم البحرية العسكرية، فكان البحارة المسلمون على دراية عميقة بأنواع السفن العسكرية، وتكتيكات المناورات الحربية، وعمليات القوات الخاصة في الإنقاذ والإنزال البحري."},{"question":"Ààlọ́ o!Òjìji fìí, arógba aṣọ má balẹ̀.Kíni o?","answer":"Igi Ọ̀pẹ ni o."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa  Kumuu Ahaa Raysul wasaarihii labaad(2) ee wadanka soomaaliya?","answer":"Muhamad Xaaji Ibraahim Cigaal."},{"question":"ਅਲੈਕਸੀ ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਆਗਾਮੀ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਇਮਾਨਦਾਰੀ ਨਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਰਹੀਆਂ।ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਨੇ ਰੂਸੀ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਟਵੀਟ ਕਰਕੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਨਜ਼ਰਬੰਦ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।ਇਸਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਮਾਇਤੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਦੇਸ ਭਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋ ਰਹੇ ਧਰਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੋਣ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਛਾਪਾ ਮਾਰ ਕੇ ਕੁੱਝ ਉਪਕਰਨ ਵੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਕਬਜ਼ੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੈ ਲਏ ਸਨ।ਪੂਰੇ ਦੇਸ ਵਿੱਚ 180 ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਨਜ਼ਰਬੰਦ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਹਨ।ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਪੂਤਿਨ ਦੇ ਕੱਟੜ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ।ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਪੂਤਿਨ ਦੇ ਕੱਟੜ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਉੱਪਰ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਲੜਨ 'ਤੇ ਪਾਬੰਦੀ ਲੱਗੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਟਵਿਟਰ ਹੈਂਡਲ 'ਤੇ ਪਾਈਆਂ ਤਸਵੀਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਹਿਰਾਸਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਤੇ ਲਿਟਾਉਂਦੇ ਦੇਖੇ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਟਵੀਟ ਕੀਤਾ, \\"ਕਿਸੇ ਇੱਕ ਨੂੰ ਫੜ ਲੈਣਾ ਬੇਅਰਥ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂ ਕਿ ਅਸੀਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹਾਂ। ਕੋਈ ਆਓ ਤੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਥਾਂ ਲਓ।\\"ਰੂਸ ਦੇ ਕਈ ਸ਼ਹਿਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਧਰਨੇ-ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਚੱਲ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਮਾਸਕੋ ਤੇ ਸੈਂਟ ਪੀਟਰਜ਼ਬਰਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੰਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ।ਪੁਲਿਸ ਦਾ ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਦੇ ਸੰਗਠਨ 'ਤੇ ਛਾਪਾ।ਐਤਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਰੂਸੀ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਨੇ ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਦੀ ਭ੍ਰਿਟਾਚਾਰ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਸੰਗਠਨ ਦੀ ਮਾਸਕੋ ਵਿਚਲੀ ਜਾਇਦਾਦ 'ਤੇ ਛਾਪਾ ਮਾਰਿਆ। ਯੂ ਟਿਊਬ 'ਤੇ ਅਪਲੋਡ ਇੱਕ ਵੀਡੀਓ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਛਾਪਾ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ।ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਦੇ ਬੁਲਾਰੇ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਨੇ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੋਣ ਲਈ ਭਾਰੀ ਔਜ਼ਾਰ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਤੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਮਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੰਬ ਹੋਣ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਦਸ਼ਾ ਹੈ।ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਆਗਾਮੀ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਮਾਨਦਾਰੀ ਨਹੀ ਬਰਤੀ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।ਰੂਸ ਨੇ ਹਥੌੜੇ ਅਤੇ ਦਾਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਉਂ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਕੌਮੀ ਚਿੰਨ੍ਹ?ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਦੇ ਹਮਾਇਤੀਆਂ 'ਤੇ ਦਬਾਅ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਪੂਤਿਨ ਨੂੰ ਬਰਾਬਰੀ ਦੇ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਰਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਅਪਰਾਧਿਕ ਮਾਮਲਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਚਲਦੇ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਲੜਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਬੰਦੀ ਲਾਈ ਗਈ ਹੈ।2011-12 ਦੀਆਂ ਸਰਦੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਨੇ ਵਿਸ਼ਾਲ ਜਨਤਕ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ।","answer":"ਰਾਜਧਾਨੀ ਮਾਸਕੋ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੂਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਦੇ ਬਾਈਕਾਟ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾ ਰਹੇ ਇੱਕ ਰੋਸ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰ ਦੇ ਆਗੂ ਅਲੈਕਸੀ ਨੈਵੇਲਨੀ ਨੂੰ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਨੇ ਨਜ਼ਰਬੰਦ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Manana teny mikorotana ianao : AALSOmeno ny teny tena marina:","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"LASA\\""},{"question":"２０１１年にメジャーデビューした４人組のバンドで、メンバーがFukase、Nakajin、Saori、DJ LOVEといえば何？","answer":"SEKAI NO OWARIです。"},{"question":"கேள்வி : மின்தடையை கண்டுபிடித்தவர் யார் ?","answer":"பதில் : ஓம்."},{"question":"त्वयि मेऽनन्यविषया मतिर्मधुतेऽसकृत् |रतिमुद्वहताद्धा गङ्गेवोघमुदन्वति || कुन्ती भागवत १ स्कंध ८ अध्याय","answer":"अर्थ : हे मधू राक्षसाचा वध करणाऱ्या श्रीकृष्णा, गंगेचा प्रवाह ज्याप्रमाणे [न थांबता, सतत ] समुद्राकडे झेप घेतो त्याप्रमाणे तुझ्याविषयी माझ्या मनात एकान्तिक [दुसरा कुठलाही विचार न येता फक्त तुझेच चिंतन एवढा एकच] विचार येवो"},{"question":"ما هي السورة التي تسببت في إسلام عمر بن الخطاب؟","answer":"– سورة طه."},{"question":"أين تقع باريس؟","answer":"تقع باريس في فرنسا وهي عاصمتها وأكبر مدنها من حيث عدد السكان. تقع على ضفاف نهر السين في الجزء الشمالي من البلاد في قلب منطقة إيل دو فرانس. بلغ عدد سكانها 2,243,833 عام 2010 ضمن نطاقها الإداري فقط، بينما يربو عدد سكان المدينة مع ضواحيها على 12 مليون نسمة."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 日本はEPAという約束で、2009年からフィリピン人の看護師が日本で働くことができるようにしています。今までに660人以上が日本に来ています。フィリピンのマニラで22日、日本で働きたい看護師を面接する会がありました。参加した看護師は17人で、今まででいちばん少なくなりました。フィリピンは給料が安いため、看護師の30％ぐらいが外国で働いていると言われています。新型コロナウイルスが広がってから、世界で看護師を集める競争が激しくなっています。日本は、円が安くなって給料が少なくなることや、日本語の問題があるため、人気が低くなっているようです。面接をした宮城県の病院の人は「とても人が少なくて驚きました」と話していました。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。- 看護師: 1）医者の手助けや、病人の世話を仕事にしている人。- 面接: 1）じかに会うこと。- 参加: 1）仲間に入ること。- 給料: 1）やとい主が、働いた人にはらうお金。給与。サラリー。- 広がっ: 1）広くなる。2）広々と見わたせる。3）行きわたる。4）大きくなる。- 激しく: 1）勢いが強い。2）ものごとの程度がきつい。- 人気: 1）世の中の人たちのよい評判。"},{"question":"ഡഫർ ബ്രദേഴ്‌സ് സൃഷ്‌ടിച്ച ഒരു ജനപ്രിയ സയൻസ് ഫിക്ഷൻ ഹൊറർ സീരീസാണ് \\"സ്ട്രേഞ്ചർ തിംഗ്സ്\\". 1980 കളുടെ പശ്ചാത്തലത്തിൽ, അത് അമാനുഷിക ഘടകങ്ങളെ സർക്കാർ ഗൂഢാലോചനയും ഗൃഹാതുരമായ പരാമർശങ്ങളും സമന്വയിപ്പിക്കുന്നു. ഒരു ആൺകുട്ടിയുടെ ദുരൂഹമായ തിരോധാനവും സൈക്കോകൈനറ്റിക് കഴിവുകളുള്ള ഒരു പെൺകുട്ടിയുടെ രൂപവും കൈകാര്യം ചെയ്യുന്ന സാങ്കൽപ്പിക പട്ടണമായ ഹോക്കിൻസിലെ ഒരു കൂട്ടം കുട്ടികളെ ചുറ്റിപ്പറ്റിയാണ് ഇതിവൃത്തം. 80കളിലെ പോപ്പ് സംസ്‌കാരത്തോടുള്ള ഗൃഹാതുരമായ ആദരവ്, കഥപറച്ചിൽ, കഥാപാത്രങ്ങൾ എന്നിവയ്ക്ക് ഈ പരമ്പരയ്ക്ക് വൻ ആരാധകവൃന്ദവും നിരൂപക പ്രശംസയും ലഭിച്ചു.ഈ ഭാഗം എന്തിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്?","answer":"അമാനുഷിക ഘടകങ്ങൾ, ഗവൺമെന്റ് ഗൂഢാലോചന, ഗൃഹാതുരമായ പരാമർശങ്ങൾ എന്നിവയ്ക്ക് പേരുകേട്ട 1980-കളിലെ പ്രശസ്തമായ സയൻസ് ഫിക്ഷൻ ഹൊറർ സീരീസായി ഇതിനെ വിവരിക്കുന്ന \\"അപരിചിതമായ കാര്യങ്ങൾ\\" എന്നതിന്റെ ഒരു ഹ്രസ്വ അവലോകനം ഈ ഭാഗം നൽകുന്നു."},{"question":"வேண்டுமென்று இச்சொல்லைப் பிரித்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது ________வேண்டு + மென்றுவேண்டும் + என்றுவேண் + டுமென்றுவேண்டி + என்று","answer":"விடை : வேண்டுமென்று இச்சொல்லைப் பிரித்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது __வேண்டும் + என்று"},{"question":"కింది ప్రకృతులను వికృతులతో జతపర్చండి.1) రథం\\tఅ) ఆన2) కుమారుడు\\tఆ) అరదం3) ఆజ్ఞ\\tఇ) కొమరుడు","answer":"1) రథం\\tఆ) అరదం2) కుమారుడు\\tఇ) కొమరుడు3) ఆజ్ఞ\\tఅ) ఆన"},{"question":"\\"සිංහල ජය ගීත හඬට\\" ගීතයේ ඉතිරි පද සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.","answer":"සිංහල ජය ගීත හඬටසිංහල කොඩිවැල් ලෙල දෙනසිංහල දෙරණේසරණ සිංහල සරණේමූදු වගේ වැව් බැඳුනේ යෝධ විකුම් බල නැගුනේවීර හැඟුම් මල් පිපුණේ සාර රටක් ලොව මැවුනේගල් මත බුදු රූ දිලුනේ මහ මෙත් සිසිලෙන් තෙමුනේමහ බෝ හිස දළු සැලුනේ සදහම් පණිවිඩ ඇසුණේරුදු රුපු ඔද තෙද සිඳුනේ සුර විරු රණ ගී ගැයුනේමව් බිම දියුණට පොරණේ දහදිය කඳු ගොඩ ගැසුනේසිරි දළදා රැකවරණේ රන් වැලි මහ සෑ කිරණේමරණින් මතු නව අරණේ යළි උපදිමු මේ දෙරණේ"},{"question":"Ngiyabonga sayitsheni. Ukube anifikanga ngabe indaba yamiisingumlando. Ngibonga kakhulu sayitsheni.Ubonga ngakhona Duma kodwa nguwe oyimbangela yalokhu.Usho ukuthini sayitsheni? Yimi yini ovimba intuthuko lapha kulendawo?Uyakhumbula ngikubuza ukuthi uyathathisa na enkosini umauzokwenza utho endaweni yayo? Wathini wena? Angithi wadazainkani? Nenhlangano yakho yaphinde yakuyala ngokuhlonipha inkosi,wena wenza okuthandwa nguwe. Bafile-ke manje abantu. UMbandlwasiyezwa ukuthi ubengungqa phambili ekutheni wenze lokhuobukwenza. Naye uDlamini kuyavela ukuthi ubethukuthela aze enzeizinto ezingalungile njengakho ukushaya uMbandlwa.Angimsoli-ke yena kakhulu ngoba ubehlukunyezwa ngukubona wenauthela inkosi yakhe ngothuli.(ukuzithoba kuyadlondlobala. Useze watshekisa ngisho nekhanda.Izandla zakhe ulokhu ezihlanganisa njengomuntu okhuluma nomuntuamhlonipha ngendlela exakile) Ngiyezwa sayitsheni. (athule kancane)Sekwenzekile-ke okubuhlungu sayitsheni. Ngiyaphinda ngithi velesekonakele. Manje, ngizocela nigcine ukuthula endaweni, minasengizowuyeka-ke lo msebenzi wobukhansela.(enyuse izwi ngenxa yentukuthelo) Uthini? Uyeke? Niqala izinto besenigabisa ngokuyeka uma sekonakele? Lutho! Wena yelekelelaekucisheni lo mlilo wothathe osuwokhele.Kahle sayitsheni. Ngizowucisha kanjani lo mlilo? Bazongibulala phelaabantu.1. Bakuphi laba abakhulumayo kulesi siqeshana? ","answer":"Basesikhumulweni samaphoyisa."},{"question":"ما هي أطول سورة بالقرآن الكريم؟","answer":"\\tالبقرة"},{"question":"Wat voor emotie zal iemand hebben als die een verrassende rekening krijgt? Er zijn de volgende opties:A: ergernisB: geïrriteerdC: humorD: geschoktE: gelukkig","answer":"In deze context is het juiste antwoord A of B."},{"question":":كم عدد السنوات التي عاشتها اليمن تحت الاحتلال العثماني الثاني؟","answer":"65 سنة"},{"question":"ရွှေတိဂုံ စေတီတော်က ဘယ်မှာ ကုန်းတော်ပေါ်မှာ တည်ရှိသလဲ။ ","answer":"ရွှေတိဂုံ စေတီတော်ကြီးက ရန်ကုန်မြို့ရှိ သိင်္ဂုတ္တရ ကုန်းတော်ပေါ်တွင် တည်ရှိပါသည်။"},{"question":"Zientzia sozialean, nola ulertzen du globalizazioak nazioarteko harremanak eta kultura-trukeak?","answer":"Globalizazioak mundu osoan harremanak eta trukeak errazten ditu. Honek kulturak elkarrekin interakzionatzea ahalbidetzen du eta gizartearen ulermen globala hobetzen du."},{"question":" Inona no tendrombohitra avo indrindra eran-tany?","answer":"Ny tendrombohitra avo indrindra eto an-tany dia Everest."},{"question":"Completa la siguiente frase :  Ha estado presente en los Mundiales de Fútbol de Francia,","answer":"Lo completaría de la siguiente manera: Corea y Japón y Alemania; en las Eurocopas de 2000 y 2008 y en los Juegos Olímpicos de Atenas 2004. También ha seguido, como enviado especial, las ediciones del Tour de Francia de 1999, 2000 y 2002."},{"question":"📚 Манас эпосундагыКайсы манасчынын варианты ―-Бай Жакыптын катыны, баатыр тууп жатыры деген саптар менен башталат? Бул кабарды ким айтат, аны ким уккан?а) Ашым Жакыпбеков, жылаңач бала, Акбалтаб) Саякбай, дубана, Меңдибайв) Сагымбай, дербиш, Чегебайг) Бегыш, олуя, Жакып","answer":"а) Ашым Жакыпбеков, жылаңач бала, Акбалта"},{"question":"வினா: உடலின் வெப்பநிலையைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த யானை எந்தப் பகுதியைப் பயன்படுத்துகிறது?","answer":"விடை: உடலின் வெப்பநிலையைக் கட்டுப்படுத்த யானையானது காது  என்ற பகுதியைப் பயன்படுத்துகிறது.யானை பாலூட்டி வகையைச் சேர்ந்த ஒரு தாவர உண்ணி (இலையுண்ணி) விலங்காகும். இது நிலத்தில் வாழும் விலங்குகள் யாவற்றினும் மிகப் பெரியதாகும். மிக நீண்ட நாட்கள் வாழக்கூடியதும் ஆகும் (~ 70 ஆண்டுகள்). மனிதர்கள் தவிர்ந்த மற்றைய விலங்குகளில் இதுவே அதிக நாட்கள் வாழும் தரைவாழ் விலங்கு ஆகும். யானைகள் மிகவும் வலிமையானவை; வேட்டை விலங்குகளும் காட்டுயிர்களின் உணவுப் படிநிலையில் உயர்நிலையில் உள்ளவைகளுமான சிங்கம் (அரிமா), புலி முதலியன கூட நெருங்க முடியாத வலிமை கொண்டவை. சிங்கங்கள் ஒன்றாகச் சேர்ந்து, தனியாக வர நேரிடும் களைத்த அல்லது இளைத்த யானையைக் கொல்லும். ஆனால், இவ்வகை நிகழ்வுகள் மிகமிகக் குறைவே. யானைகள் குடும்பமாக வாழும். மேலும், இவை அதிக ஞாபக சக்தி கொண்டவை.யானைகளில் மூன்று சிற்றினங்கள் இன்று உலகில் எஞ்சியுள்ளன. அவை, ஆப்பிரிக்கப் புதர்வெளி யானைகள், ஆப்பிரிக்கக் காட்டு யானைகள், ஆசிய யானைகள் ஆகும். இவைகளுக்கிடையே சிறப்பான வேறுபாடுகள் உள்ளன. பொதுவாக, எல்லா யானைகளும் ஏறத்தாழ 70 ஆண்டுகள் வரை உயிர்வாழ்கின்றன.ஆண் யானைக்குக் களிறு என்று பெயர். பெண் யானைக்குப் பிடி என்று பெயர். யானையின் குட்டியைக் கன்று என்றோ, குட்டியானை என்றோ சொல்வர். யானை உரக்க எழுப்பும் ஒலியைப் பிளிறுதல் என்பர்."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Yaya za a rubuta ɗari ɗaya da goma sha-biyar a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 115"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Giá gas giảm lần thứ 4 liên tiếp","answer":"Ngày 31/7, nhiều doanh nghiệp kinh doanh gas thông báo điều chỉnh giảm giá mặt hàng này từ ngày mai (1/8). Đây là lần giảm thứ 4 liên tiếp từ đầu năm đến nay. Theo đó, mỗi bình gas loại 12kg đến tay người tiêu dùng tiếp tục giảm trung bình 18.000 đồng, loại 45kg giảm 67.500 đồng/bình, tùy thương hiệu. Công ty TNHH MTV Dầu khí TP.HCM (Saigon Petro) thông báo từ ngày 1/8 giá bán gas Saigon Petro giảm 18.500 đồng/bình 12kg. Với mức giảm này, giá bán lẻ gas thương hiệu này đến tay người tiêu dùng sẽ ở mức 430.500 đồng/bình 12kg và bình 45kg ở mức 1.190.000 đồng. Tương tự, Công ty cổ phần kinh doanh LPG Việt Nam chi nhánh miền Nam cũng cho biết từ tháng 8 giá gas giảm 18.000 đồng/ bình 12kg và 67.500 đồng/bình 45kg. Theo đó, giá bán lẻ đến người tiêu dùng 432.900 đồng/bình 12kg và 1.623.390 đồng/bình 45kg. Như vậy, đây là tháng thứ tư liên tiếp giá gas trong nước được điều chỉnh giảm. Lũy kế mức giảm 4 tháng qua khoảng 87.000 đồng/bình 12kg. Tính từ đầu năm đến nay, giá gas bán lẻ trong nước đã có 3 lần tăng và 5 lần giảm. Hiện, giá loại nhiên liệu này đã về mức thấp hơn thời điểm đầu năm 2022. Thời gian qua, giá xăng, dầu, gas tăng lên mức cao làm ảnh hưởng trực tiếp đến tiêu dùng của người dân, các ngành vận tải, sản xuất. Việc giá gas và xăng dầu có xu hướng giảm liên tục góp phần làm giảm áp lực cho doanh nghiệp sản xuất kinh doanh và người tiêu dùng trong bối cảnh phục hồi sau đại dịch Covid-19. Theo số liệu vừa được Tổng cục Thống kê công bố, chỉ số giá tiêu dùng (CPI) tháng 7 đã tăng 3,14% so với cùng kỳ năm trước. Giá tiêu dùng tăng chủ yếu do giá thịt lợn tăng cao, nhu cầu sử dụng điện, nước sinh hoạt tăng do thời tiết nắng nóng. Cùng với đó là giá hàng hóa và dịch vụ tiêu dùng thiết yếu tăng theo giá nguyên liệu đầu vào và chi phí vận chuyển."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao :  \\" Aza ny lohasaha mangina no jerena, fa .........................  \\" ","answer":"\\"   Aza ny lohasaha mangina no jerena, fa Andriamanitra ao antampon'ny loha \\""},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકના એક લેખનના શરૂઆતના ફકરા નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે.\\"બાપા, બૂતાન બીડી દ્યોને ?⁠બા, આ નથી ઊપડતું.⁠બેન, બૂટ પહેરાવોને ?\\"આ માથાફોડના આગળના ફકરા લખો.","answer":"બા, નવરાવી દ્યોને ?⁠નાના કાકા, સાંકળ વાસી દ્યોને !⁠બાપુ, ચોપડી નથી જડતી; ગોતી આપોને ? \\"બા, ઊભી રહીને સાથે ચાલને ? મોટાભાઈ, રૂમાલનો દડો કરી દ્યોને ?"},{"question":"*من هو آخر حاكم لقب بخليفة المسلمين ؟","answer":"عبد المجيد الثاني"},{"question":"ラテン語ではミオソチス、英語ではフォゲット・ミー・ノットというムラサキ科の多年草は何でしょう？","answer":"ワスレナグサです。"},{"question":"இரு சொற்களையும் பயன்படுத்தி ஒரே தொடரில் அமைத்து எழுதுக .","answer":"மடு – மாடு: மடுவில் (குட்டையில்) மாடு நீர்க் குடித்தது.மலை – மாலை : மலை மீது ஏறி மாலையில் விளையாடினேன். வளி – வாளி : வளியும் (காற்றும்) வாளியும் (அன்பும்) இல்லாமல் வாழ முடியாது."},{"question":"\\"Таалайына таш тийүү\\" дегендин маанисин чечмелеп бер.","answer":" Оор абалга, кыйын ишке, кырсыкка дуушар болуу, кирептер болуу. Эр жеткен уулум былтыр каза таап, таалайыма таш тийбедиби деп кейиди («Ала-Тоо»)"},{"question":"Quel est le plus grand pays d’Europe ?","answer":"La Russie est le plus grands pays d'Europe, est aussi dans le monde."},{"question":"أكبر عدد مضروب في 7 و الناتج أقل من 115?","answer":"بالتجريب نجد أن 16 × 7 = 112 , وهو اكبر عدد مضروب في 7 و الناتج أقل من 115"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"Mandry aloha tsy ................... \\".","answer":"\\"Mandry aloha tsy mirirana\\"."},{"question":"Água com gás hidrata da mesma forma que água sem gás?","answer":"Sim, os estudos indicam que hidrata igual, mas a aceitabilidade do humanos a água com gás é menor, ou seja, é mais fácil tomar 1 litro de água sem gás do que com gás. "},{"question":"செல்வம் இருப்பதற்கான வழியாக வள்ளுவம் உரைப்பன யாவை?","answer":"ஒருவரிடம் இருக்கும் செல்வம் குறையாமலிருக்க வேண்டுமென்றால், அவர் பிறருடைய கைப்பொருளை விரும்பாமல் இருத்தல் வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Shin gaskiyane cewa: Brazil ita ce ƙasa mafi girma a Kudancin Amurka ta yanki. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"Qual o grupo em que todas as palavras foram escritas corretamente em português do Brasil?a) Asterístico, beneficiente, meteorologia, entertidob) Asterisco, beneficente, meteorologia, entretidoc) Asterisco, beneficente, metereologia, entretidod) Asterístico, beneficiente, metereologia, entretidoe) Asterisco, beneficiente, metereologia, entretido","answer":"A resposta correta é a alternativa: b) Asterisco, beneficente, meteorologia, entretido."},{"question":"السؤال: ماذا كان يعمل الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم ؟","answer":"الإجابة: عمل في رأي الأغنام وفي التجارة مع عمه أبي طالب"},{"question":"Inona ny atao hoe \\"adirenalinina\\"?","answer":"Ny \\"adirenalinina\\" dia ranoka ao anaty tena mpanafaingana ny fitepon'ny fo."},{"question":"Кыргыз накыл кептери англис тилинде жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"All bread is not baked in one oven – Беш манжа бирдей эмес."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的音樂學院是哪一個？","answer":"答案：奧地利的維也納音樂與表演藝術大學"},{"question":"Oríkì Àjọbí, Àṣà Yorùbá Ti Ó Nparẹ́ Lọ","answer":"Oríkì* jẹ ọ̀rọ̀ ìwúrí ti Yorùbá ma nlò lati fi sọ ìtàn àṣà àti ìṣe ìdílé lati ìran dé ìran.  Ninú oríkì ni a ti lè mọ ìtàn ìṣẹ̀dálẹ̀ ẹbí ẹni àti ohun ti a mọ ìdílé mọ́, bí i irú iṣẹ ti wọn nṣe ni ìdílé, oriṣiriṣi èdè ìbílẹ̀ Yorùbá, oúnjẹ ti wọn njẹ àti èyí ti wọn ki i jẹ, ẹ̀sìn ìdílé, àdúgbò ti wọ́n tẹ̀dó si tàbi ìlú ti a ti ṣẹ̀ wá, àṣeyọrí ti wọn ti ṣe ni ìran ẹni àti bẹ́ ẹ̀ bẹ́ ẹ̀ lọ.Ni inú oríkì ti a ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ si i kọ, a ó ri àpẹrẹ ohun ti Yorùbá ṣe ma a nsọ oríkì pàtàki fún iwuri nigbati ọkùnrin, obinrin, ọmọdé àti ẹbí ẹni bá ṣe ohun rere bi ìṣílé, ìgbéyàwó, àṣeyorí ni ilé-iwé, oyè jijẹ tàbi ni ayé òde òni, àjọyọ̀ ọjọ́ ìbí.Oríkì jẹ ikan ninú àṣà Yorùbá ti ó ti nparẹ́, nitori ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ọmọ Yorùbá bẹ̀rẹ̀ si kọ èdè àti àṣà wọn sílẹ̀ fún èdè Gẹ̀ẹ́sí.  Ẹ ṣe àyẹ̀wò àpẹrẹ oríkì ti ìyá Olùkọ̀wé yi sọ fún ni ibi ayẹyẹ ọjọ́ ìbí rẹ̀ ni ojú ìwé yi.  A ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ si kọ oríkì oriṣiriṣi ìdílé Yorùbá.Ọmọ ẹlẹ́ja ò tú mù kẹkẹỌmọ a mẹ́ja yan ẹjaỌmọ ò sùn mẹ́gbẹ̀wá ti dọ̀ ara rẹ̀Ọmọ gbàsè gbàsè kẹ́ ṣọbinrin lọyinỌmọ kai, eó gbé si yàn únỌmọ a mú gbìrín eó b’ọ̀dìdẹ̀Ìṣò mó bọ, òwíyé wàarèỌmọ adáṣọ bù á lẹ̀ jẹỌmọ a má bẹ̀rẹ̀ gúnyán k’àdó gbèrìgbè mọ mọ̀Ọmọ a yan eó meka runỌmọ a mẹ́ kìka kàn yan ẹsinsun t’ọrẹÉ e ṣojú un ríro, ìṣẹ̀dálẹ̀ rin niỌmọ a mi malu ṣ’ọdún ìgbàgbọ́Ọmọ elési a gbàrùnbọ̀ morunỌmọ elési a gbàdá mo yókoÈsì li sunkún ètìtù kọ gbà àrán bora li Gèsan ỌbaỌmọ Olígèsan òròrò bílẹ̀Ọmọ alábùṣọrọ̀, a múṣu mọdiÀbùṣọrọ̀ lu lé uṣu, mọ́ m’ẹ́ùrà kàn kàn dé bẹ̀Kare o ‘Lúàmi, ku ọdún oni o, è í ra ṣàṣe mọ ri a (Àṣẹ)"},{"question":"ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ, 24 ਫਰਵਰੀਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਦੇ ਨੇੜਲੇ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇਦਾਰ ਰੌਬਰਟ ਵਾਡਰਾ ਨੇ ਅੱਜ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਇਕ ਵਾਰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਚੱਲ ਰਹੇ ਕੇਸ (ਭ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟਾਚਾਰ ਦੇ ਦੋਸ਼ਾਂ ਤਹਿਤ) ਖ਼ਤਮ ਹੋ ਜਾਣ, ਉਹ ‘ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਲਈ ਵੱਡੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ’ ਨਿਭਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ। ਵਾਡਰਾ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਬਿਆਨ ਨੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਆਸਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਵਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਸਰਗਰਮ ਸਿਆਸਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੈਰ ਧਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ। ਇਸ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਭਾਜਪਾ ਨੇ ਵਾਡਰਾ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਬਿਆਨ ’ਤੇ ਚੁਟਕੀ ਲੈਂਦਿਆਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ‘ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਲਈ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਪਦ ਦਾ ਉਮੀਦਵਾਰ’ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਹੈ।ਪੂਰਬੀ ਯੂਪੀ ਤੋਂ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੀ ਜਨਰਲ ਸਕੱਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਿਯੰਕਾ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਦੇ ਪਤੀ ਵਾਡਰਾ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਫੇਸਬੁੱਕ ਪੋਸਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਹਾ, ‘ਮੁਲਕ ਦੇ ਵੱਖ ਵੱਖ ਹਿੱਸਿਆਂ ਖਾਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਉੱਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਤੇ ਮਹੀਨਿਆਂਬੱਧੀ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਲਈ ਹੋਰ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।’ ਇੰਨੇ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਦੇ ਤਜਰਬੇ ਤੇ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਨੂੰ ਇਵੇਂ ਅਜਾਈਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਣ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ, ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਚੰਗੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਲਾਇਆ ਜਾਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।…ਇਕ ਵਾਰ ਇਹ ਕੇਸ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਹੋ ਜਾਣ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਮਰਪਿਤ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਵੱਡੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਉਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ।’ ਉਧਰ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਨੇ ਵਾਡਰਾ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਬਿਆਨ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਲੰਮੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਤੋਂ ਕਈ ਐਨਜੀਓਜ਼ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਸਮਾਜ ਲਈ ਵੀ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਹ ਹਰ ਕਿਸੇ ਦਾ ਫ਼ਰਜ਼ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਖੂਬੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੀ ਭਲਾਈ ਲਈ ਵਰਤਣ। ਵਾਡਰਾ ਵੱਲੋੋਂ ਸਿਆਸਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਸੰਕੇਤ ਬਾਰੇ ਪੁੱਛੇ ਜਾਣ ’ਤੇ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਤਰਜਮਾਨ ਪਵਨ ਖੇੜਾ ਨੇ ਇਥੇ ਪੱਤਰਕਾਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਬੋਧਨ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਹਾ, ‘ਕੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੇ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਮੋਦੀ ਜੀ (ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨਰਿੰਦਰ ਮੋਦੀ) ਤੋਂ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਲੈਣ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਹੈ। ਪੂਰਬੀ ਯੂਪੀ ਤੋਂ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦਾ ਜਨਰਲ ਸਕੱਤਰ ਕੌਣ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਪ੍ਰਿਅੰਕਾ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਪੂਰਬੀ ਯੂਪੀ ਤੋਂ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੀ ਜਨਰਲ ਸਕੱਤਰ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"கேள்வி: கிறிஸ்டியானோ ரொனால்டோ எந்த விளையாட்டுடன் தொடர்புடையவர்?","answer":"பதில் : கால்பந்துகிறிஸ்டியானோ ரொனால்டோ போர்த்துகீச கால்பந்து போர்த்துகீசிய நாட்டு கால்பந்தாட்ட வீரர் ஆவார். இவர் 2003-2022 வரை உலகின் தலைச்சிறந்த கால்பந்தாட்ட வீரர்கள் பட்டியலில் தொடர்ந்து முன்னிலை வகித்து வந்தார்."},{"question":"ગુજરાતીમાં હાર્લેમમાં ક્રિમિનલ રિવ્યુ આપો.","answer":"હાર્લેમ ગુજરાતીમાં ગુનાહિત સમીક્ષા:હાર્લેમ એ શહેરની મધ્યમાં આવેલો એક ઐતિહાસિક અને રસપ્રદ વિસ્તાર છે. તે તેના સંગીત, ભોજન, અને સાંસ્કૃતિક સ્થળો માટે પ્રખ્યાત છે. પરંતુ તે પણ તેની ગુનાહિત દરો માટે ખ્યાતિ છે.2020 માં, હાર્લેમમાં 10,886 ગુનાઓ બન્યા હતા, જે શહેરની સરેરાશ કરતા 17% વધારે છે. આમાં હત્યા, ચોરી, અને હુમલોનો સમાવેશ થાય છે.હાર્લેમમાં ગુનાહિત દરો ઘટી રહ્યા છે, પરંતુ તેઓ શહેરની સરેરાશ કરતા ઉચ્ચ રહે છે. 2019 માં, હાર્લેમમાં 11,247 ગુનાઓ બન્યા હતા, જે 2018 માં 12,683 ગુનાઓથી ઘટી ગયા હતા.હાર્લેમના ગુનાઓનો મોટો ભાગ હિંસક નથી. 2020 માં, હાર્લેમમાં 57 હત્યાઓ બની હતી, જે શહેરની સરેરાશ કરતા 13% વધારે છે. આમાં ગોળીબારી અને ખૂનનો સમાવેશ થાય છે.હાર્લેમમાં ગુનાહિત દરો ઘટાડવા માટે કેટલાક પ્રયાસો કરવામાં આવી રહ્યા છે. શહેર પોલીસ વિભાગ ગુનાગૃહો સામે ટર્મ્પોલોલોઝ અને અન્ય પગલાં લઈ રહ્યું છે. શાળાઓ અને સમુદાય સંસ્થાઓ પણ ગુનાહિતતા અટકાવવા માટે કામ કરી રહી છે.હાર્લેમમાં રહેવું પણ સુરક્ષિત છે. અહીં ઘણા સુરક્ષિત વિસ્તારો છે અને લોકો સામાન્ય રીતે મિત્રતાપૂર્ણ અને મદદરૂપ છે. જો તમે હાર્લેમમાં ફરવાનું અથવા રહેવાનું યોજી રહ્યા છો, તો તમે કાળજીપૂર્વક ચાલો અને તમારી આસપાસ ધ્યાન આપતા રહો. જો તમને કોઈ ગુનાહિત પ્રવૃત્તિ જણાય તો, તરત જ પોલીસને બોલાવો."},{"question":"*ما عاصمة روسيا ؟","answer":"موسكو"},{"question":"Awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ PDP darapọ mọ APC ni Kwara","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Kwara, Abdulrahman Abdulrasaq, ti gbalejo ọgọọrọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP ti wọn ju ẹgbẹ ọhun silẹ bii amuku ọsan, ti wọn si dara pọ mọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC.Abdulrasaq gbalejo wọn lati fi sami ayẹyẹ ijọba awa-ara-wa niluu Ilọrin ti ṣe olu ilu ipinlẹ Kwara.Lara awọn to darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC ni oludije sipo Aarẹ tẹlẹ ninu ẹgbẹ ACPN, Alhaji Ganiyu Galadimo, ati gbogbo awọn alaga kansu tẹlẹ lawọn ijọba ibilẹ mẹrẹẹrindinlogun ti wọn dibo yan labẹ asia ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP.Alaga ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC, ẹka ti ipinlẹ Kwara, Alhaji Abdullahi Samari, to sọrọ nibi ayẹyẹ ọhun sọ pe ẹgbẹ ti tẹwọ gba awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ PDP ati ọmọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu miiran to le ni ẹgbẹrun mẹta jake-jado ipinlẹ Kwara, ti wọn si sọ pe, aseyori ti ẹgbẹ APC ẹka ti Kwara ti ṣe labẹ iṣejọba Abdulrahman Abdulrasaq lo wu awọn lórí tawọn fi darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu onitẹsiwaju ọhun."},{"question":"Lan lañuy baye Senegal ?\\t","answer":"IRA."},{"question":"２０２２年も活躍した、メジャーリーグの大谷翔平選手。さて、日本で活動していた時期に所属していたプロチームはどこでしょう？","answer":"北海道日本ハムファイターズです。"},{"question":"Ano ang dapat unahin sa paggisa? Bawang o sibuyas?","answer":"Walang tamang sagot kung bawang o sibuyas ang dapat unahin sa paggisa. Pero kung susunod sa karaniwang kasanayan, ang sibuyas ang inuuna para ito ay maging \\"translucent\\" saka isusunod ang bawang."},{"question":"What is the significance of Sri Lanka's traditional dance forms?","answer":"Sri Lankan traditional dances, such as the Kandyan and low-country dances, hold cultural and historical significance. These dances often depict stories from folklore, mythology, and ancient rituals, showcasing the island's rich cultural heritage. The intricate costumes, rhythmic movements, and symbolic gestures contribute to a captivating visual spectacle. Performances are frequently associated with religious ceremonies, festivals, and traditional events, providing a means of preserving and passing down cultural narratives through the generations."},{"question":"වී බිස්ස ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න.","answer":"වී බිස්ස වනාහී සිංහල ගොවියාගේ වී වගාවේ පසු අස්වනු සංරක්‍ෂණය කරන නිර්මාණයකි. ඒ හා බැදුනු සංස්කෘතියෙහි බොහෝ ලක්ෂණ විද්‍යාත්මකය.භාණ්ඩ හුවමාරු ආර්ථිකයක් පැවති අතීත සමාජයෙහි වී බිස්සට සුවිශාල සමාජ වටිනාකමක් හිමිවිය.වී බිස්සක් නොතිබුණු ගොවි ගෙදර ආර්ථිකය අනාරක්ෂිත බව පිලිගත්තකි.ඵබදු නිවසකින් විවාහයක් කරගැනීම මදි පුංචිකමක් ලෙස සැලකීමට පවා ගැමි ජනයා පුරුදු වී සිටියේය.ඵහෙත් විසි ඓක්වෙනි සියවසට අවතීර්ණ වෙමින් සිටින අද දවසේ වී බිස්සේ උරුමයද එකී විද්‍යාත්මක සංස්කෘතියෙහි ලක්ෂණද මෙරට ගොවි සමාජයෙන් ඈත්වෙමින් තිබේ.ඊටද සමාජ සාධක ගණනාවක් බලපා ඇත.කාලයේ වැලිතලාවෙන් යටවී යන මෙම ඵෙතිහාසික විද්‍යාත්මක සංස්කෘතිය ගවේශණය කිරීම අතිශයින්ම වැදැගත්ය.එමගින් නෙලාගත හැකි වටිනාකම අනාගතයේදී තීරණය කෙරෙනු ඇත.එහෙත් එය ක්‍ෂණිකව පවත්නා වෙළදපොලේ රුපියල් සත වලට පෙරළිය නොහැක.වී බිස්ස"},{"question":"D’où viennent les poux ?","answer":"Les poux sont de touts petits insectes munis de pattes se terminant par des griffes qui s’accrochent à… nos cheveux ! Ces abominables parasites se nourrissent en piquant la peau de notre crâne et en aspirant un peu de sang. Alors, ça démange ! Et ces saletés, bien à l’abri dans nos cheveux, pondent leurs œufs, appelés lentes. Il est alors bien difficile de s’en débarrasser. Mais aucune honte à avoir, les poux aiment toutes les personnes, partout dans le monde, avec des cheveux lisses ou bieb frisés, sales ou propres."},{"question":" Sheeg Imisa Ayey Kala Ahaayeen Ciidamadii Uu Watay Nabi Suleymaan Cs","answer":" Waxa Loo-Qeybiyay Shan Qeybood Oo Kala Ah1- Jiniga.2- Insiga.3- Shimbiraha4- Duufaanta5- Asxaabtiisa"},{"question":"Wo kann ich im Internet Videos ansehen?","answer":"Es gibt verschiedenste Webseiten für Videos. Für kostenlose Angebote gibt es unter anderem folgende Seiten:- https://youtube.com- https://vimeo.com- https://d.tube"},{"question":"Berikan saya lirik lagu negeri Melaka.","answer":"Lirik lagu negeri Melaka adalah seperti berikut:Melaka Bandar BersejarahTempat tumpah darah kitaDijunjung dengan sepenuh jiwaUntuk maju dan jayaRakyat Melaka sudah bersatu paduBerikrar taat setiaJujur berkhidmat setiap masaMelaka maju jaya"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Aza manao fihavana-molotra:............................. \\" ","answer":"\\"  Aza manao fihavana-molotra , rehefa tezitra vao mifanatona. \\" "},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fifidianana maro an'isa?","answer":"Ny latsa-bato maro an'isa dia rafi-pifidianana izay ahafahan'ny kandidà na antoko manana vato be indrindra mahazo ny fahefana na seza rehetra."},{"question":"කෙකටිය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කෙකටිය කාණ්ඩයට අයත් ශාක වර්ග හයක් ලංකාවෙන් හමුවන අතර ඒ සියල්ල පොදුවේ කෙකටිය ලෙස හඳුන්වයි ඉන් විශේෂ 4ක් ලංකාවට ආවේණිකයි එමෙන්ම දුර්ලභයි සෙන්ටි මීටර 5ක් දක්වා දිගට හා සෙන්ටි මීටර් 4.5 ක් පළලට පත්‍ර වැඩි ඇති පත්‍ර සහිතයි කුඩා මල් සහිතයි. මල් ආහාරයට ගනි. ඔසුවකි. ලංකාවට පමණක් ආවේණිකය. විද්‍යාත්මක නම - aponogeton crispus"},{"question":"Sheeg Magaca Rasuulka (N.N.K.H) Hooyadii Oo Seddexan?","answer":"Aamina Bintu Wahab Bin Cabdi Manaaf."},{"question":"\\"Ze heeft een boek geschreven.\\" geef me het lijdend voorwerp.","answer":"Het lijdend voorwerp van de zin is \\"boek\\"."},{"question":" ආලෝක පරාවර්තනය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ආලෝකය කිසියම් පෘෂ්ඨයක වැදී හැරී නැවත එම මාධ්‍යයටම ගමන් කිරීමේ සංසිද්ධිය ආලෝක පරාවර්තනයයි.ආලෝකය කැඩපතක් හෝ  සිනිඳු ජලය වැනි පරාවර්තක මතුපිටක් හමු වූ විට, එය දිශාව වෙනස් කර මතුපිටින් අවශෝෂණය කර ගැනීම වෙනුවට එය ආරම්භ වූ මාධ්‍යයට නැවත පැමිණේ. මෙම සංසිද්ධිය පරාවර්තන නීතිය අනුගමනය කරයි, එහි සඳහන් වන්නේ පතන (ආලෝකය මතුපිටට පහර දෙන කෝණය) පරාවර්තක කෝණයට (ආලෝකය පරාවර්තනය වන කෝණය) සමාන බවයි. දර්පණයක වස්තූන් දැකීම හෝ  ජලය මත ආලෝකය බැබළීම ඇතුළු බොහෝ  එදිනෙදා  දෘශ්‍ය අත්දැකීම් සඳහා  පරාවර්තනය දායකවේ. "},{"question":"香港有什麼優勢？","answer":"香港司法制度優良、社會風氣廉潔、監管制度高效、市場開放；政府致力維持良好的營商環境、自由開放的貿易，並維持低稅率、簡單稅制、法治及司法獨立。"},{"question":"猫的生命周期是多长？","answer":"答：猫的平均寿命通常在10-15年，但有些猫在良好的护理下可以活到20年以上。"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਤ੍ਰੈ ਗੁਣ ਵਖਾਣੈ ਭਰਮੁ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ਬੰਧਨ ਨ ਤੂਟਹਿ ਮੁਕਤਿ ਨ ਪਾਇ ॥ਮੁਕਤਿ ਦਾਤਾ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਜੁਗ ਮਾਹਿ ॥੧॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਪ੍ਰਾਣੀ ਭਰਮੁ ਗਵਾਇ ॥ਸਹਜ ਧੁਨਿ ਉਪਜੈ ਹਰਿ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਤ੍ਰੈ ਗੁਣ ਕਾਲੈ ਕੀ ਸਿਰਿ ਕਾਰਾ ॥ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਚੇਤਹਿ ਉਪਾਵਣਹਾਰਾ ॥ਮਰਿ ਜੰਮਹਿ ਫਿਰਿ ਵਾਰੋ ਵਾਰਾ ॥੨॥ਅੰਧੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਤੇ ਭਰਮੁ ਨ ਜਾਈ ॥ਮੂਲੁ ਛੋਡਿ ਲਾਗੇ ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਈ ॥ਬਿਖੁ ਕਾ ਮਾਤਾ ਬਿਖੁ ਮਾਹਿ ਸਮਾਈ ॥੩॥ਮਾਇਆ ਕਰਿ ਮੂਲੁ ਜੰਤ੍ਰ ਭਰਮਾਏ ॥ਹਰਿ ਜੀਉ ਵਿਸਰਿਆ ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਏ ॥ਜਿਸੁ ਨਦਰਿ ਕਰੇ ਸੋ ਪਰਮ ਗਤਿ ਪਾਏ ॥੪॥ਅੰਤਰਿ ਸਾਚੁ ਬਾਹਰਿ ਸਾਚੁ ਵਰਤਾਏ ॥ਸਾਚੁ ਨ ਛਪੈ ਜੇ ਕੋ ਰਖੈ ਛਪਾਏ ॥ਗਿਆਨੀ ਬੂਝਹਿ ਸਹਜਿ ਸੁਭਾਏ ॥੫॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸਾਚਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਏ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਮਾਇਆ ਸਬਦਿ ਜਲਾਏ ॥ਮੇਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸਾਚਾ ਮੇਲਿ ਮਿਲਾਏ ॥੬॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਦਾਤਾ ਸਬਦੁ ਸੁਣਾਏ ॥ਧਾਵਤੁ ਰਾਖੈ ਠਾਕਿ ਰਹਾਏ ॥ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰ ਤੇ ਸੋਝੀ ਪਾਏ ॥੭॥ਆਪੇ ਕਰਤਾ ਸ੍ਰਿਸਟਿ ਸਿਰਜਿ ਜਿਨਿ ਗੋਈ ॥ਤਿਸੁ ਬਿਨੁ ਦੂਜਾ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਈ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਬੂਝੈ ਕੋਈ ॥੮॥੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 231 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਪਰ, ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪਸਾਰੇ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਦਿਲ-ਚਸਪੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਦੀ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਦੂਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ, ਉਸ ਦੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੇ) ਬੰਧਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਟੁੱਟਦੇ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਤੋਂ) ਖ਼ਲਾਸੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਤੋਂ ਖ਼ਲਾਸੀ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ (ਸਿਰਫ਼) ਗੁਰੂ (ਹੀ) ਹੈ ।੧। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੀ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਦੀ ਰੌ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਪਾ ਨਾਲ) ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੋੜੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪਸਾਰੇ ਵਿਚ ਦਿਲ-ਚਸਪੀ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਾਲਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਸਿਰ ਉਤੇ (ਸਦਾ) ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਦਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਚੱਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਿਰਜਣਹਾਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਕਦੇ ਯਾਦ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦੇ, ਉਹ ਮੁੜ ਮੁੜ (ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਜੰਮਦੇ ਹਨ, ਮਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜੰਮਦੇ ਹਨ ਮਰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੨। (ਪਰ, ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਆਪ) ਅੰਨ੍ਹੇ ਹੋਏ ਹੋਏ ਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ (ਸਰਨ ਆਏ ਸੇਵਕ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਦੀ) ਭਟਕਣਾ ਦੂਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ । (ਅਜੇਹੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਤਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਗੋਂ) ਜਗਤ ਦੇ ਮੂਲ-ਕਰਤਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸਦੇ ਹਨ । (ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ) ਜ਼ਹਰ ਵਿਚ ਮਸਤ ਹੋਇਆ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉਸ ਜ਼ਹਰ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਮਗਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩। (ਅਭਾਗੀ) ਮਨੁੱਖ ਮਾਇਆ ਨੂੰ (ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦਾ) ਆਸਰਾ ਬਣਾ ਕੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ ਹੀ) ਭਟਕਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਭੁਲਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਪਰ, ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉੱਤੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਰਹਿਮ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜਿੱਥੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਪੋਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ) ।੪। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਉਸ ਦੇ) ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਪਰਕਾਸ਼ ਕਰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਗਤ ਨਾਲ ਵਰਤਣ-ਵਰਤਾਵ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਭੀ ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਖਾ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਬਾਹਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਪਰਕਾਸ਼ ਹੋ ਜਾਏ), ਉਹ ਜੇ ਇਸ (ਮਿਲੀ ਦਾਤਿ) ਨੂੰ ਲੁਕਾ ਕੇ ਰੱਖਣ ਦਾ ਜਤਨ ਭੀ ਕਰੇ ਤਾਂ ਭੀ ਸਦ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਦਾ ਪਰਕਾਸ਼) ਲੁਕਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ (ਟਿਕ ਕੇ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ (ਇਸ ਅਸਲੀਅਤ ਨੂੰ) ਸਮਝ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੫। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੋੜੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਉਹ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਹਉਮੈ ਤੇ ਮਾਇਆ (ਦਾ ਮੋਹ) ਸਾੜ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ) ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਾਈ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।੬। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ) ਦਾਤਿ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਸੁਣਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਭਟਕਦੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਲੋਂ) ਬਚਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਰੋਕ ਕੇ ਕਾਬੂ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਜੀਵਨ-ਜੁਗਤਿ ਦੀ ਸਹੀ) ਸਮਝ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੭। ਜੋ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਸਿਰਜਣਹਾਰ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਆਪ ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਵਾਰੀ) ਨਾਸ ਕੀਤੀ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ (ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ) ਨਹੀਂ ਹਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਆਖ—ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਕੋਈ (ਵਿਰਲਾ ਵਡਭਾਗੀ) ਮਨੁੱਖ ਇਹ ਸਮਝ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ।੮।੬।  \\""},{"question":" Qual é o ponto turístico mais famoso de Paris?","answer":"A Torre Eiffel."},{"question":"ఒక విషయాన్ని బోధించే పదాల సమాహారమే వాక్యం. అంటే, ఒక విషయాన్ని ఇతరులకు చెప్పడానికి నిర్దిష్ట క్రమంలో పదాల చేరిక ఉంటే దాన్ని వాక్యం అని పిలువవచ్చు. సామాన్య వాక్యం గురించి రాయండి.","answer":"ఒక సమాపక క్రియ మాత్రమే కలిగి ఉంటే అది సామాన్య వాక్యం .ఉదాహరణ :‘అంబేద్కర్ మన రాజ్యాంగాన్ని రచించాడు’ (ఇందులో రచించాడు అన్న క్రియ ఉంది) క్రియ లేకుండా కూడా సామాన్య వాక్యాలు ఉంటాయి. ఆమె ఉపాధ్యాయురాలు. ఆయన పెద్దవాడు.వీటిలో క్రియ లేదు. అయినా పూర్తి అర్థాన్ని ఇస్తున్నాయి. కాబట్టి ఇవీ సామాన్య వాక్యాలే.వీటిని క్రియా రహిత వాక్యాలు అంటారు."},{"question":"What role would social media play in your campaigns?","answer":"The role of social media in campaigns can vary widely depending on the goals and target audience, but here are some common ways it can be utilized:Awareness and Outreach: Social media platforms are powerful tools for reaching a wide audience quickly and cost-effectively. Campaigns often use social media to increase awareness about their cause, product, or message.Engagement and Interaction: Social media enables two-way communication between the campaign and its audience. Campaigns can engage with their followers through comments, likes, shares, and direct messages. This helps build a sense of community and fosters a deeper connection with the audience.Content Distribution: Campaigns can share various types of content, including text, images, videos, and infographics, to convey their message. They can also leverage features like live streaming and stories to keep the audience engaged.Targeted Advertising: Social media platforms offer highly sophisticated targeting options, allowing campaigns to reach specific demographics, interests, and behaviors. This helps in delivering messages to the most relevant audience segments.Data Collection and Analysis: Social media provides valuable data on audience behavior, engagement metrics, and user demographics. Campaigns can use this data to refine their strategies and tailor their messages.Fundraising and Donations: Nonprofit organizations and political campaigns can use social media to promote fundraising campaigns and solicit donations. Many platforms also offer donation features directly within their interfaces.Influencer Marketing: Collaborating with social media influencers can help campaigns reach a broader and more engaged audience. Influencers can endorse the campaign or product, lending credibility and trust.Crisis Management: Social media can be a double-edged sword. It can amplify both positive and negative messages. Campaigns need to be prepared to manage crises and respond to negative feedback promptly.Community Building: Campaigns can create online communities around their cause or message, allowing supporters to connect and share their experiences. This can help foster a sense of belonging and encourage ongoing engagement.Feedback and Iteration: Social media platforms provide a direct channel for receiving feedback from the audience. Campaigns can use this feedback to make adjustments to their strategies and messages in real-time."},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai. Cikgu Natrah menegur murid yang suka __ sewaktu beliau sedang mengajar. Pilihan:  A)  lembik-lembikB)  malu-maluC)  jauh-jauhD)  main-main","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah D) main-main"},{"question":"Koks yra klausimas: \\"Senovės graikai manė, kad Trojos karas buvo istorinis įvykis, įvykęs XII- XIII amžiuje prieš Kristų, ir tikėjo, kad Troja buvo įsikūrusi šiuolaikinėje Turkijoje netoli Dardanelių\\" Tema yra Trojos karas.","answer":"\\"Kada įvyko Trojos karas?\\""},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Ampanga diso an' Andringitra : _\\"","answer":"\\"herintaona ngarangidina ka tovon-tanana ihany.\\""},{"question":"１．外国人に対し日本語で話すことが難しいです。２．外国人に対し日本語で話すのが難しいです。　における「の」と「こと」の違いは？","answer":"例の文は１→１a．外国人に対し［ては］日本語で話すことが難しいです。　　　　２→２b．外国人に対し［ては］日本語で話すのが難しいです。または１→１c．外国人に対し［て］日本語で話すこと［は］難しいです。　　 　２→２d．外国人に対し［て］日本語で話すの［は］難しいです。のどちらかの表現にしたほうがいいと思います。さて、「の」「こと」の使い分けですが、ニュアンスの違いがありますが、文としては「の」も「こと」も使えると思います。前に私の他の掲示板に書いた記事を下に再録しておきますので、参考にして下さい。　　　　＊用言を受ける形式名詞「の」は「もの」「ひと」「こと」の意を表す、というのが国文法における一般的な説明でしたが、現代日本語を外国語として観ると、「の」を形式名詞「こと」との比較において分析し、両者の特性を明確にする必要が生じて来ました。ちょうどこの両者の違いについての質問がありましたので、具体的に示された例文で検討し、考えてみたいと思います。皆さんと一緒に知恵を出し合い、現代日本語の文法を再検討して行きたいと考えています。「日本語の文法を観る」への投稿をお待ちしています。*①≪英語を話す「こと」はおもしろい≫の形式名詞「こと」は、活用語の連体形を受けて名詞句を作り、その内容を「抽象的・一般的に考えられた概念（経験・習慣・必要・状態等）として示す」働きを持ち、②≪英語を話す「の」はおもしろい≫の形式名詞「の」は、先行の活用語を名詞化し「その行為・状態を具体的・個別的な状況・実態として示す」働きを持っていると思われます。したがって、① は≪「一般的に」英語を話す「という経験・習慣」はおもしろい≫ということになり、②は≪「具体的に（例えば私が）」英語を話す「という行為の状況・実態」はおもしろい≫ということになります。　他の例文を挙げてみます。≪彼が走っている（○の）（×こと）を見た（○こと）（×の）がない≫この文の「の」は彼が走っている具体的状況・実態を示し、「こと」は見るという行為を抽象的な経験という概念に置き換えて示している、と言えるでしょう。また、≪信じる「こと」はできる「こと」である≫≪早く起きる「こと」にしている≫≪泣く「こと」はないのに≫≪うまい「こと」やったね≫などの「こと」は「の」に置き換えることはできなく、抽象的な概念としての内容を示しています。一方、≪読む「の」は問題ないが書く「の」はどうもね≫の「の」は「こと」に置き換えられるが、「こと」にすれば、より抽象的・一般的な色彩が強く感じられます。「もの」「ひと」「こと」を示す「の」については、いくつかの文法的名称がありますので、補足しておきます。形式名詞（時枝誠記氏等）、準体助詞（橋本進吉氏）、形式体言、代名助詞などです。また、格助詞の下の体言が省略されたものとする説もあります。"},{"question":"Кандай дарактардын жалбырактары жүрөктүн формасында? ","answer":"Линда жалбырактарынын "},{"question":"Jinsi ya kupanda mahindi","answer":"Kwanza ni kutayarisha shamba lako. Baada ya shamba kuwa tayari, unatengeneza mistari ya kupanda mbegu zako. Kisha unaweka mbegu  kwa utaratibu kulingana na mistari yako na kutilia mchanga. Kisha unangoja mvua kunyesha ama unanyunyuzia maji mwenyewe."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. පාසල් උයනේ නා ගස් හෙවණේපෙරදා පෙරදා පෙරදා පෙරදාසැණකෙළි දිනයේ මතකද අප හමු වූවාආදි සිසුන් ගේ මල් සල ළඟ දීපැරණි හැඟුම් මතු කරවාසොඳුරු සිනා පා ආදර හැඟුමින් පිළි ගත්තා","answer":"පාසල් උයනේ නා ගස් හෙවණේපෙරදා පෙරදා පෙරදා පෙරදාසැණකෙළි දිනයේ මතකද අප හමු වූවාආදි සිසුන් ගේ මල් සල ළඟ දීපැරණි හැඟුම් මතු කරවාසොඳුරු සිනා පා ආදර හැඟුමින් පිළි ගත්තාපාට පාට විදුලි පහන් නිවී නිවී යළි දිලී ගියාබිඳී තිබුණු මා හදවත් මල් මී එයින් සසල වූවාපියවි ලොවින් මොහොතක් සමු ගෙනසිහින ලොවේ වල්මත් වූවාපාසල් උයනේ තුරුලිය ගොමුවේමලින් පිරී තිබුණාඑනමුදු කාලය සැඩපහර වැදීසිතුවිලි සිත්තම් බොඳ වූවාසිතුවම් නිවහන් ගරා වැටී ඇතයළි එය ගොඩ නංවන්න එපාඅතීත මතකය මිය යන්නට හැරපෑරුණු සිත මගෙ සුවපත් වන්නටඔබ සිත් දැහැනින්මම සමු ගනිමි ප්‍රියේඅයිවෝ ඩෙනිස්"},{"question":"Siapakah Loganathan Arumugam? Jelaskan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 60 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Dato' Loganathan Arumugam (15 Julai 1953 – 4 Jun 2007), atau dikenali sebagai Loga merupakan penyanyi malaysia dan salah seorang pengasas utama kumpulan band lagenda Malaysia, Alleycats. Beliau merupakan adik kepada David Arumugam. Beliau meninggal dunia pada 4 Jun 2007 akibat kanser paru-paru. Beliau dianugerahkan Darjah Indera Mahkota Pahang (DIMP) oleh Sultan Pahang pada 28 Oktober 2008."},{"question":"サンバといえばブラジルの民族音楽ですが、ルンバはどこの国の民族音楽でしょう？","answer":"キューバです。"},{"question":"次の文章を読んで、その内容に適したタイトルを付けてください： 台風7号が日本の本州の近くに来ています。15日には東海地方から近畿地方に来そうです。▶ 台風の新しい情報はこちらです。台風が近くに来ているため、四国、近畿、東海、関東などで雨が降っています。太平洋側などではこれからもたくさん降って、とても強い風が吹く心配があります。海の波もとても高くなりそうです。気象庁は、山などが崩れたり、川の水があふれたりする危険があるため、十分気をつけるように言っています。雷や竜巻などにも気をつけるように言っています。台風はゆっくり進んでいるため、雨や風が長く続きそうです。市や町が出す情報などをよく調べて、雨や風がひどくなる前に避難してください。JRは、15日は名古屋駅と岡山駅の間で新幹線の運転をしないことを決めました。","answer":"台風7号　15日に東海地方から近畿地方に来そう"},{"question":"இதை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்-compare","answer":"ஒப்பிடு"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'mulut satu lidah bertopang'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang jahat hati itu perkataannya lain daripada hasrat hatinya"},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Pokok apa yang suka berkahwin?","answer":"Jawapan : Pokok pinang"},{"question":"من هو أول من لقب بقاضي القضاه في الاسلام؟","answer":"ابو يوسف القاضي."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - \\"Rolf krakes saga\\" i dess \\"nuvarande\\" form är inte mycket äldre än \\"Bjarkarímur\\" och påtagligt förvanskad. Sagan var dock från början en del av den stora \\"Sköldungasagan\\" som gick förlorad i","answer":"Köpenhamns brand år 1728. En latinsk summering av denna saga, skriven av Arngrímur Jónsson, finns dock kvar. Som Finnur Jónsson var den förste att påvisa överensstämmer \\"Bjarkarímur\\" betydligt bättre med \\"Sköldungasagan\\" enligt Arngrímur än med \\"Rolf krakes saga\\", och förklarar också på ett trovärdigare sätt sköldungarnas och ynglingarnas släktrelationer och inbördes strider. Slutsatsen blir att det måste vara den nu förlorade \\"Sköldungasagan\\" som har varit rimadiktarens källa. Därmed kan rimorna också på flera punkter komplettera Arngrímur, vars version av \\"Sköldungasagan\\" har många uteslutningar. "},{"question":"ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ: ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਾਸਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਮੇਟੀ (ਸੀਓਏ) ਦਾ ਕਮੇਟੀ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਬੀਸੀਸੀਆਈ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਾਲਾਨਾ ਮੀਟਿੰਗ ਅਤੇ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਨਾਲ ਨਜਿੱਠਣ ਲਈ ਲੋਕਪਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਨੈਤਿਕਤਾ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਫੌਰੀ ਨਿਯੁਕਤ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਨੂੰ ਸੌਂਪੀ ਗਈ ਦਸਵੀਂ ਸਥਿਤੀ ਰਿਪੋਰਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੀਓਏ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਅਗਲੀਆਂ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਇਹ ਨਿਯੁਕਤੀਆਂ ਕਿਉਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹਨ। ਸੀਓਏ ਨੇ ਰਿਪੋਰਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਹਾ, ‘‘ਬੀਸੀਸੀਆਈ ਦੇ ਨਵੇਂ ਸੰਵਿਧਾਨ ਤਹਿਤ ਸਾਲਾਨਾ ਆਮ ਮੀਟਿੰਗ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਨਾਲ ਨਜਿੱਠਣ ਲਈ ਲੋਕਪਾਲ ਦੀ ਨਿਯੁਕਤੀ ਬੇਹੱਦ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ।’’ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਵੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਲੋਕਪਾਲ ਸੇਵਾਮੁਕਤ ਜੱਜ ਜਾਂ ਹਾਈ ਕੋਰਟ ਦਾ ਚੀਫ ਜਸਟਿਸ ਹੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਸਾਲ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਜਕਾਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਤਿੰਨ ਸਾਲ ਤੱਕ ਵਧਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਸਕੇ।ਇੱਕ ਲੋਕਪਾਲ ਨੂੰ ਕਿੰਨਾ ਸਮਾਂ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਇੱਕ ਲੋਕਪਾਲ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਮਿਆਦ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਜਾਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਕਿ ਤਿੰਨ ਸਾਲ ਤੱਕ ਵਧਾਈ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"ما هي لقاحات الملاريا التي توصي بها منظمة الصحة العالمية ومن هي الفئات التي يمكن تطعيمها؟","answer":"اعتباراً من 2 تشرين الأول/أكتوبر 2023، أوصت المنظمة باللقاحين RTS,S/AS01وR21/Matrix-M للوقاية من الملاريا لدى الأطفال. وينبغي توفير لقاح الملاريا في جدول مكوّن من 4 جرعات لدى الأطفال بدءاً من عمر 5 أشهر تقريباً. (قد تختار برامج التطعيم إعطاء الجرعة الأولى في عمر أكبر أو عمر أصغر قليلاً بناءً على اعتبارات تشغيلية).وتعمل لقاحات الملاريا على مكافحة ملاريا المتصورة المنجلية، وهي أكثر طفيليات الملاريا فتكا ًعلى مستوى العالم والأكثر انتشاراً في أفريقيا.وفي تشرين الأول/أكتوبر 2021، أوصت المنظمة لأول مرة بلقاح الملاريا RTS,S من أجل الوقاية من الملاريا لدى الأطفال. ومنذ عام 2019، حصل على اللقاح مليونا طفل تقريباً في غانا وكينيا وملاوي من خلال برنامج التطعيم باللقاح المضاد للملاريا. وأدّى إدخال لقاح الملاريا RTS,S في هذه البلدان الثلاثة التجريبية إلى تأثير كبير، وقلّل من دخول الأطفال إلى المستشفيات بسبب الملاريا الوخيمة، وأنقذ الأرواح. ومن المتوقع حدوث تأثير مماثل عند طرح لقاح R21 في أماكن مماثلة.ويتسم كلا اللقاحين بالمأمونية والفعالية. ونظراً إلى أن اللقاحين متشابهان، وأن اللقاح RTS,S كان له تأثير كبير في المناطق ذات الانتقال المرتفع والمعتدل والمنخفض، فمن المرجح أن يكون اللقاح R21 فعالاً أيضاً في جميع الأماكن التي تتوطنها الملاريا.ويمكن إنقاذ عشرات الآلاف من أرواح الأطفال كل عام من خلال التنفيذ الواسع النطاق للقاحي الملاريا هذين."},{"question":"விடுகதை : நூல் நூற்கும் நெசவாளிக்கு கட்டிக்கொள்ள துணியில்லை அது என்ன?","answer":"விடை : நூல் நூற்கும் நெசவாளிக்கு கட்டிக்கொள்ள துணியில்லை அது சிலந்தி ஆகும்.சிலந்திகள் அல்லது எட்டுக்கால் பூச்சிகள் என்பன எட்டுக்கால்களை உடைய, சவைக்கும் வாய்ப்பகுதிகள் இல்லாத, இருபகுதியான உடல்பிரிவுகள் உடைய, காற்றை உள்வாங்கி மூச்சுவிடும் கணுக்காலி வகைப் பூச்சிகள். இவை தம் உடலில் உள்ள சுரப்பியில் இருந்து மெல்லிய நூல் போன்ற இழை ஆக்குவது இதன் சிறப்பியல்பு ஆகும். இந்த சிலந்திநூலை நூலாம்படை என்றும், சிலந்தியை நூலாம்பூச்சி  என்றும் கூறுவர். சிலந்திகளில் பல வகைகள் பல வகையான நஞ்சுகள் கொண்டிருக்கின்றன. மற்ற வகையான பூச்சிகளைப் போல் இவற்றுக்கு உணர்விழைகள் கிடையா. 2011ஆம் ஆண்டு திசம்பர் 31 வரை உலகில் 42,751  வகையான சிலந்திகள் அல்லது எட்டுக்கால்பூச்சிகள் அறிவியலில் அடையாளம் காணப்பட்டு  விளக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. இவை 110 பேரினங்களில் அடங்கும். சிலந்திகள் 300 மில்லியன் ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பே இருந்து வாழ்ந்து வந்திருக்கின்றன. சிலந்திகள் அராக்னிடா  என்னும் வகுப்பில், சிலந்திப்பேரினம் அல்லது அரனியே  என்று அழைக்கப்படும் வரிசையில் உள்ள உயிரினம்.உடற்கூறு அடிப்படையில் சிலந்திகள் மற்ற கணுக்காலிகளைப் போலல்லாமல் உடல் பகுதிகள் இரண்டு இணைவுத் துண்டுகளாக  காணப்படுகிறது. தலைநெஞ்சுப்பகுதிமற்றும் வயிற்றுப்பகுதி  என்ற அந்த இரண்டு பகுதிகள் சிறிய உருளை வடிவ காம்பின் மூலம் இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. பூச்சிகளைப் போல சிலந்திகளுக்கு உணர்கொம்புகள்  இல்லை.மிகவும் பழமையான மிசோதீலே  குழுவைச்சார்ந்த சிலந்தியைத் தவிர மற்ற கணுக்காலிகளில் சிலந்திகள் அனைத்தும் மையப்படுத்தப்பட்ட நரம்பு மண்டலத்தைக் கொண்டுள்ளன.தலைநெஞ்சுப்பகுதியில் நரம்புச்செல்கள் கொத்தாக இணைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. மற்ற கணுக்காலிகளைப் போல் சிலந்திகளின் கால்களில் விரிவடையக்கூடிய தசைகள் காணப்படுவதில்லை அதற்குப் பதிலாக நீர்ம அழுத்தத்தால்  மேலெழும்பித் தாவுகின்றன.சிலந்தியின் வயிற்றுப் பகுதியில் துணை உறுப்பாகக் காணப்படும் ஆறு விதமான நூற்பு சுரப்பி உறுப்புகள் பட்டு நூலினை வெளித்தள்ளுகின்றன. ஒட்டும் தன்மையுள்ள நூலின் பயன்படுத்தப்பட்ட அளவைப் பொறுத்து சிலந்தி வலைகளின் அளவுகளில் பரவலாக வேறுபாடுகள் காணப்படுகின்றன. சுருள் கோள வலைகள்  சிலந்திகளின் ஆரம்பகால வலைப்பின்னல் வடிவமாக இருக்கின்றன. சில சிலந்திகள் சுருள் கோள வலைகளை விட அதிகப்படியான சிக்கலான நூற்கூடுகளைக் கட்டுகின்றன.பட்டு உற்பத்தி செய்யும் கூம்பல் கொண்ட சிலந்தி போன்ற இனம் 386 மில்லியன் ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு டெவோனியன் புவியியல் காலத்தில் தோன்றின, ஆனால் அந்த விலங்குகளுக்கு வெளிப்படையாக நூற்பு உறுப்புகள் இல்லை.உண்மையான சிலந்திகள் 318 முதல் 299 மில்லியன் ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முற்பட்ட காலத்திய கரிமப்பாறைகளில் புதைபடிவங்களாக கண்டிறியப்பட்டுள்ளன. அவை அடிப்படை சிலந்தி இனமான மீசோதீலே பிரிவைச் சார்ந்த சிலந்தியினத்துடன் ஒத்திருந்தது.தற்போதுள்ள நவீன சிலந்தியினங்கள் 200 மில்லியன் ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன் மூன்றாய காலத்தில் தோன்றிய மைகலோமார்ஃபே மற்றும் அரானியோமார்ஃபே ஆகியனவாகும்."},{"question":"河南有哪些著名的高校？","answer":"答：河南有许多著名的高校，如郑州大学、河南大学、河南工业大学等。"},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：什么是骨骼系统，它的组成部分和功能是什么？","answer":"答案：骨骼系统是人体内部支撑和保护身体的系统。它包括骨骼、关节和韧带。骨骼：由多个骨头组成，形成人体的框架和支撑结构。骨骼提供力量和支持，保护内脏器官，并参与血液细胞的生产。关节：连接骨头，允许骨头之间的运动。关节的类型包括球-and-socket关节（如肩关节）、滑动关节（如手腕关节）和铰接关节（如膝盖关节）。韧带：连接骨头和骨头之间的结合点，提供稳定性和限制关节运动的范围。骨骼系统的功能包括支撑身体、保护内脏器官、提供运动的支持和稳定性，以及储存钙和矿物质等。"},{"question":"Iza no nosy ao amin'ny helodranon'i San Francisco malaza amin'ireo fonja maro ao aminy?","answer":"Ny Nosy \\"Alcatraz\\" dia malaza amin'ireo fonja maro ao aminy ao amin'ny helodranon'i San Francisco."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai cembul dapat tutupnya\\"?","answer":"Amat sesuai"},{"question":"පේශිකංකාල පද්ධතිය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"පේශිකංකාල පද්ධතිය (Human musculoskeletal system) සමන්විත වනුයේ මිනිස් ඇටසැකිල්ල ( අස්ථීන්, බන්ධනියන්, කණ්ඩරාවන්, සහ ‍කෝමලාස්ථි අන්තර්ගතවූ) සහ සම්බන්ධිත මාංශපේශීන් ගෙනි. එය විසින් සිරුරෙහි සාමාන්‍ය ව්‍යුහය හා චලන හැකියාව ලබා දෙයි. ව්‍යුහය ලබාදීමේ ඒවායේ භූමිකාවට අමතරව, සිරුරෙහි විශාල අස්ථීන් තුල අන්තර්ගත වන ඇට මිදුලු විසින්, රුධිර සෛල නිෂ්පාදනය සිදු කෙරේ. මෙලෙසම, සියළු අස්ථීන් කැල්සියම් සහ පොස්ෆේට් ගබඩා කර තැබෙන ප්‍රධාන අඩවි වෙති."},{"question":"வினா: தாவரவியலாளரான முதல் இந்தியப் பெண் யார்? ","answer":"விடை: ஜானகி அம்மாள் (ஜானகி அம்மாள் கரும்புகள் இனிப்பு சுவையை அதிகமாக்கினார்)"},{"question":"Which is the only edible food that never expires?","answer":"Honey"},{"question":"من هو مكتشف كوكب أورانس ؟","answer":"كان الفلكي الألماني الإنجليزي وليام هيرشل هو الشخص الذي اكتشف كوكب أورانوس. قام هيرشل بالاكتشاف في 13 مارس 1781، وكان ذلك اكتشافًا هامًا في علم الفلك حينها، حيث أضاف أورانوس إلى الكواكب المعروفة في النظام الشمسي في تلك الفترة."},{"question":"Дүйнөдөгү кызыктуу фактылардан жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Жапон үй-бүлөлөрүндө бир туугандардын бири – бири менен сүйлөшпөөсү адаттагы эле көрүнүш. Телефон номерлерин да билбей калышы толук мүмкүн."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe tsio-rivotra?Valiny: ","answer":"Ny tsio-drivotra dia rivotra malefaka sy tsy mitsahatra mitsoka matetika eo akaikin'ny morontsiraka noho ny tsy fitovian'ny mari-pana eo amin'ny tany sy ny rano."},{"question":"Aiza no misy an'i Tegucigalpa ?1- Honduras2- Angleterre","answer":"Any Honduras no misy an'ni Tegucigalpa ."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'jangan disesar gunung berlari, hilang kabut tampaklah dia'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sesuatu perkara yang telah tentu itu tidak perlu digopoh-gopohkan sangat (hendaklah sabar mengerjakannya)"},{"question":"غني خان چیرته زیږیدلی؟","answer":"غني خان چې په پښتو ادب کې مشهوره څېره ده او د خان عبدالغفار خان زوی (چې په باچا خان هم مشهور دی) د برتانوي هند په خیبر پښتونخوا ایالت کې د هشتنغر په کلي کې زېږېدلی دی. دا کلی اوس د پاکستان برخه ده. د غني خان د زېږېدو ځای هشتنغر تاريخي اهميت لري ځکه چې دا نه يوازې د هغه د زېږېدو ځای دی بلکې هغه ځای هم دی چې د پښتنو د حقونو او هوساينې لپاره يې د کورنۍ ميراث پيل کړی و."},{"question":"أجب على السؤال التالي : ماهي رائداة الشركة الأوروبية للصناعات الجوية في عام 2009 ؟","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة هي إيرباص.إيرباص ساس (بالإنجليزية: Airbus SAS)‏. هي شركة صناعة الطائرات التابعة لشركة EADS، الشركة الأوروبية للصناعات الجوية. ويقع مقرها في تولوز، فرنسا، وهي ذات نشاط كبير في جميع أنحاء أوروبا، حيث تنتج ما يقرب من نصف طائرات العالم النفاثة."},{"question":"Cad a dhéanfá dá mbuafá an crannchur náisiúnta?","answer":"Bheadh orm mo mhachnamh a dhéanamh faoi sin. Bheinn thar a bheith sásta dá dtarlódh a leithéid. An chéad rud a dhéanfainn ná screadaílfinn agus chuirfinn glaoch ar mo cháirde. Ansin thosóinn ag smaoineamh ar conas an t-airgead a chaitheamh. Rachainn ar saoire timpeall an domhain. Ba bhreá liom carr nua nóteach nua a cheannach. Thabharfainn airgead do na daoine bochta agus cheannóinn bronntanais do mo cháirde."},{"question":"Ọkunrin kan lọọ hu oku olokuu l’Abẹokuta, nibi to ti n hu u lo ku si","answer":"Titi dasiko yii lawọn eeyan ṣi n sọ pe boya iku ojiji to pa ọkunrin yii lasiko to n hu oku olokuu niboji, n’Ibẹrẹkodo, l’Abẹokuta, yoo kọ awọn yooku rẹ to n ṣiṣẹ ibi ọhun lọgbọn.Ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, niṣẹlẹ yii waye niboji oku ti wọn maa n sin awọn Musulumi si, n’Ibẹrẹkodo, niluu Abẹokuta. Ọwọ oru lọkunrin ti ko sẹni to mọ orukọ rẹ naa ji lọ si saaree oku ọhun, o si ko awọn irinṣẹ ti yoo fi hu oku dani.Ṣugbọn nibi to ti n hu oku naa lọwọ ni wọn ni o ti ṣubu sinu saaree ọhun, bẹẹ ni ko le tẹsiwaju ninu iṣẹ to n ṣe naa mọ.Ẹjẹ tilẹ bẹrẹ si i jade lẹnu rẹ bi wọn ṣe wi, nigba tawọn alaboojuto si debẹ ni wọn ri i pe ẹni to waa hu oku olokuu ti ba oku nile, oun funra rẹ si ti dẹni to n ba ara ọrun ṣe.Nigba to n ba awọn akọroyin sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ yii, Imaamu agba Oke-Ọna, Alaaji Musiliu Nasir, ṣalaye pe kutu hai lawọn kan waa sọ foun pe ẹni kan waa hu oku nitẹ oku awọn Musulumi, n’Ibẹrẹkodo. Boya ori lo fẹẹ ge, boya gbogbo ara oku naa lo si fẹẹ di sapo ni, wọn ṣaa ni nibi to ti n ṣe e lọwọ lo ti ṣubu sinu saaree naa, o si ti ku patapata.Ọkunrin kan bayii to ni oun ko fẹẹ darukọ oun, ṣalaye fun ALAROYE pe itosi iboji naa ni ile oun wa, oun si maa n ri ohun to n ṣẹlẹ nibẹ daadaa.O ni ni nnkan bii aago meji aabọ oru ọjọ Sannde yii, oun kofiri ẹnikan niboji naa, ara si fu oun nigba toun ri i bo ṣe n ṣe. O ni ṣugbọn ẹru n ba oun, oun ko le jade loru naa. Afi bi ilẹ ṣe mọ tawọn ba oku ọkunrin kan to ki ori bọ saaree to n hu lọwọ, bẹẹ lawọn nnkan to fi n hu ori oku naa si wa lẹgbẹẹ rẹ nibẹ.Awọn ọlọpaa ni wọn waa gbe oku naa lọ bi wọn ṣe wi. Awọn irinṣẹ ti wọn si ni wọn ba lẹgbẹẹ ọkunrin naa ni ada, ọbẹ kan ti wọn lo mu gidi ati foonu rẹ to wa lapo rẹ nigba to ku iku ojiji naa."},{"question":"Completa questa domanda. \\"Chi ha dipinto La Gioconda?\\"","answer":"Risposta: \\"Leonardo da Vinci\\""},{"question":"ශිථිල යන පදය පැහැදිලි කර විරුද්ද පදය කුමක්ද කියන්න.","answer":"ශිථිල -ධනිත (විරුද්ධ පදය )ශිථිල යන්නෙහි අරුත ලිහිල් යන්න ය."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"Ny vondrona ara-poko _ dia fantatra amin'ny sary sokitra antsoina hoe aloaloalo.\\"","answer":"Ny vondrona ara-poko Mahafaly  dia fantatra amin'ny sary sokitra antsoina hoe aloaloalo."},{"question":"Manomeza famintinana ho an'ity lahatsoratra manaraka ity:Mavo, novonoin olona Randria, hoy i Dokotera Rabary. Amboary aloha ny sainao, Hevero izay hanjo an'i Malanto kely raha misy mahazo anao koa. Notantaraina an-dRamavo ny ady teo amoron- tevana, saingy salovan-tava miendrika sarivato no manoloana an'i Dokotera Rabary sy ny Mpitandrina. Nifandimby nampionona izy roalahy. ...Mitraka Ramatoa. Jereo ity mahazo ny zanakao mipitrapitra. Izay vao niverina ny sain-dRamavo Nohontonkontsoniny mafy ny soro-janany, toa tiany ho taitra, tiany hiara-mitoreo sy hiara-ory aminy ny zanany.Ny fandrombahan ny fahafatesana ny olon-tiany eo am-pelatanany dia ahatsapana fa misy ampahana aina misoaka avy amin'ny tena, miara-maty aminy, ary ratra sy fangirifitina tsy voalazan'ny teny fampiasa andavanandro no mandrotika ny fo.Mafy tamin-dRamavo ny fisarahana. Tsaroany tokoa ny herin'ny fahafatesana, tsy azo ivalozanaTsy zakan'ny sainy ny mahita ny nofon-dRandria gejaina ao anaty lambamena telo sosona, ny nofon'ny olon-tiany fantsihina ao anatin'ity vata, velezina tantanana ary totofana vovoka sy tany.","answer":"Ity ny famintinana ny lahatsoratra : Tampoka tamin-dRamavo loatra ny fahafatesam- badiny. Tiany hahalala izany ny zanany ka nanaovany fihetsika.Mafy taminy ny fisarahana sy ny fahitany fihetsika natao tamin'ny vata-mangatsiakam-badiny. "},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Ông Biden nhận kết quả xét nghiệm dương tính với SARS-CoV-2 vào sáng 30/7 sau khi dường như đã hồi phục và xét nghiệm âm tính hôm 26/7. Bác sĩ riêng của Tổng thống Biden giải thích rằng ông có thể bị \\"tái phát bệnh\\" – tình trạng xảy ra ở một số ít bệnh nhân dùng thuốc kháng virus của Pfizer. Kết quả xét nghiệm dương tính của ông Biden được bác sĩ Nhà Trắng Kevin O'Connor thông báo trong một bức thư gửi Thư ký Báo chí Karine Jean-Pierre. Trong thư, ông O'Connor lưu ý rằng Tổng thống Biden đã xét nghiệm âm tính với SARS-CoV-2 hàng ngày kể từ thứ Ba, nhưng sẽ quay trở lại cách ly sau khi nhận kết quả dương tính vào sáng thứ Bảy. Trước khi xét nghiệm âm tính hôm 26/7, ông Biden đã làm việc từ xa và cách ly trong Nhà Trắng 5 ngày, đồng thời chỉ có các triệu chứng nhẹ. Tổng thống Biden đã tiêm đủ 2 mũi vắc xin ngừa COVID-19 và 2 liều nhắc lại. Khi được xác định mắc bệnh, ông đã sử dụng Paxlovid – một loại thuốc kháng virus của Pfizer được Cục Quản lý Thực phẩm và Dược phẩm (FDA) Mỹ cấp phép khẩn cấp vào tháng 12. Bác sĩ O'Connor lưu ý rằng \\"một tỷ lệ nhỏ\\" bệnh nhân điều trị COVID-19 bằng Paxlovid có khả năng gặp phải \\"tình trạng tái dương tính sau khi phục hồi\\". Trong trường hợp của Tổng thống Biden, ông \\"không gặp phải các triệu chứng khi tái phát và tiếp tục cảm thấy khỏe\\". Bác sĩ Anthony Fauci – chuyên gia về COVID-19 của Nhà Trắng cũng từng bị tái dương tính khi dùng thuốc Paxlovid hồi tháng 5. Sau khi có kết quả âm tính hồi đầu tuần này, Tổng thống Biden đã mô tả Paxlovid là \\"yếu tố thay đổi cuộc chơi\\" trong cuộc chiến chống lại COVID-19, và kêu gọi người Mỹ mua thuốc từ các hiệu thuốc trên khắp cả nước.","answer":"Bác sĩ giải thích lý do Tổng thống Biden tái dương tính sau vài ngày khỏi COVID-19"},{"question":"O que significa o ditado popular: \\"Depois da tempestade vem a bonança\\"?","answer":"Frase usada para dizer que é sempre depois de uma fase ruim, de um acontecimento não tão legal, é que vem a sensação de bem-estar, consequência do que aprendemos com tal episódio.Exemplo: “Foi difícil, né? Mas a bonança chegou depois da tempestade!”"},{"question":"Hãy chọn đáp án đúng nhất cho câu hỏi sau:Địa phương duy nhất nào giáp với 8 tỉnh?A. Hà NộiB. TP HCMD. Bình Dương","answer":"A. Hà NộiHà Nội giáp 8 tỉnh, trong đó Thái Nguyên, Vĩnh Phúc ở phía Bắc; Hà Nam, Hòa Bình phía Nam; Bắc Giang, Bắc Ninh và Hưng Yên phía Đông; Hòa Bình, Phú Thọ phía Tây.Địa hình Hà Nội vừa có núi, đồi (tập trung ở phía Bắc và Tây), thấp dần từ Bắc xuống Nam và từ Tây sang Đông, trong đó, đồng bằng chiếm 3/4 diện tích tự nhiên của thành phố. Các đỉnh cao nhất là Ba Vì 1.281 m, Gia Dê 707 m, Chân Chim 462 m, Thanh Lanh 427 m và Thiên Trù 378 m... Khu vực nội đô có một số gò đồi thấp, như gò Đống Đa, núi Nùng."},{"question":" Qual substância não se mistura com a água?","answer":"O óleo."},{"question":"قال الله سبحانه وتعالى في سوره البقره الايه 58 (وإذ قلنا ادخلوا القرية فكلوا منها حيث شئتم رغداً) شنو المقصود المقصود بـ(القرية)..؟","answer":"بيت المقدس"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Biru dan kuning boleh melahirkan saya.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah hijau"},{"question":"ஆண்டாளின் கனவுக் காட்சிகளை எழுதுக.","answer":"• சதிராடும் இளம்பெண்கள், தம் கைகளில் கதிரவன் போன்ற ஒளியையுடைய விளக்கையும் கலசத்தையும் ஏந்தியவாறு வந்து எதிர் கொண்டு அழைக்கிறார்கள்.• மதுராபுரியை ஆளும் மன்னனாம் கண்ணன், பாதங்களில் பாதுகை அணிந்து கொண்டு புவி அதிர மகிழ்ச்சியுடன் நடந்து வருகிறான்.• மத்தளம் முழங்க, வரி சங்கம் ஊத, முத்துக்களையுடைய மாலைகள் தொங்கவிடப்பட்ட பந்தலின் கீழ் என்னைத் திருமணம் செய்து கொள்கிறான் என்று ஆண்டாள் கனவு கண்டதாகக் கூறுகிறாள்."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Lakis var med i den grekiska landslagstrupp som vann EM 2004 i Portugal. Han","answer":"gjorde två framträdanden i turneringen, ett i en gruppspelsmatch mot Portugal och ett i kvartsfinalen mot Frankrike."},{"question":"請用簡潔的語言回答以下問題：人類學是如何研究不同文化的青年與教育？","answer":"答案：人類學通過研究不同文化對青年的期望、教育機會、青年群體的文化參與等方面來了解其青年與教育的社會背景和文化意義。"},{"question":"ਕਾਰ ਖ਼ਰਾਬ ਹੋ ਗਈ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਡਰਾਈਵਰ ਨੇ ਟੈਲੀਫ਼ੋਨ ਦੇ ਖੰਭੇ ਨਾਲ ਟੱਕਰ ਮਾਰੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਡਰਾਈਵਰ ਨੇ ਲਾਲ ਲਾਈਟ ਤੋੜ ਦਿੱਤੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਡਰਾਈਵਰ ਨੇ ਟੈਲੀਫ਼ੋਨ ਦੇ ਖੰਭੇ ਨਾਲ ਟੱਕਰ ਮਾਰੀ।"},{"question":"Xagee ka helnaa oksajiinta?","answer":"Oksajiinta waxaan ka helnaa dhirta."},{"question":"Qual è la risposta corretta a questa domanda?\\"Cosa succede a Mario quando mangia un fiore?\\"","answer":"La risposta corretta a questa domanda è:\\"Spara palle di fuoco\\""},{"question":"参考下面的段落,然后以回答后面的问题:  穿越:蒙特雅克 (Muntjacs, MUN-jahk),也被称为吠叫鹿和马斯特雷尼鹿,是南亚本土的蒙蒂亚克斯属的小鹿. 蒙特雅克人被认为在15~35亿年前开始出现,其遗骸在法国,德国和波兰的米奥纪沉积物中被发现. 它被IUCN列为最不关心的物种.  问题:蒙特雅克人什么时候开始出现?","answer":"在15至35亿年前"},{"question":"Siapakah Chef Wan?","answer":"Chef Wan adalah seorang chef, pengacara, penulis, ahli perniagaan dan pelakon Malaysia yang terkenal."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഓരോ പ്രവർത്തനത്തിനും തുല്യവും വിപരീതവുമായ പ്രതികരണം ഉണ്ടെന്ന് പറയുന്ന നിയമം എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഓരോ പ്രവർത്തനത്തിനും തുല്യവും വിപരീതവുമായ പ്രതിപ്രവർത്തനം ഉണ്ടെന്ന് പറയുന്ന നിയമം ന്യൂട്ടന്റെ മൂന്നാം ചലനനിയമമാണ്."},{"question":"ගස් වලින් පැන්සල් සාදා ගන්නේ කෙසේද?","answer":"පැන්සල් සෑදීම සඳහා, ගස් වලවල් සහිත ස්ලැබ් වලට කපා ඇත. වර්ණ රේඛා වලවල් වලට ඇතුල් කරනු ලැබේ. ස්ලැබ් එකට සැන්ඩ්විච් කර පසුව පැන්සල් වලට අඹරනු ලැබේ. මකනයක් ෆෙරූල් සමඟ අමුණා ඇත."},{"question":"அதிக நாடுகளைக் கொண்ட கண்டம் எது?","answer":"ஆப்பிரிக்கா"},{"question":"வினா:ஓசோன் படலத்தின் பயன்களைக் கூறு. ஓசோன் படலத்தில் உருவான ஓட்டையினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய தீமைகள் யாவை?","answer":"விடை :ஓசோன் அடுக்கு வரையறை\\"ஓசோன் அடுக்கு என்பது பூமியின் அடுக்கு மண்டலத்தில் உள்ள ஒரு பகுதி, இது ஓசோனின் அதிக செறிவுகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளது மற்றும் சூரியனின் தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் புற ஊதா கதிர்வீச்சிலிருந்து பூமியைப் பாதுகாக்கிறது.\\"ஓசோன் படலம் முக்கியமாக பூமியின் வளிமண்டலத்தின் கீழ் பகுதியில் காணப்படுகிறது. பூமியில் உள்ள உயிர்களை சேதப்படுத்தும் சூரியனிலிருந்து வரும் தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் புற ஊதா கதிர்வீச்சுகளில் சுமார் 97-99% உறிஞ்சும் திறன் கொண்டது. ஓசோன் படலத்தின் பயன்கள்:• கதிரவனிடமிருந்து வெளிவரும் புறஊதாக் கதிர்களைத் தடுக்கிறது.• புவியைப் போர்வை போலச் சுற்றி கதிரவனின் வெப்பத்தைக் குறைத்துக் கொடுக்கிறது.ஓசோன் அடுக்கு சிதைவு என்றால் என்ன?ஓசோன் அடுக்கு சிதைவு என்பது மேல் வளிமண்டலத்தில் இருக்கும் ஓசோன் படலம் மெலிந்து போவதாகும். வளிமண்டலத்தில் உள்ள குளோரின் மற்றும் புரோமின் அணுக்கள் ஓசோனுடன் தொடர்பு கொண்டு ஓசோன் மூலக்கூறுகளை அழிக்கும்போது இது நிகழ்கிறது.ஓசோன் படலத்தில் உருவான ஓட்டையினால் ஏற்படக்கூடிய தீமைகள்:• புறஊதாக் கதிர்கள் நேரடியாக உயிரினங்களைத் தாக்குவதால் மிகுந்த துன்பத்தை உயிரினங்கள் அடைகின்றன.• கண்களும் தோலும் பாதிப்படைகின்றன.ஓசோன் அடுக்கு சிதைவின் விளைவுகள்ஓசோன் படலத்தின் சிதைவு சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கு தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும். மனிதனுக்கும் சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்கும் ஓசோன் படலத்தின் சிதைவின் முக்கிய விளைவுகளைப் பார்ப்போம்.மனித ஆரோக்கியத்தின் மீதான விளைவுகள்ஓசோன் படலத்தின் சிதைவு காரணமாக சூரியனின் தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் புற ஊதா கதிர்வீச்சுக்கு மனிதர்கள் நேரடியாக வெளிப்படுவார்கள். இது தோல் நோய்கள், புற்றுநோய் , வெயில், கண்புரை, விரைவான வயதான மற்றும் பலவீனமான நோயெதிர்ப்பு அமைப்பு போன்ற மனிதர்களிடையே கடுமையான உடல்நலப் பிரச்சினைகளை ஏற்படுத்தக்கூடும் .விலங்குகள் மீதான விளைவுகள்புற ஊதாக் கதிர்களின் நேரடி வெளிப்பாடு விலங்குகளில் தோல் மற்றும் கண் புற்றுநோய்க்கு வழிவகுக்கிறது.சுற்றுச்சூழல் மீதான விளைவுகள்வலுவான புற ஊதா கதிர்கள் தாவரங்களில் குறைந்த வளர்ச்சி, பூக்கும் மற்றும் ஒளிச்சேர்க்கைக்கு வழிவகுக்கும். புற ஊதாக் கதிர்களின் தீய விளைவுகளையும் காடுகள் தாங்க வேண்டியுள்ளது.கடல் வாழ் உயிரினங்கள் மீதான விளைவுகள்தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் புற ஊதா கதிர்களின் வெளிப்பாட்டால் பிளாங்க்டன்கள் பெரிதும் பாதிக்கப்படுகின்றன. இவை நீர்வாழ் உணவுச் சங்கிலியில் அதிகம். பிளாங்க்டான்கள் அழிக்கப்பட்டால், உணவுச் சங்கிலியில் இருக்கும் உயிரினங்களும் பாதிக்கப்படும்."},{"question":"Umhlaba ungumhlaba ngokuhlabaUwuhloniphe uwukhonze uyakuhloniphaUbazonda kabi abazazi ukuhlakanipha.Lunye kuwo uhamboImpinda ayikho.Sinye kuwo isikhathiSifushane aseneleUbupigogo nobusakabuli buyaqedwaBushazwe yizangqotho nemishazo yomhlabaOmahlalothini abantengenyekayo ntengentengeBawe bhu bahuhuluze okwamahoboshaAbaqhwaklazela phezul' onontandakubukwaBaphenduk’izinqibi kugayingane imilomoOsemuva limshwibe shwi limbeke phambiliNgentobeko yobuphansi okwentuthaneBhala isibonelo somugqa onesenzukuthi enkondlweni beseuyasidwebela.","answer":"Osemuva limshwibe shwi limbeke phambili. / Bawe bhu bahuhuluze okwamahobosha / Omahlalothini abantengenyekayo ntengentenge."},{"question":"Afaka mamaly fanontaniana ve ny famaliana ny fanontaniana izay mitaky ny fampifangaroana ny fampahalalana amin'ny faritra maro amin'ny lahatsoratra?","answer":"Eny, ny valin'ny fanontaniana manintona dia afaka mamantatra sy mampifangaro fampahalalana amin'ny faritra samihafa amin'ny lahatsoratra mba hamoronana valiny iraisana."},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 仙台市は津波の警報などが出たときに、ドローンが自動で飛んで、避難するように伝えるシステムを作りました。","answer":"津波の警報などが出ると、直径1mぐらいの2つのドローンが一緒に出発します。ドローンは、プログラムどおりに海岸を50mの高さで飛びます。そして、「巨大な津波のおそれ」などと音を出して、釣りをしている人や泳いでいる人に避難するように伝えます。ドローンにはカメラがついていて、市の職員が映像を見ることもできます。 2011年の東日本大震災では、避難するように伝えていた市の職員が津波に流されました。このため仙台市は、安全に避難の案内ができるシステムを作りました。"},{"question":"Sheeg labada wadan ee halka buundo i sku xirto?","answer":"Labada wadan  ey isku xirto halka Buundo waa Sacuudiga iyo Baxreyn."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe tsingerin'ny rano?","answer":"Ny tsingerin'ny l  no atao hoe tsingerin'ny rano"},{"question":"लक्ष्मीप्रसाद देवकोटा को हुन् ?","answer":"लक्ष्मीप्रसाद देवकोटा एक नेपाली कवि, नाटककार, उपन्यासकार र राजनीतिज्ञ थिए। नेपाली साहित्यमा महाकविको उपाधीले सम्मानित उनी सुनौलो हृदयका कविका रूपमा परिचित थिए । उहाँलाई नेपालको सबैभन्दा ठूलो र प्रसिद्ध साहित्यिक व्यक्तित्व मध्ये एक मानिन्छ।"},{"question":"බාල දක්ෂ ව්‍යාපාරයේ ආරම්භකයා කවුද?","answer":"බාල දක්ෂ ව්‍යාපාරයේ ආරම්භකයාබේඩන්‌ පවල්‌ සාමීවරයාය‍. ලොව පුරා විසිරී සිටින බාලදක්ෂයින් B.P යන ආදර නාමයෙන් හඳුන්වන “ගිල්වෙල්හි රොබට් ස්ටීවන්සන් ස්මිත් බේඩන් පවෙල් සාමිවරයා” බාලදක්ෂ ව්‍යාපාරයේ නිර්මාතෘවරයාය. 1857 පෙබරවාරි මස 22 දින එංගලන්තයේ ලන්ඩනයේ උපත ලැබීය. මෙතුමා ගේ පියා “ඔක්ස්ෆර්ඩ් හි මහාචාර්ය බේඩන් පවෙල්”ය. මව “හෙන්රිආටා ග්‍රෙස් ස්මිත් බේඩන් පවෙල්” මැතිණියයි. B.P ට වයස අවුරුදු 03 දී තම පියා මිය ගියේය. පවුලේ දරුවන් 09 දෙනෙකි බී.පී 06 වෙනියා විය. 1921 දී පළමු වරට ලෝක බාලදක්ෂ ව්‍යාපාරයේ නායක බේඩන් පවෙල් සාමිවරයා සහ ඔලේව් සෙන්ට් ක්ලෙයාර් මැතිනියගේ ලංකාවට සැපත් වීම සිදු විය. එම අවස්ථාවේ දී ඔවුන් පිළිගැනීමට කොළඹ ගාලූ මුවදොර පිටියේ රැළියක් පැවැත්විය. 1929 දී  V වන ජෝර්ජ් රජු ඔහුට \\"ගිල්වෙල්හි බේඩන් පවෙල්\\" යන වංශාධිපති පදවියකින් ගෞරව කරන ලදී. 84 වන ඡන්ම දිනයට  ආසන්නව තිබියදී 1941 ජනවාරි 08 වන දින B.P පරලොව සැපත් විය."},{"question":" కింది పేరాను చదవండి.ఒకనాడు బలరామకృష్ణులూ, గోపబాలురు అందరూ కలిసి వనభోజనాలు చేయాలని సరదాపడ్డారు. పొద్దుటే లేచి, గబగబా తమ ఇంటి లేగదూడలను బయటికి తోలుకొని వచ్చారు. అందమైన కొమ్ము బూరలను పూరించి ఊదగానే మిగిలిన గోపకుమారులందరూ మేల్కొన్నారు. చల్ది అన్నపు కావడులను భుజాలకు తగిలించుకొన్నారు. తల్లులు సిద్ధం చేసి ఉంచిన రకరకాల పిండివంటలు మూటలు కట్టుకొన్నారు. కాళ్ళకు చెప్పులు వేసుకున్నారు, చేతికర్రలు పట్టుకున్నారు. లెక్కపెట్టడానికి కూడా కష్టమనిపించే తమతమ లేగలమందలను ‘హెహెయ్’ అని కేకలతో తోలుకొంటూ బయలుదేరారు. పరుగులతో ఆయాసపడుతూ అడవిలోకి ప్రవేశించారు. బంగారు, మణి భూషణాలు ధరించి ఉన్న పూలను, చిగుళ్ళను, చిన్నచిన్న పండ్లను అలంకారాలుగా ధరించారు.కొమ్ముబూరలు పూరిస్తూ, పిల్లనగ్రోవులు ఊదుతూ, తుమ్మెదలతోబాటు ఝుమ్మని పాడుతూ, నెమళ్ళతో సమానంగా నాట్యంచేస్తూ, కోకిలలను, మిగిలిన పక్షులను అనుకరించి కూతలు కూస్తూ, చిలకలతోపాటు అరుస్తూ కేరింతలు కొట్టారు. పైన పక్షులు ఎగురుతూ ఉంటే వాటి నీడలతోపాటు తామూ పరుగులెత్తారు. జలజలపారే సెలయేళ్ళను చెంగున దాటారు. హంసలపక్కనే వాటిని అనుకరిస్తూ నడిచారు. కొంగలతో పాటు ఒంటికాలిమీద నిలబడ్డారు. బెగ్గురు పక్షులను తరిమితరిమి అలసిపోగొట్టారు. నదీ జలాలలో స్నానాలు చేశారు. తీగల ఉయ్యాలలు ఊగారు. గోతులలో దాక్కొన్నారు. దూరాలకు పరుగు పందాలు వేసుకొన్నారు. కోతులవలె చెట్టు ఎక్కారు. పండ్లు తిని, ఆ రుచులకు పరవశించిపోయారు. కుప్పించి దూకి, తమ నీడలను చూసి నవ్వుకొన్నారు. ఒకరితో ఒకరు పోట్లాడుకున్నారు. కేరింతలు కొడుతూ, పరుగెడుతూ, పడుకొంటూ, అలసిపోతూ ఇలా ఎన్నో రకాలుగా ఆటలు ఆడుకొన్నారు.పై పేరాకు వీలైనన్ని ప్రశ్నలు రాయండి.","answer":"బలరామకృష్ణులు దేనికి సరదా పడ్డారు?వారు వేటిని తోలుకొని వచ్చారు?బలరామకృష్ణులు గోపకుమారులను నిద్ర నుండి ఎలా లేపారు?గోపబాలకులు వేటిని భుజాలకు తగిలించు – కున్నారు?గోపబాలురు వేటిని మూటకట్టుకున్నారు?వారు కాళ్ళకు ఏమి ధరించారు?వారి లేగల మందలు ఎన్ని ఉన్నాయి?వారు లేగలను ఎలా తోలుకుంటూ వచ్చారు?వారు దూడలతో ఎక్కడ ప్రవేశించారు?గోపబాలుర అలంకారాలు పేర్కొనండి.గోపబాలురు ఎలా కేరింతలు కొట్టారు?గోపబాలురు దేనితో పాటు పరుగులెత్తారు?గోపబాలురు దేనిని దాటారు?గోపబాలురు దేని ప్రక్కన ఎలా నడిచారు?గోపబాలురు ఎలా నిలబడ్డారు?గోపబాలురు ఏ పక్షులను తరిమి అలిసి పోయారు?గోపబాలురు ఎక్కడ స్నానం చేశారు?గోపబాలురు దేనిలో ఊగారు?గోపబాలురు ఎక్కడ దాక్కొన్నారు?గోపబాలురు ఏమి పందాలు వేసుకున్నారు?వారు ఏమి ఎక్కారు?వారు దేనికి పరవశించిపోయారు?గోపబాలురు దేన్ని చూసి నవ్వుకున్నారు?ఏమి చేస్తూ గోపబాలురు ఆడుకున్నారు?"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai batik lasam\\"?","answer":"Makin lama dipakai, makin elok"},{"question":"Mitovy va ireto fanambaràna manaraka ireto:\\"Manamavo ny ririnina izy\\" sy \\"Ny ririnina no vanim-potoana faran'izay tsy tiany indrindra\\" .","answer":"Eny, samy manondro fomba fijery ratsy momba ny vanim-potoana ririnina avokoa izy ireo."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: * Lần đầu người Trung Quốc biểu tình tập thể đồng loạt. Nhiều công dân Trung Quốc học tập và sinh sống ở nước ngoài đang tổ chức các cuộc biểu tình phản đối thương hiệu thời trang xa xỉ Dior (Pháp). Theo Thời báo Hoàn Cầu ngày 31-7, các cuộc biểu tình này diễn ra ở nhiều nước như Tây Ban Nha, Pháp, Mỹ... sau khi Dior bị cáo buộc sao chép thiết kế của \\"váy mã diện\\" (hay còn gọi là váy mặt ngựa, loại trang phục truyền thống Trung Quốc có từ thời Tống) trong bộ sưu tập mùa thu 2022 mà không nói rõ nguồn gốc và từ chối giải quyết vấn đề sau khi bị phản đối. * Hoạt động xuất khẩu ngũ cốc từ Ukraine có thể bắt đầu hôm nay (1-8). Theo Hãng tin Tass, thông tin này do ông Ibrahim Kalin, người phát ngôn của tổng thống Thổ Nhĩ Kỳ, cung cấp. \\"Con tàu chở ngũ cốc đầu tiên có thể rời cảng Ukraine vào sáng 1-8\\" - ông nói ngày 31-7. * Thái tử Charles của Anh vướng bê bối tiền bạc. Người kế vị ngai vàng Hoàng gia Anh được cho là đã nhận 1 triệu bảng Anh từ Bakr và Shafiq bin Laden, anh em cùng cha khác mẹ với trùm khủng bố Osama bin Laden, cho Quỹ The Prince of Wales' Charitable Fund (PWCF) vào năm 2013. Số tiền đó được cho là \\"trả ơn\\" việc giúp đỡ cho một doanh nhân Saudi lấy được quốc tịch Anh. Thông tin này được báo Sunday Times (Anh) dẫn các nguồn tin tiết lộ, nhưng Điện Clarence House của Thái tử Charles đã phủ nhận. Điện Clarence House nói rằng quyết định nhận khoản tiền quyên góp này là do thành viên thuộc quỹ từ thiện này đưa ra, chứ không phải do Thái tử Charles. * Tuyến đường sắt Trung Quốc - Lào bắt đầu khai thác. Theo TTXVN, ngày 30-7, tỉnh Sơn Tây của Trung Quốc vận hành chuyến tàu vận tải hàng hóa quốc tế đầu tiên đi qua tuyến đường sắt Trung Quốc - Lào. Theo Công ty đường sắt Taiyuan Group của Trung Quốc, tàu đã rời tỉnh Sơn Tây và dự kiến đến thủ đô Vientiane của Lào trong vòng 7 ngày. Tàu chở các khoang hàng hóa bao gồm đồ gốm sứ, sơn và phân bón. Khánh thành vào ngày 3-12-2021, tuyến đường sắt Trung Quốc - Lào dài 1.000km, nối thành phố Côn Minh, thủ phủ của tỉnh Vân Nam, tây nam Trung Quốc, với thủ đô Vientiane của Lào. * Ông trùm ngũ cốc Ukraine trúng tên lửa Nga. Thành phố cảng Mykolaiv (miền nam Ukraine) hứng chịu các cuộc tấn công dữ dội của quân Nga qua đêm và đầu ngày 31-7, khiến chủ sở hữu công ty xuất khẩu ngũ cốc thiệt mạng. Theo Hãng tin Reuters, thông tin trên Telegram, thống đốc Mykolaiv Vitaliy Kim cho biết ông Oleksiy Vadatursky, người sáng lập kiêm chủ sở hữu Công ty nông nghiệp Nibulon, và vợ đã thiệt mạng tại nhà riêng do cuộc tấn công của Nga. Đây là một trong những công ty sản xuất và xuất khẩu ngũ cốc lớn nhất của Ukraine. Tổng thống Ukraine Volodymyr Zelensky mô tả cái chết của ông Vadatursky là \\"mất mát to lớn đối với toàn bộ đất nước Ukraine\\". * Cựu tổng thống Philippines Fidel Ramos qua đời ở tuổi 94 vào hôm 31-7. Ông là một trong những nhà lãnh đạo chính trị được đánh giá cao trong lịch sử Philippines. Theo Hãng tin AFP, các nhà lập pháp, nhà ngoại giao, cựu chính trị gia và chính quyền mới của Philippines đã có các bài viết tưởng nhớ ông Ramos trên mạng xã hội. Làm tổng thống Philippines giai đoạn 1992 - 1998, ông Fidel Ramos đã mang tới một thời kỳ hòa bình và tăng trưởng ổn định cho Philippines. * Tổng thống Mỹ Joe Biden đang cảm thấy khỏe và tiếp tục cách ly sau khi tái dương tính với COVID-19. Theo Hãng tin Reuters, thông tin này do bác sĩ của ông Biden cung cấp và được Nhà Trắng công bố ngày 31-7. Ông Biden có kết quả xét nghiệm COVID-19 dương tính lần 1 vào hôm 21-7 và khỏi bệnh sau đó, nhưng tái dương tính hôm 30-7. * Kentucky dự báo phải nhiều tuần mới biết hết số thiệt hại do mưa lũ. Số người chết đã tăng lên 26 do một trong những trận lũ lụt tàn phá nhất lịch sử bang Kentucky. Ngày 31-7, thống đốc Andy Beshear của bang Kentucky (miền đông nước Mỹ) cho biết lực lượng cứu hộ đang nỗ lực tìm kiếm từng nhà trong điều kiện thời tiết xấu do mưa, để xác định vị trí các nạn nhân trong trận lũ lụt tàn phá khu vực phía đông của bang này. Lũ lụt đã biến đường phố thành sông, cuốn trôi cầu và nhà cửa, khiến ít nhất 26 người thiệt mạng tại Kentucky cho đến nay. \\"Đây là một trong những trận lũ lụt tàn phá và gây chết chóc nhất mà chúng tôi từng chứng kiến trong lịch sử của chúng tôi\\" - ông Andy Beshear nói trên kênh NBC. * Nga có kế hoạch phát triển các đường ống xuất khẩu khí đốt ở biển Đen và biển Azov. Hãng tin Tass cho biết, cũng theo Học thuyết hải quân mới vừa được Tổng thống Nga Vladimir Putin thông qua hôm 31-7, Nga còn xây dựng các cơ sở mới để xử lý và vận chuyển hydrocacbon.","answer":"Tin thế giới 1-8: Dân Trung Quốc phản đối nhà tạo mốt Dior; 'vua' ngũ cốc Ukraine thiệt mạng"},{"question":"కంచుతో తయారైన ఈ శిల్పాన్ని స్పెయిన్‌లోని సెగోవియా నగరంలోని ఓ వ్యక్తి గౌరవార్థం 'ప్రముఖ కాలువపైకి ఎక్కిన దెయ్యం' విగ్రహాన్ని ఏర్పాటు చేయాలని ప్రతిపాదించారు.కానీ, స్థానికులు మాత్రం ఈ భూతం నవ్వుతూ, సెల్ఫీ తీసుకుంటున్నట్లుగా ఉందని, చూడటానికి చాలా స్నేహపూర్వకంగా ఉన్నట్లుందంటూ అభ్యంతరం వ్యక్తం చేస్తున్నారు.ఈ శిల్పం క్రైస్తవుల మనోభావాలను కించపరిచేలా ఉందో లేదో పరిశీలించేవరకూ దీని ఏర్పాటును తాత్కాలికంగా ఆపేయాలని జడ్జి ఆదేశించారు.దీని ఏర్పాటును రద్దు చేయాలని కోరుతూ నగరంలోని దాదాపు 5400 మంది (అక్కడి జనాభాలో 10శాతం పైగా) ఓ పిటిషన్‌పై సంతకాలు చేశారు.ఫోన్ పట్టుకుని నవ్వుతూ ఉన్నట్లున్న ఈ శిల్పం దెయ్యాలను ఎక్కువ చేసి చూపుతున్నట్లు ఉందని, ఇది క్యాథలిక్కులకు అభ్యంతరకరంగా ఉందని వారు ఆరోపిస్తున్నారు. ఈ శిల్పం చాలా కోపంగా, అసహ్యంగా ఉంటూనే ఎలాంటి హానీ చేయదనిపించే విధంగా ఉండాలని వారంటున్నారు.శిల్పాన్ని రూపొందించిన కళాకారుడు జోస్ ఆంటోనియో అబెల్లా ఈ అభ్యంతరాలపై ఆశ్చర్యం వ్యక్తం చేస్తున్నారు.\\"ఓ గొప్ప వ్యక్తిని గుర్తుచేసుకోవడానికి ఏర్పాటు చేసిన ఈ శిల్పాన్ని ఎందుకింత తీవ్రంగా వ్యతిరేకిస్తున్నారో నాకు ... గరిష్టంగా మరో 4000 అక్షరాలతో కథనాన్ని కొనసాగించండి:","answer":"అర్థం కావట్లేదు. నాకు ఈ నగరం అంటే చాలా ఇష్టం. మూడు దశాబ్దాలు ఇక్కడే నివసించాను. దానికి కృతజ్ఞతగా సెగోవియాలో ఈ శిల్పాన్ని ఏర్పాటుచేయాలనుకున్నా. ఈ శిల్పాన్ని రూపొందించడానికి నేను డబ్బు తీసుకోలేదు. డబ్బుల కోసం నేను దీన్ని చేయట్లేదు, నేను నివసించిన నగరానికి నేనిచ్చే నివాళి ఇది. నా భావాలను అర్థం చేసుకోండి.\\" అని జోస్ విజ్ఞప్తి చేశారు.ఈ విగ్రహంపై వివాదం అసంబద్ధంగా ఉండని నగర్ కౌన్సిలర్ క్లాడియా డి శాంటోస్ వ్యాఖ్యానించారు. అనుకున్నవిధంగా విగ్రహం ఏర్పాటు జరిగేందుకు ప్రయత్నిస్తానని ఆమె 'ఎల్ పైస్' పత్రికతో తెలిపారు.ఇవి కూడా చదవండి.(బీబీసీ తెలుగును ఫేస్‌బుక్, ఇన్‌స్టాగ్రామ్‌, ట్విటర్‌లో ఫాలో అవ్వండి. యూట్యూబ్‌లో సబ్‌స్క్రైబ్ చేయండి.)"},{"question":"heeg magaca ciyaartoy caalami ahaa oo dalkiisa ka noqday Wasiirka Isboortiga?","answer":" Waxa uu ahaa Belle"},{"question":"清华大学的历史是怎样的？","answer":"答：清华大学成立于1911年，最初是为了培养送往美国留学的学生而设立的预备学校，名为“清华学堂”。自成立以来，清华大学一直是中国高等教育和科学研究的重要中心。"},{"question":"Adele Ajosun","answer":"Oba Adele tàbí Adele Ajosun (ó fi ayé sílẹ̀ ní ọdún 1837) jọba ní Èkó fún ṣáà méjì; àkọ́kọ́ , láti ọdún c1811 sí 1821, àti ẹlẹ́kejì láti ọdún 1835 sí 1837. Bàbá rẹ̀ ni Oba Ologun Kutere, àwọn ẹbí rẹ̀ sì ni Oba Osinlokun àti Ọba Akitoye, ìran Ologun Kutere ti gun orí oyè ọba Èkó fún ọ̀pọ̀ ìgbà láti ìgbà náà.Adele gun orí ìtẹ́ ọba Èkó lẹ́yìn ọdún márùn-ún tí bàbá rẹ̀, Ologun Kutere, fi ayé sílẹ̀. Àwọn ìtàn àti àkọọ́lẹ̀ kòkan fihàn pé ète Ologun Kutere ni pé kí Adele di Oba Èkó nítorí iṣẹ́ ribiribi tí ó ti ṣe fún Ologun Kutere. Onítàn John. B. Losi kọ́ pé Adele tọ́ju àwọn ohun ìní Ologun Kutere.Nígbà ìjọba Adele, ẹ̀sìn Mùsùlùmí gba ilẹ̀ ní Èkó."},{"question":"请回答这个问题：地球上最大的半島是哪個？","answer":"答案：阿拉伯半島"},{"question":"ボクサーが手にはめるのはグローブ。では口にはめるのは何？","answer":"マウスピースです。"},{"question":"لمن كانت اول جائزه نوبل في الادب؟","answer":"الفرنسي معولي بردوم عام 1901م."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：哪位英国首相领导了英国的反恐战争和军事行动？","answer":"答案：托尼·布莱尔是领导了英国的反恐战争和军事行动的英国首相，特别是在阿富汗和伊拉克的行动。"},{"question":"Em qual cidade surgiu a banda The Beatles?","answer":"The Beatles surgiu na cidade de Liverpool, que fica no noroeste da Inglaterra. "},{"question":"Euskal Herriko arkitektura zein da bere erabilpen praktiko eta estetikoa?","answer":"Bere erabilpen praktikoa da ingurumenarekin bat egitea eta estetikoa da hainbat elementu tradizionalak eta modernoak uztartzea."},{"question":"सर्वात लहान ग्रह कोणता?उत्तर : ","answer":"बुध"},{"question":"سيلز پنهنجي ڊي اين اي کي ڪيئن نقل ڪندا آهن؟","answer":"سيلز کي ڊي اين اي جي نقل ذريعي انهن جي ڊي اين اي کي نقل ڪيو. هي نيم قدامت پسند عمل کي يقيني بڻائي ٿو ته هر ڌيء سيل والدين جي سيل جي ڊي اين اي جي هڪ صحيح ڪاپي حاصل ڪري ٿي. ڊي اين اي نقل مخصوص سائيٽن تي شروع ٿئي ٿو. ڊي اين اي ڊبل هيلڪس اينجيمز طرفان انوميز آهي، هڪ نقل ڪانٽو ٺاهڻ. ڊي اين اي پوليمسيرس کي ٽيمپليٽ واري اسٽرينڊ ۾ مڪمل ڊي اين اي جي اسٽرينڊ کي ترتيب ڏيندي نئين ڊي اين اي اسٽرينڊ کي ترتيب ڏيو. هڪ ڀيرو ٻيهر نقل مڪمل آهي، ٻه هڪجهڙا ڊي اين اي ماليڪيولز پيدا ڪيا ويا آهن، هر هڪ هڪ پراڻي ۽ هڪ نئين اسٽينڊ سان."},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 滋賀県は去年10月、AIを使って結婚の相手を紹介するサービスを始めました。サービスを利用する人は、生活の中で大事にしたいことや結婚の相手にしないでほしいことなど、100ぐらいの質問に答えます。AIがこの答えに合う相手を探して、紹介してくれます。県によると、今までに800人以上がサービスを利用しています。そして、県に住んでいる2組のカップルが結婚することを決めました。どちらのカップルも、付き合い始めてから3か月ぐらいです。県の職員は「付き合い始めてから結婚までに2年か3年かかるというデータがあります。しかし、AIで紹介した人たちがとても早く結婚することになって、驚きました」と話しています。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。- AI: 1）記憶・学習・思考・判断など、人間の知能に近いはたらきをするコンピューターシステム。AI。- 相手: 1）ものごとをいっしょにするときの、もう一方の人。2）争ったりするときの、もう一方の側。- サービス: 1）人のために尽くすこと。奉仕。2）客をもてなすこと。3）直接物を作る以外の仕事。- 組: 1）組むこと。また、組んだもの。2）ひとそろいになること。3）そろいになった物。4）仲間。5）学級。クラス。- カップル: 1）夫婦や恋人のような、男と女のひと組み。- 付き合い: 1）親しくする。交際する。2）いっしょに、同じ行動をする。- 職員: 1）役所・学校・団体などに勤めている人。- データ: 1）考えるもとになる材料や事実。2）コンピューターで使えるように、数字や記号に置きかえられた資料。"},{"question":"‘படியானையே பிணிப்புண்பனவடிமணிச்சிலம்பே யரற்றுவன’ -இடஞ்சுட்டிப் பொருள் விளக்கம் தருக.","answer":"இடம் சுட்டுதல் :இராசராச சோழனின் மெய்க்கீர்த்திப் பகுதியில் இவ்வரிகள் இடம்பெறுகின்றன.பொருள் விளக்கம் :இராசராச சோழன் நாட்டில் யானைகள் பிணிக்கப்படுகின்றன. ஆனால் மக்கள் பிணிக்கப்படுவதில்லை. சிலம்புகள் புலம்புகின்றன. ஆனால் மக்கள் புலம்புவதில்லை."},{"question":"İrlanda da Schengen geçerli mi?","answer":"Turizm amaçlı olarak 6 aylık dönem için en fazla 90 günlüğüne verilen Schengen vizesi 22 Avrupa Birliği ülkesinin yanı sıra İzlanda, Norveç, Lihteştayn ve İsviçre'de kullanılıyor. AB üyesi oldukları halde İrlanda, Bulgaristan, Romanya ve Kıbrıs, Schengen bölgesinde yer almıyor."},{"question":"Adigunjale atawọn Amọtẹkun doju ibọn kọra wọn l’Ọyọọ","answer":"Bii igba ti wọn wa loju ogun lọrọ ri laarin ikọ eleto aabo ilẹ Yoruba, Amọtẹkun, ẹka ipinlẹ Ọyọ, atawọn ogboju adigunjale kan nigba ti awọn mejeeji fija pẹẹta, ti wọn si n rọ̀jò ibọn ranṣẹ sira wọn lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ana.Ni nnkan bii aago meji aabọ ọsan niṣẹlẹ ọhun waye laduugbo Baara, niluu Ọyọ. Nigbẹyin ija naa, ibọn ba oṣiṣẹ Amọtẹkun kan to n jẹ Amo Ṣangodoyin nikun, meji ninu awọn afurasi adigunjale naa, Tiamiyu Abiọdun ati Saka Rokeeb si fara gbọta.Oludari ikọ Amọtẹkun nipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ọgagun-fẹyinti Ọlayinka Ọlayanjusọ, sọ pe lasiko ti awọn ọbayejẹ eeyan naa n fibọn ja awọn araadugbo Baara, niluu Ọyọ, lole lawọn araadugbo ọhun fi iṣẹlẹ naa to awọn leti lori ẹrọ ibanisọrọ, ti awọn eeyan oun si ta lọọ koju awọn igaara ọlọṣa naa.Amọ ṣa, ohun ti awọn Amọtẹkun ro kọ ni wọn ba pade nitori kaka ki awọn ẹruuku wọnyi sa lọ nigba ti awọn Amọtẹkun ba wọn lalejo, ibọn ni wọn fi ki wọn kaabọ, ibọn si ba ọkan ninu awọn ọmoogun agbofinro naa nikun.Lọgan lawọn eleto aabo naa mura ija, ti awọn ikọ mejeeji si bẹrẹ si i jọ dana ibọn funra wọn ya karakara.Ọwọ ibọn ba bii meji ninu awọn kọlọransi wọnyi, wọn si woye pe ija yii ki i ṣe ohun ti awọn le bori, nigba naa ni wọn pẹyin da, n ni wọn ba fere ge e.Ṣugbọn ẹ̀pa kò bóró fun ikọ awọn adigunjale ẹlẹni mẹrin yii, nitori gbogbo wọn pata lọwọ awọn Amọtẹkun tẹ tibọn-tibọn ọwọ kaluku wọn.Orukọ awọn afurasi ọdaran naa ni Idowu Taofeek, Yekin Awwal, Tiamiyu Biọdun ati Saka Rokeeb.Ajagunfẹyinti Ọlayanju fidi ẹ mulẹ pe nibi ti awọn agbofinro ti n sinmi aṣeyọri yii lọwọ ni ipe tun ti wọle sori aago awọn Amọtẹkun, wọn lawọn adigunjale mi-in tun n pitu lọwọ nibomin-in nigboro ilu Ọyọ kan naa.Ninu iṣẹlẹ keji yii lọwọ ti ba ọkan ninu awọn adigunjale naa ti wọn pe lakẹkọọ fasiti kan nipinlẹ Ọyọ.Gẹgẹ bi ọga awọn Amọtẹkun ṣe fidi ẹ mulẹ, awọn eleto aabo yii ni wọn gbe Biọdun, ẹni ogun ọdun (20) ati Rokeeb ti i ṣe ẹni ọdun mejidinlogun (18) lọ sileewosan ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ to wa niluu Ọyọ fun itọju nigba ti wọn fa awọn mẹta yooku le awọn ọlọpaa lọwọ ni teṣan wọn to wa ni Durbar, niluu Ọyọ."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Dù phải hành quân đến Cần Thơ ở vòng 9 Giải Hạng nhất quốc gia 2022 nhưng tân binh Phú Thọ vẫn tự tin bắt nhịp trận đấu và ghi bàn mở tỉ số ở đầu hiệp 2. Sau nhiều nỗ lực tìm bàn gỡ, đội chủ nhà cũng hiện thực tham vọng bằng pha lập công của Thiện Chí ở phút 70. Đáng nói, bàn gỡ của CLB Cần Thơ Trong đã bị trọng tài biên căng cờ báo việt vị nhưng trọng tài chính Nguyễn Anh Vũ vẫn công nhận bàn thắng. Điều này khiến đội khách Phú Thọ phản ứng dữ dội và gần như sa sút tinh thần thi đấu. Trong khi đó, đoàn quân HLV Nguyễn Việt Thắng trở nên hưng phấn hơn sau bàn gỡ, tiếp tục dồn lực tấn công và có thêm bàn thắng để","answer":"dẫn trước đối thủ ở phút 83. Những tưởng đội bóng Tây đô sẽ có trọn vẹn 3 điểm trên sân nhà thì ở thời gian bù giờ cuối cùng, Phú Thọ lại cân bằng tỉ số hòa 2-2 chung cuộc. Từ tình huống đá phạt, Mạnh Duy lập công bằng pha đánh đầu đẹp mắt ở phút 90+5, giúp Phú Thọ giành lại 1 điểm quý giá. Kết quả hòa đáng tiếc khiến Cần Thơ có 10 điểm sau 9 vòng đấu, có cùng điểm số với đội xếp trên là Phù Đồng nhưng vẫn giậm chân ở vị trí thứ 9 vì kém hơn đối thủ về chỉ số phụ. Trong khi đó, đoàn quân HLV Vũ Như Thành vẫn tiếp tục đứng cuối bảng đấu nhưng đã có cùng 6 điểm với đội áp chót Bình Phước."},{"question":"De onde obtemos o amendoim?","answer":"O amendoim é uma planta herbácea, com caule pequeno e folhas compostas e pinadas. Possui abundante indumento, raiz aprumada, medindo entre 30–50 cm de profundidade. As flores são pequenas e amareladas e, depois de fecundadas, penetram no solo, com a ajuda de uma estrutura denominada ginóforo e de um fenómeno conhecido como geocarpia, onde os legumes se desenvolvem subterraneamente. O fruto é uma vagem que nasce sob a terra. Os maiores produtores mundiais de amendoim são a China e a Índia."},{"question":"Jaona dia mpiasa feno fanoloran-tena sy miasa mafy ao amin'ny orinasa fitanterana entana. Niara-niasa tamin'ny orinasa nandritra ny dimy taona izy ary nahazo fisondrotana maromaro noho ny zava-bitany miavaka.","answer":"Iza no mpiasa feno fanoloran-tena sy miasa mafy ao amin'ny orinasa fitanterana entana, izay niaraka tamin'ny orinasa nandritra ny dimy taona ary nahazo fisondrotana maromaro noho ny zava-bitany miavaka?"},{"question":"Dê um exemplo de uma pergunta trivia da categoria: política","answer":"Quem morreu no cargo em mil novecentos e um? William McKinley"},{"question":"નીચેના સોરઠી બોલી શબ્દોનો શું અર્થ થાય છે? દરેક શબ્દ માટે એક શબ્દ માં જવાબ આપો.1. અખાજ2. અખિયાત3. અટવાવું4. અડવું (અંગ)5. અડાબીડ6. અણખંડી7. અધગાળે8. અનરાધાર, અંદ્વાધાર, ઇંદ્રાધાર9. અનિયા10. અમલ 11. અરઘવું12. અસમદનાં પગલાં, અસમેરનાં પગલાં, અસમાનનાં પગલાં13. અસરાણપત14. અંજળ15. અંતરિયાળ16. અંબોડાળી (ભેંસ)","answer":"આ દરેક સોરઠી બોલીના શબ્દ માટે, એક શબ્દમા જવાબ નીચે મુજબ છે:1. અખાજ: અખાદ્ય2. અખિયાત: આખું, સુવાંગ3. અટવાવું: ગૂંચવાઈ જવું4. અડવું (અંગ): ખાલી, અલંકાર વગરનું5. અડાબીડ: સંખ્યાબંધ, ભરપૂર6. અણખંડીઃ અખંડિત7. અધગાળેઃ વચ્ચે8. અનરાધાર, અંદ્વાધાર, ઇંદ્રાધાર: મોટી ધારે વરસતો વરસાદ. (ઈંદ્ર મહારાજ વરસાવે સામાન છે એવી લોકકલ્પના છે.)9. અનિયાઃ અન્યાય10. અમલઃ અફીણનો કૅફ11. અરઘવું: ઓપવું, શોભવું12. અસમદનાં પગલાં, અસમેરનાં પગલાં, અસમાનનાં પગલાં: આસમાનમાં પગલાં, મૃત્યુકાળે પગે ચાલીને સ્મશાનમાં જઈ ચિતા પર ચડવાની વિધિ.13. અસરાણપતઃ અસુરો (યવનો)નો પતિ14. અંજળ: અન્નજળ, પરસ્પરની લેણાદેણી15. અંતરિયાળ: નિર્જન પ્રદેશમાં, મુકામથી દૂર, નિરાધાર સ્થળે16. અંબોડાળી. (ભેંસ): જેનાં શીંગડાં આંટા લઈ ગયેલાં હોય છે તે. (સ્ત્રીના માથાના અંબોડાની કલ્પના છે) "},{"question":"Content: ਸੁਖਜਿੰਦਰ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਤੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਸਾਲ ਬਾਅਦ ਵੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਉਸ ਮੁਆਵਜ਼ੇ ਲਈ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਦਫ਼ਤਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਚੱਕਰ ਕੱਟ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਇਹ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਸੁਖਜਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਭਰਾ ਗੁਰਜੰਟ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੇ ਹਨ। ਸੁਖਜਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ 40 ਸੀਆਰਪੀਐਫ਼ ਜਵਾਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਸੀ ਜੋ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਸਾਲ 14 ਫਰਵਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਪੁਲਵਾਮਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਏ ਹਮਲੇ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਮਾਰੇ ਗਏ ਸਨ।ਅੱਜ ਸੁਖਜਿੰਦਰ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਤੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਸਾਲ ਬਾਅਦ ਵੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਉਸ ਮੁਆਵਜ਼ੇ ਲਈ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਦਫ਼ਤਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਚੱਕਰ ਕੱਟ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਐਲਾਨ ਪੁਲਾਵਾਮਾ ਹਮਲੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ।ਸੁਖਜਿੰਦਰ ਦੇ ਭਰਾ ਗੁਰਜੰਟ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਸਰਕਾਰ 'ਤੇ ਕਈ ਸਵਾਲ ਖੜ੍ਹੇ ਕੀਤੇ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਕਿ ਪੁਲਵਾਮਾ ਹਮਲੇ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਕੌਣ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਕਿ ਹਮਲਾ ਕਿਸਨੇ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਭਰਾ ਨੂੰ ਗਵਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਗੁਰਜੰਟ ਸਿੰਘ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦਾ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਉਸੇ ਦਿਨ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ ਜਦੋਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਧਮਾਕੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੁਖਜਿੰਦਰ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਬਰ ਮਿਲੀ ਸੀ।ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੀ ਮਾਲੀ ਹਾਲਤ।ਸੁਖਜਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਦਾ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਤਰਨਤਾਰਨ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਦੇ ਪਿੰਡ ਗੰਡੀਵਿੰਡ ਧਤਾਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਕੋਲ ਤਕਰੀਬਨ ਤਿੰਨ ਏਕੜ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਹੈ।ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸੂਬਾ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ 12 ਲੱਖ ਰੁਪਏ ਅਤੇ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਦੇਣ ਦਾ ਵਾਅਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਅਜੇ ਤੱਕ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪੰਜ ਲੱਖ ਰੁਪਏ ਮਿਲੇ ਹਨ।ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਸੂਬਾ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ 12 ਲੱਖ ਰੁਪਏ ਅਤੇ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਦੇਣ ਦਾ ਵਾਅਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਕੈਪਟਨ ਅਮਰਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਸਾਲ ਐਲਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਪੁਲਵਾਮਾ ਹਮਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਾਰੇ ਗਏ ਜਵਾਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ 12 ਲੱਖ ਰੁਪਏ ਅਤੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਨੂੰ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਦੇਣਗੇ। ਸੁਖਜਿੰਦਰ ਦੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਸਰਬਜੀਤ ਕੌਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਪੇਕੇ ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਸਮਾਂ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਉਹ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ਦੇ ਅਖੀਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਹੁਰੇ ਘਰ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ।ਵਾਅਦਾ ਖਿਲਾਫ਼ੀ ਦਾ ਇਲਜ਼ਾਮ।ਸਰਬਜੀਤ ਕੌਰ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ, \\"ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਵਾਅਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਵਿੱਤੀ ਮਦਦ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਦੇਣਗੇ। ਇਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਮੇਰਾ ਪੁੱਤਰ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਡੇਢ ਸਾਲ ਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਚਪੜਾਸੀ ਦੀ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਦੀ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ ਜਦਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਚੰਗੀ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਲਈ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ।\\" ਇੱਥੇ ਇਹ ਦੱਸਣਾ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸਰਬਜੀਤ ਕੌਰ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ 12ਵੀਂ ਤੱਕ ਹੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ \\"ਬਿਹਤਰ ਨੌਕਰੀ\\" ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਦਾ ਮਾਮਲਾ \\"ਪਾਈਪਲਾਈਨ\\" ਵਿੱਚ ਹੈ।      ਸਰਬਜੀਤ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਰ ਰੋਜ਼ ਜਵਾਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਬਰ ਸੁਣਨ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ।","answer":"\\"ਦੇਸ ਲਈ ਮੇਰਾ ਭਰਾ ਸ਼ਾਹੀਦ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਸਾਡੇ ਲਈ ਉਹ ਮਰ ਚੁੱਕਿਆ ਹੈ, ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾ ਲਈ ਜਾ ਚੁੱਕਿਆ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਸਾਫ਼ ਸ਼ਬਦਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਹਿੰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਸਾਡੇ ਜਵਾਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਰਵਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।\\""},{"question":"Unsaon pagpadako sa akong pag-tuo kang Hesukristo?","answer":"Adlaw adlaw paminaw sa pulong ni Hesukristo."},{"question":" கேள்வி: “இரட்டைக்கிளவி போல் இணைந்தே வாழுங்கள் பிரிந்தால் பொருளில்லை…” என்று பாடியவர் யார்?அ) சுரதா                                                                ஆ) மு.மேத்தாஇ) தாரா பாரதி                                                       ஈ) அப்துல் ரகுமான்","answer":"சரியான பதில்: அ) சுரதா "},{"question":"Given the following statement, predict the tags for each word: Insights from Eye-Tracking","answer":"Here are the predicted parts of speech tags for each word in the sentence \\"Insights from Eye-Tracking\\":Insights: NOUNfrom: ADPEye: NOUN-: PUNCTTracking: NOUN"},{"question":"सन्दीप लामिछाने ","answer":"सन्दीप लामिछाने  (जन्म: २०५७ साउन १८) एक नेपाली क्रिकेट खेलाडी हुन् जो नेपाली राष्ट्रिय क्रिकेट टोलीको लागि खेल्दछन्। दायाँ हाते स्पिन बलर, लामिछानेले इन्डियन प्रिमियर लिगमा दिल्ली क्यापिटल्स, बिग ब्यास लिगमा होबार्ट हुरिकेन र पाकिस्तान सुपर लिगमा लाहोर कलन्दर सहित विश्वभर आयोजना हुने प्रमुख ट्वान्टी२० खेल प्रतियोगिताहरूमा खेल्ने गर्दछन्। साउन २०७५ मा, लामिछानेले गिती सङ्ग्रह प्रतीक्षामा समावेश उनको पहिलो गीत \\"उदाश थियो\\" जारी गरेका थिए।सन्दीपले सन् २०१८ मा आइसिसी विश्व ११ बाट खेल्दै वेस्ट इन्डिज विरुद्ध टि२० मा पदार्पण गरेका थिए।संयुक्त टोलीको प्रतिनिधित्व गर्दै टि२० अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय पदार्पण गर्ने उनी पहिलो नेपाली क्रिकेट खेलाडी समेत हुन्। उनी सन् २०१८ अगस्तमा नेदरल्यान्ड विरुद्ध नेपालको पहिलो एकदिवसीय अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय खेल खेल्ने एघार क्रिकेट खेलाडी मध्ये एक थिए।"},{"question":"தற்குறிப்பேற்ற அணி அமைவதை எடுத்துக்காட்டுக.","answer":"தற்குறிப்பேற்ற அணி:இயல்பாய் நிகழும் நிகழ்ச்சியின் மீது கவிஞன் தன் குறிப்பை ஏற்றிக் கூறுவது தற்குறிப்பேற்ற அணி எனப்படும்.(எ.கா.) ‘போருழந் தெடுத்த ஆரெயில் நெடுங்கொடிவாரல் என்பனபோல் மறித்துக்கை காட்ட’பொருள்:கோட்டை மதில் மேல் இருந்த கொடியானது வரவேண்டாம் எனத் தடுப்பதுபோல, கை காட்டியது என்பது பொருள்.அணிப்பொருத்தம் :கோவலனும், கண்ணகியும் மதுரை மாநகருக்குள் சென்றபோது மதிலின் மேலிருந்த கொடிகள் காற்றில் இயற்கையாக அசைந்தன. ஆனால், இளங்கோவடிகள் கோவலன் மதுரையில் கொலை செய்யப்படுவான் எனக்கருதி அக்கொடிகள் கையை அசைத்து, ‘இம்மதுரைக்குள் வரவேண்டா’ என்று தெரிவிப்பது போலக் காற்றில் அசைவதாகத் தம் குறிப்பைக் கொடியின் மீது ஏற்றிக் கூறுகிறார். இவ்வாறு இயல்பாக நிகழும் நிகழ்ச்சியின் மீது கவிஞன் தன் குறிப்பை ஏற்றிக் கூறுவது தற்குறிப்பேற்ற அணி எனப்படும்."},{"question":"Sheeg Nabi Cismaaciil Cs Meesha Uu Ku Aasan Yahay?","answer":"Waa Magaalada Makkah."},{"question":"Суроо: Геометриялык фигурада \\"айланалуу тегерек\\" деген эмне?","answer":"Жооп: Айланалуу тегерек - математикадагы негизги геометриялык фигуралардын бири. Бул тегеректин борбору деп аталган бир борбордук чекиттен бирдей аралыкта жайгашкан бардык чекиттерден турган жалпак фигура. Бул аралык айлананын радиусу деп аталат.Чөйрөнүн негизги мүнөздөмөлөрү төмөнкүлөрдү камтыйт:1)Айлананын борбору: айлананын бардык башка чекиттери жайгашкан борбордук чекит.2) Айлананын радиусу: Айлананын борборунан анын каалаган чекитине чейинки аралык. \\"р\\" тамгасы менен белгиленет.3) Айлананын диаметри: радиустун эки эсе узундугу, башкача айтканда, тегеректин чек арасындагы бир чекиттен борбор аркылуу чек аранын башка чекитине чейин. \\"d\\" тамгасы менен белгиленет жана \\"2r\\" га барабар."},{"question":"السؤال: ما أقسام المعاصي؟","answer":"الإجابة: كبائر وصغائر"},{"question":"السؤال: من أول قاضي في مصر ؟","answer":"الإجابة : قيس بن أبي العاص ."},{"question":"Táíwò Ajai-Lycett","answer":"Taiwo Ajai-Lycett (bíi ọjọ́ Keta oṣù kejì ọdún 1941) ni òṣeré, oníròyìn àti atọ́kùn ará ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà. Ajai-Lycett ni obìnrin àkọ́kọ́ tí ó ṣe iṣẹ́ olóòtú ìwé-ìròyìn Africa Woman ni ọdún 1970.Wọn bí Lycett ni ọjọ́ Keta oṣù kejì ọdún 1941 ni ìpínlè Èkó, bàbà rẹ jẹ ọmọ ìran Àwórì. Ó lọ sí ilé ẹ̀kọ́ Mt Carmel Convent School àti Methodist Girl's High School ni ìpínlè Èkó.Ó lọ sí ìlú London láti ka ìwé ímo Business and administration. Ó lọ sí ilé ẹ̀kọ́ gíga tí Hendon College of Technology nibẹ ni ó ti gba HND nínú Business Studies ni ọdún 1969. Ní Igba tí ó wà ní ilẹ̀ ẹ̀kọ́ gíga, ó ń ṣíṣe ni Lyson tea shop, ilé ifiwe ranse ati ilé iṣẹ́ ìpolówó.O bẹ̀rẹ̀ rẹ̀ sì ní ṣe ère ni ọdún 1966 ni gba ti o kópa nínú eré The lion and the jewel. Kò lérò láti kópa nínú eré na tẹ́lẹ̀, ṣùgbọ́n olùdarí eré náà, William Gaskill sọ fún pé kí ó wà kópa nínú eré náà. Lẹ́yìn eré náà ni ó wà lọ sí ilé ẹ̀kọ́ orin àti eré tí \\"Guildhall School of Music and Drama\\".O kópa nínú àwọn ère orí ìtàgé bíi Life everlasting , The national health àti Parcel post. O tí kópa nínú àwọn eré tí Nàìjíríà bíi Tinsel àti Olibiri.Ní ọdún 1975, Lycett darapọ̀ mọ àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ ní ilé iṣẹ́ Africa Magazine.O jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ́ Society of Nigerian Theatre Artists (SONTA).Ni ọjọ́ kìíní oṣù kẹwàá ọdún 2006, Lycett gba ebun Officer of the Order of Niger láti ọwọ́ Chief Olusegun Obasanjo. Ní oṣù kejì ọdún 2008, wọn fi ṣe olórí British-African theatre, pelu Dotun Adebayo àti Yemi Ajíbádé."},{"question":"Mikä on otsonikerros ja onko se ohenemassa?","answer":"Ilmakehän otsonikerron suojaa elämää maapallolla haitalliselta auringon ultraviolettisäteilyltä eli UV-säteilyltä. Otsonikerros on tärkeässä asemassa myös maapallon ilmakehän säteilytasapainon kannalta. 1980-luvun alkupuolella tutkijat huomasivat tämän maapallon luonnollisen aurinkosuojan vähenevän hälyttävästi eteläisen napa-alueen yläpuolella. Keväisin Etelämantereen ylle muodostui ns. otsoniaukko. Syyt otsonikerroksen vähenemiseen löytyivät pian, ja vuonna 1987 solmittiin kansainvälinen yhteistyösopimus, Montrealin pöytäkirja, jossa maat sitoutuivat lopettamaan otsonia tuhoavien yhdisteiden käytön.Maailman ilmatieteen järjestön uusimmassa arviointiraportissa todetaan, että ilmakehän otsonikerros palautuu 1980-lukua edeltävälle tasolle neljän seuraavan vuosikymmenen aikana."},{"question":"Inona ny atao hoe aina?","answer":"Ny aina dia fototry ny fahavelomana ao amin’ny zavaboary manana aina rehetra. Fanomezan’Andriamanitra amin’ny maha Tompon’ny aina azy io aina io. Noho izany tsy azo atao tsinontsinona, tsy azo vonoina."},{"question":"Аталардан калган асыл нарктарыбыз кайсылар?\\r","answer":"\\rНарктар  каадалар менен \\rкоштолот жана шөкөттөлөт. Каадалар - иш-аракеттердин жүрүшүндө \\rкөрүнөт, ал иштин жүрүшүн жана аны ишке ашышын мүнөздөөчү көрүнүш. \\rКаада салт нарктуу аткарылып жаткан иштердин көркүн чыгарат, \\rкаада анын аткарылышы эмес, аткаруунун ырасмысы, сыпаты, \\rаткаруунун себеби, же себептүү натыйжа, же кандайдыр бир себептерден \\rулам аткарылуучу иш-аракет, нарктуу ишти аткаруунун мүнөзү.\\rКааданын аткарылышы нарктарды орундуу, ыктуу колдонууну жана аны \\rбилүүнү, ал тургай, адамдардын билүү даражасын, турмуштук билиминин, \\rтажрыйбасынын деӊгээлин түшүндүрөт. \\rТөмөндө аталардан калган каадаларды эстейли:\\r- карыялык кааданы тутуу-демек, карыя өзүн сөөлөттүү алып жүрүүсү."},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 去年から日本のいろいろな所で、強盗事件が起こっています。東京都狛江市の事件では、90歳の女性が殺されました。日本の警察は、フィリピンにいる日本人4人が、強盗事件を起こしたグループの中心だと考えています。4人は別の事件で捕まって、フィリピンの施設に入っています。警察は4人を日本で調べるため、フィリピンの政府に4人を日本に渡すように言いました。来週、フィリピンのマルコス大統領が日本に来る予定があります。フィリピンはそれまでに4人を渡したいと考えていて、日本と話し合っています。事件を解決するため、4人がいつ日本に戻るかが大事になっています。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。"},{"question":"नेपाललाई कहिले १४ अञ्चल र ७५ जिल्लामा विभाजन गरिएको थियो ?","answer":"B.S. २०१८ वैशाख ०१"},{"question":"\\"Nahazo ny fisondrotana tany am-piasana aho, tsy afaka ny ho faly kokoa.\\" Inona ny fihetseham-pon'io fanambarana io?","answer":"Io fanambarana io dia manondro fihetseham-po tsara satria faly be ilay olona tamin'ny fisondrotanany vao haingana."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau:TP HCM chỉ là một điểm dừng của chuỗi ngày hội \\"Thanh niên Công nhân - Lan tỏa năng lượng tích cực\\" do Trung ương Đoàn TNCS Hồ Chí Minh, Trung ương Hội Liên hiệp Thanh niên Việt Nam, Trung ương Hội Thầy thuốc trẻ Việt Nam, TCP Việt Nam và nhãn hàng Red Bull khởi xướng. Ngày hội hướng tới việc chăm lo ","answer":"cho sức khỏe thể chất cũng như đời sống tinh thần của công nhân trên cả nước.\\"Thanh niên công nhân là lực lượng lao động nòng cốt của đất nước, góp phần quan trọng trong nền kinh tế sản xuất, tạo đà cho sự phát triển của doanh nghiệp, địa phương. Chính vì thế, việc chăm lo đời sống tinh thần cho lực lượng thanh niên công nhân luôn là hoạt động thiết thực, cần được đẩy mạnh\\", đại diện ban tổ chức chia sẻ lý do xây dựng chuỗi chương trình ngày hội."},{"question":"Are athletes from disputed or unrecognized areas allowed to compete in the Olympics?","answer":"Under specific circumstances, athletes from disputed or unrecognized areas are permitted to compete in the Olympics. They can participate under the Olympic flag as independent athletes or as members of an officially recognized National Olympic Committee. This enables students to engage in the spirit of the games and display their talent."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan kepada soalan yang rumit ini: Siapakah pelawak berdiri yang mempunyai watak sokongan dalam \\"Sweethearts\\"?","answer":"Margaret Moran Cho"},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકનુ એક લેખન નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે. આજ રીતની \\"માથાફોડ\\" પર આવુ જ બીજુ લેખન લખો. \\"મને ગલૂડિયું રમાડાવું બહુ ગમે છે પણ બા કહે છે: “આપણે ગલૂડિયું ન રમાડાય.”⁠મને મંછા સાથે રમવું બહુ ગમે છે પણ બાપા કહે છે : “આપણે મંછા સાથે ન રમાય.”⁠મને શાક સુધારવું બહુ ગમે છે પણ મોટી બેન કહે છે : “તારાથી શાક ન સુધારાય.”⁠મને જોડા ગોઠાવવા બહુ ગમે છે પણ ગોઠવવા જાઉં ત્યારે કાકા કહે છે : “આપણે જોડા ન ગોઠવાય.”\\"","answer":"હું ગલૂડિયે રામતો હતો. બા કહે : “એની સાથે ન રમ; એ કરડકણું છે.”⁠હું મંછા ભેગો રમતો હતો. બાપા મને કહે : “હમણા એની ભેગો ન રમ; એને ખસ થઈ છે.”⁠હું શાક સુધારવા જતો હતો મોટી બેન કહે : “એ છરીએ ન સુધારતો; એ તાજી સજાવેલી છે.”⁠હું જોડા ગોઠવવા બેઠો. કાકા કહે : “હમણાં ન ગોઠગતો; નહાતી વખતે ગોઠવજે.”"},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau:\\"Quỳnh Nga kể từ sau loạt vai diễn phản diện là \\"tiểu tam\\", tú bà đã có màn trở lại màn ảnh với một diện mạo hoàn toàn mới. Vốn sở hữu nhan sắc xinh đẹp, hình thể nóng bỏng, mỹ nhân vũ trụ VFC luôn là tâm điểm chú ý trong mỗi cảnh quay. Nếu như diễn xuất của cô nàng Cá Sấu Chúa từng không được đánh giá cao thì phong cách thời trang lẫn gout làm đẹp của cô lại ngược lại. Còn nhớ lần vào vai Nhã \\"tiểu tam\\" trong Về Nhà Đi Con, Quỳnh Nga đã tạo nên làn sóng thời trang dữ dội như thế nào với phong cách trưng diện của mình. Hàng loạt các item váy áo trở nên \\"cháy hàng\\" trên mọi mặt trận chỉ vì Nhã quá đáng ghét và diện quá gợi cảm. Thậm chí, thiết kế 2 dây này còn có luôn tên gọi là váy tiểu tam khiến chị em phấn khích. Cô từng chia sẻ, sau nhiều tập phim có lương người theo dõi khủng, cô đã bị \\"nổ inbox\\" xin hỏi địa chỉ mua váy áo. Người đẹp chia sẻ đó cũng là một thành công mà cô tạo được thông qua vai diễn của mình. Một lần nữa, lịch sử đó lại được lặp lại ở tác phẩm đang được phát sóng trên khung giờ vàng Chồng Cũ, Vợ Cũ, Người Yêu Cũ. Trong phân đoạn mới được phát sóng trên Chồng Cũ, Vợ Cũ, Người Yêu Cũ, Minh (Quỳnh Nga) đã đến tìm Trâm để cảnh cáo về việc cô gái này liên tục gây khó dễ cho Giang (Lã Thanh Huyền), bạn thân của Minh.\\"","answer":"Mới ngày nào vào vai Nhã tiểu tam bị đánh ghen, giật tóc ở Về Nhà Đi Con, nay Quỳnh Nga lại có dịp \\"đánh ngược\\" người khác. Những hành động cực dứt khoát, lời lẽ đanh thép khi cảnh cáo \\"kẻ phản diện\\" của Minh khiến khán giả phấn khích tột độ. Ngay lập tức, bộ cánh Quỳnh Nga mặc bỗng trở thành hot item. Nguyên combo là áo sơ mi mix cùng quần jeans ống loe không cạp hot trend của thời trang 2022. Khi sơ vin, chiếc áo tôn lên đường cong tuyệt hảo của vóc dáng Quỳnh Nga. Dù trên phim hay ảnh hậu trường, combo vẫn vô cùng thời thượng. Chiếc áo được may với hoạ tiết đường kẻ cách điệu lệch 1 bên thân. Cầu vai 1 bên có khoảng hở trendy. Nhìn chung, đây là thiết kế sơ mi tay phồng hơi hướng vintage nhưng nó đã trở nên nổi tiếng vì phân đoạn \\"chiến nhau\\" cực gắt của chị em màn ảnh. Quỳnh Nga vào vai Minh Minh \\"lột xác\\" đúng nghĩa về cả tính cách nhân vật lẫn phong cách thời trang. Hầu như chẳng có 1 item 2 dây mỏng manh, gợi cảm nào mà chiếm phần lớn là đồ denim và đồ da. Phong cách bụi bặm khác hẳn với một Quỳnh Nga thường thấy vẫn nhận được lời khen tích cực. Người đẹp và đồ da, mix cùng motor phân phối lớn là combo \\"đỉnh chóp\\". Tạo hình đặc biệt này của Quỳnh Nga có lẽ là lần xuất hiện đầu tiên của màn ảnh VTV. So với một Giang (Lã Thanh Huyền) quá an toàn với gout ăn mặc nữ tính, kín đáo của một biên kịch, nhà văn thì Minh Minh lại nhận được tình cảm từ khán giả nhiều hơn. Hiện phim vẫn đang được phát sóng và hi vọng công chúng sẽ được ngắm nhiều hơn những outfit đậm chất mùa hè của Minh Minh."},{"question":"No português do Brasil, a palavra \\"tristeza\\" tem quantas sílabas?","answer":"A palavra \\"tristeza\\" tem 3 sílabas: tris-te-za."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga :\\"___ milevina amoron-dalana ka mahatantesa valin-kitsaka.\\"","answer":"\\"Mpamosavy milevina amoron-dalana ka mahantantesa valin-kitsaka.\\""},{"question":"Qual é a capital de Fiji?","answer":"Suva é a capital, cidade mais populosa e principal centro cultural e turístico das ilhas Fiji. A cidade está localizada na costa sudeste da ilha de Viti Levu, na província de Rewa, divisão de Fiji Central, de que também é o centro administrativo. Suva é uma das únicas metrópoles do Pacífico Sul."},{"question":" Sheeg Ciidaanka Caalamka Ugu Tirada Badan ?","answer":"Ciidaanka Caalamka Ugu Tirada Badan Waa Ciidanka Shiinaha (China)"},{"question":"Viết đoạn văn ngắn khoảng 200 từ về chủ đề: \\"năng lực suy nghĩ của con người\\".","answer":"Ngày nay xã hội phát triển ko ngừng. Con người lun phải cập nhật những kiến thức mới nhất. Và cách tiếp thu kiến thức tốt nhất là học. bên cạnh việc học thì chúng ta còn phải kết hợp vs làm bài tập. vậy tại sao phải kết hợp cả 2? khi học thì ta đã tiếp thu thêm 1 phần kiến thức. học càng nhiều thì lượng kiến thức càng lớn. làm sao có thể ghi nhớ hết tất cả kiến thức đó? học mà cho có câu có chữ thì chỉ là học suông, ko có thực chất. giả sử những môn như toán, lý, hóa,... , nếu như chỉ học lí thuyết mà ko làm bài tập thì liệu ta có thể hình dung được cách làm bài hay ứng dụng những j đã học vào đời sống thực tế hay ko?khi chúng ta tập trung suy nghĩ chúng ta có thể tìm ra những cách giải quyết mới. nếu ko làm bài tập thì sau 1 thời gian bạn sẽ quên đi những kiến thức đã học vì bạn ko rèn luyện nó và ko hoàn thiện nó. chúng ta cũng có thể đặt vấn đề ngược lại. nếu như chỉ chú trọng việc làm bài tập thì liệu bạn có thể làm tốt chúng khi ko học lí thuyết? ko học lí thuyết thì làm sao có kiến thức để mà làm bài tập. thực tế đã cho ta thấy điều đó! có 1 số bạn hs ko rèn luyện những kiến thức thu thập được bẳng cách làm bài tập. sau một thời gian thì những kiến thức đó dần dần mất đi. còn những bạn học sinh rèn luyện và ôn lại kiến thức đó thì sẽ làm bài tốt hơn, nhuần nhuyễn hơn. qua đó ta càng thấy việc học và làm bài tập có mối quan hệ chặt chẽ vs nhau. Càng suy nghĩ sẽ càng làm bạn thông minh hơn "},{"question":"Kayseri'nin eski adı nedir?","answer":"Dünyanın en eski şehirleri arasında yer alan Kayseri'nin en eski adı Mazaka'dır, Roma devrine kadar bu isim devam etmiştir. Roma devrinde şehre imparator şehri anlamında Kaisareia adı verilmiştir. Bu isim Araplarca Kaysariya şeklinde kullanılmıştır."},{"question":"ਸੰਯੁਕਤ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰ ਦੀ ਸਰਪ੍ਰਸਤੀ ਹੇਠ ਵਾਤਾਵਰਣ ਸੰਬੰਧੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਕਾਨਫਰੰਸ ਕਿੱਥੇ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ ?","answer":"ਇਹ ਕਾਨਫਰੰਸ ਸਟਾਕਹੋਮ (Stockholm) ਵਿਖੇ 1972 ਨੂੰ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ ।"},{"question":"\\"તકદીર ખુદ ખુદાએ લખી\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"તકદીર ખુદ ખુદાએ લખી પણ ગમી નથીસારું થયું કે કોઈ આ મનુજે લખી નથી.ત્યાં સ્વર્ગ ના મળે તો મુસીબતના પોટલા,કે મારવાની એટલે મેં ઉતાવળ કરી નથી.કેવ શુકનમાં પર્વતે આપી હશે વિદાય,નિજ ઘરથી નીકળી નદી પાછી વળી નથી.શ્રદ્ધાનો હો વિષય તો પુરાવાની શી જરૂર?કુરાનમાં તો ક્યાંય પયમ્બરની સહી નથી.મૃત્યુની ઠેસની વાગશે તો શું થશે ‘જલન’,જીવનની ઠેસની તો હજુ કળ વળી નથી."},{"question":"పూరక ఘటనలకు ఒక ఉదాహరణనివ్వండి.","answer":"పాచిక వేసినపుడు బేసిసంఖ్య పడే సంభావ్యత (E) అయితే బేసిసంఖ్య కానిది అయ్యే (E) ఘటన."},{"question":"Lasiko ti wọn n fẹhonu han nitori SARS, awọn ọdọ gbe posi lorukọ Buhari l’Oṣogbo","answer":"Lati Freedom Park, to wa ni Old Garage, niluu Oṣogbo, lawọn ọdọ naa ti bẹrẹ ifẹhonu han wọọrọwọ, nigba ti wọn de orita Ọlaiya, wọn duro, bẹẹ ni wọn ko faaye gba irinkerindo ọkọ tabi ọlọkada kankan.Bi wọn ṣe n kọ oniruuru orin, ni wọn n jo pẹlu ẹrọ amohun-bu-gbamu nla kan ti wọn gbe soju titi.Ohun ti wọn kọ si ara akọle ti wọn gbe lọwọ ni pe ṣe ni kijọba fiya jẹ gbogbo ọmọ ikọ SARS to ti lọwọ ninu iku ọdọ kan tabi omi-in lorileede yii.Bo ṣe di nnkan bii aago mẹrin irọlẹ ni wọn gbe pako ọhun de, posi ni. Aworan Aarẹ Buhari ni wọn lẹ mọ ọn lara kaakiri.Bẹẹ ni wọn bẹrẹ orin aro, wọn ni ki lo de ti awọn ọlọpaa ko gbọdọ foju kan ọdọkunrin to ba rẹwa, to mu foonu gidi lọwọ tabi to n lo mọto gidi, to waa jẹ pe pipa ni wọn n pa wọn bii ẹwurẹ.Awọn ọdọ naa ni asiko niyi funjọba orileede yii lati mọ pe bi wọn ṣe fẹẹ jẹun ọmọ lawọn obi tawọn naa fẹẹ jẹun ọmọ, ki wọn dẹkun pipa awọn nipakupa.Wọn gbe posi naa lati Ọlaiya lọ si Okefia, kọja lọ si Old Garage, ki wọn tun too dari si orita Ọlaiya."},{"question":"三角形の三辺の長さから面積を求める公式のことを、ギリシャの数学者の名前をとって何というでしょう？","answer":"ヘロンの公式"},{"question":"Comment puis-je répondre à la question d’entretien d’embauche suivante : Un bon manager pour vous, c’est quoi ?","answer":"Avec cette question, le recruteur cherche à analyser la compatibilité du candidat avec son (ou ses) futur(s) chef(s).Rien ne sert d’enrober son propos quand on répond à ce genre de question. Il faut répondre honnêtement, en disant si l’on préfère, par exemple, un manager qui délègue ou un supérieur paternaliste.Par exemple:“Je trouve qu’un bon manager sait motiver les troupes, être à l’écoute, et se montrer disponible.”"},{"question":"Que língua é falada no país Congo?","answer":"No país conhecido como República do Congo, a língua oficial é o francês. "},{"question":"Хто такий Якуб Кулик?","answer":"Якуб Філіп Кулик (1793 - 1863) народився у Львові. Після закінчення місцевої гімназії, він вивчав філософію, право і математику у Львівському університеті, а з 1814 року працював професором математики ліцею. З 1826 року Кулик став професором вищої математики Празького університету. Чимало сил учений віддав розвитку культури, науки та освіти у рідному краї. Він подарував багато книг галицьким гімназіям та Львівському університету. Кулик є автором численних наукових праць, але в історію математики він увійшов як неперевершений обчислювач і укладач математичних таблиць. "},{"question":"Miksi \\"dual use\\" -aineiden ilmoittaminen vaatimustenmukaisuusilmoituksessa on tärkeää?","answer":"Elintarviketoimija tarvitsee tiedon dual use aineista omaa riskinarviointiaan varten. Dual use aineet ovat elintarvikelisäaineita tai aromeja, joiden käytölle on annettu niitä koskevassa lainsäädännössä rajoituksia. Elintarvikealan toimijan tulee varmistaa, että elintarvike täyttää lainsäädännön vaatimukset ja arvioida mahdollisesti kontaktimateriaaleista siirtyviä elintarvikelisäaineita ja -aromeja vaikutukset elintarvikkeen turvallisuuteen ja säädöstenmukaisuuteen."},{"question":"बेहोस हुँदा कस्ता लक्षणहरू देखा पर्छन् ?","answer":"बेहोस हुँदा निम्नानुसार लक्षणहरू देखा पर्छन् :(अ) घाइते वा बिरामी अर्ध वा पुरै बेहोसको अवस्थामा हुनु(आ) घाइतेको नाडी सुस्त गतिमा चल्नु(इ) शरीरबाट पसिना आउनु(ई) घाइतेको रक्तचाप घट्नु(उ) अनुहार पहेँलो र फुस्रो हुनु "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'ibarat telur sesangkak, pecah sebiji, pecah semua'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kesilapan yang dilakukan oleh seseorang menyebabkan orang lain yang menerima akibatnya."},{"question":"Create a speculative fiction tale set in a world where books are sentient beings and their contents influence the emotions and actions of those who read them. Explore the consequences when a forbidden book with dangerous knowledge is discovered.","answer":"एक ऐसी विचारात्मक कथा बनाएं जो एक ऐसे विश्व में स्थित है जहां किताबें जीवंत प्राणियां हैं, और उनकी विषयसूचियां उनको पढ़ने वालों की भावनाओं और क्रियाओं पर प्रभाव डालती हैं। जारी किए जाने वाले खतरनाक ज्ञान के साथ एक निषिद्ध पुस्तक की खोज होने पर उसके परिणामों का अन्वेषण करें।"},{"question":"انگلينڊ يورگوائي کان شڪست ۾ ڪيترا پوائنٽون حاصل ڪيا؟ پوئين سوال کي نظر ۾ رکندي ، هڪ تناظر لکو جنهن ۾ جواب شامل آهي. اهو 1 - 20 جملا ٿي سگهي ٿو. پس منظر:","answer":"انهن جي پهرين ڪڏهن ڌارين ٽيم کي پنهنجي سرزمين تي شڪست آئرلينڊ جي جمهوريه کي 0 <unk> 2 جي نقصان هئي ، 21 سيپٽمبر 1949 تي گڊيسن پارڪ تي. 1953 ۾ هنگري کي 6-3 جو نقصان ، ويمبلي تي هڪ غير ملڪي ٽيم طرفان انهن جي ٻي شڪست هئي. بڊاپسٽ ۾ موٽڻ واري ميچ ۾ ، هنگري 71 کٽيو. هي اڃا تائين انگلينڊ جي بدترين شڪست آهي. راند کان پوءِ، هڪ حيران ٿيل سڊ اوون چيو، \\"اهو ٻاهرين خلا مان مردن کي راند ڪرڻ وانگر هو\\". 1954 ۾ فيفا ورلڊ ڪپ ۾ ، انگلينڊ پهريون ڀيرو ڪوارٽر فائنل ۾ پهتو ، ۽ 4 × 2 کي ريگنگ چيمپيئنز اروگوئي کان هارائي ويو."},{"question":"கேள்வி: லிசாஜஸ் உருவங்கள் என்றால் என்ன?","answer":"விடை: ஒன்றுக்கொன்று செங்குத்தாகவுள்ள இரு தனிச்சீரிசை இயக்கங்களை ஒரு துகளின் மீது செலுத்தும்பொழுது ஏற்படும் தொகுபயன் இயக்கத்தை வரைவதால் கிடைக்கும் உருவங்கள், லிசாஜஸ் உருவங்கள் என அழைக்கப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"ਸਲੋਕ ਮਃ ੩ ॥ ਪੰਡਿਤੁ ਪੜਿ ਪੜਿ ਉਚਾ ਕੂਕਦਾ ਮਾਇਆ ਮੋਹਿ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਬ੍ਰਹਮੁ ਨ ਚੀਨਈ ਮਨਿ ਮੂਰਖੁ ਗਾਵਾਰੁ ॥ ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਇ ਜਗਤੁ ਪਰਬੋਧਦਾ ਨਾ ਬੂਝੈ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ ਬਿਰਥਾ ਜਨਮੁ ਗਵਾਇਆ ਮਰਿ ਜੰਮੈ ਵਾਰੋ ਵਾਰ ॥੧॥ਮਃ ੩ ॥ ਜਿਨੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਿਆ ਤਿਨੀ ਨਾਉ ਪਾਇਆ ਬੂਝਹੁ ਕਰਿ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ ਸਦਾ ਸਾਂਤਿ ਸੁਖੁ ਮਨਿ ਵਸੈ ਚੂਕੈ ਕੂਕ ਪੁਕਾਰ ॥ ਆਪੈ ਨੋ ਆਪੁ ਖਾਇ ਮਨੁ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਹੋਵੈ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੀ ਵੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ ਨਾਨਕ ਸਬਦਿ ਰਤੇ ਸੇ ਮੁਕਤੁ ਹੈ ਹਰਿ ਜੀਉ ਹੇਤਿ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥੨॥ ਪਉੜੀ ॥ ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਸਫਲ ਹੈ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਪਾਵੈ ਥਾਇ ॥ ਜਿਸੁ ਹਰਿ ਭਾਵੈ ਤਿਸੁ ਗੁਰੁ ਮਿਲੈ ਸੋ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇ ॥ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੀ ਹਰਿ ਪਾਈਐ ਹਰਿ ਪਾਰਿ ਲਘਾਇ ॥ ਮਨਹਠਿ ਕਿਨੈ ਨ ਪਾਇਓ ਪੁਛਹੁ ਵੇਦਾ ਜਾਇ ॥ ਨਾਨਕ ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਸੋ ਕਰੇ ਜਿਸੁ ਲਏ ਹਰਿ ਲਾਇ ॥੧੦॥","answer":"ਪੜ੍ਹ ਪੜ੍ਹ ਕੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ (ਜੀਭ ਨਾਲ ਵੇਦ ਆਦਿਕ ਦਾ) ਉੱਚੀ ਸੁਰ ਨਾਲ ਉਚਾਰਣ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਪਰ) ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਪਿਆਰ (ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਆਪ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ) । (ਉਹ) ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਬ ਦੀ ਭਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦਾ, (ਇਸ ਕਰਕੇ) ਮਨੋਂ ਮੂਰਖ ਤੇ ਅਨਪੜ੍ਹ (ਹੀ ਹੈ) ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ (ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਤਾਂ) ਸਮਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦੀ, (ਤੇ) ਸੰਸਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਮੱਤਾਂ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ। (ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਪੰਡਿਤ) ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਜਨਮ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਗਵਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਪੈ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।1। ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਸਮਝ ਲਵੋ (ਭਾਵ, ਵੇਖ ਲਵੋ) , ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਹੋਈ ਕਾਰ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ। ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਹੀ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਤੇ ਸੁਖ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਕਲਪਣਾ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ। 'ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਖਾ ਜਾਏ (ਭਾਵ, ਆਪਾ-ਭਾਵ ਨਿਵਾਰੇ) ਤਾਂ ਮਨ ਸਾਫ਼ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ' = ਇਹ ਵਿਚਾਰ (ਭੀ) ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ (ਉਪਜਦੀ ਹੈ) । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਮੁਕਤ ਹਨ, (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਬਿਰਤੀ ਜੁੜੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ।2।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਬੰਦਗੀ (ਉ​ਂਞ ਤਾਂ ਹਰ ਇਕ ਲਈ ਹੀ) ਸਫਲ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਜਨਮ ਨੂੰ ਸਫਲਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਹੈ, ਪਰ) ਕਬੂਲ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਪੂਰਨ ਸਫਲਤਾ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ) ਜੋ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਸੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ (ਹੀ) ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਉਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤਰੁੱਠਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹੋ ਹੀ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਾਗਰ ਤੋਂ ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਹੈ। ਵੇਦ (ਆਦਿਕ ਧਾਰਮਕ ਪੁਸਤਕਾਂ) ਨੂੰ ਭੀ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਪੁੱਛ ਵੇਖੋ (ਭਾਵ, ਪੁਰਾਤਨ ਧਰਮ-ਪੁਸਤਕ ਭੀ ਇਹੀ ਗੱਲ ਦੱਸਦੇ ਹਨ) ਕਿ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਹਠ ਨਾਲ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੇ ਰੱਬ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭਾ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ) । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਹਰੀ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਉਹੀ ਜੀਵ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ (ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਾ ਕੇ) ਹਰੀ ਆਪਿ ਸੇਵਾ ਵਿਚ ਲਾਏ।10।"},{"question":"「♪ドはドーナツのド～」でご存じのドレミの歌。この曲に出てくる楽器といえば何？","answer":"ラッパです。"},{"question":"Em que ordem aparecem as cores do arco-íris?","answer":"As cores aparecem sempre na ordem: Vermelho, laranja, amarelo, verde, azul, anil (ou índigo) e violeta."},{"question":"මෙම සංකීර්ණ ප්‍රශ්නයට පිළිතුරු සපයන්න.මිසිසිපි වැලී (Mississippi Valley State) ප්‍රාන්ත විශ්ව විද්‍යාලය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ කුමන ප්‍රාන්තයේ ප්‍රදේශයේද?","answer":"මිසිසිපි ප්‍රාන්තයේ, ලෙෆ්ලෝර් ප්‍රදේශයේ"},{"question":"La capitale du Sénégal est","answer":"La capiltale du Sénégal est Dakar."},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: W czasie przejazdu przez południowe wybrzeże Florydy, były kandydat na prezydenta w 2004 roku, senator John Kerry skrytykował niemalże milczenie amerykańskich mediów w sprawie tak zwanego \\"Downing Street Memo\\". Downing Street Memo to wyciek tajnego brytyjskiego dokumentu, który szczegółowo opisuje protokoły z spotkania najwyższych rangą brytyjskich i amerykańskich urzędników rządowych w 2002 roku. W notatce stwierdza się, że George W. Bush \\"był zdeterminowany\\"","answer":"że \\"informacje wywiadowcze i fakty zostały sfałszowane wokół polityki\\". Dokładność tej notatki nie jest kwestionowana przez żaden z rządów. Notatka wywołała zamieszanie w Wielkiej Brytanii i miała znaczący wpływ na brytyjskie wybory, ale nie przyciągnęła zbyt dużej uwagi w amerykańskich wiadomościach. Kerry powiedział o notatce:"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bersekutu bertambah mutu'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud berkerjasama antara satu dengan lain dalam melaksanakan sesuatu akan menghasilkan kejayaan yang cemerlang."},{"question":"Madaxtinimo","answer":"Xukun ka iyo madaxtinimada waa musibo anan aqoon qaraabinmo waxba madhafo waxkastana cagta mariya. Laga sobilawo qaabiil iyo habiil oo ahay caruurta nabi adam cs lagu xijiyo caruurtii nabi yacqub ee nabi yusuf iyo walahis ilaa dowladihi amawiyinta iyo cabasiyinta oo dagaalo xun dhaxmareen laguna layay qaar kamida aalu beeytka nabiga scw scw scw waxa madaxtinimo isku dilayay dad qaraabo ah. Ilaa somalidena oo aan ognahay in dad isku reeraha isku layeen xukun iyo jecel madaxtinimo.Madaxtinimadu waa madhaleeys anan waxba xeerin qaraabo iyo xuramad anan kaxishoon."},{"question":"تحصیلات دکتر مریم میرزاخانی چه بوده است؟","answer":"پروفسور مریم میرزاخانی نابغه ریاضی ایران و چهره جوان و ممتاز بین‌المللی در ریاضیات جهان است؛ بانویی ساده و متواضع و در عین حال مستعد، خلاق، سخت‌کوش و باانگیزه بود که همه موانع را پشت سر گذاشت و نام وی به‌عنوان تاریخ‌ساز برای همیشه جاودانه شد. مریم نخستین زن در جهان و اولین ایرانی برنده نوبل ریاضیات است که با عنوان «مدال فیلدز» از آن یاد می‌شود. کشفیات و خدمات علمی این ریاضیدان نخبه و دانشمند برجسته علم ریاضیات در عمر کوتاه ۴۰ ساله‌اش، روزی را با عنوان او در تقویم جهانی به ثبت رسانده است. مریم میرزاخانی پس از اتمام تحصیلات ابتدایی،‌ در آزمون ورودی مدارس سمپاد (سازمان ملی پرورش استعدادهای درخشان) شرکت کرد و وارد دبیرستان فرزانگان تهران شد. میرزاخانی به‌همراه دوست و همراه همیشگی‌اش، «رویا بهشتی زواره»، اولین دخترانی بودند که به تیم المپیاد ریاضی ایران راه یافتند و  مدال‌های طلا و نقره المپیاد را با خود به خانه آوردند. او توانست در سال سوم و چهارم دبیرستان (سال‌های ۱۳۷۳ و ۱۳۷۴) مدال طلای المپیاد ریاضی کشوری را کسب کند و با شرکت در المپیاد ریاضی جهان، نام خود را بر سر زبان‌ها بیندازد.مریم میرزاخانی اولین دانش‌آموز ایرانی بود که نمره کامل را در المپیاد جهانی ریاضی در کانادا به‌دست آورد؛ او در دو سال پیاپی (۱۹۹۴ هنگ‌کنگ و ۱۹۹۵ کانادا) برنده مدال طلای المپیاد جهانی ریاضی شد و رکورد کسب مدال طلا در دو سال را نیز در بین محصلان ایرانی از آن خود کرد.مریم میرزاخانی به‌همراه رویا در سال ۱۳۷۴ وارد دانشگاه صنعتی شریف شد و دوره کارشناسی خود را در این دانشگاه به پایان رساند. میرزاخانی در این زمان به‌عنوان همکار در پژوهشگاه دانش‌های بنیادی مشغول بود و همچنین اثبات ساده‌ای برای قضیه شُر یافت که ماهنامه انجمن ریاضی آمریکا آن را به چاپ رساند.پس از‌ آن، میرزاخانی برای ادامه تحصیل،‌ بورسیه دانشگاه هاروارد را دریافت و به آمریکا مهاجرت کرد. او در کلاس‌های «کورتیس مک مولن» (Curtis T. McMullen)، از ریاضی‌دانان برجسته و برندگان جایزه فیلدز، حاضر و در سال ۲۰۰۴ به سرپرستی و راهنمایی وی، موفق به کسب مدرک دکتری از دانشگاه هاروارد شد.بعد از اخذ مدرک دکتری، مریم میرزاخانی با سمت استادیار در دانشگاه پرینستون مشغول به کار شد و تا سال ۲۰۰۸ و رسیدن به درجه استاد تمامی، در این دانشگاه به کار خود ادامه‌ داد. این در حالی بود که در سال ۲۰۰۵ میلادی، نام مریم میرزاخانی به‌عنوان یکی از ۱۰ ذهن جوان جهان، در نشریه پاپیولار ساینس آمریکا (Popular Science) مطرح شد.پس از تجربه تدریس در پرینستون، مریم در اول سپتامبر ۲۰۰۸ (۱۱ شهریور ۱۳۸۷) به دانشگاه استنفورد،‌ یکی از معتبرترین دانشگاه‌های جهان و دومین دانشگاه برتر دنیا، رفت و در سن ۳۱ سالگی به‌عنوان پروفسور یا استاد تمام، در این دانشگاه مشغول به تدریس شد.در سال ۲۰۰۹ میلادی، مریم میرزاخانی به‌دلیل دستاوردهایش در ریاضیات، جایزه بلومنتال را از سوی انجمن ریاضیات آمریکا دریافت کرد. این انجمن در اعلامیه‌ای به مناسبت برنده شدن مریم، دلیل گرفتن جایزه مهم بلومنتال توسط او را این‌گونه شرح داد:خلاقیت استثنایی و تز دکترای مبتکرانه که در آن، ابزارهای گوناگونی از هندسه هذلولوی گرفته تا روش‌های کلاسیک فرم‌های اتومورفیک و تقلیل سیمپلکتیک برای به‌دست آوردن نتایجی در سه مسئله مهم ترکیب شده‌اند.سال ۲۰۱۰ میلادی، مریم بار دیگر نبوغ خود را به رخ ریاضیات جهان کشید و پرسشی باز و بی‌‌پاسخ در ریاضی را به اثبات رساند. حدس «شار زلزله» ویلیام ترستن روی فضاهای تایشمولر، مدت‌ها در این علم به مسئله لاینحلی تبدیل شده بود که با توانایی میرزاخانی پرونده‌اش بسته شد."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന വാചകം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക: ഒന്നാം ആംഗ്ലോ-സിഖ് യുദ്ധാനന്തരം, പഞ്ചാബിൽ ഹെൻറിയേയും സഹോദരൻ ജോണിനേയും ഒരുമിച്ച് നിയമിച്ചപ്പോൾ ഇരുവരുടെയും പ്രവർത്തനരീതിയിലുള്ള വ്യത്യാസം തിരിച്ചറിഞ്ഞ ഗവർണർ ജനറൽ ഹാർഡിഞ്ച്, അവരെ ഒരു ഏറ്റുമുട്ടലിന് സാധ്യതയില്ലാത്തവണ്ണം മേൽ-കീഴുദ്യോഗസ്ഥന്മാരായാണ് നിയമിച്ചത്. എന്നാൽ ഡൽഹൗസിക്ക് ഹെൻറിയെ അപേക്ഷിച്ച് ജോണിനോടായിരുന്നു കൂടുതൽ പ്രതിപത്തി. പഞ്ചാബിന്റെ കൂട്ടിച്ചേർക്കലിനുശേഷം ഡൽഹൗസി അവരെ ഒരേയിടത്ത് ഒരേ അധികാരത്തിൽ നിയമിച്ചത് പരസ്പരം തർക്കങ്ങളിലേക്കും ഔദ്യോഗിക-വ്യക്തിബന്ധങ്ങൾക്ക് ഉലച്ചിൽവരുന്നതിനും കാരണമായി. ","answer":"എഴുത്തുകുത്തുകളിൽ ഹെൻറി വരുത്തുന്ന കാലതാമസം, പഞ്ചാബി പ്രഭുക്കൻമാരുടെ നേരെയുള്ള ഇരുവരുടെയും മനോഭാവത്തിലുള്ള വ്യത്യാസം, എല്ലാ മേഖലയിലും ഒരുപോലെ നിയന്ത്രണം നടപ്പാക്കാനുള്ള ജോണിന്റെ ആഗ്രഹം തുടങ്ങിയവയായിരുന്നു തർക്കവിഷയങ്ങൾ. ജനനേതാക്കളെ രാഷ്ട്രീയനിയന്ത്രണത്തിൽ നിർത്തിക്കൊണ്ട് താഴേത്തട്ടിൽ ഏറ്റവും മിതമായ ഇടപെടൽ ആയിരുന്നു ഹെൻറിയുടെ വീക്ഷണം. തർക്കങ്ങൾ മൂലം ഒരുമിച്ചുള്ള ഭരണം മടുത്തുവെന്ന് 1852 ഡിസംബറിൽ ജോൺ എഴുതിയിട്ടുണ്ട്. ഹെൻറിയും ഏതാണ്ട് ഇതേ അവസ്ഥയിലെത്തിയിരുന്നു."},{"question":"Wọn ti mu Taye ati Isiaka, awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun n’Ijanikin  ","answer":" ‘Ọmọ oró’ ni wọn mọ awọn gende meji tẹ ẹ n wo ninu fọto yii si, awọn ọdaju ọmọ ni wọn n pe bẹẹ, tori wọn yawọ ninu fifibọn paayan, ọmọ ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun ni wọn, idi ẹgbẹkẹgbẹ naa lọwọ awọn ọlọpaa si ti ba wọn, ti wọn fi gbe wọn janto.Taye Isreal lorukọ ẹni kin-in-ni, ekeji rẹ ni si n jẹ Isiaka Afeez. Agbegbe Ọtọ-Awori, ni Ijanikin, lọna Badagry, nipinlẹ Eko, lọwọ awọn agbofinro ti ba awọn mejeeji yii lọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii, aake sagila kan bayii ni wọn ka mọ wọn lọwọ, nibi ti wọn ti n le awọn ọmọ ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun mi-in kiri pe awọn fẹẹ gbẹsan lara wọn.Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa Eko, Olumuyiwa Adejọbi sọ f’ALAROYE pe nnkan bii aago mọkanla alẹ ọjọ naa lawọn ọlọpaa teṣan Ijanikin gba ipe idagiri, wọn lẹnikan lo ta wọn lolobo pe awọn ọmọ ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun tun ti bẹrẹ ija wọn o, wọn ti n le ara wọn kiri, wọn si ti ko jinnijinni ba awọn olugbe agbegbe ọhun.Kia ni wọn lawọn ọlọpaa naa ti kan si awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ, bi wọn si ṣe de agbegbe naa ni wọn ṣe kongẹ awọn afurasi meji yii pẹlu aake ti wọn gbe dani, ni wọn ba mu wọn.Wọn tun dọdẹ awọn ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun mi-in ni ibuba wọn, ṣugbọn awọn yẹn tete fura, boya ẹnikan lo si sọ fun wọn, wọn ni kawọn ọlọpaa to debẹ ni kaluku wọn ti ya danu, ṣugbọn wọn ṣi n wa wọn lọwọ.Lara awọn nnkan ija ti wọn ba lọwọ awọn afurasi ọdaran tọwọ ba yii ati ni ibuba wọn ni ibọn ibilẹ kan, ada ati ọbẹ oriṣiiriṣii, ọbẹ, oogun abẹnugọngọ, egboogi oloro ati amuku igbo.Wọn lawọn afurasi naa jẹwọ pe loootọ lawọn n ṣe ẹgbẹ imulẹ, eyi to lodi sofin, ati pe awọn ija nla kan wa laarin awọn ati awọn ẹlẹgbẹ wọn to n ṣe ẹgbẹ imulẹ keji, wọn lawọn lawọn n fi aake ati ibọn wa kiri lati gbẹsan.Ṣa, wọn ti taari awọn mejeeji yii si ẹka ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ni Panti, Yaba, fun iṣẹ iwadii to lọọrin, kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, Hakeem Odumosu, si ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn wa awọn ọmọ ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun yooku lagbegbe naa lawaari nibikibi ti wọn ba sa pamọ si. O ni latigba degba lawọn yoo maa tọpinpin gbogbo ibuba tawọn afurasi ọdaran ‘ọmọ oro’ ẹlẹgbẹkẹgbẹ yii, ba mori mu si nipinlẹ Eko, lati fọwọ ofin mu wọn."},{"question":" شحال العدد ديال الملائكة اللي قاتلوا مع النبي ﷺ والمسلمين فغزوة بدر؟","answer":"ج : 5000 ملك"},{"question":"નાર્કોસ અમેરિકન શ્રેણી વિશે કહો","answer":"નાર્કોસ એ અમેરિકન ક્રાઈમ ડ્રામા ટેલિવિઝન શ્રેણી છે જે ક્રિસ બ્રાન્કાટો, કાર્લો બર્નાર્ડ અને ડગ મીરો દ્વારા બનાવવામાં આવી છે. કોલંબિયામાં સેટ અને ફિલ્માંકન કરાયેલ, સીઝન 1 અને 2 કોલમ્બિયન નાર્કોટેરરિસ્ટ અને ડ્રગ કિંગપિન પાબ્લો એસ્કોબારની વાર્તા પર આધારિત છે, જે મેડેલિન કાર્ટેલના નેતા છે અને કોકેઈનના ઉત્પાદન અને વિતરણ દ્વારા અબજોપતિ બન્યા છે. આ શ્રેણી એસ્કોબારના ડ્રગ લોર્ડ્સ, ડ્રગ એન્ફોર્સમેન્ટ એડમિનિસ્ટ્રેશન (DEA) એજન્ટો અને વિવિધ વિરોધી સંસ્થાઓ સાથેની ક્રિયાપ્રતિક્રિયાઓ પર પણ ધ્યાન કેન્દ્રિત કરે છે. એસ્કોબારના પતન પછી સીઝન 3 શરૂ થાય છે અને તેઓ કુખ્યાત કાલી કાર્ટેલના ઉદયને બંધ કરવાનો પ્રયાસ કરતા DEAને અનુસરવાનું ચાલુ રાખે છે."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو حكم صيام يوم الشك بدون سبب؛ وهو اليوم الذي يسبق دخول رمضان وهو ال ( 30 / شعبان) ؟","answer":"إجابة:حرام "},{"question":"ભારતીય ચિંતકોના મત મુજબ કલાઓની સૂચી","answer":"કામસૂત્ર મુજબ:\\"કામસૂત્ર\\" અનુસાર ૬૪ કલાઓ નિમ્નલિખિત છે:(1) ગાયન, (2) વાદન, (3) નર્તન, (4) નાટય, (5) આલેખ્ય (ચિત્રકલા અને લખાણ), (6) વિશેષક (મુખાદિ પર પત્રલેખન), (7)ચોકમા રંગ પૂરણી, અલ્પના, (8) પુષ્પશય્યા બનાવવી, (9) અંગરાગાદિલેપન, (10) પચ્ચીકારી, (11) શયન રચના, (12) જલતંરગ વાદન (ઉદક વાદ્ય), (13) જલક્રીડ઼ા, જલાઘાત, (14)શ્રુંગાર્ (મેકઅપ), (15) માલા ગૂઁથન, (16) મુંગટ રચના , (17) વેશ પરીવર્તન, (18) કર્ણાભૂષણ રચના, (19) અત્તર યાદિ સુગંધદ્રવ્ય બનાવટ, (20) આભૂષણધારણ, (21) જાદૂગરી, ઇંદ્રજાળ, (22) અરમણીય ને રમણીય બનાવવુ, (23) હાથ ની સફાઈ (હસ્તલાઘવ), (24) રસોઈ કાર્ય, પાક કલા, (25) આપાનક (શર્બત બનાવવુ), (26) સૂચીકર્મ, સિલાઈ, (27) કલાબત્, (28) કોયડા ઉકેલ, (29) અંત્યાક્ષરી, (30) બુઝૌવલ, (31) પુસ્તકવાચન, (32) કાવ્ય-સમીક્ષા કરવી, નાટકાખ્યાયિકા-દર્શન, (33) કાવ્ય-સમસ્યા-પૂર્તિ, (34) વેણી બનાવવી, (35) સૂત્તર બનાવટ, તુર્ક કર્મ, (36) કંદોઇ કામ, (37) વાસ્તુકલા, (38) રત્નપરીક્ષા, (39) ધાતુકર્મ, (40) રત્નોં ની રંગપરીક્ષા, (41) આકર જ્ઞાન, (42) બાગવાની, ઉપવનવિનોદ, (43) મેઢ઼ા, પક્ષી આદિની લડાઈ, (44) પક્ષીઓને બોલતા શીખવવુ, (45) માલિશ કરવુ, (46) કેશ-માર્જન-કૌશલ, (47) ગુપ્ત-ભાષા-જ્ઞાન, (48) વિદેશી કલાઓ નુ જ્ઞાન, (49) દેશી ભાષાઓં નુ જ્ઞાન, (50) ભવિષ્યકથન, (51) કઠપુતલી નર્તન, (52) કઠપુતલી ના ખેલ, (53) સુનકર દોહરા દેના, (54) આશુકાવ્ય ક્રિયા, (55) ભાવ બદલીને કેહવુ (56) છલ કપટ, છલિક યોગ, છલિક નૃત્ય, (57) અભિધાન, કોશજ્ઞાન, (58) મહોરુ બનાવવુ (વસ્ત્રગોપન), (59) દ્યૂતવિદ્યા, (60) રસ્સાકશી, આકર્ષણ ક્રીડ઼ા, (61) બાલક્રીડા કર્મ, (62) શિષ્ટાચાર, (63) વશીકરણ અને (64) વ્યાયામ૤શુક્રનીતિ અનુસાર:\\"શુક્રનીતિ\\" અનુસાર કલાઓની સંખ્યા અસંખ્ય છે, છતાં પણ સમાજમાં અતિ પ્રચલિત ૬૪ કલાઓનો આ નીતિમાં ઉલ્લેખ થયેલો જોવા મળે છે. \\"શુક્રનીતિ\\" અનુસાર આ ૬૪ કલાની ગણના આ પ્રકારે કરવામાં આવેલી છે:(૧) નર્તન (નૃત્ય), (૨) વાદન, (૩) વસ્ત્રસજ્જા, (૪) રૂપપરિવર્તન, (૫) શૈય્યા સજાવટ, (૬) દ્યૂત ક્રીડા, (૭) સાસન રતિજ્ઞાન, (૮) મદ્ય બનાવટ અને એને સુવાસિત કરવાની કલા, (૯) શલ્ય ક્રિયા, (૧૦) પાક શાસ્ત્ર, (૧૧) બાગકામ, (૧૨) પાષાણ, ધાતુ આદિમાંથી ભસ્મ બનાવવાની કલા, (૧૩) મિઠાઈ બનાવટ, (૧૪) ધાત્વોષધિ બનાવટ, (૧૫) મિશ્ર ધાતુઓનું પૃથક્કરણ, (૧૬) ધાતુમિશ્રણ, (૧૭) નમક બનાવટ, (૧૮) શસ્ત્રસંચાલન, (૧૯) કુસ્તી (મલ્લયુદ્ધ), (૨૦) લક્ષ્યવેધ, (૨૧) વાદ્યસંકેત દ્વારા વ્યૂહરચના, (૨૨) ગજાદિ દ્વારા યુદ્ધકર્મ, (૨૩) વિવિધ મુદ્રાઓ દ્વારા દેવપૂજન, (૨૪) સારથીપણું, (૨૫) ગજાદિની ગતિશિક્ષા, (૨૬) વાસણ બનાવટ, (૨૭) ચિત્રકલા, (૨૮) તળાવ, મહેલ વગેરેના નિર્માણ માટે ભૂમિ તૈયાર કરવાની કલા, (૨૯) ઘંટાદિ દ્વારા વાદન, (૩૦) રંગસાજી, (૩૧) વરાળના પ્રયોગ-જલવાટવગ્નિ સંયોગનિરોધૈ: ક્રિયા, (૩૨) નૌકા, રથાદિ વાહનોનું જ્ઞાન, (૩૩) યજ્ઞ માટેની દોરી બટાવવાનું જ્ઞાન, (૩૪) કાપડ વણાટ, (૩૫) રત્નપરીક્ષણ, (૩૬) સ્વર્ણપરીક્ષણ, (૩૭) કૃત્રિમ ધાતુ બનાવવી, (૩૮) આભૂષણ ઘડવાની કલા, (૩૯) કલાઈ કરવાની કલા, (૪૦) ચર્મકાર્ય, (૪૧) ચામડું ઉતારવાની કલા, (૪૨) દૂધના વિભિન્ન પ્રયોગ, (૪૩) ચોલી વગેરે સીવવાની કલા, (૪૪) તરણ, (૪૫) વાસણ માંજવાની કલા, (૪૬) વસ્ત્રપ્રક્ષાલન (સંભવત: કપડાં ધોવાની તેમ જ ઇસ્ત્રી કરવાની કલા), (૪૭) ક્ષારકર્મ, (૪૮) તેલ બનાવટ, (૪૯) કૃષિકાર્ય, (૫૦) વૃક્ષારોહણ, (૫૧) સેવાકાર્ય, (૫૨) ટોપલી બનાવવાની કલા, (૫૩) કાચના વાસણ બનાવવા, (૫૪) ખેત સીંચાઇ, (૫૫) ધાતુના શસ્ત્ર બનાવવાની કલા, (૫૬) જીન, કાઠી અથવા હૌદા બનાવવાની કલા, (૫૭) શિશુપાલન, (૫૮) દંડકાર્ય, (૫૯) સુલેખન, (૬૦) તાંબૂલરક્ષણ, (૬૧) કલામર્મજ્ઞતા, (૬૨) નટકર્મ, (૬૩) કલાશિક્ષણ, ઔર (૬૪) સાધનાની ક્રિયા."},{"question":"Iza no anaran'ny zanakalahin’i Poseidon sy Amferita ?","answer":"I Tritona no anaran'ny zanakalahin’i Poseidon sy Amferita."},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana ity :    “Todim-paty aza manody, fa ............................”","answer":"   “Todim-paty aza manody, fa ny todim-pitia manodiava.”"},{"question":"ප්‍රස්ථාව පිරුළු ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න ","answer":"ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළු යනු තැනට ගැලපෙන ආකාරයට විවිධ අවස්ථාවන්හිදී විශාල අර්ථයක් ප්‍රකාශ කිරීම වෙනුවට කෙටි වැකියක් (ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළු) යොදාගැනීම සිංහල භාෂාවේ නිතර දක්නට ලැබේ. මෙය යම්විටෙක උපහාසාත්මක ප්‍රකාශ ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ද යොදා ගනී. බොහෝ අවස්ථා වලදී මෙම ප්‍රස්ථා පිරුළු බිහිවීම ගැන පසුබිම් කතන්දර/ජනකතා පවතී.ප්‍රස්තාව යනු අවස්ථාවටයි. වෙලාවටයි. සුදුසු මෙහොතටයි. ශ්‍රී සුමංගල ශබ්ද කෝෂයේ ප්‍රස්තාව යන්නට අවස්ථාව, වෙලාව අධිකාරිය, පටන් ගැන්ම 'විවාහය' යන අර්ථ ද දී තිබෙන අතර, පිරිවුඵ (පාරිවට්ට) යන්නට ඒ වෙලාවට පමණක් ප්‍රයෝජනය ගෙන පසුව හිමියාට භාරදෙනු පිණිස ඉල්ලාගත් දෙය (තාවකාලික දෙයක්) ලෙස පැහැදිලි කර තිබේ. මේ අනුව බලන විට සුදුසු අවස්ථාවට ප්‍රයෝජන ලබාගැනීම සදහා අනුන්ගෙන් ලබාගත් වැකි යන්න ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළු යන්න සුදුසුම ආසන්න අර්ථය බව දැක්වීම නිවැරදි වෙයි.කිසි වචනයක හෝ වාක්‍යයක අර්ථය වඩාත් කැපී පෙනෙන පරිදි උකහා දැක්වීම සඳහා සිංහල සම්ප්‍රධායේ යම් යම් යෙදුම් යොදා ගනී. මේවා යුගල පද, ඉඟි වැකි, ප්‍රස්ථාව පිරුළු වශයෙන් කොටස් කිහිපයකට බෙදා දැක්විය හැකිය. එදා සිංහලයා මෙන්ම අද සිංහලයාද මේ ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළු උපයෝගී කරගනිමින් තමන්ගේ අදහස වඩාත් කැපී පෙනෙන පරිදිත් වඩාත් අලංකාරවත් වන පරිදිත් අදහස් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට යොදා ගනී. මෙම ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළු ලිවීමේදී මෙන්ම ව්‍යවහාරයේදීත් එක සේ භාවිතා කළ හැකිය. ඉතා ඈත අතිතයේ සිට ම සිද්ධියක් හෝ අවස්ථාවක් අරබයා ගොඩ නැගී ඇති නියමයන් ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළු වශයෙන් ගැනේ. මේවා භාෂිත මෙන්ම ලේඛණ ව්‍යහාරයේ දී ත් යොදා ගැනෙන්නේ පවසන අදහස රසවත් හා අර්ථවත් කිරීමට ය. එම ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළු ද පහත සඳහන් පරිදි වර්ග කළ හැකිය."},{"question":"Indro misy toe-javatra :\\"Mitsambikina ny lanitra amin'ny haavo manjavozavo, ny Tendrombohitra Everest no tendrombohitra avo indrindra eto an-tany. Any amin'ny Himalayas, ity tendrombohitra mijoalajoala ity dia mahasarika mpihanika sahisahy manerana izao tontolo izao, voasariky ny fanamby goavana amin'ny fandresena ny tampon'izy io rakotra lanezy.\\" Raha ohatra ka \\"Tendrombohitra Everest\\" no valiny dia inona no fanontaniana mety napetraka?","answer":"Iza no tendrombohitra avo indrindra eran-tany?"},{"question":"ચાલો જાણીએ એલિટ સીઝન 2 ના પ્લોટ વિશે","answer":"એલિટની બીજી સીઝન મરીનાની હત્યા અને સેમ્યુઅલના ગુમ થવાના પરિણામ પર ધ્યાન કેન્દ્રિત કરે છે. જેમ જેમ વિદ્યાર્થીઓ તેમના વરિષ્ઠ વર્ષ માટે પાછા ફરે છે, ત્યારે તેઓ જે રહસ્યો ધરાવે છે અને મરિનાના મૃત્યુની અસરથી તેઓ ઝૂકી જાય છે. નવા વિદ્યાર્થીઓ રેબેકા, કેયેટાના અને વેલેરીયો તેમના પોતાના શ્યામ રહસ્યો મિશ્રણમાં લાવે છે, જ્યારે સેમ્યુઅલ તેના ભાઈ નેનોની નિર્દોષતા માટે લડવાનું ચાલુ રાખે છે. પોલો તેની ક્રિયાઓના અપરાધ સાથે સંઘર્ષ કરે છે, જ્યારે પોલોને ગુપ્ત રાખવાના વજન હેઠળ એન્ડરનું માનસિક સ્વાસ્થ્ય બગડે છે. કાર્લાનો અપરાધ તેણીને પોલોના ગુનાની કબૂલાત કરવા તરફ દોરી જાય છે, પરંતુ આખરે તેને છોડી દેવામાં આવે છે અને તે શાળામાં પાછો ફરે છે."},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?ශුද්ධ ","answer":"අශුද්ධ"},{"question":"Напиши продовження тексту: На чемпіонаті світу 2019 року кваліфікувалась до фіналу багатоборства ","answer":"та здобула особисту олімпійську ліцензію в багатоборстві на Олімпійські ігри 2020 у Токіо, Японія. У фіналі багатоборства з 54,366 бала посіла 15 місце."},{"question":"केमिकल इन्जिनियरहरूले वातावरण संरक्षणमा कसरी योगदान गर्छन्?","answer":"केमिकल इन्जिनियरहरूले वातावरणीय प्रभावलाई कम गर्ने प्रक्रियाहरू विकास गरेर पर्यावरण संरक्षणमा योगदान पुर्‍याउँछन्। तिनीहरू फोहोर घटाउने, दिगो ऊर्जा उत्पादन, र पर्यावरण-मैत्री उत्पादन अभ्यासहरूमा काम गर्छन्।"},{"question":"தமிழ் இலக்கியங்கள் காட்டும் சான்றாண்மைக் கருத்துக்களைத் தனிநாயக அடிகளாரின் வழி நிறுவுக.","answer":"உலக நாடுகளையும் மக்களையும் உட்படுத்தி பாராட்டுவது நம் இயல்புஅதனையே “யாதும் ஊரே யாவரும் கேளிர்” என்ற புறநானூறு வரிகளையும்,“யாதானும் நாடாமல் ஊராமால் என்னொருவன்சாந்துணையும் கல்லாத வாறு” – என்னும் குறட்பா வரிகளும் கூறுகின்றன.மக்கள் அனைவரும் உடன் பிறந்தவர்கள். பிறப்போ, சாதியோ, சமயமோ அவர்களை தாழ்த்தவோ, உயர்த்தவோ முடியாது.இத்தகைய அரிய கொள்கையைத் தமிழ் மக்கள் கடைப்பிடித்திருந்தனர் என்னும் உண்மை பெரும் வியப்பைத் தருகின்றது.திருக்குறள் பற்றி ஆல்பர்ட் சுவைட்சர் குறிப்பிடும் போது “இத்தகைய உயர்ந்த கொள்கைகளைக் கொண்ட செய்யுட்களை உலக இலக்கியத்திலேயே காண்பதரிது” என்பார் ஆல்பர்ட் சுவைட்சர்."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"adat memakai, syarak mengata\\"?","answer":"Adat yang tidak sesuai dengan hukum tuhan dan tidak selaras dengan keadaan masa tidaklah guna dipertahankan, kerana adat harus takluk kepada hukum syarak"},{"question":"ਵਿਸ਼ਾਃਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ: 35 ਸਾਲ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਇੱਥੋਂ ਦੇ ਲੋਕ ਦੇਖਣਗੇ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਹਾਲ 'ਚ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ।","answer":"ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੇ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਚੇਨ ਏਐਮਸੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਏ ਕਰਾਰ ਦੇ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ, ਅਗਲੇ ਪੰਜ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਤੱਕ ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ ਦੇ 15 ਸ਼ਹਿਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ 40 ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਹਾਲ ਖੇਲ੍ਹੇ ਜਾਣਗੇ।1970 ਵਿੱਚ ਬੰਦ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਸਨ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਹਾਲ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਨੋਰੰਜਨ ਦੀ ਇੰਡਸਟਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਵਾਪਸ ਲਿਆਉਣ ਲਈ ਪਿਛਲੇ 10 ਸਾਲਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਚਲ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਵਿਜ਼ਨ 2030 ਕ੍ਰਾਊਨ ਪ੍ਰਿੰਸ ਮੋਹੰਮਦ ਬਿਨ ਸਲਮਾਨ ਦੀ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਅਤੇ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੁਧਾਰ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਯੋਜਨਾ ਹੈ।ਰੂੜੀਵਾਦੀ ਮੁਸਲਿਮ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰ ਵਿੱਚ 1970 ਦੇ ਦਹਾਕੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਹਾਲ ਸਨ। ਪਰ ਕੱਟੜਪੰਥੀ ਮੁਸਲਿਮ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਆਗੂਆਂ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਬੰਦ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।ਕੁਝ ਦਿਨਾਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਜਨਵਰੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਮੁਫ਼ਤੀ ਸ਼ੇਖ ਅਬਦੁਲ ਅਜ਼ੀਜ਼ ਅਲ-ਸ਼ੇਖ ਨੇ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੀਆਂ ਬੁਰਾਈਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਚੇਤਾਵਨੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਜੇਕਰ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਮਿਲੀ ਤਾਂ ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਨੈਤਿਕਤਾ ਭ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟ ਹੋ ਜਾਵੇਗੀ।2030 ਤੱਕ 350 ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਹਾਲ ਦਾ ਟੀਚਾ।ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਾਹੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਸੰਗਠਨ ਸੁੰਨੀ ਇਸਲਾਮ ਦੇ ਕੱਟੜ ਰੂਪ ਵਹਾਬੀ ਵਿਚਾਰਧਾਰਾ ਨੂੰ ਮੰਨਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਇਸਲਾਮੀ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਅਤੇ ਪਹਿਰਾਵੇ ਨੂੰ ਸਖ਼ਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਲਾਗੂ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ।ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਬ ਦੇ ਲੋਕ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਅਤੇ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਪਸੰਦ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਘਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਫ਼ੋਨ ਤੇ ਟੀਵੀ ਜ਼ਰੀਏ ਨਿਜੀ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਦੇਖਣਾ ਪਸੰਦ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ।ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਆਪਰੇਟਰ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੰਨਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ 2030 ਤੱਕ ਲਗਭਗ 350 ਥੀਏਟਰਾਂ ਜ਼ਰੀਏ ਸਲਾਨਾ ਟਿਕਟਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਿਕਰੀ ਵਿੱਚ 1 ਅਰਬ ਡਾਲਰ ਤੱਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਧਾ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। ਕੀ ਹੈ ਵਿਜ਼ਨ 2030?ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਕਰੀਨਿੰਗ ਰਾਜਧਾਨੀ ਦੇ ਕਿੰਗ ਅਬਦੁੱਲਾ ਫਾਇਨਾਂਸ਼ੀਅਲ ਡਿਸਟ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ।ਇੱਕ ਸੂਤਰ ਨੇ ਰਾਇਟਰਸ ਨਿਊਜ਼ ਏਜੰਸੀ ਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਦਿਖਾਈ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਮਾਰਵਲ ਸਟੂਡੀਓ ਦੀ ਬਲਾਕਬਸਟਰ ਬਲੈਕ ਪੈਂਥਰ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ।ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਇਹ ਸਪੱਸ਼ਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦਿਖਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ।ਵਿਜ਼ਨ 2030 ਦਾ ਟੀਚਾ ਸਾਊਦੀ ਅਰਥਚਾਰੇ ਦੀ ਤੇਲ 'ਤੇ ਨਿਰਭਰਤਾ ਹਟਾਉਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਦਦ ਕਰਨਾ ਹੈ, ਨਵੀਆਂ ਨੌਕਰੀਆਂ ਦੇਣਾ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਦੀ ਥਾਂ ਪੈਸਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਘਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਖ਼ਰਚ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਵਜ੍ਹਾ ਦੇਣਾ ਹੈ।ਫ਼ਿਲਹਾਲ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਿਵੇਸ਼ ਲਿਆਉਣ ਦੀ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੱਗੇ 32 ਸਾਲਾ ਕ੍ਰਾਊਨ ਪ੍ਰਿੰਸ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਸਮਾਗਮ ਦੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਸੀ।ਮਕਸਦ ਤੇਲ 'ਤੇ ਨਿਰਭਰ ਮੁਲਕ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰਕ ਅਤੇ ਮੋਨਰੰਜਨ ਗਤੀਵਿਧੀਆਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਘਰੇਲੂ ਖ਼ਰਚ ਨੂੰ 2.9% ਤੋਂ ਵਧਾ ਕੇ 2030 ਤੱਕ 6%  ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"คอมพิวเตอร์สามารถใช้ทำอะไรได้บ้าง","answer":"สามารถใช้ทำงานได้หลากหลาย เช่น- ทำงานเอกสารออนไลน์- ดูหนัง- เขียนโปรแกรม- เล่นเกม"},{"question":"السؤال: متى بدأت الحرب العالمية الأولى؟","answer":"الإجابة: 1914م"},{"question":"मैं उत्तम उबला अंडा कैसे बनाऊं?","answer":"यहां उबला अंडा बनाने के चरण दिए गए हैं:1. एक सॉस पैन में इतना पानी भरें कि उसमें अंडे बिना डूबे रखे जा सकें।2. पानी में एक चुटकी नमक मिला लें.3. तेज आंच पर पानी को उबलने दें।4. जब पानी उबलने लगे तो आंच को मध्यम कर दें।5. करछुल की मदद से अंडे को धीरे से पानी में डालें.6. अंडों को 11 मिनट तक पानी में उबलने दें.7. आंच बंद कर दें, अंडे हटा दें और उन्हें बर्फ के स्नान में रखें।8. एक बार अंडे ठंडे हो जाएं, तो उन्हें छीलकर परोसा जा सकता है।यह विधि किसी भी संख्या में अंडों के लिए काम करती है, कृपया अपने लिए सही सॉस पैन और पानी चुनें।"},{"question":"สรุปหัวข้อหลักของย่อหน้านี้: ปรัชญา (อังกฤษ: Philosophy จาก กรีก: φιλοσοφία, philosophia, 'ความรักในปัญญา') เป็นการศึกษาปัญหาทั่วไปและปัญหาพื้นฐาน เช่น เกี่ยวกับการดำรงอยู่ (อภิปรัชญา) เหตุผล (ตรรกศาสตร์), ความรู้ (ญาณวิทยา) คุณค่า (จริยศาสตร์) จิตใจ และ ภาษา แหล่งข้อมูลบางแหล่งอ้างว่าแนวคิดนี้คิดขึ้นโดยพีทากอรัส (c. 570 – c. 495 ปีก่อนค.ศ.) ในขณะที่บางส่วน ปฏิเสธและเชื่อว่าพีทากอรัสนำคำนี้มาใช้จากคำเดิมที่ปรากฏอยู่แล้ว วิธีวิทยาของปรัชญาประกอบด้วยการตั้งคำถาม การถกเถียงเชิงวิพากษ์ การถกเถียงด้วยเหตุผล และการนำเสนออย่างเป็นระบบระเบียบ","answer":"ข้อความนี้มีใจความหลักเกี่ยวกับความหมายของปรัชญา"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Tàu sân bay Vikrant của Ấn độ (ảnh: BI) Sau hơn một thập kỷ hoàn thiện, hôm 28.7, hải quân Ấn Độ đã nhận được tàu sân bay Vikrant. Đây là tàu sân bay đầu tiên do Ấn Độ tự đóng. Vikrant dài 262 mét, lượng choán nước 45.000 tấn. Tàu có 14 boong, 2.300 khoang và có thể chở thủy thủ đoàn 1.700 người. Tốc độ tối đa của Vikrant là 28 hải lý/giờ. Dẫn tuyên bố của hải quân Ấn Độ,tờ Hoàn cầu của Trung Quốc cho biết tàu Vikrant của Ấn Độ trị giá 3,13 tỷ USD. Với Vikrant, Ấn Độ chính thức gia nhập nhóm các nước có thể tự đóng tàu sân bay, bao gồm Mỹ, Anh, Nga, Pháp và Trung Quốc. Theo Hoàn cầu, việc đóng tàu sân bay Vikrant cho thấy tham vọng trở thành cường quốc hàng hải của Ấn Độ. Tuy nhiên, về công nghệ đóng tàu, nước này vẫn còn \\"thua xa\\" Trung Quốc. Việc thiết kế và hoàn thiện tàu sân bay Vikrant của Ấn Độ kéo dài từ năm 1999 đến 2022. Trong khoảng thời gian này, Trung Quốc đã hạ thủy 3 tàu sân bay. Trong đó, tàu sân bay Phúc Kiến được Trung Quốc ra mắt hồi tháng 6 được trang bị công nghệ phóng máy bay bằng hệ thống phóng điện từ, hiện đại ngang ngửa tàu sân bay Mỹ. Song Zhongping – chuyên gia quân sự Trung Quốc – cho rằng, tàu sân bay Vikrant của Ấn Độ thậm chí còn không hiện đại bằng tàu sân bay Liêu Ninh do Trung Quốc hạ","answer":"thủy vào năm 2012. \\"Liêu Ninh là tàu sân bay cỡ lớn trong khi tàu Vikrant chỉ là cỡ trung bình. Xét về khả năng hoạt động, Liêu Ninh cũng mạnh mẽ hơn Vikrant\\", ông Song nói. Tàu sân bay Phúc Kiến do Trung Quốc đóng (ảnh: Hoàn cầu) \\"Nền công nghiệp quân sự của Ấn Độ tương đối yếu. Phát triển tàu sân bay nội địa là thách thức đối với họ. Trung Quốc có thể tự hoàn thiện toàn bộ quá trình thiết kế tàu sân bay, trong khi Ấn Độ chỉ có thể làm một phần\\", ông Song nói. \\"Ấn Độ luôn cho rằng Ấn Độ Dương là đại dương của Ấn Độ và cần phát triển hải quân với tàu sân bay là trung tâm. Tuy nhiên, ngành công nghiệp của họ chưa mạnh mẽ cho lắm, vì vậy, Ấn Độ mất nhiều thời gian để đóng một tàu sân bay\\", ông Song nói thêm. Dẫn lời Zhang Zhaozhong, chuyên gia quân sự nghiên cứu tàu sân bay tại Đại học Quốc phòng Trung Quốc, Hoàn cầu cho rằng, quá trình phát triển tàu sân bay của Ấn Độ tồn tại nhiều \\"bất ổn và khúc quanh\\". Điều này dẫn đến ảnh hưởng về tư duy thiết kế, thiếu tính liên tục trong cả quá trình sản xuất tàu sân bay. Nguồn: https://www.nguoiduatin.vn/chuyen-gia-tq-34-che-34-tau-san-bay-tu-ong-au-tien-cua-an-o-a562361.h...Nguồn: https://www.nguoiduatin.vn/chuyen-gia-tq-34-che-34-tau-san-bay-tu-ong-au-tien-cua-an-o-a562361.html"},{"question":"« Raha misy mpianatra tendren-dRamose hiambina ny namany na hanatitra kahie hotsaraina any an-tranony, na hanoratra eo amin’ny hazomainty rahefa sora-tononina, tsy mba maka aminay ireo mihitsy izy. »Inona no fihetseham-po fonoson’io fanambarana eo ambony io ?","answer":"Io fanambarana io dia maneho fihetseham-po miiba satria  misy fanambaniana sy fanvakavahana ataon’ny mpampianatra."},{"question":"ما هي أقدم جامعة في النمسا ؟أجب على السؤال أعلاه.","answer":"جامعة في فيينا."},{"question":"‘విద్యావంతుడైన ఒక యువకుడు ఉద్యోగాల కోసం పాకులాడకుండా, స్వంతంగా వ్యవసాయం చేస్తూ, చక్కగా పంటలు పండిస్తూ, ఎంతోమందికి ఆదర్శంగా నిలిచాడు. ప్రభుత్వంచే ఆవార్డులను కూడా పొందాడు.’ అటువంటి యువకుణ్ణి పొగుడుతూ అభినందన వ్యాసం రాయండి.","answer":"ఆధునిక సమాజంలో శాస్త్రసాంకేతిక రంగ ప్రభావం తీవ్రంగా ఉంది. విజ్ఞానశాస్త్ర ప్రభావంతో మానవుడు సమున్నత స్థాయికి చేరుకుంటున్నాడు. సాధారణం గా ఎంతోమంది ప్రభుత్వ ఉద్యోగాలు కోసం వెంపర్లాడుతారు. స్వయం ఉపాధి మార్గాలకై అన్వేషింపరు.కాని ఈ యువకుడు విద్యావంతుడై కూడా ప్రభుత్వ ఉద్యోగాలకోసం పాకులాడలేదు. స్వయంశక్తితో ఎదగాలనుకున్నాడు. తాను బ్రతుకుతూ మరికొందరికి ఉపాధిని కల్పించాలను కున్నాడు.వ్యవసాయంలో ప్రవేశించాడు. వ్యవసాయంలో ఆధునిక సాంకేతిక విజ్ఞానాన్ని వినియోగించాడు. అధిక దిగుబడులను పొందాడు. అందరికి ఆదర్శంగా నిలిచాడు. ప్రభుత్వ ప్రోత్సాహకాలను పొందాడు. అందువల్ల అతడు నిజంగా అభినంద నీయుడు. అందరికి మార్గదర్శకంగా నిలిచాడు. నేటియువతరమంతా నిరుత్సాహ పడకుండా స్వయంఉపాధి మార్గాలను అన్వేషించాలి."},{"question":"Kọ́ntínẹ́ẹ̀tì wo ni Peru wà?","answer":"Apá Gúúsù Amẹ́ríkà"},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina diso amin'ity fehezanteny ity:\\"Mamolavola ny isa-batan’olona ho olo-banona sy vonna ny literatiora.\\"","answer":"Indro ny fehezanteny voahitsy tsipelina:\\"Mamolavola ny isam-batan’olona ho olom-banona sy vonona ny literatiora.\\""},{"question":"ਆਪਣੇ ਨਿਵਾਸ ਸਥਾਨ ਦੇ ਆਲੇ-ਦੁਆਲੇ ਦੇ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਲ ਸੰਹਿਣ ਦੀ ਪਰੰਪਰਾਗਤ ਪੱਧਤੀ ਦਾ ਪਤਾ ਕਰੋ ।","answer":"ਸਾਡੇ ਨਿਵਾਸ ਖੇਤਰ ਦੇ ਆਸ-ਪਾਸ ਵਰਖਾ ਦੇ ਪਾਣੀ ਨੂੰ ਤਲਾਬਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਛੱਪੜਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਰਿਵਾਜ ਸੀ । ਭੂਮੀਗਤ ਟੈਂਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਜਲ ਸੰਹਿਣ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਚਲਨ ਸੀ ।"},{"question":"په طبیعي ډول د یو ډول دننه بدلونونه په عمده توګه د تغیراتو پایله ده او انتخابونه: (A) د جنسي زیږون. (B) متحرک توازن. (C) میتابولیزم. (D) د پټوالي. ځواب دا دی:","answer":"(A) د جنسي زیږون."},{"question":"දිට්ඨිය ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"දිට්ඨිය යන වචනය සම්‍යග්දෘෂ්ටි මිථ්‍යාදෘෂ්ටි දෙකට ම සාධාරණ වුව ද මේ අකුශල චෛතසික කථාවෙහි එයින් අදහස් කරනුයේ මිථ්‍යාදෘෂ්ටිය ය. නොයෙක් හේතු යුක්තිවලට අනුව කාරණය සත්‍ය වශයෙන් ප්‍ර‍ඥාවෙන් හෙවත් සම්‍යග්දෘෂ්ටියෙන් දක්නාක් මෙන් වරදවා ගන්නා ලද දක්නා ලද හේතු යුක්තිවලට අනුව කාරණය වරදවා ගන්නා වූ වරදවා දක්නා වූ ස්වභාවය දෘෂ්ටිය ය. එය දෘෂ්ටි ගතිකයනට පෙනෙන්නේ ප්‍ර‍ඥාව හෙවත් සම්‍යග්දෘෂ්ටිය ලෙසට ය. එබැවින් ඔවුහු සම්‍යග්දෘෂ්ටිය මිථ්‍යාදෘෂ්ටියක් වශයෙන් ගනිති. වරදවා දැකීම් වශයෙන් දෘෂ්ටිය සාමාන්‍යයෙන් එකක් වුව ද ගන්නා වූ ආකාරයන්ගේ වශයෙන් අනේක ප්‍රභේද වේ. ශාශ්වත දෘෂ්ටිය ය, උච්ඡේද දෘෂ්ටියය යන දෙක ප්‍ර‍ධාන දෘෂ්ටි දෙක ය. තවත් ඇත්තා වූ බොහෝ දෘෂ්ටීහු ඒ දෙකින් ලියලා යන දෘෂ්ටීහු ය. දෘෂ්ටීන් බොහෝවක් ශාශ්වත දෘෂ්ටියෙන් ම ලියලූ ඒවා ය. නාස්තික දෘෂ්ටිය, අහේතුක දෘෂ්ටිය, අක්‍රිය දෘෂ්ටිය යි කර්ම පථ බවට පැමිණෙන දෘෂ්ටි තුනෙකි. දන් දීමෙන් පලක් නැත යනාදීන් පවත්නා වූ නාස්තික දෘෂ්ටියේ ම ප්‍රභේද වූ දෘෂ්ටි දශයෙකි. එයට දශවස්තුක මිථ්‍යාදෘෂ්ටිය යි කියනු ලැබේ. සත්කායදෘෂ්ටි විස්සෙකි. බ්‍ර‍හ්මජාලයෙහි දැක්වෙන දෘෂ්ටි දෙසැටකි."},{"question":"வினா: இந்திய தேசிய காங்கிரஸ் எந்த வட்டமேசை மாநாட்டில் பங்கேற்றது?","answer":"விடை: 1931 இல் இரண்டாவது வட்ட மேசை மாநாடு"},{"question":"Dammi un esempio di curiosità in questa categoria: \\"Musica\\"","answer":"Quanto è alta la cantante di Big Girls don't Cry? 5'4\\""},{"question":"Mitä tarkoittaa kelirikko?","answer":"Kelirikko voidaan jakaa kahteen tyyppiin, pinta- ja runkokelirikkoon. Keväällä sorateitä koettelee ensin pintakelirikko, kun lämpö sulattaa pien pintakerroksen, mutta kosteus ei pääse valumaan jäätyneen tierakenteen läpi. Tällöin tien pintakerros voi pehmentyä pahastikin. Pintakelirikkoa voi esiintyä myös kesällä ja syksyllä, jos ilmat ovat pitkään sateisia.Runkokelirikko alkaa lämmön edelleen sulattaessa tierakennetta. Tien runko ja siinä oleva vesi alkaa sulaa. Rakenteen sulaminen voi aiheuttaa suuriakin muodonmuutoksia tiessä. Tässä vaiheessa tierakenteen kantavuuskin on heikoimmillaan ja joissakin tapauksissa voidaan joutua rajoittamaan liikennettä asettamalla tielle painorajoitus."},{"question":"ఈ క్రింది పద్యమును చదివి, క్రింద ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నలకు సమాధానములు వ్రాయండి.నీళ్ళలోని చేప నెరిమాంసమాశకుగాలమందు చిక్కి కూలినట్లుఆశపుట్టి మనుజుడారీతి చెడిపోవువిశ్వదాభిరామ ! వినురవేమ !ప్రశ్నలు:1. చేప దేనికి ఆశపడును ?2. దేనికి చిక్కును ?3. చేప ఏమగును ?4. చేపతో పోల్చబడినది ఎవరు ?5. ఈ పద్యంలోని మకుటం ఏది ?","answer":"ప్రశ్నలు – జవాబులు :1. చేప దేనికి ఆశపడును ?జవాబు:చేప మాంసమునకు ఆశపడును.2. దేనికి చిక్కును ?జవాబు:గాలానికి చేప చిక్కును.3. చేప ఏమగును ?జవాబు:చేప మరణించును.4. చేపతో పోల్చబడినది ఎవరు ?జవాబు:ఆశగల మానవుడు చేపతో పోల్చబడినాడు.5. ఈ పద్యంలోని మకుటం ఏది ?జవాబు:ఈ పద్యంలోని మకుటం విశ్వదాభిరామ! వినుర వేమ!"},{"question":"క్రింది మూలకాలలో అర్ధ లోహము ఏది?A) సిలికాన్B) సోడియమ్C) క్లోరిన్D) అల్యూమినియమ్","answer":"A) సిలికాన్"},{"question":"اللغز: أحد أنواع الطيور التي تلد ولا تبيض؟","answer":"الجواب: الخفاش."},{"question":"Awọn Fulani ni kijọba mu Sunday Igboho, ki wọn si da Seriki pada s’Igangan","answer":"Latari lile ti wọn le Seriki Fulani, Alaaji Salihu AbdulKadir, kuro nilu Igangan, nijọba ibilẹ Ariwa Ibarapa, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, ti wọn si tun dana sun awọn dukia rẹ kan, ẹgbẹ awọn Fulani ilẹ Naijiria kan ti ke sijọba pe ayafi ti wọn ba fi pampẹ ofin mu Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho, ti wọn si da Seriki Fulani ti wọn le naa pada siluu Igangan ni alaafia too le wa.Ẹgbẹ awọn Fulani naa to fikalẹ siluu Abuja (Gan Allah Fulani Development Association of Nigeria) GADFAN, sọ ọrọ yii nigba ti wọn ṣabẹwo ibanikẹdun si Alaaji Salihu niluu Ilọrin, nipinlẹ Kwara.Ẹgbẹ naa ni bi ijọba ko ṣe ti i fi pampẹ ọba mu Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ, tawọn eeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho, ki wọn si ba a ṣẹjọ, ko tẹ awọn lọrun rara.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Alaga apapọ ẹgbẹ wọn, Alaaji Sulaiman Yakubu ati akọwe rẹ, Ibrahim Abdullahi, buwọ lu lorukọ ẹgbẹ ọhun lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, wọn ni ko yẹ ki Sunday Igboho ṣi wa lominira, ko maa yan fanda kiri ilu, tori awọn gbagbọ pe oun gan-an lo ṣagbatẹru akọlu ti wọn ṣe si Alaaji Salihu niluu Igangan lọjọsi.Ẹgbẹ naa tun parọwa sijọba pe ki wọn fi pampẹ ofin gbe gbogbo awọn alatilẹyin Sunday Igboho, ati awọn ti wọn ba lọwọ ninu bi wọn ṣe dana sun awọn dukia Seriki Fulani ti wọn le jade niluu ọhun.Lara ohun ti wọn tun beere pawọn fẹ kijọba ṣe ni pe ki wọn ṣeto bi Alaaji Salihu AbdulKadir yoo ṣe pada siluu Igangan, ki wọn pese aabo to peye fun un, ki wọn si san owo ‘gba ma binu’ fun un latari awọn dukia olowo iyebiye rẹ to padanu sinu iṣẹlẹ ọhun.Atẹjade naa ka lapa kan pe: “Ẹgbẹ GADFAN n fi asiko yii ke sijọba apapọ ati ti ipinlẹ Ọyọ lati ri i pe wọn ṣe idajọ ododo fun Alaaji Saliju AbdulKadir ati awọn eeyan rẹ, ki i ṣe pe kijọba mu Sunday Igboho atawọn bọisi ẹ nikan ni, ṣugbọn ki wọn ba wọn ṣẹjọ, ki wọn si fiya jẹ wọn, lẹyin naa, ki wọn ri i pe wọn san owo to yẹ fun Seriki Fulani ati awọn eeyan rẹ, ki wọn si da wọn pada si ibi ti wọn ti n gbe tẹlẹ naa.A ti kiyesi i pe akọlu ti wọn ṣe si Seriki Fulani nilu Igangan mu ko padanu ọpọlọpọ maaluu, ewurẹ, aguntan, ẹyẹ awo, ileewe aladaani rẹ kan, awọn ileetaja ati mọṣalaaṣi, aropọ eyi ti owo rẹ ju miliọnu lọna ẹẹdẹgbẹta naira (#500m) lọ.Nipari atẹjade naa, wọn sọ pe awọn ti n ba awọn agbẹjọro awọn sọrọ, awọn si ti ṣetan lati gbe igbesẹ ofin tijọba ko ba tete dahun si awọn nnkan tawọn fẹ wọnyi."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina amin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\" Nifandibiasana ny olona nanaovana ny asa. Ny olona avy niasana voalohany dia tsy iverenan intson raha tsy tapitsa niasana avokoa ny olona rehetra. ( atero ko alao)\\"","answer":"Ity ny fanambarana miaraka amin'ireo hadisoana voahitsy:\\" Nifandimbiasana ny olona nanaovana ny asa. Ny olona avy niasana voalohany dia tsy iverenana intsony raha tsy tapitra niasana avokoa ny olona rehetra. ( atero ko alao)\\""},{"question":"பாரதியாரின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"நெஞ்சு பொறுக்குதில்லையே- இந்த நிலை கெட்ட மனிதரை நினைந்து விட்டால்,அஞ்சி அஞ்சி சாவார் - இவர்அஞ்சாத பொருளி ல் லை  அவனியிலே ;"},{"question":"右手にたいまつを挙げていることで有名な元々はフランスからの贈り物というニューヨークの象徴とも言える像の名は？","answer":"自由の女神です。"},{"question":"විශාලතම ක්ෂීරපායී සත්වයා කුමක්ද?","answer":"නිල් තල්මසා"},{"question":"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ॥ ਬਿਨੁ ਪਿਰ ਧਨ ਸੀਗਾਰੀਐ ਜੋਬਨੁ ਬਾਦਿ ਖੁਆਰੁ ॥ ਨਾ ਮਾਣੇ ਸੁਖਿ ਸੇਜੜੀ ਬਿਨੁ ਪਿਰ ਬਾਦਿ ਸੀਗਾਰੁ ॥ ਦੂਖੁ ਘਣੋ ਦੋਹਾਗਣੀ ਨਾ ਘਰਿ ਸੇਜ ਭਤਾਰੁ ॥੧॥ ਮਨ ਰੇ ਰਾਮ ਜਪਹੁ ਸੁਖੁ ਹੋਇ ॥ ਬਿਨੁ ਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰੇਮੁ ਨ ਪਾਈਐ ਸਬਦਿ ਮਿਲੈ ਰੰਗੁ ਹੋਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ ਗੁਰ ਸੇਵਾ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਈਐ ਹਰਿ ਵਰੁ ਸਹਜਿ ਸੀਗਾਰੁ ॥ ਸਚਿ ਮਾਣੇ ਪਿਰ ਸੇਜੜੀ ਗੂੜਾ ਹੇਤੁ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਜਾਣਿ ਸਿਞਾਣੀਐ ਗੁਰਿ ਮੇਲੀ ਗੁਣ ਚਾਰੁ ॥੨॥ ਸਚਿ ਮਿਲਹੁ ਵਰ ਕਾਮਣੀ ਪਿਰਿ ਮੋਹੀ ਰੰਗੁ ਲਾਇ ॥ ਮਨੁ ਤਨੁ ਸਾਚਿ ਵਿਗਸਿਆ ਕੀਮਤਿ ਕਹਣੁ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ ਹਰਿ ਵਰੁ ਘਰਿ ਸੋਹਾਗਣੀ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਸਾਚੈ ਨਾਇ ॥੩॥ ਮਨ ਮਹਿ ਮਨੂਆ ਜੇ ਮਰੈ ਤਾ ਪਿਰੁ ਰਾਵੈ ਨਾਰਿ ॥ ਇਕਤੁ ਤਾਗੈ ਰਲਿ ਮਿਲੈ ਗਲਿ ਮੋਤੀਅਨ ਕਾ ਹਾਰੁ ॥ ਸੰਤ ਸਭਾ ਸੁਖੁ ਊਪਜੈ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਨਾਮ ਅਧਾਰੁ ॥੪॥ ਖਿਨ ਮਹਿ ਉਪਜੈ ਖਿਨਿ ਖਪੈ ਖਿਨੁ ਆਵੈ ਖਿਨੁ ਜਾਇ ॥ ਸਬਦੁ ਪਛਾਣੈ ਰਵਿ ਰਹੈ ਨਾ ਤਿਸੁ ਕਾਲੁ ਸੰਤਾਇ ॥ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਅਤੁਲੁ ਨ ਤੋਲੀਐ ਕਥਨਿ ਨ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾਇ ॥੫॥ ਵਾਪਾਰੀ ਵਣਜਾਰਿਆ ਆਏ ਵਜਹੁ ਲਿਖਾਇ ॥ ਕਾਰ ਕਮਾਵਹਿ ਸਚ ਕੀ ਲਾਹਾ ਮਿਲੈ ਰਜਾਇ ॥ ਪੂੰਜੀ ਸਾਚੀ ਗੁਰੁ ਮਿਲੈ ਨਾ ਤਿਸੁ ਤਿਲੁ ਨ ਤਮਾਇ ॥੬॥ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਤੋਲਿ ਤੋੁਲਾਇਸੀ ਸਚੁ ਤਰਾਜੀ ਤੋਲੁ ॥ ਆਸਾ ਮਨਸਾ ਮੋਹਣੀ ਗੁਰਿ ਠਾਕੀ ਸਚੁ ਬੋਲੁ ॥ ਆਪਿ ਤੁਲਾਏ ਤੋਲਸੀ ਪੂਰੇ ਪੂਰਾ ਤੋਲੁ ॥੭॥ ਕਥਨੈ ਕਹਣਿ ਨ ਛੁਟੀਐ ਨਾ ਪੜਿ ਪੁਸਤਕ ਭਾਰ ॥ ਕਾਇਆ ਸੋਚ ਨ ਪਾਈਐ ਬਿਨੁ ਹਰਿ ਭਗਤਿ ਪਿਆਰ ॥ ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਵੀਸਰੈ ਮੇਲੇ ਗੁਰੁ ਕਰਤਾਰ ॥੮॥੯॥","answer":"ਹੇ ਮਨ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ, (ਤੈਨੂੰ) ਸੁਖ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ। (ਪਰ ਮਨ ਭੀ ਕੀਹ ਕਰੇ? ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਨਾਹ ਹੋਵੇ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਮੁੜ ਮੁੜ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਯਾਦ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਏ? ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਇਹ) ਪਿਆਰ ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣ ਸਕਦਾ। ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਰੰਗ ਚੜ੍ਹ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।1। ਰਹਾਉ।(ਜੇ ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਗਹਿਣਿਆਂ ਆਦਿਕ ਨਾਲ) ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਸਜਾ ਲਏ, ਪਰ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਤੀ ਨਾਹ ਮਿਲੇ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਜੁਆਨੀ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਆਤਮਾ ਭੀ ਦੁਖੀ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਹ ਆਨੰਦ ਨਾਲ ਪਤੀ ਦੀ ਸੋਹਣੀ ਸੇਜ ਮਾਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ, ਪਤੀ-ਮਿਲਾਪ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਸਿੰਗਾਰ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਭਾਗਹੀਣ ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਦੁਖ ਵਿਆਪਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਵਿਚ ਸੇਜ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਖਸਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦਾ (ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਬਾਹਰ-ਮੁਖੀ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਉੱਦਮ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ-ਸੇਜ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਗਟ ਨਾਹ ਹੋਵੇ) ।1।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਉਸੇ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਅਡੋਲ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ (ਜੁੜ ਕੇ) ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਸਿੰਗਾਰਿਆ ਹੈ। ਉਹੀ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਦੀ ਸੋਹਣੀ ਸੇਜ ਮਾਣ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਉਸ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ (ਜੁੜੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ) , ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਗੂੜ੍ਹਾ ਹਿਤ ਹੈ ਗੂੜ੍ਹਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਮਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾ ਕੇ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਸਿੰਞਾਣਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਇਹ ਸਿੰਞਾਣ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਸਾਡਾ ਹੈ) , ਉਹ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਜਿਸ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਾਇਆ ਹੈ) ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਮਿਲਾਇਆ ਹੈ।2।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਦੀ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ! ਉਸ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ) ਵਿਚ (ਸਦਾ) ਮਿਲੀ ਰਹੁ। ਪਤੀ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ (ਜਿਸ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਦਾ) ਰੰਗ ਚਾੜ੍ਹ ਕੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਵਲ ਖਿੱਚ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਸਦਾ ਮਨ ਉਸਦਾ ਤਨ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਖਿੜ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ (ਉਸਦਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਇਤਨਾ ਅਮੋਲਕ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈ ਸਕਦਾ। ਉਹ ਸੁਹਾਗ ਭਾਗ ਵਾਲੀ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ (ਜੁੜ ਕੇ) ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਆਤਮਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ (ਹਿਰਦੇ) ਘਰ ਵਿਚ (ਹੀ ਲੱਭ ਲੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ) ।3।ਜੇ (ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਦਾ) ਥੋੜ੍ਹ-ਵਿਤਾ ਮਨ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਵਿਸ਼ਾਲ) ਮਨ ਵਿਚ (ਥੋੜ੍ਹ-ਵਿਤੇ ਸੁਭਾਅ ਵਲੋਂ) ਮਰ ਜਾਏ, ਤੇ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਇਕੋ ਧਾਗੇ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰੋਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਮੋਤੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਹਾਰ ਗਲ ਵਿਚ ਪਾ ਲਈਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਜੇ (ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਹੀ) ਇਕੋ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਧਾਗੇ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਮਿਕ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਹੋ ਜਾਏ ਤਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪਤੀ ਉਸ ਜੀਵ-ਨਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਪਰ ਇਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਸਤਸੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਸਤਸੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ (ਮਨ ਨੂੰ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸਹਾਰਾ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ।4।(ਜੇ ਮਨ ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਵਾਂਜਿਆ ਰਹੇ, ਤਾਂ ਮਾਇਆ ਆਦਿਕ ਦੇ ਲਾਭ ਨਾਲ) ਇਕ ਖਿਨ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ (ਇਉਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਵੇਂ) ਜਿਊ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਤੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਆਦਿਕ ਦੀ ਘਾਟ ਨਾਲ) ਇਕ ਖਿਨ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਦੁਖੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਕ ਖਿਨ (ਗੁਜ਼ਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ) ਉਹ ਜੰਮ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਕ ਖਿਨ (ਗੁਜ਼ਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ) ਉਹ ਮਰ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਨਾਮ ਦੇ ਸਹਾਰੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮਾਇਆ ਜੀਵ ਦੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਜੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਆਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਉਤਸ਼ਾਹ, ਜੇ ਜਾਏ ਤਾਂ ਸਹਮ) । ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਜੁੜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਮੌਤ (ਦਾ ਡਰ) ਸਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ। (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਿਆਂ ਇਹ ਤਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਕਿ) ਉਸ ਮਾਲਕ (ਦੀ ਹਸਤੀ) ਨੂੰ ਤੋਲਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕੇ, ਉਹ ਤੋਲ ਤੋਂ ਪਰੇ ਹੈ (ਹਾਂ, ਇਹ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਹੈ) ਨਿਰੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ।5।ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵ-ਵਣਜਾਰੇ ਜੀਵ ਵਪਾਰੀ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੋਂ) ਰੋਜ਼ੀਨਾ ਲਿਖਾ ਕੇ (ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਆਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਭਾਵ, ਹਰੇਕ ਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੇ ਸੁਆਸ ਤੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ) । ਜੇਹੜੇ ਜੀਵ ਵਪਾਰੀ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਕਾਰ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ (ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦਾ) ਲਾਭ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਪਰ ਇਹ ਲਾਭ ਉਹੀ ਖੱਟ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਉਹ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਆਦਿਕ ਦਾ) ਤਿਲ ਜਿਤਨਾ ਭੀ ਲਾਲਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ। (ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲੀ) ਰਾਸ-ਪੂੰਜੀ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਥਿਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ।6।(ਇਨਸਾਨੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੀ ਸਫਲਤਾ ਦੀ ਪਰਖ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਸੱਚ ਹੀ ਤਰਾਜ਼ੂ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਸੱਚ ਹੀ ਵੱਟਾ ਹੈ (ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਪੱਲੇ ਸੱਚ ਹੈ ਉਹੀ ਸਫਲ ਹੈ) , ਇਸ ਪਰਖ-ਤੋਲ ਵਿਚ ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪੂਰਾ ਉਤਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁੱਖ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਿਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ) ਸੱਚੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਕੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਮੋਹ ਲੈਣ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਆਸਾਂ ਤੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਮਾਇਕ ਫੁਰਨਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ (ਮਨ ਉਤੇ ਵਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ) ਰੋਕ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਪੂਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਤੋਲ (ਦਾ ਮਿਆਰ) ਕਦੇ ਘਟਦਾ ਵਧਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ, ਉਹੀ ਜੀਵ (ਇਸ ਤੋਲ ਵਿਚ) ਪੂਰਾ ਤੁਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਦੇ ਕੇ) ਆਪ (ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਾਹ ਨਾਲ) ਤੁਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।7।ਨਿਰੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਕਰਨ ਨਾਲ ਜਾਂ ਪੁਸਤਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਢੇਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਢੇਰ ਪੜ੍ਹਨ ਨਾਲ ਆਸਾ ਮਨਸਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕੀਦਾ। (ਜੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਨਹੀਂ, ਤਾਂ ਨਿਰੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਦੀ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ) ਨਾਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਭੁੱਲਦਾ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਮੇਲ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ।8।9।"},{"question":"Туура аналогияны таңда.Эт : куурулган(А) тартылган : сүрөт(Б) күйгүзүлгөн : көмүр (В) курулган : үй(Г) балык : ыштылган","answer":"1)Эталондук(үлгү) жуп: эт : куурулган;2)Үлгү жуптагы байланыштын түрү : Зат жана анын сыпаты байланышы;3)Зат жана анын сыпаты байланышындагы аналогиянын түрү: Зат жана анын сын атоочтук сыпаты;Эт куурулган же чийки абалда болот. Сүрөт тартылган же тартылбаган абалда болбойт, качан гана тартып бүтсөк анан сүрөт болот. Көмүрдүн күйгүзүлгөндөн кийин күлгө айланат. Курулган : үй (А) варианты сыяктуу процесс бүткөндөн кийин пайда болуучу зат,башка сөз менен айтканда, үйдү пландап, куруп бүткөндөн кийин үй болот. (Г) вариантындабалык ышталган же чийки абалды болушу мүмкүн. Туура жооп – (Г)."},{"question":"ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਕੈਦੀ, ਦਿਲ ਤੋ ਪਾਗਲ ਹੈ, ਫ਼ਿਜ਼ਾ, ਜ਼ੁਬੈਦਾ, ਬੀਵੀ ਨੰਬਰ ਵਨ, ਸਪਨੇ ਸਾਜਨ ਕੇ, ਅੰਦਾਜ਼, ਸਪੂਤ, ਜੁੜਵਾ’ ਸਮੇਤ ਕਈ ਹਿੱਟ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਫ਼ਿਲਮੀ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਅਲਵਿਦਾ ਕਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੀ 37 ਸਾਲਾ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਮਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਨੌਂ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਦੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਵਕਫ਼ੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਫਿਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮੀ ਪਰਦੇ ‘ਤੇ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਮਾ ਨੇ 2003 ‘ਚ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੇ ਸਨਅਤਕਾਰ ਸੰਜੇ ਕਪੂਰ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਾਉਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਫ਼ਿਲਮੀ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਅਲਵਿਦਾ ਕਹਿ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਸੀ। ਹੁਣ ਉਹ ਵਿਕਰਮ ਭੱਟ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਤ ਰੁਮਾਂਚਿਕ 3-ਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਡੇਂਜਰਸ ਇਸ਼ਕ’ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਅਲੱਗ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਮੰਨਦੀ। ਇਸ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਦੇ ਅੰਸ਼ ਪੇਸ਼ ਹਨ:ਸੁਆਲ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਡੇਂਜਰਸ ਇਸ਼ਕ’ ‘ਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਖਾਸ ਵਜ੍ਹਾ?ਜੁਆਬ: ਮੈਂ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਧੰਨਵਾਦੀ ਹਾਂ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਹੌਸਲਾ ਅਫ਼ਜ਼ਾਈ ਸਦਕਾ ਮੈਂ ਫਿਰ ਤੋਂ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹਾਂ। ਮੈਂ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਵੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਸੀ ਸ਼ਾਪਿੰਗ ਕਰਨ ਜਾਂ ਏਅਰਪੋਰਟ ਲੋਕ ਪੁੱਛਦੇ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਹੁਣ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕਿਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਦੇਖਣਗੇ। ਇਸ ਗੱਲ ਨੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਹੌਸਲੇ ‘ਚ ਵਾਧਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਤੇ ‘ਡੇਂਜਰਸ ਇਸ਼ਕ’ ਜਿਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਮੈਂ ਕਰ ਸਕੀ।ਸੁਆਲ: ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਨੌਂ ਸਾਲ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਕਰਨਾ ਕਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਲੱਗ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ?ਜੁਆਬ: ਮੈਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਡੇਂਜਰਸ ਇਸ਼ਕ’ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਮੰਨਦੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਕਿਤੇ ਗਈ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਜੋ ਵਾਪਸ ਆ ਰਹੀ ਹਾਂ। ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਮੇਰਾ ਕਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਘਰੇਲੂ ਕਾਰਨਾਂ ਤੇ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਪਾਲਣ-ਪੋਸ਼ਣ ਲਈ ਛੁੱਟੀਆਂ ਲਈਆਂ ਸਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮੈਂ ਚੰਗੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਾਣਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਹੁਣ ਕੰਮ ‘ਤੇ ਵਾਪਸ ਆ ਗਈ ਹਾਂ। ਕੰਮ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਹਰ ਵਿਆਹੁਤਾ ਔਰਤ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਮੇਵਾਰੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਤੇ ਬੱਚੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਜੇ ਸਮਾਂ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੀ ਰਹਾਂਗੀ। ਦੂਜੀ ਗੱਲ ਇਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਮੈਂ ਸੀਰੀਅਲ ‘ਕਰਿਸ਼ਮਾ:ਏ ਮਿਰੇਕਲ ਆਫ ਡੈਸਟਿਨੀ’ ‘ਚ ਅਭਿਨੈ ਕੀਤਾ ਤੇ ਰਿਆਲਟੀ ਸ਼ੋਅ ‘ਨੱਚ ਬੱਲੀਏ-4’ ਨੂੰ ਜੱਜ ਕੀਤਾ ਤੇ ਟੀ.ਵੀ. ਕਮਰਸ਼ੀਅਲ ਵੀ ਕੀਤੇ।ਸੁਆਲ: ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਸਾਡੀ ਇੰਡਸਟਰੀ ‘ਚ ਵੀ ਹੀਰੋਇਨਾਂ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਵਾਂਗ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਜੀਵਨ ‘ਚ ਮਾਂ ਬਣਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਲੱਗੀਆਂ ਹਨ?ਜੁਆਬ: ਬਿਲਕੁਲ ਠੀਕ ਕਿਹਾ। ਅਸੀਂ ਸਾਰੇ ਪੱਛਮ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਕਬੂਲ ਰਹੇ ਹਾਂ। ਐਂਜਲੀਨਾ ਜੌਲੀ ਜਾਂ ਕੇਟ ਵਿਨਸਲੇਟ ਦੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਵੀ ਦੋ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਹਾਂ ਪਰ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਬਾਵਜੂਦ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹਾਂ। ਵਿਕਰਮ ਭੱਟ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਯੂਨਿਟ ਨੇ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਦੀਆਂ ਤਾਰੀਖਾਂ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਰੱਖੀਆਂ ਕਿ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਲਈ ਸਮਾਂ ਕੱਢਣ ‘ਚ ਕੋਈ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਲ ਨਾ ਆਵੇ।ਸੁਆਲ: ਕੀ ਇਹੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ‘ਡੇਂਜਰਸ ਇਸ਼ਕ’ ਦੇ ਪੋਸਟਰ ‘ਚ ਐਂਜਲੀਨਾ ਜੌਲੀ ਦੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਲਾਲ ਪੁਸ਼ਾਕ ਪਾਈ ਹੈ?ਜੁਆਬ: ਈਮਾਨਦਾਰੀ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪੋਸਟਰ ਬਾਰੇ ਤਾਂ ਅਸੀਂ ਸੋਚਿਆ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ। ਇਹ ਫੋਟੋ ਸ਼ੂਟ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਮਾਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਇਹ ਐਂਜਲੀਨਾ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਲ ਖਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਉਸ ਤੋਂ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਿਤ ਨਹੀਂ। ਇਸ ਫੋਟੋ ਸ਼ੂਟ ‘ਚ ਸੰਜਨਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਕਦਮ ਅੱਗੇ ਵਧਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ, ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਇੱਕ ਔਰਤ ਦਾ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਹੈ।ਸੁਆਲ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਡੇਂਜਰਸ ਇਸ਼ਕ’ ਨਾਲ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਜੁੜੇ?ਜੁਆਬ: ਤਕਰੀਬਨ ਚਾਰ ਸਾਲ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਵਿਕਰਮ ਭੱਟ ਤੇ ਅਸੀਂ  ਕੌਫੀ ਪੀਣ ਗਏ ਮਿਲੇ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਸੁਣਾਈ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਮੇਰੇ ਬੱਚੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਛੋਟੇ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਧਿਆਨ ਨਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਸਾਲ 2010 ਵਿੱਚ ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਲਿਆ ਤੇ ਕਹਾਣੀਆਂ ਸੁਣਨੀਆਂ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤੀਆਂ ਤਾਂ ਵਿਕਰਮ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਦੁਬਾਰਾ ਸੁਣਾਈ ਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਨਾਂਹ ਨਾ ਕਰ ਸਕੀ। ਮੈਨੂੰ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਮੈਂ ਅੱਜ ਤਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਤੇ ਇਹ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਹੈ।ਸੁਆਲ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਡੇਂਜਰਸ ਇਸ਼ਕ’ ‘ਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੀ ਕਹੋਗੇ?ਜੁਆਬ: ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਚੁਣੌਤੀਪੂਰਨ ਰਿਹਾ। ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਦਰਸ਼ਕ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੇਖਣਗੇ। ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਦੀ ਉੱਘੀ, ਖ਼ੂਬਸੂਰਤ, ਬੁੱਧੀਮਾਨ ਮਾਡਲ ਸੰਜਨਾ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਇਆ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਮੁਲਕ ਦੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਵੱਡੇ ਉਦਯੋਗਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਪੁੱਤ ਰੋਹਣ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਸਮਾਜ ‘ਚ ਇਹ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਚਰਚਿਤ ਜੋੜੀ ਹੈ। ਅਚਾਨਕ ਸੰਜਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਪੈਰਿਸ ‘ਚ ਮਾਡÇਲੰਗ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਡੀ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਸ਼ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਉਹ ਆਖਰੀ ਪਲਾਂ ‘ਤੇ ਪੈਰਿਸ ਜਾਣ ਦਾ ਖਿਆਲ ਛੱਡ ਦਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਰੋਹਣ ਤੋਂ ਦੂਰ ਜਾਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ, ਸਗੋਂ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਦਿਲ ਗਵਾਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਭਰਦਾ ਤੇ ਰੋਹਣ ਅਗਵਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਸਾਰੇ ਮੁਲਕ ‘ਚ ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਫੈਲ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਸੰਜਨਾ ਕਈ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਵਾਲਾਂ ‘ਚ ਉਲਝ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਅਗਵਾਕਾਰ ਰੋਹਣ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡਣ ਬਦਲੇ ਪੰਜਾਹ ਕਰੋੜ ਰੁਪਏ ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਸੰਜਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝ ‘ਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਕੀ ਕਰੇ। ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਖੋਜ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਸੰਜਨਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਰੋਹਣ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਖਰੇ ਯੁੱਗ ‘ਚ ਪਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਅਹਿਸਾਸ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਕਿ ਜੇ ਉਹਨੇ ਰੋਹਣ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਤੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਨੂੰ ਬਚਾਉਣਾ ਤਾਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਪਿਛਲੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਕਹਾਣੀਆਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਾਣਨਾ ਪਵੇਗਾ। ਫਿਰ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਕਈ ਜਨਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ।ਸੁਆਲ: ਕੀ ਇਹ ਪੁਨਰ-ਜਨਮ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਹੈ?ਜੁਆਬ: ਜੀ ਹਾਂ, ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਪੁਨਰ-ਜਨਮ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਖ਼ੁਦ ਇਸ ‘ਚ ਯਕੀਨ ਕਰਦੀ ਹਾਂ ਤੇ ਸਾਡੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਹੋਰ ਬਹੁਤੇ ਲੋਕ ਵੀ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਯਕੀਨ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ।ਸੁਆਲ: ਵਿਕਰਮ ਭੱਟ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਤਜਰਬਾ ਕਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਰਿਹਾ?ਜੁਆਬ: ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਲਈ ਵਿਕਰਮ ਨੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਵੈਸੇ ਵੀ 3-ਡੀ ਤੇ ਔਰਤ ‘ਤੇ ਆਧਾਰਤ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਬਣਾਉਣ ‘ਚ ਉਹ ਮਾਹਰ ਹਨ।ਸੁਆਲ: ਅੱਜ-ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਔਰਤ ‘ਤੇ ਅਧਾਰਿਤ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਦੌਰ ਚੱਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਤੁਹਾਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵੀ…?ਜੁਆਬ: ਹਾਂ, ਲੋਕ ਵਿਦਿਆ ਬਾਲਨ ਕਾਰਨ ਔਰਤ ਦੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਹੋਣ ਦਾ ਸ਼ੋਰ ਮਚਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਇਹ ਸਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ। ਔਰਤ ਦੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਬਣਦੀਆਂ ਆਈਆਂ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਵੀ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਮੈਂ ਖ਼ੁਦ ਬੀਵੀ ਨੰਬਰ ਵਨ ਤੇ ਜ਼ੁਬੈਦਾ ਜਿਹੀਆਂ ਔਰਤ ਦੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ। ਚੰਗੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਤੇ ਵਿਸ਼ੇ ਵਾਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ।ਸੁਆਲ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਤੋਂ ਕੀ ਉਮੀਦਾਂ ਹਨ?ਜੁਆਬ: ਮੈਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਭਵਿੱਖ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਕਹਿ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ ਬਸ ਅਸੀਂ ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਨੇ ਪੂਰੀ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ।ਸੁਆਲ: ਬੀਤੇ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਛੋਟੀ ਭੈਣ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਨੇ ਦੋਸ਼ ਲਾਇਆ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਦਾਦਾ ਮਰਹੂਮ ਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ?ਜੁਆਬ: ਮੈਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਉਹਨੇ ਦੋਸ਼ ਲਾਇਆ ਬਲਕਿ ਉਹਦੇ ਕਹਿਣ ਦਾ ਢੰਗ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਵਧੀਆ ਸੀ। ਮੈਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਪੋਤੀ ਸੀ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਮੇਰੀਆਂ ਅੱਖਾਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ‘ਤੇ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਸਨ। ਫਿਰ ਕਰੀਨਾ, ਰਣਬੀਰ, ਰਿਦਮਾ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਏ। ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਦਾਦਾ ਜੀ ਨਾਲ ਰਹਿਣ ਦਾ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਸਮਾਂ ਮਿਲਿਆ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਮਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੇ ਦਾਦਾ ਜੀ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਲਿਖੋ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ  ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਮਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੇ ਦਾਦਾ ਜੀ ਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਸਨ।"},{"question":"भारताचे राष्ट्रगीत कोणते आहे?(A) वंदे मातरम्(B) जन गण मन(C) सारे जहाँ से अच्छा(D) (A) आणि (बी)=>","answer":" (B) जन गण मन – रवींद्रनाथ टागोर"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന വാക്യങ്ങൾ നൽകിയിരിക്കുന്നു:വാചകം 1: ഞാൻ ഒരു സുഹൃത്തിനോടൊപ്പം സർവകലാശാലയിലേക്ക് നടന്നു.വാചകം 2: ഞാനും എന്റെ ഒരു സുഹൃത്തും ഒരുമിച്ച് ക്യാമ്പസിലേക്കു പോയി.മുമ്പത്തെ വാക്യങ്ങൾ ഒരേ കാര്യത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണോ സംസാരിക്കുന്നത്?","answer":"അതെ, രണ്ട് വാക്യങ്ങളും രണ്ട് സുഹൃത്തുക്കൾ ഒരുമിച്ച് സർവകലാശാലയിലേക്ക് പോകുന്നതിനെക്കുറിച്ച് സംസാരിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"Zer da pilates metodologia?","answer":"Pilates metodologia kirol eta osasunaren ariketa fisiko bat da, gorputza indartu, tonifikatu, eta orekatzeko, baita hainbat lesio prebenitzeko ere."},{"question":"Tsy mijery afa tsy ny marika aho rehefa mividy sakafo any amin'ny fivarotam-be ireny ary tonga dia omeko ny zanako mba hohaniny izany aveo. Mila mitandrina kokoa ve aho ? Valio eny na tsia","answer":"Eny, mila mitandrina kokoa rehefa mividy sakafo amin'ny fivarotam-be satria tsy fantatra izay sandoka. Mila mijery ny fotoana izay mahalany daty azy mba tsy hividy zavatra hamparary. "},{"question":"Raha jerena ireto fehezanteny roa ireto:Fehezanteny A: \\"Efa lavitra ny dia, fa nandalo ny fanadinana ihany aho tamin'ny farany.\\"Fehezanteny B: \\"Taorian'ny fanandramana maro dia nahavita ny fitsapana aho.\\"Mitovy ve ny dikany?","answer":"Eny, mitovy ny dikan'ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"中国地方で唯一県名と県庁所在地が一致しない県の県庁所在地は？","answer":"松江です。"},{"question":"ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ, 3 ਮਾਰਚਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਆਧਾਰਿਤ ਜੈਸ਼-ਏ-ਮੁਹੰਮਦ ਦੇ ਖ਼ਤਰਨਾਕ ਦਹਿਸ਼ਤੀ ਹਮਲਿਆਂ ਕਰਕੇ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਦੋ ਦਹਾਕਿਆਂ ’ਚ ਭਾਰਤ ਅਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੋ ਵਾਰ ਆਹਮੋ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਹਨ। ਜੈਸ਼ ਦੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਜਹਾਦ (ਗਜ਼ਵਾ-ਏ-ਹਿੰਦ) ਦੀ ਰਣਨੀਤੀ ਕਰਕੇ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਮੁਲਕਾਂ ’ਚ ਤਲਖ਼ੀ ਵਧਦੀ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।ਪਿਛਲੇ 20 ਸਾਲਾਂ ’ਚ ਜੈਸ਼ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਖ਼ਤਰਨਾਕ ਹਮਲਿਆਂ ’ਚ ਹਵਾਈ ਸੈਨਾ ਦੇ ਪਠਾਨਕੋਟ ਬੇਸ, ਉੜੀ ’ਚ ਥਲ ਸੈਨਾ ਦੇ ਬ੍ਰਿਗੇਡ ਹੈੱਡਕੁਆਰਟਰ, ਸ੍ਰੀਨਗਰ ਦੀ ਬਦਾਮੀਬਾਗ ਛਾਉਣੀ ਅਤੇ ਜੰਮੂ ਕਸ਼ਮੀਰ ਵਿਧਾਨ ਸਭਾ ’ਚ ਧਮਾਕੇ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹਨ।ਭਾਰਤ ਅਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ 2001 ’ਚ ਜੈਸ਼-ਏ-ਮੁਹੰਮਦ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸੰਸਦ ਅਤੇ ਹੁਣ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਮਹੀਨੇ 14 ਫਰਵਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਪੁਲਵਾਮਾ ’ਚ ਸੀਆਰਪੀਐਫ ਬੱਸ ’ਤੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਹਮਲੇ ਨਾਲ ਜੰਗ ਦੇ ਬੱਦਲ ਛਾ ਗਏ ਸਨ। ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਨੇ ਖ਼ੁਫ਼ੀਆ ਰਿਪੋਰਟ ਦਾ ਜ਼ਿਕਰ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਅਲ ਕਾਇਦਾ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੀ ਜਥੇਬੰਦੀ ਜੈਸ਼ ਨੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਓਕਾਰਾ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ’ਚ 27 ਨਵੰਬਰ 2017 ’ਚ ਕਾਨਫ਼ਰੰਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਅਹਿਦ ਲਿਆ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਭਾਰਤ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ‘ਗਜ਼ਵਾ-ਏ-ਹਿੰਦ’ ਜਾਰੀ ਰੱਖੇਗਾ।ਪਿਛਲੇ 20 ਸਾਲਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਭਾਰਤ 'ਤੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਖਤਰਨਾਕ ਹਮਲਾ ਕੀ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਪਿਛਲੇ 20 ਸਾਲਾਂ 'ਚ ਭਾਰਤ 'ਤੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਖਤਰਨਾਕ ਹਮਲਾ ਪਠਾਨਕੋਟ ਏਅਰ ਫੋਰਸ ਬੇਸ 'ਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਧਮਾਕੇ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai dihentak alu luncung\\"?","answer":"Dialahkan oleh orang yang tidak pandai atau yang lemah"},{"question":"با توجه به متن زیر به سؤال پرسیده شده پاسخ دهید: متن: هرچند شاگردان رشیدی در ست سوم شروع خوبی داشتند اما در دقایق پایانی چین‌تایپه امتیازات برتر را از آن خود کرد و این ست هم با نتیجه 26 بر 24 به نفع تایپه به پایان رسید، تا این تیم مقام نهم مسابقات قهرمانی زنان آسیا را از آن خود کند و شاگردان رشیدی با عنوان دهمی به کار خود پایان دهند.سؤال: رشیدی کیست؟","answer":"رشیدی مربی تیم والیبال بانوان ایران در مسابقات قهرمانی زنان آسیا است."},{"question":"පහත අර්ථයට ගැලපෙන ගීතය කුමක්ද?ඇරඹුමම කඳුළක්‌ වෙලා මා බලා ඉද්දී ඒ දිහාආ දුරත් දුර වැඩි නිසාඅවසානයට පෙර ඈ ගියා…දුක්‌බරම කවියක්‌ ලියාඑහි පද පෙළක්‌ අඩුවෙන් තියා…//අරුත පසදින්නට කියාඅවසානයට පෙර ඈ ගියා… ශෝකාන්තය එන තුරාඑහි රැඳෙන්නට සිත් නැති නිසා…//අනන්තය ළඟ මා දමාඅවසානයට පෙර ඈ ගියා…","answer":"කෙටි කාලීන ජනප්‍රියත්වයක් හිමි මෑත කාලීන ගීත කලාව තුල බිහි වූ ඉතාමත් අර්ථ හා භාව පූර්ණ වූ මෙන්ම රසික ආදරය එක සේ දිනා සිටින ඇරඹුමම කඳුළක්‌ වෙලා ගීතය රචනා වන්නේ ගීත රචනා කලාවට මහඟු සේවයක් ඉටු කල කරුණාරත්න අබේසේකරයන්ගේ පුත් දිලීප අබේසේකරයන් විසිනි. ගීතයේ පද තුල තිබෙන ගැඹුරු බව නිසාම මෙම ගීතයේ අරුත පිළිබඳව රසිකයින් බොහෝ සැලකිල්ලක් දැක්වූ අතර ඒ හරහා ගීතයට විවිධ අර්ථකතන ලැබී තිබෙනු කිහිප විටක්ම දැක අසා ගනටද හැකි විය. ඇතැමෙකුගේ අදහස වූවේ මෙය මව් ගුණ ගීයක් යනුවෙනි. කෙසේ වුවද ගීතයෙන් පැවසෙන්නේ අන් කිසිවක් පිළිබඳව නොව වර්තමානය තුල සුලභ තාවකාලික අරුත් සුන් ප්‍රේමය පිලිබඳවයි. ඇරඹුමම කඳුළක්‌ වෙලාමා බලා ඉද්දී ඒ දිහාආ දුරත් දුර වැඩි නිසාඅවසානයට පෙර ඈ ගියා… මෙය පෙම්වතෙකුගේ අසරණ ප්‍රකාශනයක් ලෙස දිස් වෙයි. ප්‍රේමය ආරම්භයේදීම එහි ඉමක් නොදකින බව හඳුනා ගන්න නිසාවෙන්ම සැමටම සිතට සහනයක්, සතුටක් ගෙනෙන ප්‍රේමය මේ ප්‍රේම මවන්තයාට ගෙන දෙන්නේ දුකක්. කිසිවක් කර ගත නොහැකි පෙම්වතා හට බලා සිටිනවා. ආදරය නමැති මාතෘකාව තුල ඇය බොහෝ දුරක් ඇවිදින්. මේ ප්‍රේමය තවත් එක නවාතැනක් පමණයි. පෙම්වතා බලාපොරොත්තු වන අන්දමට මේ පෙම්වතියගේ ගමනාන්තය නොවෙයි. ඇය ඔහු වෙතින් නික්ම යන්නේ ඒ නිසයි. දුක්‌බරම කවියක්‌ ලියාඑහි පද පෙළක්‌ අඩුවෙන් තියා…//අරුත පසදින්නට කියාඅවසානයට පෙර ඈ ගියා… ඇය ලියූ ආදර කවිය පෙම්වතාට බොහෝ දුක්බර වූ කවියක්. එකී දුක්බර කවියේ පවා පද පෙළක් අඩුවෙනුයි ඇය ලියා යන්නේ. එවන් කවියක අරුතක් කෙසේ සොයන්නද.. පෙම්වතා බලාපොරොත්තු වන්නට ඇත්තේ අරුත් පූර්ණ වූ ප්‍රේමයක් මිස තාවකාලික පෙම් කතාවක් නොවේ.මෙවන් ප්‍රේමයක අරුත විමසන්න ඇයත් නොමැති තැන ඔහු තවත් අසරණයි. ශෝකාන්තය එන තුරාඑහි රැඳෙන්නට සිත් නැති නිසා…//අනන්තය ළඟ මා දමාඅවසානයට පෙර ඈ ගියා… කඳුලින් අරඹන මෙකී ප්‍රේමය කෙරේ යම් දිනක ශෝකාන්තයක් පැමිණෙන බව දෙදෙනාම දැන නොසිටියාම නොවෙයි. පෙම්වතා සිටියේ දිරිමත්ව එයට මුහුණ දීමට. නමුත් පෙම්වතිය තුල එයට දිරියක් ඇත්තේ නෑ. විසඳා ගත නොහැකි ඉමක් නොපෙනෙන ගැටළු ගොන්නක් ඉතිරි කර පෙම්වතා තනිකර පෙම්වතිය ඔහු කෙරෙන් නික්මී ගොසින් …! කසුන් කල්හාරයන් සිය හඬ තුල විවිධ හඬ හැඩතල මවන්නෙක්. මේ ගීයට අවැසි වන ශෝකී ස්වරූපය මුසු ඔහුගේ හඬත්. නාලක අංජන කුමාර සංගීතවේදියාගේ මිහිරි සංගීතයත් ඉහත පද රචනයට සිදු කොට ඇත්තේ වචනයෙක් කිව නොහැකි සාධාරණයක්. ගීතයේ සාර්ථකත්වය කෙරෙහි බල පා ඇත්තේද එයම විය යුතුයි."},{"question":"බැට්මින්ටන් ක්‍රීඩාව ජාතික ක්‍රීඩාව වන්නේ කුමන රටේද?","answer":"මැලේසියාව"},{"question":"Berikan jawapan kepada soalan rumit ini: Berapakah pembunuhan dari pembunuh bersiri Ted Bundy yang disiasat oleh Robert D. Keppel sebelum dihukum mati?","answer":"30 pembunuhan"},{"question":"\\"Ny fiakaran'ny haino aman-jery sosialy dia nanova ny fomba ifandraisan'ny olona sy ny fifaneraserana. Ireo rindrambaiko toa ny Facebook, Instagram ary Twitter dia nampifandray ny olona manerana an'izao tontolo izao. Na izany aza, ny ahiahy momba ny fanitsakitsahana ny tsiambaratelo, ny diso ary ny fitondran-tena manandevo dia niteraka fanontaniana momba ny fiantraikan'ny media sosialy amin'ny fiaraha-monina.\\"","answer":"Ny lohahevitra tamin'ny andalana teo aloha dia ny Media sosialy sy ny vokany"},{"question":"what important event is this text about: De Sciglio bắt đầu sự nghiệp thi đấu chuyên nghiệp dưới màu áo Milan vào năm 2011, trưởng thành từ lò đào tạo trẻ của câu lạc bộ, dù thuận chân phải nhưng De Sciglio có khả năng thi đấu tốt ở cả hai bên cánh. De Sciglio có trận đấu đầu tiên cho đội tuyển quốc gia vào tháng 3 năm 2013 và đã cùng đội tuyển Italia tham dự Cúp Liên đoàn các châu lục 2013, World Cup 2014, Euro 2016.","answer":"Dựa vào câu: \\"De Sciglio có trận đấu đầu tiên cho đội tuyển quốc gia vào tháng 3 năm 2013 và đã cùng đội tuyển Italia tham dự Cúp Liên đoàn các châu lục 2013, World Cup 2014, Euro 2016.\\", sự kiện quan trọng được nhắc tới là Cúp Liên đoàn các châu lục 2013, World Cup 2014, và Euro 2016."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk sardin gulung? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah yang terperinci.","answer":"Bahan inti sardin: 1 tin sederhana sardin dalam sos tomato, 1 biji bawang besar - dipotong bulat nipis-nipis, 2 ulas bawang putih - dimayang, 2 sudu besar cili kisar, Garam dan gula secukup rasaBahan kulit/pastri: 2 cawan tepung gandum, 2 sudu besar marjerin, Sedikit garam, 1 cawan air sejuk dari peti sejuk, 1 biji telur - dipukulCara memasak inti sardin:1. Panaskan minyak dalam kuali dan tumiskan bawang putih dan bawang besar sehingga layu.2. Masukkan cili kisar dan tumis sehingga garing.3. Masukkan sardin berserta sos, hancurkan sardin dengan sudip. Tambah garam, gula secukup rasa dan kacau rata. Masak sehingga inti hampir kering.4. Masak sekejap kemudian angkat dan biarkan inti sejuk.Cara membuat kulit pastri:1. Gaulkan tepung gandum, marjerin dan garam dengan tangan sehingga sebati dan menjadi tekstur seakan serbuk roti.2. Masukkan air sejuk sedikit demi sedikit dan uli sehingga menjadi doh yang tidak melekat pada bekasadunan.3. Rehatkan doh selama 15 minit.4. Potong dan bulatkan doh ke bentuk bulat sebesar bola ping pong setiap satu.5. Ambil doh bulat dan canaikan hingga leper memanjang.6. Sudukan inti sardin, lipat doh sekadar menutupi inti, picit tepi doh untuk seal. Gulung ketat-ketat dan gamkan hujung pastri dengan sedikit sapuan telur.Cara Menggoreng:1. Panaskan minyak dalam kuali dengan api sederhana.2. Goreng dan balik-balikkan sardin roll sehingga warna perang keemasan sekata.3. Angkat, tuskan kemudian hidang.Cara membekukan sardin gulung:1. Gorengkan sekejap, angkat ketika ia masih berwarna putih dan biarkan sejuk.2. Masukkan ke dalam plastik kedap udara dan simpan dalam ruang freezer peti sejuk.3. Bila nak makan, ambil dari peti sejuk, nyah bekukan sekejap, kemudian goreng."},{"question":"리그1을 왜 리그앙이라 부르나요","answer":"LEAGUE 1의 프랑스 발음이 리걍(Ligue un)에 가깝기 때문에 리그앙이라고 부릅니다. 불어로 1은 앙이라고 발음되기 때문입니다."},{"question":"الجملة 1: ماكارون على الطراز الفرنسي ممكن نلاقيه خارج كندا في أوروبا والولايات المتحدة. الجملة 2: خارج أوروبا ، ماكرون على الطراز الفرنسي ممكن يلاقيه في كندا والولايات المتحدة. سؤال: الجملة 1 والجملة 2 بتعبر عن نفس المعنى؟ نعم ولا لا؟","answer":"لأ. الجملتان لا تعبران عن نفس المعنى"},{"question":"කවීන්ද්‍ර යන්නේ අරුත කුමක්දැ ?","answer":"කවි+ ඉන්ද්‍රශ්‍රෙෂ්ඨ ,උත්තරීතර කවියාකවීන් අතර රජුඉන්ද්‍ර යනු හින්දු දේවකථා සාහිත්‍යයේ එන දෙවිවරුන්ගේ රජුය.බෞද්ධ සාහිත්‍යයේ එන ශක්‍ර දෙවියන්ද ඉන්ද්‍රම වන අතර නරයන්ගේ රජු නරේන්ද්‍ර වූවා සේ කවීන්ගේ රජු හෙවත් ඉතා දක්ෂ කවියා  කවීන්ද්‍ර විය."},{"question":"شنو كايتسمى الجزء الملون من العين ؟","answer":"القزحيه وهو اللي كايحيط بوسط العين اللي هو البؤبؤ وتيكون داير عليه البياض ديال العين"},{"question":"Shoko rekuti Hanways, rakambotanga nei uye rinozikanwa nechii?","answer":"Shoko rekuti \\"Hanways\\" rinoreva maamburera uye rinobva  pazita raJonas Hanway, muRungu uyo anowanzonzi ndiye aita kuti kushandiswa kwemaamburera muLondon kuzivikanwe muzana remakore rechi18. Kushandisa kwaHanway amburera kuti azvidzivirire pakunaya pakutanga kwakashorwa uye kushorwa, asi kutsungirira kwake kwakaita kuti zvishoma nezvishoma agamuchirwe uye atore maamburera sechishandiso chekudzivirira kunaya kwemvura."},{"question":"aa ina Fulani suka fi yawa?","answer":"A matsayin kashi na yawan al'ummar, saboda haka Fulani suna wakiltar kusan kashi 38% na al'ummar Guinea-Conakry, 30% a Mauritania, kasa da kashi 17% a Guinea-Bissau, 16% a Mali da Gambia, 12% a Kamaru, 22% a Senegal, kasa da kashi 9% a Najeriya, kashi 7.6% a Nijar, kashi 6.3% a Burkina Faso, kashi 5% a Saliyo da Jamhuriyar Afirka ta Tsakiya, kasa da kashi 4% a Chadi sai kaso kadan a Ghana da Cote d'Ivoire."},{"question":"Кыргызстан 🇰🇬  жөнүндө кызыктуу факты жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Кыргызстандагы эң кызык жер Баткенде. Мындагы Кыштут деген жерде кышында бир ай, жайында бир ай күн тийбейт."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'berniaga buluh kasap, hujung hilang pangkal lesap'?","answer":"'Berniaga buluh kasap, hujung hilang pangkal lesap' bermaksud mengerjakan sesuatu dengan tidak mengetahui caranya (mendatangkan kerugian sahaja)"},{"question":"问题：朝鲜是否有大学？","answer":"答案：朝鲜拥有多所大学，如金日成大学和平壤大学等。"},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini:  Tidak boleh dilihat tetapi boleh ditimbang?","answer":"Jawapan : Bertimbang rasa"},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Nouvelle-Zélande","answer":"Péeyum réwum Nouvelle-Zélande mu ngi tudu Wellington"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Messi và Neymar rực sáng, PSG có danh hiệu đầu tiên ở mùa giải mớiĐoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Theo chuyên gia cấp cao về cấp cứu của WHO châu Âu Catherine Smallwood, mục tiêu của các nước là làm gián đoạn chuỗi lây nhiễm và ngăn chặn đợt dịch này. Bà Smallwood cũng lưu ý dù hầu hết ca bệnh đậu mùa khỉ tự khỏi, bệnh này có thể gây ra các biến chứng nghiêm trọng. Các đánh giá trên được đưa ra sau khi Tây Ban Nha ngày 30.7 báo cáo ca tử vong thứ 2 liên quan đậu mùa khỉ. Một ngày trước đó, cả Tây Ban Nha và Brazil đều ghi nhận người đầu tiên tử vong sau khi nhiễm bệnh. Đây là các ca tử vong vì đậu mùa khỉ đầu tiên bên ngoài châu Phi. Theo WHO, hơn 18.000 ca bệnh đậu mùa khỉ bên ngoài châu Phi đã được phát hiện ở 78 quốc gia từ đầu tháng 5, với 70% trường hợp mắc bệnh ở châu Âu và 25% ở châu Mỹ.","answer":"Châu Âu báo động ca tử vong liên quan đậu mùa khỉ"},{"question":"Buatlah rangkuman dari artikel berita berikut ini.Judul: Ahok dan Meme-meme Lucu di Hari Ulang Tahunnya.Artikel:Ketika Ahok marah...jadilah Ahulk! Sebuah meme dari pengguna Twitter, @cenayangfilm. Tagar #HBD50Ahok menjadi yang terpopuler di Twitter Indonesia dengan lebih dari 16.000 kicauan. Sejumlah twit yang banyak dibagikan adalah foto dan kutipan Ahok terkait korupsi. \\"Mereka emosi dan mengatai saya anjing. Loh memang saya anjing: anjing yang menjaga harta tuannya. Tuan saya adalah Warga DKI!! Saya heran sama mereka para pejabat, padahal disumpah loh pake kitab suci, kok mencuri?? Makanya saya bilang mereka itu T!!! Sama Tuhan saja berani berkhianat apalagi sama rakyat.\\"Lainnya, memilih kutipan Ahok terkait kelompok-kelompok intoleran. \\"Gue gak peduli, jika gue dikata-katain kafir. Yang penting rakyat gue gak ditindas sama orang yang ngaku-ngaku beragama,\\" begitu tulisan dalam unggahan ucapan ulang tahun dari pengguna Twitter Alitt Susanto.Walau banyak diterpa kritik, pengguna media sosial masih menilai Ahok positif, kata lembaga analisa data Datalyst Indonesia. Namun citra positif ini tidak sekuat ketika Ahok naik menjadi gubernur pada 2014 lalu. Beberapa pengguna merayakan ulang tahun gubernur Jakarta ini dengan humor.\\"Mbah dan ngkoh mengucapkan selamat ulang tahun buat Ahok! #HBD50AHOK semoga tetap sehat, bahagia, dan disayang,\\" kata akun Twitter @cenayangfilm. Pengguna lain membuat dan mengunggah berbagai aksi Ahok dalam berbagai pertarungan, sebagai anggota The Avengers atau bertarung dalam laga Street Fighter. Dan, melawan The Assassin (Cecep Arif Rahman) dalam film The Raid 2: Berandal. Juga ketika ikut dalam aksi Mace Windu dalam Attack of the Clones. Akun bernama Rendy (@imandita) mengatakan membuat meme-meme ini setahun lalu untuk iseng saja dan kembali mengunggahnya hari ini sebagai ucapan selamat hari jadi bagi orang nomor satu di DKI Jakarta itu. Jawaban:","answer":"Rangkuman dari artikel berita tersebut adalah:Gubernur DKI Jakarta, Basuki Tjahaja Purnama selalu menjadi sosok yang 'dibenci tapi juga dirindu' oleh pengguna internet di Indonesia - dan ini tergambar dari keriuhan ucapan ulang tahunnya ke 50 di media sosial Twitter dengan tagar #HBD50AHOK."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaan suurada quraanka ka midka ah oonan lagu arag xarafka miim (ć)? Markii laga reebo Bisimka.","answer":"Waa suuratul Kowthar ama inaa Acdheenaa."},{"question":"Magbigay ng mga halimbawa ng palidrome sa wikang Ingles.","answer":"Ang palindrome ay isang uri ng salita na parehas pa rin ang baybay o spelling kapag binaliktad mo ang ayos ng mga titik nito. Ilang halimbawa ng palindrome sa Ingles ay ang sumusunod:1. racecar2. mom3. level4. rotor5. kayak6. madam7. refer"},{"question":"සිංහල  කතන්දරයට සුදුසු මාතෘකාවක් දෙන්න. ඔන්න දිනක් මැස්සෙක් ආහාර සොයමින් ගමන් කරන්න ට වුණා. ආහාරයක් හමු වූ මැස්සා එය ආහාරයට ගත්තා. ආහාර ගන්නා අතරතුර මැස්සා ට උගේ නම අමතක වුණා.ඉතින් මේ මැස්සා තමාගේ නම කුමක්දැයි දන්නා, දන්නා අයගෙන් ඇසීමට පටන් ගත්තා. මැස්සා පළමුවෙන්ම ගියේ පිහාටු අම්මා ලඟට යි. \\"පිහාටු අම්මේ !! පිහාටු අම්මේ.!! මට මගේ නම අමතක වුණා. ඔබ මාගේ නම දන්නවාද?\\" මැස්සා ඇහුවා. \\"මට ඔබේ නම මතක නෑ. මගේ පුතාගෙන් අහන්න.\\" පිහාටු අම්මා කීවා. මැස්සා පිහාටු අම්මාගේ පුතා ලඟට ගියා. \\"පිහාටු අම්මාගේ පුතේ...!!, ඔබ මාගේ නම දන්නවාද? මට මගේ නම අමතක වුණා.\\" මැස්සා ඇහුවා. \\"මට ඔබේ නම මතක නෑ. එත් මගේ මේ පොරවෙන් අහන්න. එයා කියයි.\\" පුතා පිළිතුරු දුන්නා.\\"පිහාටු අම්මාගේ පුතාගේ පොරව...!! මට මගේ නම මතක නැහැ. ඔබට වත් මගේ නම මතකද?\\" මැස්සා පොරවෙන් ද ඇසුවා. \\"මට නම් මතක නෑ ඔබේ නම. ඒත් මන් කපපු ගහෙන් අහන්න. එයා කියයි.\\" පොරව කිව්වා. මැස්සා ගස සොයාගෙන පියෑඹුවා.පිහාටු අම්මාගේ පුතාගේ පොරව කපපු ගස....!! ඔබ මාගේ නම දන්නවා ද?? මට මගේ නම මතක නෑ. මා කෙසේ නම් ඔබේ නම දැන ගන්නද? මගේ අතු වල ඉන්නා කුරුල්ලන්ගෙන් අසා බලන්න. ඔවුන් ඔබට උදව් කරාවි.\\" ගස මැස්සා ට පැවසුවා. මැස්සා කුරුල්ලන්ට කතා කළා. \\"පිහාටු අම්මාගේ පුතාගේ පොරව කපපු ගසේ ඉන්න කුරුල්ලනි. මට මාගේ නම අමතක වුණා. ඔබලාට මාගේ නම මතකද?\\" \\"අපි නම් ඔබේ නම දන්නේ නැහැ. නමුත් ඔබ අපි වතුර බිව් ගංගාවෙන් අසන්න.\\" කුරුල්ලන් ගංගාව ට යන පාර කිව්වා.මැස්සා ගංගාව අසලටත් ගියා. \\"අනේ...පිහාටු අම්මාගේ පුතාගේ පොරව කපපු ගසේ ඉන්න කුරුල්ලන් වතුර බිව් ගංගා යාලුවේ..... ඔබට මාගේ නම මතකද? මට මාගේ නම අමතක වෙලා.\\" මැස්සා දුකින් ඇහුවා.\\"සමාවෙන්න යාලුවේ, මට ඔබට උදව් කරන්න වෙන්නේ නැහැ. මට ඔබගේ නම මතක නෑ. මා තුළ පිහිනන මාලළුවා ගෙන් අහන්න.\\" ගංගාව කිව්වා. මෙලෙස මැස්සා, මාළුවා ගෙන් ද, ඉන්පසු මාළුවා ඇල්ලීමට තැත් කළ පිරිමි ළමයාගෙන් ද, පිරිමි ළමයාගේ අශ්වයාගෙන් ද, තමාගේ නම කුමක් දැයි විමසුවා. නමුත් ඔහුට කාගෙන්වත් නම නම් දැන ගන්නට ලැබුනේ නෑ. \\"යහළුවේ....!! ඔබේ නම මාගේ බඩ තුළ සිටින මාගේ අශ්ව පටවාගෙන් අහන්න. ඔහු අනිවාර්යයෙන්ම ඔබට පිළිතුරු දෙයි.\\" අශ්වයා මැස්සාට පැවසුවා. \\"චූටි අශ්ව පැටියෝ...!!! ඔයා මගේ නම දන්නවා ද?? මට උදව් කරන්න මගේ නම මතක් කර ගන්න. එය දැන් මට මතක නෑ.\\" මැස්සා ඇසුවා. \\"අයියෝ...!! ඔයාගේ නම තමයි \\"මැස්සා\\". බඩේ සිටි අශ්ව පැටියා පිළිතුරු දුන්නා.\\"ආහ් .!! ඔව් නේන්නම්. මගේ නම \\"මැස්සා\\" තමයි.\\" එය පිළිගත් මැස්සා, අශ්ව පැටියා ට ස්තූති කරමින් සතුටින් ඉගිලෙමින් යන්න ගියා. ","answer":"මැස්සාගේ මතකය"},{"question":"Qual estado brasileiro tem a sigla AP?","answer":"O estado brasileiro com a sigla AP é o Amapá. É o ponto de entrada para a selva amazônica, com sua natureza exuberante e rica diversidade cultural. O Amapá é conhecido por sua beleza natural, com suas florestas, rios e praias paradisíacas. É um lugar que combina aventura e tranquilidade, como um tesouro escondido no norte do Brasil. Infelizmente, o desmatamento tem sido uma grande preocupação na região e devemos nos preocupar com a preservação das suas lindíssimas florestas."},{"question":"வினா:சீதைக்குக் காவலிருந்த பெண்?","answer":"விடை:திரிசடை"},{"question":"Алманбет жактырып калган Айган хандын кызы ким?а) Алтынай б) Кызсайкалв) Кардыгач г) Күлийпа","answer":"Алманбет жактырып калган Айган хандын кызы Күлийпа. Туура жообу г) варианты болот."},{"question":"Bu paragrafın devamını yazın: \\"Tarih\\"in yedinci kitabı Otanis'e dair en çok ilgi içeren kısımdır. Kitabın 40. paragrafına Patiramphes'in oğlu olarak tanıtılan Otanis, I. Serhas'ın arabacısı olarak görülmektedir. 61. paragrafta I. Serhas'ın eşi Amestris'in babası olduğu ve Yunan Seferi","answer":"'nde orduyu kumanda ettiği bilgisi verilmekte, devam eden 62. paragrafta oğlu Anaphes'in de kumandan olarak sefere katıldığı aktarılmaktadır. 82. paragraftaysa Otanis'in oğlu olarak tanıtılan Smerdomenes'in de yine sefere kumandan olarak katıldığı belirtilmektedir."},{"question":"ગામીત બોલી વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"ગામીત બોલી તાપી નદીના ખીણ પ્રદેશમાં વસતા આદિવાસીઓ પૈકીના ગામિત જાતિના લોકોની પરાપૂર્વથી સામાજીક વહેવારમાં વપરાતી પરંપરાગત બોલી છે. આ બોલી બોલનારા ગામીત લોકોની વસ્તી ગુજરાતમાં વિશેષ છે. આ બોલી ખાસ કરીને દક્ષિણ ગુજરાતના રાનીપરજ વિસ્તારના તાપી જિલ્લામાં વધુ બોલાય છે. આ બોલી સાંભળતાં તેમાં થોડા શબ્દો ગુજરાતી ભાષા જેવા તથા થોડા શબ્દો સંસ્કૃત તથા મરાઠી ભાષા જેવા છે.વ્યાકરણ તથા ઉચ્ચારણગામીત બોલીમાં બહુવચન હોતું નથી. તેથી આ બોલીમાં દાદાને પણ તુ અને પુત્રને પણ તુ કહીને બોલાવવામા આવે છે. આ બોલીમાં વાક્યને અંતે લ્હેકા સાથે વા બોલાય છે, જે આ બોલીનું વૈવિધ્ય છે. ગામીત બોલીનાં લોકગીતો પૈકીનું રોડાલી ગીત ખુબ જ લોકપ્રિય છે.કેટલાક શબ્દો:આબહો -> પિતાઆયહો, આયો -> માતાબાહા -> ભાઈબાયહો, બાઈ -> બહેનપોહો -> પુત્રપોહી -> પુત્રીમાટળો, માટી, ધનારો -> પતિયેનો -> આવ્યોમાન -> મનેકોલા -> કેટલાપાનાં -> પાંદડાંબોજાહા -> ભાભીનિચાક -> છોકરોનિચકી -> છોકરીથેએ, દોનારી -> પત્નીરાને -> ખેતરેબોળજે -> બળદગાવડે -> ગાયકોદી -> ચોખાવોરાડ -> લગનનીંગયો -> નિકળ્યોપાહલા -> પાછળકેસ જા -> ક્યાં જાઓ છો?કાઇ કઓતોહો -> શું કરો છો?ઉજાળો ઓ વી ગીયો -> સવાર થઇ ગઇકેસ જાં? -> ક્યાં જવાના?"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Anastasija Mochniuk, född 1 januari 1991 i Nova Kachovka, är en ukrainsk friidrottare som tävlar i sjukamp. Hon är silvermedaljör i sjukamp från","answer":"2016 års världsmästerskap inomhus."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai anjing buruk kepala\\"?","answer":"Orang jahat yang dibenci oleh masyarakat."},{"question":"Que idioma é falado no País Camarões?","answer":"Oficialmente, em Camarões os idiomas falados são o francês e o inglês. Porém, tendo sido colonizado por alemães, o alemão também é ensinado e utilizado no País."},{"question":"Adajọ to yẹ aga mọ ijọba Ṣonẹkan nidii ni 1993 ti ku o","answer":"Ọpọ eeyan jankanjankan lagbo oṣelu ati ni ẹka eto idajọ, paapaa nipinlẹ Eko, lo ti n daro Oloogbe Adajọ Dọlapọ Akinsanya, ẹni to jade laye loru Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, to kọja yii.Ẹni ọdun mọkandinlọgọrin (79) ni mama naa nigba ti iku fi pa oju rẹ de lẹyin aisan ranpẹ kan.Lara awọn oloṣelu to daro oloogbe yii ni Aṣiwaju Bọla Ahmed Tinubu, o ni iru kaun-un ṣọwọ lawujọ okuta, akọni pataki lawujọ awọn adajọ ni adajọ-binrin yii, tori lasiko tijọba ologun gbegi dina fun eto ijoba demokresi nilẹ wa lobinrin yii gbe idajọ nla kalẹ lati gbeja eto iṣejọba awa-araawa.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kọkanla ọdun 1993 ni Oloogbe Adajọ-binrin Akinsanya tile ẹjọ giga ijọba apapọ nigba naa gbe idajọ kalẹ lori ẹjọ kan ti Oloye Moshood Kasimawo Abiọla pe tako ijọba fidi-hẹẹ ti ijọba ologun ajagun-fẹyinti Ibrahim Babangida gbe kalẹ.Ninu idajọ naa lo ti kede pe ijọba fidi-hẹẹ ko bofinmu, ko lẹtọọ lati wa nipo, o si tipa bẹẹ yẹ aga mọ Oloye Ẹrnest Shonekan to jẹ olori ijọba fidi-hẹẹ naa nidi. O ni Babangida to buwọ lu ofin ti wọn fi ṣedasilẹ ijọba fidi-hẹẹ yii ko lagbara lati ṣe bẹẹ, tori o ti kuro lori aleefa lọjọ kẹrindinlọgbọn oṣu kẹjọ, ki ijọba tuntun naa too yọju sita.Ọpọ eeyan lo gboṣuba fun idajọ yii, ati ọkan akin tobinrin naa fi gbe idajọ naa kalẹ, laibẹru awọn ologun. Idajọ yii lo ṣokunfa bi Oloogbe Sani Abacha ṣe ko awọn ologun sodi, ti wọn si palẹ ijọba fidi-hẹẹ naa mọ, lalẹ ọjọ tidajọ naa waye gan-an.Ọdun 1989 ni Akinsanya di adajọ, ọdun mẹtadinlogun lo si fi wa lori aga idajọ, lati kootu kan si omi-in, ko too fẹyin ti lọdun 2006."},{"question":"రాజ్యానికి గల ఏవైనా రెండు నిర్వచనాలను ఉదహరించండి.","answer":"‘రాజ్యం’ అనే పదాన్ని అనేకమంది రాజనీతిశాస్త్ర పండితులు అనేక రకాలుగా నిర్వచించారు. వారిలో కొందరు ఇచ్చిన నిర్వచనాలను కింది విధంగా పేర్కొనడమైంది.అరిస్టాటిల్: “మానవునికి సుఖప్రదమైన, గౌరవప్రదమైన జీవనాన్ని ప్రసాదించడమే లక్ష్యంగా కలిగిన కుటుంబాలు, గ్రామాల సముదాయమే రాజ్యం”.బ్లంటి: “ఒక నిర్ణీత ప్రదేశంలో నివసిస్తూ రాజకీయంగా వ్యవస్థీకృతమైన ప్రజల సముదాయమే రాజ్యం”."},{"question":"お寿司のかっぱ巻きに使われる具はどんな野菜？","answer":"きゅうりです。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai apa payahnya menaupkan bibir atas bawah\\"?","answer":"Banyak janji, tetapi tidak ditepati"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH dos Bahamas?","answer":"0,812., ficando assim em 55ª posição no mundo."},{"question":"ਗਲੋਬ ‘ਤੇ ਜਾਂ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਸਥਿਤੀ ਦੀ ਸੰਖੇਪ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਦਿਓ ।","answer":" 1. ਭਾਰਤ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਦੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੇ ਮਹਾਂਦੀਪ ਏਸ਼ੀਆ ਦੇ ਦੱਖਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਥਿਤ ਹੈ ।2. ਇਸਦੇ ਉੱਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਿਮਾਲਿਆ ਪਰਬਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਿਸ਼ਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਅਸਮਾਨ ਛੂੰਹਦੀ ਦੀਵਾਰ ਫੈਲੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ।3. ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਦੱਖਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਿੰਦ ਮਹਾਂਸਾਗਰ ਹੈ ।4. ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਦੱਖਣੀ ਪਠਾਰ ਦੇ ਪੂਰਬ ਵਿਚ ਬੰਗਾਲ ਦੀ ਖਾੜੀ ਅਤੇ ਪੱਛਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਰਬ ਸਾਗਰ ਸਥਿਤ ਹੈ ।5. ਕਰਕ ਰੇਖਾ (2312° ਉ.) ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਮੱਧ ਤੋਂ ਲੰਘਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਨੂੰ ਦੋ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡਦੀ ਹੈ ।6. ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਥਲ ਸੀਮਾ ਸੱਤ ਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਛੂੰਹਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਂ ਹਨ-ਮਯਨਮਾਰ, ਅਫ਼ਗਾਨਿਸਤਾਨ, ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ, ਨੇਪਾਲ, ਭੂਟਾਨ, ਬੰਗਲਾਦੇਸ਼ ਅਤੇ ਚੀਨ ।7. ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਅਤੇ ਅਫ਼ਗਾਨਿਸਤਾਨ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਉੱਤਰ-ਪੱਛਮ ਵਿਚ, ਨੇਪਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਭੂਟਾਨ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਉੱਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਤੇ ਮਯਨਮਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਬੰਗਲਾ ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਉੱਤਰ-ਪੂਰਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਥਿਤ ਹੈ ।8. ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਦੱਖਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ੍ਰੀਲੰਕਾ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਲਦੀਪ ਸਾਡੇ ਗੁਆਂਢੀ ਦੇਸ਼ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"berat kepala\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud pening atau sakit kepala."},{"question":"පළමු ඔත්තේ සංඛ්‍යා  ඇති  NumPy අරාවක් සාදන්න.","answer":"import numpy as nparray = np.arange(1, 20, 2)"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. සුවඳයි මල් සුවඳ සේමිහිරියි මී පැණි වගේජීවත් වෙන්න ආසයිහැමදාම හිමිදිරිය සේ","answer":"සුවඳයි මල් සුවඳ සේමිහිරියි මී පැණි වගේජීවත් වෙන්න ආසයිහැමදාම හිමිදිරිය සේමල් පියලි විසිරෙයි වනේරොන් සුවඳ සුළඟට දැනේනැහැ පුඩුව සිනිඳුයි ඒ සුවඳ පුරුදුයිමල් කැකුළු පූදින්න වාගේදිය කඩිති නිල් බර වුණේපොඩි තිත්ත පැටවුන්ටනේඅල්ලන්න ආසයි උන් එක්ක යාළුයිපීනන්න දිය කඩිති ගානේසමන්ත පෙරේරා, ඉන්දිකා උපමාලිලූෂන් බුලත්සිංහලප්‍රේමසිරි කේමදාස(ඇසළ කළුවර ටෙලි නාට්‍යය)"},{"question":"Hipofiz bezi tümörü ameliyatı tehlikeli mi?","answer":"Hipofiz tümörü ameliyatı riskli midir? Eksiden oldukça riskli bir ameliyattı ancak artık endoskopik yöntemle burundan girilerek yapıldığı için risk en düşük seviyededir."},{"question":"كم خلية دم حمراء يستطيع أنتاجها الجسم في اليوم الواحد ؟","answer":"يستطيع الجسم انتاج 200 مليون خلية في اليوم الواحد."},{"question":"Dame por favor una lista de tres lugares para visitar en Cali, Colombia.","answer":"Por supuesto, a continuación te presento una lista con tres lugares para visitar en Cali:1. Zoológico de Cali: el zoológico de Cali es uno de los mas lindos del país, es muy grande y tiene mucha variedad de animales.2. Bosque El Descanso: es una joya dentro la geografía del territorio Colombiano, un lugar exótico ubicado en el departamento del Valle del Cauca. 3. Caliwood Museo de la Cinematografía: este museo conserva la colección más grande de proyectores de teatro, cámaras de cine, cámaras fotográficas, carteles, parafernalia y recuerdos relacionados con el desarrollo de la industria cinematográfica en Colombia."},{"question":"Gloria Young","answer":"Gloria Young (bí ní ọjọ́ kẹrin oṣù kejì ọdún 1967) jẹ́ òṣèré ni orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà tí ó gbà àmì ẹ̀yẹ Movie Couple of the Year láti ọ̀dọ̀ City People Entertainment Awards ní ọdún 2018.Wọ́n bí Gloria sí ìpínlẹ̀ Abia. Ó lọ sí ilé ẹ̀kọ́ Methodist Girls High School ní Yaba ní ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó. Ó lọ sí ilé ẹ̀kọ́ gíga ni orílẹ̀ èdè Amẹ́ríkà.Gloria bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ gẹ́gẹ́ bíi oníróyìn. Ó gbajúmọ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí òṣèré ní ọdún 2014 lẹ́hìn tí ó kó ipa Doris nínú eré Glamour Girls.Young ti ṣe ìgbéyàwó pẹ̀lú ẹlẹ́gbẹ́ Nollywood rẹ̀ Norbert Young àti pé àwọn méjéèjì ní ọmọ mẹ́ta papọ̀. Ìdíje eré bọ́ọ̀lù tuntun kan ni wọ́n ṣètò ní pápá ìṣeré ti orílẹ̀-èdè ní Surulere, ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó ní òmìrán láti ṣe ayẹyẹ 'jubilee' fàdákà rẹ̀ ní Nollywood.Gloria jẹ́ ìyàwó fún Nobert Young, wọ́n sì ti bí ọmọ mẹ́ta."},{"question":"إمتى توفى السلطان قلاوون ؟","answer":"الإجابة : السلطان قلاوون سلطان مملوكي حكم مصر من 1279 حتى ل 1290 السنه ديال الوفاه ديالو ."},{"question":"நிரல்நிறை அணியை விளக்குக.","answer":"அணி விளக்கம்:சில சொற்களை வரிசைப்படுத்தி, அச்சொற்களுடன் தொடர்புள்ளவற்றையும் முறையாக வரிசைப்படுத்தி அதன்படி பொருள் கொள்ள வைப்பதே ‘நிரல்நிறையணி’யாகும்.(எ.கா.) அன்பும் அறனும் உடைத்தாயின் இல்வாழ்க்கைபண்பும் பயனும் அது.விளக்கம்:மேற்காணும் குறளில், அன்பும், அறனும், முதலடியில் அமைந்துள்ளன. அச்சொற்களுக்கு முறையாகப் பொருந்தும்படி, பண்பும், பயனும், இரண்டாவது அடியில் வரிசையாக வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.இதன் மூலம் அன்பே பண்பாகவும், அறனே பயனாகவும் இல்லறம் அமைய வேண்டும் என்பது உணர்த்தப்படுகிறது. இங்ஙனம் அன்பிற்குப் பண்பும், அறத்திற்குப் பயனும் என வரிசைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது.(நிரல் – வரிசை ; நிறை – நிறுத்துதல், நிரல் நிறை வரிசையாக நிறுத்துதல்)"},{"question":"السؤال: عندما وصل البابا غريغوري التاسع إلى السلطة ، ما هو الحيوان الداجن الذي أمر بإبادته في جميع أنحاء أوروبا معتقدًا أنه تم استخدامه في عبادة الشيطان وحرفة الساحرات؟","answer":"الإجابة: القطط"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Setiap negara mempunyai benda ini. Benda ini boleh dikibarkan. ","answer":"Jawapan: bendera. Bendera ialah simbol visual yang melambangkan identiti kebangsaan sesebuah negara."},{"question":" ਪ੍ਰਿਅੰਕਾ ਚੋਪੜਾ ਨਾਲ  'ਤੇਰੀ ਮੇਰੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ' ਦੇ ਸੈਟ ਤੇ ਇਕ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ।","answer":"ਆਸ਼ੂਤੋਸ਼ ਗੋਵਾਰੀਕਰ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਵੱਟ ਇਜ਼ ਯੂਅਰ ਰਾਸ਼ੀ’ ਵਿੱਚ 14 ਅਤੇ ‘ਸਾਤ ਖ਼ੂਨ ਮਾਫ਼’ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੱਤ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਉਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਪ੍ਰਿਅੰਕਾ ਚੋਪੜਾ ਨੇ ਕੁਨਾਲ ਕੋਹਲੀ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਤੇਰੀ ਮੇਰੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ‘ਚ ਤਿੰਨ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਏ ਹਨ। ਪ੍ਰਿਅੰਕਾ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਹਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਉਣ ‘ਚ ਵਧੇਰੇ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਪ੍ਰਿਅੰਕਾ ਨੇ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਆਪਣੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਅਹਿਮ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਸਾਂਝੀਆਂ ਕੀਤੀਆਂ:ਪ੍ਰਃ ਤੇਰੀ ਮੇਰੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੀ ਕਹੋਗੇ।– ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਪਿਆਰ ਤੇ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦਾ ਜਸ਼ਨ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ‘ਚ ਬਹੁਤ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਹਾਂ। ਮੇਰਾ ਮੰਨਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪਿਆਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਘੁਮਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਹੁਣ ਤਕ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣੀ ਹੈ।ਪ੍ਰਃ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਕਿਉਂ ਕੀਤੀ।– ਜਦੋਂ ਕੁਨਾਲ ਨੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਕੋਲ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ ਤੇ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਸੁਣਾਉਣੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤੀ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਐਨੀ ਰੌਚਿਕ ਲੱਗੀ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਚੁੱਪਚਾਪ ਸੁਣਦੀ ਰਹੀ। ਮੈਂ ਕੁਨਾਲ ਨੂੰ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਕਿ ਇਸ ‘ਚ ਮੈਂ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਤਿੰਨ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਉਣੇ ਹਨ। ਉਹ ਹੈਰਾਨ ਹੋਇਆ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਉਣ ‘ਚ ਮਜ਼ਾ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਲਈ ਹਾਮੀ ਭਰਨ ਦਾ ਦੂਜਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ।ਪ੍ਰਃ ਕਮੀਨੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਇੱਕ ਵਾਰ ਫਿਰ ਸ਼ਾਹਿਦ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਕੇ ਕਿੰਜ ਲੱਗਿਆ।– ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਾਹਿਦ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਕੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ ਹੋਈ ਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਅੱਗੇ ਵੀ ਸ਼ਾਹਿਦ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨਾ ਪਸੰਦ ਕਰਾਂਗੀ।  ਸ਼ਾਹਿਦ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਜੋ ਵੀ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਛਪਦੀਆਂ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਸਭ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਦੀ ਦਿਮਾਗੀ ਉਪਜ ਹਨ।ਪ੍ਰਃ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਲਈ ਪਿਆਰ ਤੋਂ ਕੀ ਭਾਵ ਹੈ।– ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਪਿਆਰ ਫੁੱਲ ਜਾਂ ਚਾਕਲੇਟ ਤੋਂ ਕਈ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਮਾਅਨੇ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ। ਤੁਸੀਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋ ਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਹਰ ਦਿਨ ਨਵੇਂ ਢੰਗ ਨਾਲ ਕਹਿ ਸਕਦੇ ਹੋ।ਪ੍ਰਃ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼-3 ਬਾਰੇ ਕੀ ਕਹੋਗੇ।-ਫਿਲਹਾਲ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਹਿ ਸਕਦੀ। ਸਹੀ ਸਮਾਂ ਆਉਣ ਦਿਓ, ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਦੱਸਾਂਗੀ। ਹਾਲੇ ਇਹੀ ਕਹਿ ਸਕਦੀ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਬਿਹਤਰੀਨ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਬਣ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।ਪ੍ਰਃ ਕਿਸਮਤ ‘ਚ ਯਕੀਨ ਰੱਖਦੋ ਹੋ।– ਮੈਂ ਕਿਸਮਤ ‘ਚ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸ ਰੱਖਦੀ ਹਾਂ। ਕਿਸਮਤ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਖੇਡ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਇੱਥੇ ਇੱਕ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਦਿਲਾਂ ‘ਚ ਵਸੀ ਹੋਈ ਹਾਂ, ਨਹੀਂ ਤਾਂ ਬਰੇਲੀ ਜਿਹੇ ਛੋਟੇ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਦੀ ਮੱਧਵਰਗੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਸਬੰਧਤ ਕੁੜੀ ਇੱਥੋਂ ਤਕ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਸਕਦੀ ਸੀ? ਸਿਰਫ਼ 17 ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਤੇ ਬਾਰ੍ਹਵੀਂ ਤਕ ਦੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਪੂਰੀ ਹੁੰਦੇ  ‘ਮਿਸ ਵਰਲਡ’ ਦਾ ਖਿਤਾਬ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਨਾ ਕਿਸਮਤ ਹੀ ਕਹੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ। ਅੱਜ ਮੈਂ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਵੀ ਹਾਂ, ਇੱਥੋਂ ਤਕ ਪਹੁੰਚਣ ਬਾਰੇ ਕਦੇ ਸੋਚਿਆ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਤਕਦੀਰ ‘ਚ ਲਿਖੇ ਨੂੰ ਕੌਣ ਮਿਟਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। ਐਨਾ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਹਰ ਕੰਮ ਲਗਨ ਨਾਲ ਕਰਦੀ ਹਾਂ। ਮੁੰਬਈ ਮਹਾਂਨਗਰ ਖਾਸਕਰ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੇਰੀ ਕੋਈ ਜਾਣ-ਪਛਾਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕੰਮ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਗਿਆ ਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਕਰਦੀ ਚਲੀ ਗਈ।ਪ੍ਰਃ ਕਦੇ ਰਿਐਲਿਟੀ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਬਿੱਗਬੌਸ ਦਾ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਬਣਨਾ ਚਾਹੋਗੇ।– ਸਵਾਲ ਹੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ। ਜੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਦਾ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਬਣਨ ਲਈ ਮੋਟੀ ਰਕਮ ਵੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਜਾਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਸੌਣ ਸਮੇਂ, ਚੱਲਦੇ-ਫਿਰਦੇ, ਖਾਂਦੇ-ਪੀਂਦੇ ਹਰ ਵਕਤ ਕੈਮਰਾ ਮੇਰੇ ‘ਤੇ ਹੋਵੇ, ਇਹ ਮੈਂ ਕਦੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ। ਮੈਂ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਬਿੱਗਬੌਸ ਦੇ ਘਰ ‘ਚ ਆਸ਼ੂਤੋਸ਼ ਗੋਵਾਰੀਕਰ, ਸਾਜਿਦ ਖ਼ਾਨ, ਰਾਖੀ ਸਾਵੰਤ, ਮੀਕਾ ਸਿੰਘ ਤੇ ਰੇਖਾ ਨੂੰ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਜਾਵੇ। ਰੇਖਾ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੇ ਭੇਦ ਬਣੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਵੀ ਇੱਛਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਰੇਖਾ ਦਿਨ ਭਰ ਕੀ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਜਾਨਣ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲੇ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਮੈਂ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਦਲੇਰ ਮਹਿੰਦੀ ਤੇ ਸ਼ਸ਼ੀ ਥਰੂਰ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਕਰਨ ਜੌਹਰ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਬਿੱਗਬੌਸ ‘ਚ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ਮਿਲੇ।ਪ੍ਰਃ ਕੋਈ ਸਮਾਂ ਸੀ ਜਦੋਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ‘ਚ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਦਰੱਖਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਆਲੇ-ਦੁਆਲੇ ਨੱਚਣ-ਗਾਉਣ ਤਕ ਸੀਮਤ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਹੁਣ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੁਝ ਵੀ ਪਰਦੇ ‘ਤੇ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਆ ਰਿਹਾ। ਕੀ ਕਹੋਗੇ।– ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੀ ਤਸਵੀਰ ਹੈ। ਅੱਜ ਦਾ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਅੱਜ ਦੇ ਸਮਾਜ, ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀ ਨੂੰ ਧਿਆਨ ‘ਚ ਰੱਖ ਕੇ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੀ ਅਬਾਦੀ ਦਾ 60 ਫ਼ੀਸਦੀ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਲੋਕ 35 ਸਾਲ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਉਮਰ ਦੇ ਹਨ। ਹੁਣ ਕੁੜੀਆਂ ਵੀ ਆਜ਼ਾਦ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਹਰ ਖੇਤਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਖੱਲ੍ਹ ਕੇ ਵਿਚਰ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਅਜਿਹੇ ਹਾਲਾਤ ਦੇ ਮੱਦੇਨਜ਼ਰ ਹੀਰੋਇਨਾਂ ਭਾਵ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਲਈ ਖਾਸ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਲਿਖੇ ਜਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਮੇਰੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਨਾਲ ਸਜੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਫੈਸ਼ਨ ਤੋਂ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ। ਸੱਚ ਕਹਿੰਦੀ ਹਾਂ, ਅੱਜ ਦੀ ਤਾਰੀਖ ‘ਚ ਜੋ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਬਣ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਉਹ 10 ਸਾਲ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਬਣਾਈਆਂ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀਆਂ ਸਨ।ਪ੍ਰਃ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ‘ਚ ਆ ਰਹੇ ਬਦਲਾਅ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਭਵਿੱਖ ‘ਚ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਔਰਤ ‘ਤੇ ਕੇਂਦਰਤ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ।– ਨਹੀਂ, ਇਹ ਸੰਭਵ ਨਹੀਂ। ਭਾਰਤ ਮਰਦ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੁਲਕ ਹੈ, ਇਸ ਲਈ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵੀ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਹੀਰੋ ‘ਤੇ ਕੇਂਦਰਤ ਰਹੇਗਾ।"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو أول من وضع أسس المعتزلة ورأسهم؟","answer":"الإجابة: عمرو بن عبيد ، وواصل بن عطاء "},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الذي حاول قومه تعذيبه بالنار فجعلها الله عليه بردًا وسلامًا ؟","answer":"الإجابة: إبراهيم عليه السلام"},{"question":"नेपाली चलचित्र उद्योगको स्थापनामा प्रारम्भिक प्रभावहरू के के थिए?","answer":"नेपाली चलचित्र उद्योग, जसलाई कलिउड पनि भनिन्छ, यसको जरा भारतीय र अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय सिनेमाको प्रारम्भिक प्रभावहरूमा फेला पार्छ। चलचित्र निर्माण प्रविधिको आगमन र भारतीय चलचित्रको लोकप्रियताले नेपाली चलचित्रको सुरुवातलाई प्रेरित गर्‍यो।"},{"question":"ਮੈਂ ਪੜਛੱਤੀ ਦੀ ਧੂੜ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਹ ਲਿਆ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੈਨੂੰ ਹਿਚਕੀ ਆਈ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਂ ਛਿੱਕ ਮਾਰੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਂ ਛਿੱਕ ਮਾਰੀ।"},{"question":"西门庆对后世的影响是什么？","answer":"西门庆是一个具有代表性的人物，他反映了当时社会中的一些现实问题，比如道德的沦丧、人性的扭曲。西门庆的故事也给后世留下了深刻的印象，成为了人们反思的对象。"},{"question":"Биз жашаган планетанын жаңы өзгөрүүлөрү жөнүндө жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Абанын эң төмөн жана эң бийик деңгээли:Мындан 25 жыл мурун 1983-жылдын 21-июлунда Антарктикадагы советтик “Чыгыш” станциясында аба ырайынын эң төмөн деңгээли,тактап айтканда, -89,2 градус катталган. Ал эми 1992-жылы сентябрда Ливиянын Эль-Азизия шаарында абанын температурасы +58 градуска жеткен."},{"question":"வருகின்ற கோடை விடுமுறையில் காற்றாலை மின் உற்பத்தியை நேரில் காண்பதற்கு ஆரல்வாய்மொழிக்குச் செல்கிறேன் – இத்தொடர் கால வழுவமைதிக்கு எடுத்துக்காட்டாக அமைவது எவ்வாறு?","answer":"கோடையில் பள்ளி விடுமுறை என்பதால் ஆரல்வாய்மொழிக்குச் செல்லத் திட்டமிட்டிருக்கும் உறுதித்தன்மை நோக்கி காலவழுவமைதிக்கு எடுத்துக்காட்டாக இத்தொடர் அமைகிறது."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றைத்தருக ","answer":"பெரியார் என அனைவராலும் அன்பாக அழைக்கப்படும் ஈ.வெ. ராமசாமி அவர்கள் செப்டம்பர் 17, 1879-ம் ஆண்டு ஈரோட்டில் பிறந்தார். இவர் சமூக சீர்திருத்தத்திற்காகவும், சாதி வேற்றுமையினை அகற்றுவதற்காகவும், மூடநம்பிக்கைகளை மக்களிடமிருந்து களைவதற்காகவும், பெண் விடுதலைக்காகவும், சாதி மற்றும் பாலின சமத்துவம் போன்ற கொள்கைக்காகவும் போராடிய மிகப்பெரிய பகுத்தறிவாளர். தந்தை பெரியாரின் பொன்மொழிகளுள் சில.உற்சாகம் வேண்டுமானாலும்பிற மனிதனுக்கு தொண்டுசெய்வதன் மூலம் தேடிக்கொள்.யார் சொல்லி இருந்தாலும்எங்கு படித்திருந்தாலும்நானே சொன்னாலும்உனது புத்திக்கும் அறிவுக்கும்பொருந்தாத எதையும் நம்பாதே.உன் சத்திரத்தை விடஉன் முன்னோரை விடஉன் வெங்காயம்வெளக்கமாத்தாய் விடஉன் அறிவு பெரிது அதை சிந்தி.உருவில் மனிதனாகவும்செயலில் மிருகமாகவும்இருப்பதய் மாற்றி மனித தன்மை உடையமனித சமுதாயத்தை உருவாக்குவதே எனது லட்சியம்.ஒவ்வொரு மனிதனும் செத்து போவது உண்மைதான்என்றாலும் அவனோடு அவனுடைய முயற்சிகளும்அவன் துவக்கிய காரியங்களும் செத்து போய்விடுவதில்லை."},{"question":"请用简洁的语言回答以下问题：问题：临床心理学如何应用于儿童和青少年？","answer":"答案：临床心理学在儿童和青少年领域应用包括儿童发展评估、行为问题治疗、学业困扰辅导等。"},{"question":"රොනල්ඩ්ස්වේ ගුවන් තොටුපළ පිහිටා ඇත්තේ කුමන දූපතේද?","answer":"රොනල්ඩ්ස්වේ ගුවන්තොටුපළ (Manx: Purt Aer Vannin, Ronaldsway Airport ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ) (IATA: IOM, ICAO: EGNS) පිහිටා  ඇත්තේ මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය සහ අයර්ලන්තය අතර අයර්ලන්ත මුහුදේ   බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය කිරීටයේ ස්වයං-පාලන   වන අයිල් ඔෆ් මෑන් හි ය. ගුවන් තොටුපළ දිවයිනේ දකුණු කොටසේ කාසල්ටවුන් නගරය ආසන්නයේ පිහිටා  ඇත. එය අයිල් ඔෆ් මෑන් සඳහා ප්‍ රධාන සිවිල් ගුවන් තොටුපළ ලෙස ක්‍රියා කරන අතර දේශීය හා  ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් ගමන් සපයයි."},{"question":"محمد استغرق 10 دقائق لبيت وليد واستغرق ذهابهما لبيت خالد 7 دقائق، وعندما عاد أحمد إلى منزله استغرقه ذلك  3 دقائق، فكيف يكون ذلك؟","answer":"منازل الثلاثة الأصدقاء على نفس الاستقامة وبيت خالد يكون بين بيوت الكل من أحمد ووليد"},{"question":"Maxaa loo yaqaanaa Codka uu Geela sameeyo?","answer":"Waxaa loo yaqaanaa Codka uu Geela sameeyo Olol."},{"question":"یک سؤال طرح کنید که جواب آن متن زیر باشد:شکار بیش از حد و صید بی رویه نیز باعث کاهش بعضی گونه‌های جانوری شده است. وقتی شکارچیان برای تفریح یا استفاده از پوست، شاخ‌ها و استخوان، حیواناتی مثل گورخر، آهو یا پرندگان را در یک دشت محاصره و به آنها حمله می‌کنند، به تدریج نسل این گونه‌ها رو به کاهش می‌گذارد یا در خطر انقراض قرار می‌گیرد.","answer":"این سؤال می‌تواند برای پاسخ موردنظر، مناسب باشد: شکار بی رویه چگونه نسل بسیاری از جانوران را در خطر انقراض قرار می دهند؟"},{"question":"Buuge ayad bilowday?","answer":"Assalamu-Alaikum dhamaantii jimce wanaagsan walaayaal caafimaad iyo cibaado suuban  baan idin rajaynayaa dhamantiin.#Bacdayn maanta waa jimce buugee Buugee bilowdy.. "},{"question":"What is the capital of Laos?","answer":"The capital of Laos is Vientiane."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga:“Ambony fipetraka _ fa ambany fijery”","answer":"“Ambony fipetraka Andriamanitra fa ambany fijery”"},{"question":"د مقالې لنډیز:  د مانچسټر یونایټډ ډیو مارکوس روجو او انجل دی ماریا د ایسټر د یکشنبې په ورځ لیسبون ته د الوتنې په واسطه د آسټن ویلا په وړاندې د 3-1 بریا ولمانځله. د یونایټډ مدافع روجو د خپل ځان یو انځور اپلوډ کړ چې د ارجنټاین د ملي لوبډلې د ډیا ماریا او د هغوی د کورنیو ترڅنګ په یوه خصوصي الوتکه کې ناست دی. روجو، چې د خپلې میرمنې او لور تر څنګ ناست و، د ویلا په وړاندې بشپړ 90 دقیقې لوبې وکړې پداسې حال کې چې د پریمیر لیګ ریکارډ لاسلیک کولو ډی ماریا د وروستي 20 لپاره راغلل. مارکوس روجو (په ښي اړخ کې) له خپلې کورنۍ او انجل دی ماریا سره پرتګال ته د سفر پر مهال انځورونه وړاندې کوي. دواړه روجو (په چپ اړخ کې) او دی ماریا (په ښي اړخ کې) د شنبې په ورځ د مانچسټر یونایټډ لخوا د اسټون ویلا په وړاندې په ۳-۱ ماتې کې ولیدل شول. د مانچسټر یونایټډ او ارجنټاین ډوډۍ د دوبي د لیږد په کړکۍ کې اولډ ټرافورډ ته حرکت کوي. پرتګال د روجو او ډی ماریا دواړو لپاره پیژندل شوی منزل دی ځکه چې دوی په ترتیب سره د سپورتینګ لیسبون او بینفیکا لپاره لوبیدلي مخکې لدې چې په پای کې په دوبي کې متحده ایالاتو سره یوځای شي. روجو د شنبې په ماښام د غلطو دلایلو له امله سرلیکونه جوړ کړل ځکه چې د یکشنبې په ورځ په ځانګړي ډول د میل په اړه څرګنده کړه چې هغه د فټنس ښوونکي سارا واټسن سره اړیکه درلوده. هغې ادعا وکړه چې روجو پیسې وړاندیز کړې چې شپه له هغه سره تیر کړي مخکې لدې چې په پای کې د 25 کلن سره خوب وکړي پرته لدې چې پوه شي چې هغه واده شوی او یوه لور لري. ویل کیږي چې د مانچسټر یونایټډ مدافع په اونۍ کې د 200,000،XNUMX پونډو په ارزښت هغې ته د څرګند پیغامونو او ننگو عکسونو سره بمبار کړی. سارا واټسن د تورونو له مخې د خپل نوم د پاکولو لپاره هوډ درلود. واټسن ادعا کوي چې هغې ته د روجو (ښي اړخ) سره د شپې تیرولو لپاره پیسې وړاندیز شوې وې مګر رد شوې. واټسن ادعا کوي چې یوې ورځپاڼې هغې ته د ۳۵۰۰۰ پونډو وړاندیز وکړ چې د روجو سره د هغې د اړیکې په اړه کیسه وپلوري. هغې د یونایټډ په کرسمس پارټي کې د روجو سره د لیدو پرمهال وویل: <unk> هغه زما ته راغی او ناست شو. د هغه انګلیسي ډېره خرابه وه خو هغه ډېر خبرې کوونکی و او زما په اړه یې ښې خبرې کولې چې زه څنګه ښکارېدم او دا چې هغه زما د ورساچ جامې څومره خوښوي. هغه وويل: \\"تاسو ښکلې ياست، تاسو دلته تر ټولو ښکلې نجلۍ ياست\\". دا ټول ډېر بې ارزښته وو، خو هغه دومره ښکلی و چې ما ورته خپله شمېره ورکړه. <unk>هغه له ما څخه وپوښتل چې دا څومره...","answer":"مارکوس روزو او انجیل دی ماریا به د ایسټر یکشنبه په پرتګال کې تیر کړي. د مانچسټر یونایټیډ مدافع روزو په الوتکه کې د ځان عکس پوسټ کړ. روجو د خپلې کورنۍ سره یوځای شو - د هغه میرمن او لور په ګډون. د ارجنټاین اکیس روزو د فټنس روزونکي سره په خوب کولو تورن شوی دی. ریډ ډیویلز د اپریل په ۱۲ د مانچسټر سیټي سره مخ کیږي."},{"question":"Maneran-tany, inona ny hosodoko malaza indrindra? i Léonard de Vinci no nandoko azy.","answer":"Ny hosodoko \\"La Joconde\\" no hosodoko malaza indrindra maceran-tany. Endrik'i Mona Lisa no nolokoin'i Léonard de Vinci tamin'izauy tamin'ny taona 1503-1506 /1513-1516-1517. (taona tay mazava)."},{"question":"Iza no vahiny tonga voalohany teto Madagasikara?1. Sinoa2. Arabo3. Portogey4. Frantsay","answer":"Valiny 2 - Ny Arabo no vahiny tonga voalohany teto Madagasikara tamin'ny taon-jato VIII."},{"question":"「手のひらを太陽に」の１番の歌詞で生きている友達はみみず、おけらと何？","answer":"あめんぼです。"},{"question":"¿Cuál fue la primera película de Walt Disney?","answer":"Blancanieves y los siete enanitos es el primer largometraje de Disney; fue lanzado en 1937."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa cuna xanuunka: Sababaha Keeno iyo qaababka loo dabiibo?","answer":"Cuna xanuunka wuxuu keeni karaa cuncun, sidoo kale waxaa adkaan karta in la liqo cuno ama la cabo biyo, xanuunka waxaa suurta gal ah inuu kasii daro marka qofku uu wax liqaayo, astaamaha kale waxaa ka mid ahCunaha oo qalayl noqdaQanjirada dhuunta oo bararaQumanka oo ay fulaan waxyaaba cadcadXabeebCuna xanuun wuxuu asiibi karaa qof kasta, hasa yeeshi khatartiisu waxay ku badan tahay dadka qaar sida:CaruurtaDadka caba sigaarkaDadka qaba xasaasiyadaDadka uu difaaca jirkoodu kala dhantaalan yahayDadka oo lala wadaaga boos ciriiri ah waxay kor uqaadi karta infekshanada ku dhaca qeybta kore ee habka hawa mareenka, taas oo keeni karta cuna xanuunMaxaa sababa cuna xanuunka?Infekshan uu keenay fayrusinta badan cunaha oo xanuuna waxaa sababa fayrus, infekshanka kale ee uu fayruska sababo waxaa ka mid ah hargabka, jadeecada, iyo busbuskaInfekshan ay keentay bakteeriyoBakteeriyada waxay sababi kartaa  infekshan keena cunaha oo xanuuna, waxaa ka mid ah infekshanadaas, gawracatada, xiiqdheertaWalxaha deegaankaCuna xanuunada oo dhan kama dhashaan fayrus ama bakteeriya, waxa yaabaha kale ee horseedi kara cunaha oo xanuun waxaa ka mid ahXasaasiyada, hawada oo qalayl ah, cabidda sigaarka, qeylida ama hadalka badan.Laab jeexa: Waa xaaladaha ku dhaca habka dheefshiidka, astaamaha uu leeyahayna waxaa ka mid ahCunaha oo xanuuna, xabeeb, laabjeex, lalabo.Gormaa la arkaa dhaqtarInta badan cuna xanuun uma baahna daryeel caafimaad, hasa yeeshee waa muhiim in aad aragtid dhaqtar hadii cuna xanuunkaaga oo ka badan yahay hal todobaada iyo hadii aad dareentid astaamahaan soo socdaNeef qaadashada oo adkaataKala goys yada oo ku xanuunaWax liqida oo adkaataDheg xanuunFuruuruc/finanQandho 38.33 digrii ama 101 FXaako dhiig wadataBuro kutaala cunahaXabeeb kabadan laba todobaad iyo ka badan.Sida guriga loogu daaweeyo cuna xanuunkaBiyo cusbo/milix leh oo lagu luqluqadoCabidda biyo badan oo diiran, sida shaaha, maraqIn laga fogaado xasaasiyad ciyaasha sida sigaarka iyo kiimikaalada kaleYareynta caabuqa ayadoo la isticmaalayo xanuun baabi’iyashaHadii infekshan uu sababay bakteeriyada waxaad ubaahan tahay in dhaqtar dawo kuu soo qoro oo aad sida uu ku faray u raacdidSida looga hortago cuna xanuunkaWaxyaabaha badan ee sababa waa infekshan, tilaabooyinka waxay ka hortagi karaa infekshan kugu dhaca mustaqbalka. Gacmaha oo si joogta ah loo dhaqo waxay dileysaa geermiska, bakteeriyada, iyo fayrusyada, tilaabooyinka kale waxaa ka mid ahHala wadaagin dadka weelasha wax lagu caboGacmaha saabuun isaga dhaq ama biyoYaree taabashada aad taabatid meelaha dadka intoo badan ay taabtaanYaree la kulan ka xasaasiyad kiciyaashaKa fogoow cabidda sigaarka."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය ගයනා  කරන්නේ කවුද?වරදක් කලත් සිතකින් නොවේ. රිදවන්නෙ පලිගන්නෙ ඇයි.ඔබ මෙන් ඇයත් ඇය මෙන් ඔබත් මට මාගෙ ඇස් දෙක වගෙයි..ඔබෙ ගිනි නිව ඇගෙ සිත දවා අප එක් වෙලා කුමටදෝ..වෙනසක් නොවී මගෙ හිස් අතින් පිසලන්නෙ කොයි කදුලදෝ..අසරන ඔබයි තනිවුණ ඇයයි මට සාප කර යාවි දෝ..ඔබෙ ලෝකයෙන් ඇගෙ ලෝකයෙන් සමුගන්න සිදුවේවිදො..","answer":"සනත් නන්දසිරි "},{"question":"kiongozi ni nani?","answer":"kiongozi ni mtu amabaye ana uwezo wa kufanya ushawishi kwa watu ili waweze kufanikisha malengo flanoi yaliyokusudia na kikundi. kiongozi pia anafanya kazi ya kuanzisha na kuendeleza malengo yaliyowekwa ili kuleta maendeleo ya taasisi husika."},{"question":"Iza no mpanjaka frantsay nogadraina nandritra ny Revolisiona Frantsay tamin'ny 1793?","answer":"Nogadraina i Louis XVI nandritra ny Revolisiona Frantsay tamin'ny 1793."},{"question":"* ما الأشعة التي تمتصها طبقة الأوزون ؟","answer":"فوق البنفسجية"},{"question":"Qual a resposta correta para a pergunta a seguir: Qual é o ponto mais alto no Oregon que também entrou em erupção em torno de 220-170 anos atrás?","answer":"A resposta correta é Mount Hood"},{"question":"सिंधू संस्कृतीचे क्षेत्र सध्या कोठे आहे ?","answer":"सिंधू संस्कृतीचे क्षेत्र सध्या पाकिस्तानमध्ये आहे . "},{"question":"පහත යෙදුමේ තේරුම කුමක්ද?කිරි අප්පට බල්ලො පැනපි!","answer":"කවුද අප්පේ මේ කිරි අප්ප?  ඉස්සර කිරි කියන කොටස මුලට දාල තමන්ගෙ  අම්මගෙ පාර්ශ්වයේ නෑයින් ඇඳින්නුව සමහර පැතිවල ! තාත්තගෙ  තාත්ත, අත්ත/ මුත්ත වෙනකොට අම්මගෙ තාත්ත  කිරි අත්ත/ කිරිමුත්ත වුනා . සමහරු කිරි අප්ප/ කිරි අප්පොච්චි  කියලත් කිව්ව!! කිරි අම්ම කිව්වෙ අම්මගෙ අම්මට.   පස්සෙකාලෙක මේක කවලම්වුණා. විශේෂයෙන් මේ කිරි අම්මලගෙ දානෙ නිසා. ඒකෙ ඉස්සර කිරි අම්මල එක්කන් එන්න පාන්දර ම කලුවරේ එලි පත්තුකරන් ගියේ කිරි අප්ප( අම්මගෙ තාත්ත ) ඉතින්  එහෙම  යනකොට බල්ලො පැන්නම දානෙ අවුල්. මේ වැඩේ කිරි අම්මල තනියම සංවිධානය  කරගන්නකොට කිරි අප්ප කියල කුඩා දරුවෙක් ගත්ත! "},{"question":"Em \\"Aprendizado de Máquina,\\" explique o termo \\"Aprendizado Não-Supervisionado\\".","answer":"O \\"Aprendizado Não Supervisionado\\" é um ramo do \\"Aprendizado de Máquina,\\" onde os algorítimos são treinados, em dados não rotulados, buscando identificar padrões e estruturas ocultas nos dados, como conjuntos (\\"clusters\\") em dados de agrupamento."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最高的瀑布是哪個？","answer":"答案：天使瀑布（Angel Falls）"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'ilmu dunia'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud ilmu pengetahuan hanya untuk keperluan semasa hidup sahaja"},{"question":"පැණි මීයේ කෑ මුත් බඩගිනි නැද්දමෙහි පැණි මීයේ යනු මොනවාද?","answer":"මී වදයේ ඇති පැණිමීයේ පැණි = මීපැණි"},{"question":"පහත උපමාවට පසුබිම් වූ කතාව කුමක්ද?\\"පණ්ඩිතයට එදණ්ඩේ යන්න බෑ \\"","answer":"ඇත්තටම මේ කතාව ගොඩාක් අය හිතාගෙන ඉන්නේ මේ වැරදි විදියට . පණ්ඩිත මිනිස්සුන්ට ඒ කියන්නේ දැනුම වැඩි ගැබුරින් හිතන මිනිස්සු එදණ්ඩ ( ඇල මාර්ගයක් තුලින් එගොඩ විමට ඇති ලි දණ්ඩ) හරහා  යන්න බැ කියලා , මොකද ඔක වැටෙයි කියලා  හිතන හින්දා  කියලා .නමුත් ඇත්තටම මිට පසුබිම් උන කතාව වෙනස් එකක් . ඒ කියන්නේ වලන් කද ගෙනියන මනුස්සයන්ට  ඉස්සර පණ්ඩිතයා  කියලා  ව්‍යවහාර කරලා  තියෙනවා .ඉතින් ලියක දෙපැත්තේ වලන් තියාගෙන කරෙ තියාගෙන හරියට බැලන්ස් කරගෙන එදණ්ඩේ යන්න අමාරුයි . එකයි පණ්ඩිතයන්ට එදණ්ඩේ යන්න බෑ  කියන්නේ."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'ada hati'. Nyatakan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud ada keinginan yang melebihi kesanggupan. Contoh ayat: Jamal ada ahti hendak meminang anak hartawan itu."},{"question":"Escreva uma mensagem de parabéns para o meu melhor amigo.","answer":"Feliz Aniversário, amigo!Hoje celebramos a passagem de mais um ano em que você nos honra com a sua personalidade fantástica. A nossa amizade enche a minha vida de luz e harmonia. Você está sempre aqui para me ajudar e suportar nos momentos altos e baixos da vida. A sua bondade genuína, positividade e habilidade de procurar sempre ver o melhor em cada situação me inspiram a ser uma pessoa melhor.Neste dia especial, te desejo felicidade abundante, sucesso e inúmeras aventuras.Obrigada por ser o amigo fenomenal que você é. Vamos brindar a mais um ano repleto de momentos preciosos!"},{"question":"Indro misy toe-javatra: \\"Voankazo miendrika rotsa-dranomaso ny poara misy tohotra malefaka sy mamy izay matetika nohanina vaovao na am-bifotsy.\\" Inona no fanontaniana azo apetraka raha ohatra ka \\"ny poara\\" no valiny?","answer":"Ny fanontaniana azo apetraka hahazoana ny valiny hoe \\"ny poara\\" dia : Iza amin'ireo voankazo miendrika ranomaso no manana endrika malefaka sy mamy, ary matetika no hanina vaovao na am-bifotsy?"},{"question":"શબ્દસમૂહ એટલે શું?","answer":"‘શબ્દસમૂહ’ તત્પુરુષ સમાસ છે, શબ્દસમૂહ એટલે (એકથી વધારે) શબ્દોનો સમૂહ. આમ, સામાસિક શબ્દ પોતે શબ્દસમૂહને બદલે ‘એક શબ્દ’ નું કામ કરે છે. દા. ત.,તમે કશીય ચિંતા કર્યા વિના બેસો. તમે નિશ્ચિન્ત બેસો. વાક્ય (1) માં ‘કશીય ચિંતા કર્યા વિના' એ શબ્દસમૂહ છે. સ્વતંત્ર રીતે એનો ભાગ્યે જ કશો સ્પષ્ટ અર્થ છે, પણ વાક્યમાં પ્રયોજાતાં એ શબ્દસમૂહ સાથે (સ + અર્થ) બને છે.વાક્ય (2) માં જે અર્થ શબ્દસમૂહ (કશીય ચિંતા કર્યા વિના) થી મળે છે, તે જ અને તે જ અર્થ એક શબ્દ (‘નિશ્ચિન્ત’) થી મળે છે. આ રીતે શબ્દસમૂહથી વાક્યમાં લાઘવ, સરળતા, સચોટતા ઉપરાંત ભાષાવિચારને પ્રૌઢિ પ્રાપ્ત થાય છે.ભાષાવિચારની અભિવ્યક્તિમાં સામાસિક ઉપરાંત અન્ય શબ્દસમૂહો પણ જુદે જુદે સ્તરે, વાક્યબોધ કે વાક્યઅર્થના ઘડતર માટે પૂરક થતા હોય છે. વ્યક્તિ બોલવામાં સરળતા ઇચ્છે છે, પરિણામે સમયાંતરે જે-તે શબ્દસમૂહો એકાદ શબ્દનું રૂપ પકડી લે છે."},{"question":"குடும்பம் என்னும் சிறிய அமைப்பிலிருந்தே மனித சமூகம் என்னும் பரந்த அமைப்பு கட்டமைக்கப்படுகிறது – எவ்வாறு? விளக்குக.","answer":"குடும்பம் என்ற அமைப்பு ஏற்படுவதற்கு அடிப்படை திருமணமே.குடும்பம், திருமணம் இரண்டும் ஒன்றையொன்று சார்ந்து உள்ளது. நாணயத்தின் இருபக்கங்கள் போலகுடும்பமும்திருமணமும் உள்ளது. திருமணம், குடும்பம் தொல்காப்பியத்திலோ சங்க இலக்கியத்திலோ இடம் பெறவில்லை குடும்பம் என்ற சொல் திருக்குறளில் பயின்று வருகிறது.கட்டமைப்பு:* ‘குடும்பு’ எனும் சொல் கூடிவாழ்தல் என்று பொருள்படுகிறது. பண்டைத்தமிழர்கள் குடும்பம் 1 என்ற அமைப்புடன் வாழ்ந்த இடங்கள் பல. அவற்றுள் சில: புக்கில், தன்மனை.* புக்கில் என்பது தற்காலிகத் தங்குமிடம் ஆகும். தன்மனை என்பது திருமணம் ஆன கணவன், மனைவி பெற்றோரை விட்டு வாழும் இடம் ஆகும்.* மணந்தகம் என்பது மணம் புரிந்த கணவன் மனைவியும் சேர்ந்து வாழத் தொடங்கி முதல் குழந்தை பிறக்கும் வரை உள்ள காலக்கட்டத்தைக் குறிப்பது ஆகும். . சங்க காலத்தில் பெரும்பான்மையான சமூகத்தில் தாயே தலைமை ஏற்றிருப்பாள். பெண் திருமணம் செய்த பின்னும் தன் வீட்டிலே வாழ்க்கை நடத்தும் முறை இருந்தது. பெண் குழந்தைகள் பேறு முதன்மைப்படுத்தப்பட்டது.தந்தை வழிக் குடும்பம்:சங்க காலத்தில் தாய் வழிக் குடும்பம் போலவே தந்தை வழிக் குடும்பமும் வேரூன்றியது. பெண் திருமணம் ஆன பிறகு கணவனின் தந்தை வீட்டில் வாழ வேண்டும் என்பதை ‘மனையுறை மகளிர்க்கு ஆடவர்’ என்கிறது குறுந்தொகை.தனிக்குடும்பம்: தனிக்குடும்பம் என்பது படிமலர்ச்சியில் இறுதியில் ஏற்பட்டது. இது இன்று தொழிற் சமூகத்தில் பெரும்பான்மையாகக் காணப்படுகிறது. தனிக்குடும்பம், ஆதிக்குடிகளிடமும் இருந்தது என்று இனவரைவியல் ஆய்வுச் சுட்டுகிறது.விரிந்த சமூகம்:சங்க காலத்தில் தனிக்குடும்ப அமைப்பு விரிவு பெற்று இவர்களோடு பெற்றோர் ஒருவரின் தந்தையும் உடன் வாழும் விரிந்த குடும்பமாகக் காணமுடிகிறது. கணவன், மனைவி, குழந்தைகள் சேர்ந்து பெற்றோர்கள் சேர்ந்து வாழும் நேர்வழி விரிந்த குடும்ப முறை காணமுடிகிறது. இன்றைய மனித சமூக கட்டமைப்பில் தாய்வழிக் குடும்பம், தந்தைவழிக் குடும்பம் என்ற நிலையைக் கடந்து தனிக்குடும்பம் என்ற நிலைக்குத் தள்ளப்பட்டது. சங்கச் சமூகம் குடும்பம் என்ற அமைப்பிலிருந்தே மனித சமூகம் கட்டமைக்கப்படுகிறது. அவற்றின் தொடர்ச்சியாகவே இன்றைய கூட்டுக்குடும்பம், தனிக்குடும்பம் என்ற அலகைக் கொண்டதாக அமைகிறது. அதுவும் தந்தைவழிக் குடும்ப அமைப்பைக் கொண்டதாக இருக்கிறது. தொன்மைமிக்க இக்குடும்ப அமைப்பு முறை தமிழ்ச் சமூகத்தின் அடையாளமும் பெருமிதமும் ஆகும்.குடும்பமே சமூகத்தைக் கட்டமைக்கும் களம் :* குடும்பம் தனி மனிதருக்காகவும் சமுதாயத்திற்காகவும் பெரும் பங்காற்றுகிறது. மனித சமூகத்தின் அடிப்படைகளான அன்பு செலுத்துதல், பொருளாதாரப் பகிர்வு, பொழுதுபோக்கு, பாதுகாப்பு, சமயச்செயல்கள், கல்விபெறுதல் ஆகியவை குடும்பத்திலே கற்பிக்கப்படுகின்றன.* பண்பாட்டைக் குழந்தைப் பருவத்தில் குடும்பம் கற்றுக் கொடுக்கிறது. சமுதாயத்தின் நெறிமுறைகள் அன்றாட வாழ்வில் பின்பற்றப்பட வேண்டிய பழக்கவழக்கங்கள் பொருளாதாரச் செயல்களாகச் செய்யும் முறைகள், சமுதாய சமய வாழ்வில் ஆற்ற வேண்டிய கடமைகள் போன்ற எண்ணற்ற வகைகளில் குடும்பம் குழந்தைகளுக்குப் பயிற்சியளிப்பதால் மனித சமூகம் சிறப்பாகக் கட்டமைக்கப்படும்.* பண்பாட்டு வயமாக்கல் நிகழ்ச்சியில் குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்கள் ஒரு மாதிரி குழுவாகச் செயல்படுகின்றனர்.* குடும்பம் என்பது தனது உறுப்பினர்கள் என்ற நிலையில் குடும்ப உறுப்பினர்களுக்குப் பயிற்சிகளை வழங்கி அமைதியும் ஒழுங்கும் கொண்ட ஒரு சிறந்த சமுதாயம் அமைய அடிப்படையாக விளங்குவதால், குடும்பம் என்னும் சிறிய அமைப்பில் இருந்தே மனித சமூகம் என்னும் பரந்த அமைப்புக் கட்டமைக்கப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"බුදු දහමේ එන  රූපය ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"අනුන්ට ඔවුන්ගේ කැමැත්තේ සැටියට හැසිරෙන්නට නො දී තමන්ගේ කැමැත්තේ හැටියට අනුන් හසුරුවන රාජාදීහු අධිපතීහු ය. ඔවුන් කෙරෙහි ඇති එසේ කළ හැකි බලය අධිපති බව ය. ඇතැම් පුද්ගලයන්ට මෙන් අධිපතිබලය ඇත්තා වූ නාම රූප ධර්මයෝ ඇත්තාහ. ඔවුන්ගේ අධිපති බව නිසා ඔවුන්ට අනුකූල වීම් වශයෙන් ඇතැම් නාම රූප ධර්මයෝ උපදිති. එසේ උපදනා නාම රූප ධර්මයනට බලවත් ධර්මයන්ගේ අධිපති බව ඉපදීමේ හේතුවක් වේ. ඉපදීමට උපකාරයක් වේ. එබැවින් අධිපති භාවය ඇත්තා වූ ධර්මය තමා නිසා උපදනා ධර්මයට අධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෙන් උපකාර වේය යි කියනු ලැබේ. ඒ උපකාර ඒ ධර්මය කෙරෙහි ඇත්තා වූ අධිපති ශක්තිය ම ය. ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයය සහජාතාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයයි අධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය දෙවැදෑරුම් වේ. එයින් ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍ය වන්නේ ගරු කළ යුතු අරමුණ ය. මඟ යන කල්හි කසල ගොඩක් දුටුවකුට එය අමතක වන්නාක් මෙන්, මුදල් ගොඩක් දුටුවකුට එය අමතක නො වන්නේ ය. ඔහුට එය නැවත නැවත සිහි වන්නේය. සිහිවීමය යනු මුදල් ගොඩ පිළිබඳව නැවත නැවත සිත් ඇතිවීමය. මුදල් ගොඩ දුටුවහුට එය පිළිබඳව නැවත නැවතත් සිත් ඇති වන්නේ මුදලෙහි ඇති එය අරමුණු කොට නැවත නැවත සිත් ඉපදවීමේ ශක්තිය නිසා ය. කසල ගොඩෙහි එබන්දක් නැති බැවින් දුටුවහුට එය අමතක වන්නේ ය. මුදල් ගොඩෙහි ඇති එය ගැන නැවත නැවත සිත් ඉපදවීමේ ශක්තිය එහි අධිපති භාවය ය. ඒ අධිපති භාවය නිසා එයට අවනතව බොහෝ චිත්ත චෛතසිකයෝ උපදිති. ඒ චිත්ත චෛතසිකයන්ගේ උත්පත්තියට මුදල් ගොඩ අධිපති භාවයෙන් උපකාර වේ. එසේ අධිපති භාවයෙන් තමාට අනුකූලව චිත්ත චෛතසිකයන් ඉපදීමට හේතුවන ඉෂ්ටාරම්මණයෝ ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වෙති.ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ත්‍රිරාශියවර්තමාන වූ ද අතීත වූ ද අනාගත වූ ද ගරු කළ යුතුවූ ඉෂ්ට නිෂ්පන්න රූප අටළොසය, ද්වේෂ මූලද්වයය, මෝහ මූලද්වයය, දුඃඛ සසහගත කාය විඥානයය යන මොවුන් හැර ඉතිරි සිත් සූඅසූවය, ද්වේෂ ඊර්‍ෂ්‍යා මාත්සර්‍ය්‍ය කෞතෘත්‍ය විචිකිත්සා වර්ජිත චෛතසික සත් සාළිසය, කාලමුත්ත නිර්වාණයය යන මොහු ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය ධර්මයෝ ය.ඒ ධර්ම ගරු කොට අරමුණු කරන්නා වූ ලෝභ මූල සිත් අටය, මහා කුසල් සිත් අටය, මහා ක්‍රියා ඥාන සම්ප්‍ර‍යුක්ත සිත් සතරය, ලෝකෝත්තර සිත් අටය යන සිත් විසි අටය, ද්වේෂ ඊර්‍ෂ්‍යා මාත්ර්‍ස්‍ය කෞතෘත්‍ය විචිකිත්සා අප්‍ර‍මාණ්‍ය වර්ජිත චෛතසික පන්සාළිසය යන මොහු ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෝත්පන්න ධර්මයෝ ය.කිසි ධර්මයක් ගරු කොට අරමුණු නො කරන්නා වූ ද ගරු කොට අරමුණු නො කරන අවස්ථාවෙහි වූ ද ලෞකික සිත් එක් අසූවය, චෛතසික දෙපනසය, චිත්තජාදි රූප කොටස් සතය යන මොහු ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යනීක ධර්මයෝ ය.ලෝකෝත්තර සිත්වල එක ම අරමුණ නිවන ය. ඒවායින් නිවන අරමුණු කරන්නේ ද ගරු කොට ම ය. එබැවින් ලෝකෝත්තරය සෑම කල්හි ම ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෝත්පන්නයක් වේ. ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යනීකවලදී ලෝකෝත්තර චිත්තය නො ගන්නා ලද්දේ එහි ගරු නො කොට අරමුණු කරන අවස්ථාවක් නැති බැවිනි. ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෝත්පන්න වන ලෞකික සිත් විස්ස සැම කල්හි ම යම් කිසිවක් ගරුකොට අරමුණු කරන්නේ නොවේ. ගරුකොට අරමුණු නො කරන අවස්ථාවෙහි වූ ඒ සිත් ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය නො ලබන බැවින් ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යනීක වලට ද ඒවා ගනු ලැබේ.ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වශයෙන් කියන ලද ධර්ම සියල්ල ම ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෝත්පන්න වශයෙන් කියන ලද ධර්ම සියල්ලට ම ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වන්නේ නො වේ. ඒවායේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වන පිළිවෙළ මෙසේය: ලෝභ මූල සිත් අටය, ලෞකික කුසල් සිත් සතළොසය, දුඃඛ සහගත කාය විඥානය හැර ලෞකික විපාක එක් තිසය, ක්‍රියා සිත් විස්සය, ඉෂ්ට නිෂ්පන්න රූප අටළොසය යන මොහු ලෝභ මූල සිත් අටට ආරම්මණාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වේ. ලෞකික කුසල සිත් සතොළොස මහා කුශල ඥාන විප්‍ර‍යුක්ත සිත් සතරට ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වේ. ලෞකික කුසල් සිත් සතොළොසය, අර්හත් මාර්ග අර්හත් ඵල වර්ජිත ලෝකෝත්තර සිත් සයය, නිවනය යන මොහු මහා කුශල ඥාන සම්ප්‍ර‍යුක්ත සිත් සතරට ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වේ. අර්හත් මාර්ගය ය, අර්හත් ඵලය ය, නිවනය යන මොහු මහාක්‍රියා ඥානසම්ප්‍ර‍යුක්ත සිත් සතරට ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වෙති. නිවන ලෝකෝත්තර සිත් අටට ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වේ.ඡන්දය, චිත්තය, විරිය, වීමංසය යි අධිපති ධර්ම සතරෙකි. ඒවායේ අධිපති බව පවත්නේ තමන් හා එක්ව උපදනා ධර්මයන්ට ය. එබැවින් ඒවාට සහජාතාධිපතිය යි කියනු ලැබේ. එහි ඡන්දය යනු යම් කිසිවක් සිදු කිරීම පිළිබඳ වූ බලවත් කැමැත්ත ය. තද ඕනෑකම ය. එය දෙපනස් චෛතසිකයන් අතුරෙන් ඡන්ද චෛතසිකය ය. දුබල ඡන්දය අධිපති නො වේ. මා විසින් දීම කළ යුතුය යි දීමට සිත නමාගත් තැනැත්තා කෙරෙහි, දීම සිදු කිරීම් වශයෙන් බලවත් ඡන්දය ඇති වේ. එය සිතත් තවත් චෛතසිකයනුත් සමග මිස හුදකලාව ඇති වන්නක් නො වේ. ඡන්දය ඇති වන කල්හි සිත ද එය හා ඇති වීමට සුදුසු චෛතසිකයෝ ද චිත්තජ රූපයෝ ද එයට අනුකූලව එය හා සමඟ ම උපදී. ඡන්දයට අනුව උපදනා වූ ඒ ධර්මයන් උපදින්නේ බලවත් ඡන්දය නිසා ය. ඡන්දය නැතහොත් ඒ ධර්මයෝ නූපදනාහ. එබැවින් ඡන්දය ඒ ධර්මයන් හට අධිපති භාවයෙන් ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වේ යයි කියනු ලැබේ. චිත්තාදීන් සහජාත ධර්මයන්ට ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වන සැටි ද එසේ ම දත යුතුය. ඡන්ද චිත්ත විරිය වීමංස යන ධර්ම සතර එකට බැඳී එකවර උපදී. එහෙත් එක් වරක දී අධිපති වන්නේ ඉන් එකක් පමණකි. ඉතිරි තුන ම තම තමන් අධිපති නොවන අවස්ථාවේදී අධිපති වන ධර්මයට අනුකූල වේ.සහජාතාධිපති ත්‍රිරාශියතම තමා අධිපති වන අවස්ථාවෙහි වූ දෙපනස් සාධිපති ජවන චිත්තයය, තත් සම්ප්‍ර‍යුක්ත ඡන්ද වීර්‍ය්‍ය වීමංශයෝ ය යන මොහු අධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය වන ධර්මයෝ ය.ඒ ඒ අවස්ථාවෙහි අධිපති වූ ධර්මයෙන් අන්‍ය වූ දෙපනස් සාධිපති ජවනය ය, විචිකිත්සා වර්ජිත චෛතසික එක් පනස ය, සාධිපති චිත්තජ රූපය යන මොහු ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයෝත්පන්නයෝ ය.අධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යය නො ලබන්නා වූ ද නො ලබන අවස්ථාවෙහි වූ ද කාම සිත් සිවුපනසය, මහද්ගත විපාක නවයය, චෛතසික දෙපනසය, ඒ ඒ අවස්ථාවෙහි අධිපති වන ධර්මයය, නිරාධිපති චිත්තජ රූපය, ප්‍ර‍තිසන්ධි කර්මජ රූපය, බාහිර රූපය, ආහාරජ රූපය, සෘතුජ රූපය, අසංඥ සත්ත්ව කර්මජ රූපය, ප්‍ර‍වෘත්ති කර්මජ රූපය යන මොහු සහජාතාධිපති ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යයාගේ ප්‍ර‍ත්‍යනීක ධර්මයෝ ය.සාධිපති ජවන දෙපනසය යනු මෝහ මූල සිත් දෙක හා හසිතෝත්පාදය හැර ඉතිරි ජවනයෝ ය. අධිපති ලැබෙන්නේ ද්වි හේතුක ත්‍රි හේතුක ජවනයන්හි ය."},{"question":"Iza no fanjakana lehibe indrindra any Etazonia araka ny velarantany?","answer":"Alaska no fanjakana lehibe indrindra any Etazonia amin'ny lafin'ny velarantany."},{"question":"පහත ප්‍රශ්නයට පිළිතුරු සපයන්න. ෆ්ලෑෂ් 4 වෙනි සීසන් එක නිකුත්වෙන්නේ කවදාද?","answer":"2017 ඔක්තෝබර් මස 10 වන දින"},{"question":"कोणते शहर पेशव्यांची राजधानी आहे?","answer":"पुणे शहर पेशव्यांची राजधानी आहे. "},{"question":"காந்தரக்கலை யாருடைய காலத்தில் அறிமுகப்படுத்தியது? 1. அசோகர் 2. கனிஷ்கர் 3. ஹர்சர்","answer":"விடை: 2. கனிஷ்கர். கனிஷ்கர் காலத்தில் மதுரா மற்றும் காந்தரக்கலை மிகவும் சிறப்பாக வளர்சியுற்றது. இந்திய கிரேக்கம் சேர்ந்த சிற்ப கலையே காந்தரக் கலை என அழைக்கப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"Viết một đoạn văn ngắn (khoảng 5 – 7 dòng) nêu cảm nghĩ của em về một nhân vật trong văn bản Bài học đường đời đầu tiên hoặc Ông lão đánh cá và con cả vàng, trong đoạn văn có sử dụng chủ ngữ là cụm từ. Xác định chủ ngữ là cụm từ trong đoạn văn đó.","answer":"Dế Mèn là một chàng thanh niên cường tráng. Cậu ta tự ý thức được về bản thân của mình – một vẻ đẹp khỏe khoắn. Thế nhưng tính tình của Dế Mèn lại vô cùng hống hách, ngang bướng, thích lên mặt dạy đời, trêu ghẹo người khác. Chính vì vậy cậu đã có một bài học để đời – bớt sống ích kỉ, thay vào đó là biết quan tâm đến người khác hơn."},{"question":" Sheeg Magaca Caasimada Ugu Da’da Weyn Adduunka (Caalamka)?","answer":"Waa Magaalada Dimishiiq Ee Dalka Suuriya (Syria)"},{"question":"炭酸水で水に溶けている気体と言えば何？","answer":"二酸化炭素です。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai melihat ulat\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sangat benci (meluat) melihat sesuatu."},{"question":"Manene gari a zamantakewa a Ƙasar hausa?","answer":"Haɗuwar unguwanni da yawa a waje guda shi yake samar da gari. Shi kuma gari, dagaci ne yake jagorancinsa. Matsayin dagaci shi ne kamar matsayin kansila a yanzu.Ana naɗa dagaci ne a matakin farko ta hanyar samun dattijo mai hankali daga cikin dattijan gari, wanda kuma jama’ar garin suke girmamawa, mai haƙuri da kawaici a naɗa shi a matsayin dagaci tare da goyon bayan sauran dattawan da ke wannan gari. Idan kuma wannan dattijo ya rasu, to sai ‘ya’yansa su gaje shi idan akwai. Dagan sarautar ta zama gado.Dagaci shi ne idon hukuma a garinsa. A duk lokacin da hukuma take son yin hulɗa da jama’ar garin baki ɗaya, to ta hannunsa ake bi, shi kuma sai ya miƙa saƙon zuwa ga masu unguwanninsa."},{"question":"Mustafa Kemal Atatürk soyadını kim önerdi?","answer":"Savın çıkış noktası olarak Dilâçar'ın ölümünden iki yıl sonra, 1981 tarihli Süreç dergisinin beşinci sayısında Aytunç Altındal'ın Dilâçar için kullandığı \\"Mustafa Kemal'e, Türklerin Babası anlamında kullanılması kaydıyla Atatürk adının verilmesini öneren üç kişiden biri, hatta birincisi olarak tanınır.\\" sözlerini ..."},{"question":"It should answer 2011 నాటికి మంచాల గ్రామ జనాభా ఎంత?, ","answer":"మంచాల, గుంటూరు జిల్లా, చేబ్రోలు మండలానికి చెందిన గ్రామము. ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన చేబ్రోలు నుండి 4 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన గుంటూరు నుండి 16 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 555 ఇళ్లతో, 1939 జనాభాతో 317 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 973, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 966. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 6 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 214. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 590309[1].పిన్ కోడ్: 522212. ఎస్.టి.డి.కోడ్ = 08644."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: പ്രശസ്തരായ ചില ശാസ്ത്രജ്ഞർ ആരൊക്കെയാണ്‌?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ആൽബർട്ട് ഐൻസ്റ്റീൻ, മേരി ക്യൂറി, ഐസക് ന്യൂട്ടൺ, ചാൾസ് ഡാർവിൻ, നിക്കോള ടെസ്ല, ഗലീലിയോ ഗലീലി, സ്റ്റീഫൻ ഹോക്കിംഗ്, അലക്സാണ്ടർ ഫ്ലെമിംഗ്, ജെയ്ൻ ഗൂഡാൽ, നീൽ ഡിഗ്രാസ് ടൈസൺ"},{"question":"Qual a maior fonte de energia do Brasil?","answer":"Hidrelétrica."},{"question":"كمل الفقرة:وقال الكاتبان إن هناك عددا قليلا نسبيا من الشركات التي تتعرض للمشاكل في الوقت الحالي، لكن الاتجاه يبدو","answer":"سيئا، في وقت تحتفظ وكالة \\"موديز\\" بقائمة من الشركات ذات تصنيف \\"بي بي\\" (BB) سلبي أو أقل من ذلك."},{"question":"จงเติมข้อความต่อจากข้อความนี้ให้สมบูรณ์:  เริ่มต้นในเดือนมิถุนายน ค.ศ. 1941 มุสโสลินีได้ส่งกองทัพอิตาลีเพื่อเข้าร่วมในการรุกรานสหภาพโซเวียตและอิตาลีได้ประกาศสงครามต่อสหรัฐอเมริกาในเดือนธันวาคม ในปี ค.ศ. 1943 อิตาลีต้องประสบหายนะหลายครั้งภายหลังจากนั้นอีก: ในเดือนกุมภาพันธ์ กองทัพแดงได้ทำลายกองทัพอิตาลีในรัสเซียอย่างราบคาบ ในเดือนพฤษภาคม, ฝ่ายอักษะถูกขับไล่ออกจากแอฟริกาเหนือ เมื่อวันที่ 9 กรกฎาคม,","answer":"ฝ่ายสัมพันธมิตรได้บุกครองเกาะซิซิลี และเมื่อถึงวันที่ 16 ได้เห็นอย่างชัดเจนว่าการรุกรานในช่วงฤดูร้อนในสหภาพโซเวียตล้มเหลว ด้วยผลที่ตามมา, เมื่อวันที่ 25 กรกฎาคม สภาใหญ่แห่งฟาสซิสต์ได้ผ่านการลงมติไม่ไว้วางใจต่อมุสโสลินี วันต่อมา กษัตริย์ได้ปลดเขาออกจากผู้นำคณะรัฐบาลและควบคุมตัวเขาให้อยู่ในความดูแล เพื่อแต่งตั้งปีเอโตร บาโดลโยขึ้นเป็นนายกรัฐมนตรีแทนต่อจากเขา มุสโสลินีได้ถูกปลดปล่อยจากที่คุมขังในการตีโฉบฉวยแกรน์ แซสโซโดยทหารโดดร่มเยอรมันและหน่วยคอมมานโดวัฟเฟิน-เอ็สเอ็สภายใต้การนำโดยพันตรี  Otto-Harald Mors"},{"question":"\\"Indray andro dia nisy zazavavy kely iray antsoina hoe Sophie izay nanana alika mahatoky antsoina hoe Max. Indray andro, dia narary mafy i Max.\\"Manomeza tohiny ho an'ny tantara.","answer":"Indro misy tohiny iray ho an'ny tantara: \\"Na dia teo aza ny ezaka rehetra nataon'ny veterinera, dia tsy avotra i Max. Nitomany i Sophie noho ny fahafatesan’ilay namany malalany .\\""},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai tanduk bersendi gading\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud jodoh yang tidak sepadan."},{"question":" Inona avy ireo tombontsoa azo avy amin'ny fitsaboana génomika manokana ho an'ny fitsaboana?","answer":"Ny fanafody génomika manokana dia mampiasa ny mombamomba ny fototarazo tsirairay mba hanamafisana ny fitsaboana ara-pitsaboana, izay afaka manatsara ny fahombiazan'ny fikarakarana sy mampihena ny voka-dratsiny."},{"question":"கவிஞர் சிற்பி பாலசுப்பிரமணியம் அவர்களின் ஆசை என்ன ?","answer":"‘தமிழ் பல புதிய உள்ளடக்கங்களால் தன்னைப் புதுப்பித்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டும்; பழஞ்சிறப்பைத் தக்க வைத்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டும்’, என்பதே கவிஞர் சிற்பி பாலசுப்பிரமணியம் அவர்களின் ஆசை ஆகும்."},{"question":"Uma jovem órfã é transformada em uma princesa por uma fada madrinha. Qual é o filme? Dica: É da Disney.","answer":"O filme da Disney que se encaixa na descrição fornecida é \\"Cinderela\\" (Cinderella, em inglês). Na história de \\"Cinderela\\", a jovem órfã Cinderela é transformada em uma princesa com a ajuda de sua fada madrinha, o que a permite participar do baile real e, eventualmente, encontrar o amor. \\"Cinderela\\" é um dos clássicos animados da Disney e foi lançado em 1950."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Co to jest perceptron w kontekście uczenia maszynowego?","answer":"Oto odpowiedź.Perceptron wielowarstwowy (z ang. MLP) składa się z warstwy wejściowej, jednej lub więcej warstw ukrytych i warstwy wyjściowej. Warstwa wejściowa otrzymuje dane początkowe, takie jak obiekty ze zbioru danych. Warstwy ukryte wykonują obliczenia pośrednie, przypisując wagi do danych wejściowych i przekazując wyniki przez funkcje aktywacyjne. Warstwa wyjściowa generuje ostateczne przewidywania lub dane wyjściowe modelu.Trenowanie MLP obejmuje dwa kluczowe procesy: propagację w przód i propagację wsteczną. Podczas propagacji do przodu dane wejściowe są wprowadzane do sieci, a dane wyjściowe są obliczane warstwa po warstwie, aż do uzyskania ostatecznej prognozy. Wyniki na wyjściu są następnie porównywane z oczekiwaniami w celu obliczenia błędu."},{"question":"شنو هي السوره من القران اللي تسمات على اسم من النجوم؟","answer":"الإجابة: سورة الشمس."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Yaya za a rubuta ɗari ɗaya da casa'in da biyu a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 192"},{"question":"Who starred as Juno MacGuff opposite Michael Cera in the 2007 film Juno?","answer":"Ellen Page/Elliot Page"},{"question":"多倫多有什麼旅遊好地方？","answer":"可以去：多倫多群島、安省遊樂宮（Ontario Place）、加拿大國家電視塔（CN Tower）皇家安大略博物館（Royal Ontario Museum）以及尼加拉大瀑布（Niagara Falls）等參觀。"},{"question":"অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি উপযুক্ত শিরোনাম প্রস্তাব করুন |বছরের শুরুতে শিশুরা নতুন বই পেলেও এ বছর বেশি দিন স্কুলে যাবার সুযোগ হয়নিশিক্ষা মন্ত্রণালয় জানিয়েছে কওমি মাদ্রাসা ছাড়া সব ধরণের শিক্ষা প্রতিষ্ঠানের জন্য এ সিদ্ধান্ত কার্যকর হবে। এর আগের ঘোষণা অনুযায়ী আগামী ৩১শে অগাস্ট এ ছুটি শেষ হওয়ার কথা থাকলেও এখনি শিক্ষা প্রতিষ্ঠান না খোলার ব্যাপারে অভিভাবক ও বিশেষজ্ঞদের দিক থেকে মতামত আসছিলো। এর আগে বাংলাদেশে মার্চ মাসের আট তারিখে প্রথম করোনাভাইরাস আক্রান্ত ব্যক্তি শনাক্ত হবার পর ১৬ই মার্চ সরকার ঘোষণা দেয়, ১৭ই মার্চ থেকে ৩১ মার্চ পর্যন্ত স্কুল, কলেজসহ সব ধরণের শিক্ষা প্রতিষ্ঠান ও কোচিং সেন্টার বন্ধ থাকবে।চলতি বছরের পয়লা এপ্রিল থেকে শুরু হতে যাওয়া এইচএসসি ও সমমানের পরীক্ষাও তখন স্থগিত করা হয়।পরে সরকার যখন প্রথম দফা সাধারণ ছুটি ঘোষণা করে, তখন সব শিক্ষাপ্রতিষ্ঠানে ছুটির মেয়াদ ৯ই এপ্রিল পর্যন্ত বাড়ানো হয়।বিবিসি বাংলায় আরও পড়ুন:পঞ্চম শ্রেনীর সমাপনী পিইসি পরীক্ষা হচ্ছে না এ বছরনিরাপদে স্কুল খুলতে যেসব নির্দেশনা মানার প্রস্তাব করা হয়েছেশিশুদের জেএসসি পরীক্ষার যৌক্তিকতা কী? ওই সময় পর্যন্ত সকল স্কুল, কলেজ, মাদ্রাসা, বিশ্ববিদ্যালয় ও কোচিং সেন্টারের শ্রেণীকক্ষে পাঠদান বন্ধ রাখার নির্দেশ দেয় শিক্ষা মন্ত্রনালয়।এরপর দফায় দফায় সাধারণ ছুটির মেয়াদ বৃদ্ধির সঙ্গে সঙ্গে শিক্ষা প্রতিষ্ঠানে ছুটির মেয়াদ বাড়ানো হয় এবং সবশেষ এ ছুটি ৩১শে অগাস্ট পর্যন্ত বাড়ানো হয়েছিলো। তবে মন্ত্রণালয়ের কর্মকর্তারা জানিয়েছেন শিক্ষা প্রতিষ্ঠান বন্ধ থাকলেও মাধ্যমিক পর্যায়ের শিক্ষার্থীদের জন্য 'আমার ঘরে আমার স্কুল' শিরোনামে সংসদ টেলিভিশনে ক্লাস চলছে।অপরদিকে, প্রাথমিক বিদ্যালয়ের শিক্ষার্থীদের জন্য 'ঘরে বসে শিখি' শিরোনামে সংসদ টেলিভিশনের মাধ্যমে ক্লাস নেয়া হচ্ছে।প্রসঙ্গত, বাংলাদেশে কোভিড-১৯ আক্রান্ত হয়ে এ পর্যন্ত  মোট মারা গেছেন ৪০৮২ জন। আর এখন পর্যন্ত করোনাভাইরাস আক্রান্ত শনাক্ত হয়েছেন মোট ৩ লাখ ২ হাজার ১৪৭ জন।করোনাভাইরাসের প্রাদুর্ভাব ঠেকাতে মাদ্রাসা সব শিক্ষা প্রতিষ্ঠানে ছুটি বাড়ছেকরোনাভাইরাস: সুস্থ হয়ে উঠতে কতদিন লাগে?নিজেকে যেভাবে নিরাপদ রাখবেন করোনাভাইরাস থেকে করোনাভাইরাস : কীভাবে বানাবেন আপনার নিজের ফেসমাস্কআপনার কি দ্বিতীয়বার কোভিড ১৯ সংক্রমণ হতে পারে?টাকার মাধ্যমে করোনাভাইরাস ছড়াতে পারে কি?","answer":"করোনা ভাইরাস: শিক্ষা প্রতিষ্ঠানে ছুটি বাড়লো, তেসরা অক্টোবর পর্যন্ত বন্ধ |"},{"question":"ජ්‍යාමිතියේ පියා කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"යුක්ලීඩ් යනු ජ්‍යාමිතියේ පියාය."},{"question":"జాయింట్ స్టాక్ కంపెనీకి గల ప్రయోజనాలను, పరిమితులను వివరింపుము. ","answer":"కంపెనీ వ్యవస్థ వలన ఈ క్రింది ప్రయోజనాలు ఉంటాయి.1. భారీ ఆర్థిక వనరులు : ప్రజల నుంచి విస్తారముగా నిధులు సేకరించడానికి కంపెనీ వ్యవస్థ అనువైనది. కంపెనీ వాటాలను చిన్నచిన్న మొత్తాలుగా విభజించి అమ్మడం వలన స్వల్ప ఆదాయముగల ప్రజలు కూడా వాటాలను సులభముగా కొనగలరు. అందువలన భారీ మూలధనాన్ని తేలికగా సేకరించవచ్చు.2. పరిమిత ఋణబాధ్యత : వాటాదారుల ఋణబాధ్యత వారి వాటా విలువకు పరిమితము అవుతుంది. కంపెనీ అప్పులు తీర్చడానికి సొంత ఆస్తులు తేనవసరము లేదు. వాటా సొమ్ము మాత్రమే కోల్పోతారు. నష్టభయం తక్కువ. అందువలన కంపెనీలో పెట్టుబడి పెట్టడానికి ప్రజలు ముందుకు వస్తారు.3. శాశ్వతత్వము : కంపెనీల చట్టం ప్రకారము కంపెనీకి ప్రత్యేక న్యాయసత్వము ఉన్నది. అందువలన కంపెనీ నిరాటంకముగా కొనసాగుతుంది. వాటాదారుల మరణము, దివాలా తీయడం వలన కంపెనీ మనుగడకు ఎటువంటి అంతరాయం కలగదు. అది నిరాటంకముగా కొనసాగుతుంది.4. వాటాల బదిలీ : పబ్లిక్ కంపెనీ వాటాలను ఇతరులు అనుమతి లేకుండా సులభముగా బదిలీ చేయవచ్చును. కంపెనీ వాటాలను స్టాక్ ఎక్స్చేంజిలో అమ్ముతారు. బదిలీ సౌకర్యము ద్వారా వీటిని తేలికగా నగదులోనికి మార్చుకొనవచ్చు. కాబట్టి వాటాలకు ద్రవ్యత్వ లక్షణం ఉండటంవలన కంపెనీకి స్థిరత్వము కల్పిస్తుంది.5. పెద్దతరహా కార్యకలాపాల ఆదాలు : అధిక నిధుల వలన కంపెనీలు ఉత్పత్తిని భారీగా చేపడతాయి. అందువలన కొనుగోళ్ళు, మార్కెటింగ్, సిబ్బంది వినియోగం, రవాణా తదితర వ్యవహారాలలో అనేక ఆదాలు లభిస్తాయి. ఖర్చులు తగ్గి, లాభాలు పెరుగుతాయి.6. సమర్థవంతమైన నిర్వహణ : కంపెనీకి అపారమైన నిధులు ఉండటం వలన నిర్వహణ నిపుణులను, వ్యయగణకులను, ఛార్టర్డ్ అకౌంటెంట్లు, సాంకేతిక నిపుణులను నియమిస్తే వారు నిర్వహణను సమర్థవంతముగా చేపడతారు.7. పరిశోధన మరియు అభివృద్ధి : ఒక కంపెనీ ఉత్పత్తి ప్రక్రియను మెరుగుపరచడానికి, నూతన వస్తువుల రూపకల్పనకు, కార్మికులకు శిక్షణ ఇవ్వడానికి ఎక్కువ మొత్తాన్ని పెట్టుబడిగా పెట్టవలసి ఉంటుంది. ఈ విస్తరణ కంపెనీలలోనే సాధ్యము.8. పన్ను ఆదాలు : కంపెనీలు ఆదాయపు పన్ను ఎక్కువ కట్టవలసి వచ్చినప్పటికి, ఎన్నో పన్ను మినహాయింపులు ఇవ్వడం వలన వీటికి పన్ను చెల్లించే బాధ్యత మొత్తంమీద తగ్గుతుంది.పరిమితులు :1. స్థాపనలో సౌలభ్యము లేకపోవడము : ఒక కంపెనీని స్థాపించడం చాలా కష్టముతోనూ, ఖర్చుతో కూడుకున్నది. అనేక పత్రాలు తయారుచేసి రిజిస్ట్రారుకు సమర్పించాలి. ఇందుకు నిపుణులు కావలెను. కంపెనీని తప్పనిసరిగా నమోదు చేయవలెను. కాబట్టి కంపెనీ స్థాపన సులభమైన ప్రక్రియ కాదు.2. డైరెక్టర్ల స్వార్ధపరత్వము : కంపెనీ యజమానులైన వాటాదారులు కంపెనీని పరిపాలన చేయరు. నిర్వహణ కోసం డైరెక్టర్లను ఎన్నుకుంటారు. డైరెక్టర్లు తమ అధికారాలను ముఖ్యకార్యనిర్వహణాధికారికి దత్తం చేస్తారు. ఆయన తన అధికారాలను కింద ఉద్యోగులకు అప్పగిస్తారు. వీరిలో ఎవరు అసమర్థులైనా, స్వార్థపరులైనా కంపెనీ నష్టాలపాలై దివాలా తీసే పరిస్థితి ఏర్పడుతుంది.3. శ్రద్ధాసక్తులు తక్కువ : యాజమాన్యానికి, నిర్వహణకు అంతరము ఉంటుంది. నిర్వహణ అంతా సిబ్బంది ‘ద్వారా జరుగుతుంది. సిబ్బందికి వ్యక్తిగత చొరవ, శ్రద్ధాసక్తులు ఉండకపోవచ్చు. సిబ్బంది కష్టపడినా ప్రోత్సాహముండదు కాబట్టి వారిలో అలసత్వము ఏర్పడుతుంది.4. కొద్దిమంది పరిపాలన : సిద్ధాంతరీత్యా కంపెనీ నిర్వహణ ప్రజాస్వామిక సూత్రాలను అనుసరించి ఉంటుంది. కాని ఆచరణలో ఇది అల్ప సంఖ్యాకుల నిర్వహణ. ఓటింగ్ హక్కులు, నిర్వహణాధికార్డులు చేజిక్కించుకున్న ‘ కొంతమంది డైరెక్టర్లు లోపలి వృత్తముగా ఏర్పడి సర్వాధికారాలు చెలాయిస్తారు.5. అధికమైన ప్రభుత్వ నియంత్రణ : కంపెనీ నిర్వహణలో అనేక నిబంధనలు పాటించాలి. వార్షిక నివేదికలు, తనిఖీ చేసిన లెక్కలను విధిగా రిజిస్ట్రారుకు సమర్పించాలి. డైరెక్టర్ల నియామకానికి ప్రభుత్వ అనుమతి పొందాలి. కంపెనీ ధ్యేయాలు మార్పుచేయడానికి అనేక చట్టబద్దమైన లాంఛనాలు పాటించాలి.6. వాటాలలో అనుచిత స్పెక్యులేషన్: పబ్లిక్ కంపెనీల వాటాలను స్టాక్ ఎక్స్చేంజ్ జాబితాలో చేర్చి సులభముగా కొనుగోలు, అమ్మకాలు చేయవచ్చు. వాటా ధరలు కంపెనీ ఆర్థిక పరిస్థితి, డివిడెండ్ల చెల్లింపు, కంపెనీ పేరు ప్రతిష్ట, కంపెనీ అభివృద్ధికి అవకాశాలు మొదలైనవాటి మీద ఆధారపడతాయి. కంపెనీ డైరెక్టర్లు కంపెనీ లెక్కలను తారుమారుచేసి, వాటా విలువను తమకు అనుకూలముగా మార్చుకొని స్పెక్యులేషన్ ద్వారా డైరెక్టర్లు లాభపడతారు.7. వ్యాపార నిర్ణయాలు తీసుకోవడములో జాప్యము : కంపెనీ వ్యాపారానికి సంబంధించిన నిర్ణయాలను డైరెక్టర్ల సమావేశాలలోనూ, వాటాదారుల సమావేశాలలోను తీసుకొనవలెను. ఈ సమావేశాలు ఏర్పాటు చేయడానికి కొంత కాలయాపన జరుగుతుంది.8. వ్యాపార రహస్యాలు : వ్యాపార నిర్వహణ వాటాదారులు, డైరెక్టర్లు, ఉద్యోగుల చేతులలో ఉంటుంది. కాబట్టి కంపెనీ రహస్యాలను కాపాడటానికి వీలులేదు.9. ఆసక్తుల సంఘర్షణ : ఈ తరహా వ్యాపారములో ఆసక్తులకు సంబంధించి నిరంతరము సంఘర్షణ జరుగుతుంది. సాధారణముగా వాటాదారులు, డైరెక్టర్ల మధ్య లేదా వాటాదారులు, ఋణదాతల మధ్య లేదా మేనేజ్మెంట్, సిబ్బందికి మధ్య ఎప్పుడూ కలహాలు, కొనసాగుతూనే ఉంటాయి.10. గుత్తాధిపత్యము కంపెనీలు గుత్తాధిపత్య ధోరణులను ప్రోత్సహిస్తుంది. వీరు వినియోగదారులను, శ్రామికులను దోచుకోవడం జరుగును."},{"question":"Aşağıdaki ifadeyi tamamlayın: Duşanbe'de yaşamını sürdürmektedir. Aynı zamanda Tacikistan Atletizm Federasyonu başkanlığını da yapmaktadır. Babası","answer":"Tacikistan İç Savaşı'nda öldü. Annesi ise beden eğitimi öğretmenliği ve koçluk yapmaktadır."},{"question":"Makinde ṣeto aabo fun awọn oluwọde l’Ọyọọ, o ti gbogbo ileewe pa","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ ti sọ pe awọn ọmọọta ati awọn ọmọ ganfe ti ja eto iwọde SARS to n lọ lọwọ gba pẹlu bi wọn ṣe n fa wahala loriṣiiriṣii, ti wọn si n di awọn eeyan lọwọ lati ṣiṣẹ wọn.Latari eyi, gomina ti paṣe pe ki awọn ọlọpaa adigboluja ti wọn n pe ni ‘Operation Burst’ bọ sita kaakiri ipinlẹ Ọyọ, ki wọn lọ si awọn ibi ti awọn to n ṣe iwọde ti n ṣe e lati daabo bo wọn lọwọ awọn ọmọ ganfe ti wọn le fẹẹ da eto naa ru.Lasiko ti gomina n ba awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ọyọ sọrọ lori bi nnkan ṣe n lọ si lori ọrọ iwọde naa lo sọ eleyii. Makinde ni latigba ti iwọde naa ti bẹrẹ, ko fi bẹẹ si wahala kankan, ṣugbọn lẹnu ọjọ mẹta yii ni awọn tọọgi ja iwọde naa gba, ti wọn si n di awọn eeyan lọwọ lati lọ sibi iṣẹ oojọ wọn, eyi to ni ko bojumu to.Eti lo fi ni ijọba yoo ko awọn ọlọpaa adigboluja jade lati daabo bo awọn to n ṣe iwọde naa, ki aabo to daju le wa fun wọn, ki awọn ọmọọta ma si le da a ru.O waa rọ awọn ọlọpaa lati fi iwa ọmọluabi ṣiṣẹ ti wọn gbe fun wọn yii. Bẹẹ lo pasẹ pe ki gbogbo ileewe nipinlẹ Ọyọ di titi pa lasiko yii. O ni awọn yoo ṣe agbeyẹwo bi gbogbo nnkan ba tun ṣe ri ni ọjọ Ẹti, ọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu yii, lati mọ igbesẹ to ba kan."},{"question":"Saan nanggaling ang pagkaing pansit sa Pilipinas?","answer":"Ang pansit ay unang ipinakilala sa Pilipinas ng mga mangangalakal na Tsino, tulad ng ginawa nila sa Japan, Thailand, Italy, at higit pa. Ang pinagmulan ng pancit ay umabot pa noong ika-16 na siglo nang ang pinakamatandang Chinatown sa mundo ay itinatag sa Maynila, Pilipinas ng mga mangangalakal at imigrante na Tsino."},{"question":"Complete o seguinte trecho: A competição de salto sobre a mesa feminino do","answer":"Campeonato Mundial de Ginástica Artística de 2010 teve sua final disputada no dia 23 de outubro. A qualificatória que definiu as ginastas finalistas foi disputada em 16 e 17 de outubro."},{"question":"Descreva uma visita a um parque de diversões.","answer":"O parque de diversões é um reino de cores vivas e risos contagiantes. Montanhas-russas emocionantes, carrosséis encantados e jogos desafiantes esperam por aventureiros de todas as idades. O aroma de algodão doce e pipoca paira no ar, enquanto as luzes cintilantes criam uma atmosfera mágica à noite."},{"question":"Lalam-pirenena fahafiry no mampitohy an' Antananarivo sy Toliara? ","answer":"Lalam-pirenena faha-7 no mampitohy an' Antananarivo sy Toliara. "},{"question":" 1944 திசம்பர் மாதத்தில் மட்டுமே செருமானிய துருப்புகள் \\"ஆர்டேன் தாக்குதல்\\" என்று அழைக்கப்படுகின்ற பல்ஜ் சண்டையில் 88,000 அமெரிக்க போர்வீரர்களைக் கொன்றுகுவித்தன. ஒரே மாதத்தில் மிக அதிகமான போர்வீரர் இறந்தது அச்சண்டையில்தான்.","answer":"பல்ஜ் சண்டை"},{"question":"Кайсы түс биринчи кезекте көздү тартат? ","answer":"Эң биринчи сары түс көздү тартат."},{"question":"Quelle est l'histoire de L’Aigle et l’Escarbot ?","answer":"Une aigle poursuivait un lièvre. Ce lièvre, se voyant dénué de tout secours, recourut au seul être que le hasard offrit à ses yeux ; c’était un escarbot ; il le supplia de le sauver. L’escarbot le rassura, et, voyant approcher l’aigle, il la conjura de ne pas lui ravir son suppliant. Mais l’aigle, dédaignant sa petitesse, dévora le lièvre sous les yeux de l’escarbot. Dès lors l’escarbot, plein de rancune, ne cessa d’observer les endroits où l’aigle faisait son nid, et, quand elle couvait, il s’élevait en l’air, faisait rouler les œufs et les cassait, tant qu’enfin pourchassée de partout, elle eut recours à Zeus (car c’est à Zeus que cet oiseau est consacré), et elle le pria de lui procurer un asile sûr pour y faire ses petits. Zeus lui permit de pondre dans son giron, mais l’escarbot avait vu la ruse : il fit une boulette de crotte, prit son essor, et, quand il fut au-dessus du giron de Zeus, il l’y laissa tomber. Zeus se leva pour secouer la crotte, et jeta les œufs à terre sans y penser. Depuis ce temps-là, dit-on, pendant la saison où paraissent les escarbots, les aigles ne nichent plus.Cette fable apprend à ne mépriser personne ; il faut se dire qu’il n’y a pas d’être si faible qui ne soit capable un jour de venger un affront."},{"question":"Rótìmí Akérédolú","answer":"Olúwarótìmí Ọdúnayọ̀ Akérédolú, SAN, or Rótìmí Akérédolú, ní wọ́n bí ní Ọjọ́ kọkànlélógún oṣù keje ọdún 1956 (21st July 1956) jẹ́ òṣèlú, agbẹjọ́rọ̀ àti Gómìnà ìpínlẹ̀ Oǹdó lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́ ọmọ orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó jẹ́ amòfin-àgbà SAN tí ó ti joyè alága àwọn amọ̀fin Nigerian Bar Association lọ́dún 2008. Kí ó tó di Gómìnà ìpínlẹ̀ Oǹdó, ó jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára olùdásílẹ̀ ilé iṣẹ́ amọ̀fin, Olujinmi & Akeredolu. Ó gbapò ìṣèjọba ìpínlẹ̀ Oǹdó lọ́wọ́ Gómìnà-àná ti ìpínlẹ̀ náà, Olúṣẹ́gun Mimiko"},{"question":"Ontwerp een logo voor een mobiele applicatie.","answer":"Het logo-ontwerp moet eenvoudig, modern en uniek zijn. Het moet de essentie van de applicatie vastleggen en de functies ervan communiceren. Het logo moet opvallende, felle kleuren bevatten en het ontwerp moet aanpasbaar zijn aan verschillende formaten en platforms, zoals websites en mobiele apparaten."},{"question":"برای بیان ویژگی‌های مواد از چه عباراتی استفاده می‌شود؟","answer":"برای بیان ویژگی‌های مواد، می‌توان از عبارات و واژگان مختلفی استفاده کرد که به صورت کلی مشخص کننده‌ی خصوصیات و مشخصات مواد باشند.مشخصات فیزیکی:    رنگارنگ، حجم، وزن، شکل، ابعاد، سختی، نرمی، چگالی، انعطاف‌پذیر یا انعطاف ناپذیر، جاذب آب یا ضد آب، شفاف، کدر.ویژگی‌های شیمیایی:    ترکیبات شیمیایی، اسیدی یا بازی بودن، پایداری شیمیایی، افتراق‌پذیری، خلوص.ویژگی‌های مکانیکی:    مقاومت به کشش، استحکام، انعطاف‌پذیری، سختی، کرنش، تغییر شکل.رفتار حرارتی:    دمای ذوب، دمای جوش، ضریب گسترش حرارتی، رفتار در دماهای مختلف.هدایت الکتریکی و حرارتی:    هدایت الکتریکی، هدایت حرارتی، مقاومت الکتریکی.مقاومت به عوامل خارجی:    مقاومت به خوردگی، مقاومت به حرارت، مقاومت به آب، پایداری در محیط‌های خاص.ساختار داخلی:    دانه‌بندی، ساختار بلوری، ترکیبات میکروسکوپی، سلولی.ویژگی‌های بصری:    شفافیت، لطافت، درخشندگی، رنگ، انعکاس نور.ترکیبات مضاف:    مواد افزودنی، مواد رنگزای، مواد نگهدارنده.زیست‌تخریب‌پذیری:    تجزیه‌پذیری طبیعی، اثرات زیست‌محیطی، تأثیر بر اکوسیستم"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന വാചകം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക:  ജോൺ വ്യത്യസ്തമായ പഞ്ചാബ് ശൈലിയുടെ വക്താവായിരുന്നു. 1857-ലെ ലഹളക്കാലത്ത് അദ്ദേഹം സ്വീകരിച്ച നടപടിയുടെ തുടർച്ച തന്നെയായിരുന്നു അത്. നിലവിൽ സുലൈമാൻ മലനിരകളെ അതിർത്തിയാക്കുന്നതിനു പകരം സിന്ധൂനദിയെ അതിർത്തിയായി നിർത്തിക്കൊണ്ട് പ്രതിരോധിക്കണം എന്നായിരുന്നു അദ്ദേഹത്തിന്റെ അഭിപ്രായം.","answer":"ഓക്ക്ലന്റിന്റെ അഫ്ഗാനിസ്താൻ ആക്രമണവും 1841-ലെ പരാജയവുമാണ് ജോണിനെ ഈ നയത്തിലേക്കെത്തിച്ചതിന്റെ പ്രധാനകാരണം. വടക്കുപടിഞ്ഞാറൻ അതിർത്തിപ്രദേശങ്ങളിലെ തന്റെ തന്നെ അനുഭവവും ഇതിന് കാരണമായി. തുർക്കിസ്താനിലെ റഷ്യൻ മുന്നേറ്റങ്ങൾ കണ്ട് അദ്ദേഹം വിളറിപിടിച്ചില്ല. സംഭവങ്ങൾ വീക്ഷിച്ചുകൊണ്ട് സംയമനത്തോടെ നിൽക്കുന്ന നയം അദ്ദേഹം സ്വീകരിച്ചു. ഈ നയത്തിന്റെ വക്താക്കൾ ഇതിനെ കരുതിക്കൂട്ടിയുള്ള നിഷ്ക്രിയത്വം (മാസ്റ്റെർലി ഇനാക്റ്റിവിറ്റി - ) എന്നുപറയാറുണ്ട്. പടിഞ്ഞാറുള്ള സംഭവവികാസങ്ങൾ കൊണ്ട് റഷ്യ സ്വയം ഒതുങ്ങിക്കോളുമെന്ന് ജോൺ വിശ്വസിച്ചു. അഫ്ഗാനിസ്താനിലെ ബ്രിട്ടീഷ് ഇടപെടൽ ദോഷം മാത്രമേ ചെയ്യൂ എന്നും അദ്ദേഹം കരുതി. ഏറെ സമ്മർദ്ദങ്ങളുണ്ടായിരുന്നിട്ടും, ദോസ്ത് മുഹമ്മദിന്റെ മരണത്തിനു ശേഷം അദ്ദേഹത്തിന്റെ രണ്ടു പുത്രൻമാർ തമ്മിലുള്ള അവകാശത്തർക്കത്തിൽ ഇടപെടാനും ജോൺ വിസമ്മതിച്ചു. ഇന്ത്യയിലെ മികച്ച ആഭ്യന്തരഭരണവും, കുറഞ്ഞ സപ്ലൈലൈനുള്ള മികച്ച സേനയും എതിരാളികളെ അഫ്ഗാനിസ്താനിലൂടെയുള്ള ഒരു മുന്നേറ്റത്തിന് പ്രേരിപ്പിക്കുകയേയില്ലെന്നായിരുന്നു ജോണിന്റെ കണക്കുകൂട്ടൽ. അദ്ദേഹത്തിന്റെ വൈസ്രോയ് കാലഘട്ടത്തിൽ മുഴുവനും ഈ നയത്തിനെതിരെ വിമർശനങ്ങളുണ്ടായെങ്കിലും ജോണിനെത്തുടർന്നു വന്ന വൈസ്രോയിമാരും ഈ നയം തന്നെ പിന്തുടർന്നു. 1878-ൽ ലിട്ടൻ പ്രഭുവാണ് ഇതിനൊരു മാറ്റം വരുത്തിയത്. അതിന്റെ അനന്തരഫലങ്ങളും വിനാശകരമായിരുന്നു. (രണ്ടാം ആംഗ്ലോ-അഫ്ഗാൻ യുദ്ധം കാണുക.)"},{"question":"ਭਾਰਤ ਅਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵੰਡ ਦੌਰਾਨ  ਔਰਤਾਂ ਨੇ ਜੋ ਝੱਲਿਆ ਉਹ ਅਕਸਰ ਅਣਗੌਲਿਆ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ,  ਕੁਝ ਵੇਰਵਾ।","answer":"'ਪਿਤਾ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਜੇ ਉਹ ਬਲਾਤਕਾਰ ਕਰਨਗੇ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਗੋਲੀ ਮਾਰ ਦਿਆਂਗਾ'ਸਾਡੀ ਇੱਕ ਸਰੋਤਾ ਅਮਾਇਨਾ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਾਂ ਸਗੀਰਾ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਦੱਸੀ। ਜਦੋਂ ਵੰਡ ਹੋਈ ਤਾਂ ਅਮਾਇਨਾ 14 ਸਾਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੀ। ਆਪਣੇ ਭੇਜੇ ਇੱਕ ਅਵਾਜ਼ੀ ਸੁਨੇਹੇ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਸਗੀਰਾ ਸਾਨੂੰ 1947 ਵਿੱਚ ਵਾਪਸ ਲੈ ਗਏ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਯਾਦ ਕੀਤਾ ਕਿ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਭੈਣ-ਭਰਾ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਕੀਤਾ ਕਿ ਜੇਕਰ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਕਿਸੇ 'ਤੇ ਹਮਲਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਕੋਈ ਅਗਵਾ ਜਾਂ ਬਲਾਤਕਾਰ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਕੀ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਏ।\\"ਇਹ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਡਰਾਉਣਾ ਸੀ। ਸਾਨੂੰ ਘਰੋਂ ਭੱਜਣ ਲਈ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾ ਤਿਆਰ ਰਹਿਣਾ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਸੀ। ਜੇਕਰ ਉਹ ਹਵਾਈ ਹਮਲਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਬੰਬਾਰੀ ਕਰਨ ਲੱਗ ਪੈਂਦੇ। ਅਸੀਂ ਹਰ ਚੀਜ਼ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਸੀ। ਸਾਡੇ ਕੋਲ ਛੋਟੀਆਂ- ਮੋਟੀਆਂ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਸਨ। ਇਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਇੱਕ ਦੰਦਾਂ ਦਾ ਬੁਰਸ਼, ਕੁਝ ਖਾਣਾ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਛੋਟਾ ਕੰਬਲ ਸੀ।''\\"ਇਹ ਭਾਰਤ ਅਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਸਨ ਜੋ ਇੱਕ ਦੂਜੇ ਨਾਲ ਜਾਨਵਰਾਂ ਵਾਂਗ ਸਲੂਕ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ। ਔਰਤਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਬਲਾਤਕਾਰ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ। ਉਹ ਮੁਟਿਆਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਅਤੇ ਗਾਇਬ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ।\\"\\"ਜਦੋਂ ਸਾਇਰਨ ਵੱਜਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਸਾਡੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਨੇ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਸਮਝਾਇਆ ਕਿ ਜੇਕਰ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਸਥਿਤੀ ਆਈ ਕਿ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਅਗਵਾ ਕਰ ਲੈਣ ਜਾਂ ਬਲਾਤਕਾਰ ਕਰਨਗੇ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਰਿਵਾਲਵਰ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਕਰਨਗੇ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਡੀ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਦੀ ਖਾਤਰ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਮਾਰ ਦੇਣਗੇ।\\""},{"question":"Aṣọbode gba ẹru ofin to le ni ọgọrun-un kan miliọnu naira lọwọ awọn onifayawọ ni Kwara","answer":"Ẹka to n gbogun ti iṣẹlẹ fayawọ nileeṣẹ aṣọbode lẹkun Aarin-Gbungbun orilẹ-ede Naijiria, North Central Joint Border Operations Drill (JBOD) ti gba ẹru ofin oriṣiriiṣii tiye rẹ jẹ miliọnu mẹtadinlaaadọfa naira (#107m) lọwọ awọn onifayawọ nipinlẹ Kwara atawọn ipinlẹ mi-in to wa lẹkun naa.Ọga aṣọbode to n mojuto ẹka JBOD,Ọgbẹni Olugboyega Peters, lo kede aṣeyọri ajọ naa laarin ọjọ mẹrinlelogun lasiko to n ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, niluu Ilọrin.Olugboyega ni lara ohun tawọn ri gba lọwọ wọn ni apo irẹsi ilẹ okere to din diẹ lẹgbẹrun kan, ọkọ agbepo bẹntiroolu to gbe lita epo ẹgbẹrun mẹtalelọgbọn pẹlu kẹẹgi epo bẹntiroolu marundinlaaadọta.Awọn nnkan mi-in ti wọn tun ri gba ni, paali aloku aṣọ oyinbo mọkanlelogun, kẹkẹ Maruwa meje, paali ọti taju-taju ati ọti mi-in mẹẹẹdọgbọn, ọkọ aloku mejila ati awọn ẹya ara ọkada pẹlu kẹkẹ Maruwa.O ni awọn onifayawọ ti tun n ko irẹsi ilẹ okere ti wọn ko ti i bo eepo lara rẹ sinu apo nla wọle bayii, eyi to maa da bii ti ilẹ wa loju awọn agbofinro to ba da wọn duro.O ni ọkọ tirela marun-un to ko iru irẹsi bẹẹ to le ni ẹgbẹrun kan apo, 1,677, lọwọ awọn tẹ lagbegbe Chikanda ati Okuta lẹkun Arewa Kwara tiye rẹ le ni miliọnu mejidinlogun naira, #18.4m.O waa kilọ fun gbogbo awọn to n ṣowo tijọba ti fofin de lati jawọ kiakia nitori pe ajọ naa yoo tẹsiwaju lati maa gbogun ti iṣẹlẹ fayawọ ati ohun to le mu ifasẹyin ba ọrọ-aje orilẹ-ede Naijiria."},{"question":"බරු ඇට යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"වී ඇට"},{"question":"Apakah maksud dengan peribahasa \\"gajah dipandang seperti kuman\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah terlalu marah."},{"question":"திருக்குறள்:செய்நன்றி அறிதல் அதிகாரம் குறள் எழுதி  விளக்கம் தருக.","answer":"செய்நன்றி அறிதல்குறள் பால்: அறத்துப்பால்.குறள் இயல்: இல்லறவியல்.அதிகாரம்: செய்நன்றி அறிதல்குறள் 101:செய்யாமல் செய்த உதவிக்கு வையகமும்வானகமும் ஆற்றல் அரிது.விளக்கம்:தான் எதுவுமே செய்யாதிருக்கவும், பிறன் தனக்குச் செய்த உதவிக்கு, இவ் வுலகமும் வானுலகமும் ஈடாக முடியாது.குறள் 102:காலத்தி னால்செய்த நன்றி சிறிதெனினும்ஞாலத்தின் மாணப் பெரிது.விளக்கம்:காலத்தோடு செய்த உதவியானது அளவால் சிறியதே என்றாலும் அதன் பெருமையோ உலகத்தை விடப் பெரியதாகும்.குறள் 103:பயன் தூக்கார் செய்த உதவி நயன் தூக்கின்நன்மை கடலிற் பெரிது.விளக்கம்:பயனைக் கருதாதவர் செய்த உதவியின் நன்மையினை ஆராய்ந்தால், அதன் நன்மை கடலையும்விட அளவினால் மிகப் பெரியதாகும்.குறள் 104:தினைத்துணை நன்றி செயினும் பனைத்துணையாக்கொள்வார் பயன்தெரி வார்.விளக்கம்:உதவியின் பயனைத் தெரிந்தவர்கள், தினையளவே ஒருவன் நன்மை செய்தாலும், அதனைப் பனையளவாக உளங் கொண்டு போற்றுவார்கள்.குறள் 105:உதவி வரைந்தன்று உதவி உதவிசெயப்பட்டார் சால்பின் வரைத்து.விளக்கம்:உதவியானது அதன் அளவையே எல்லையாக உடையது அன்று: அது உதவி செய்யப்பட்டவரின் பண்பையே தனக்கு அளவாக உடையதாகும்.குறள் 106:மறவற்க மாசற்றார் கேண்மை துறவற்கதுன்பத்துள் துப்பாயர் நட்பு.விளக்கம்:மனமாக இல்லாதவரின் நட்பினை ஒரு போதும் மறக்கலாகாது. துன்பக் காலத்தில் உறுதுணையாக உதவியவரின் நட்பையும் விடலாகாது.குறள் 107:எழுமை எழுபிறப்பும் உள்ளுவர் தங்கண்விழுமம் துடைத்தவர் நட்பு.விளக்கம்:தம்முடைய துன்பத்தை ஒழித்தவரின் நட்பினை, ஏழேழு பிறப்பிலும் மறவாது நினைத்துப் போற்றுவர் நன்றியுடையோர்.குறள் 108:நன்றி மறப்பது நன்றன்று நன்றல்லதுஅன்றே மறப்பது நன்று.விளக்கம்:ஒருவர் செய்த நன்மையை மறப்பது நல்ல பண்பு ஆகாது. நன்மை அல்லாத விஷயங்களை அன்றைக்கே மறந்து விடுவது நல்லதாகும்.குறள் 109:கொன்றன்ன இன்னா செயினும் அவர்செய்தஒன்றுநன்று உள்ளக் கெடும்.விளக்கம்:ஒருவர் நம்மைக் கொன்றாற்போன்றதொரு துன்பத்தைச் செய்தாலும், அவர் முன்பு செய்த நன்மை ஒன்றை நினைத்தாலும் அத் துன்பம் கெடும்.குறள் 110:எந்நன்றி கொன்றார்க்கும் உய்வுண்டாம் உய்வில்லைசெய்நன்றி கொன்ற மகற்கு.விளக்கம்:எந்ந நன்மையை அழித்தவர்க்கும் தப்புதற்கு வழி உண்டாகும்: ஆயின், ஒருவர் செய்த உதவியை மறந்து அழித்தவனுக்கு உய்வே கிடையாது."},{"question":"வினா:  “திருக்கண்ணப்ப தேவர் திருமறம் “ குறித்து எழுதுக","answer":"விடை: திருக்கண்ணப்ப தேவர் திருமறம்:  திருக்கண்ணப்ப தேவர் திருமறம்என்னும் பெயரில் பதினோராம் திருமுறையில் இரண்டு நூல்கள் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளன.10ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் வாழ்ந்த புலவர் நக்கீர தேவ நாயனார் இயற்றியது ஒன்று. இது நீண்ட ஆசிரியப்பாவில் அமைந்துள்ளது.10ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் கல்லாட தேவ நாயனார் இயற்றியது மற்றொன்று. இது 38 அடிகள் கொண்ட சுருக்கமான ஆசிரியப்பாவில் அமைந்துள்ளது.96 வகையான சிற்றிலக்கியங்களில் ‘மறம்’ என்பதும் ஒன்று.மறம் பற்றிய நூல்கள்: எதிரிகளை வெல்வது ஒருவகை மறம். மன்ன்னுக்கு என் மகளைத் தரமாட்டேன் என முழங்குவது மற்றொரு மறம். இந்த நூல் காட்டுவது திருமறம்.பாரி முல்லைக்குத் தேர் தந்தது, பேகன் மயிலுக்குப் போர்வை தந்தது ஆகியவற்றைக் ‘கொடைமடம்’ என்றனர். கண்ணப்பன் தன் கண்ணைத் தானே பிடுங்கித் தந்தது ‘கொடைமறம்’. இந்தக் கொடைமறத்தைத் திருமறமாக்குகிறது இந்த நூல்.கண்ணப்பன் கதை: பொத்தம்பி நாட்டு உடுப்பூரில் வாழ்ந்த வேடன் திண்ணன். வேட்டையாடிச் செல்லும் வழியில் காளத்தி மலைமேல் இருந்த சிவலிங்கத்தைக் கண்டான். பசியோடு இருக்குமே என எண்ணித் தான் வேட்டையாடிக் கொண்டுவந்த இறைச்சிகளைப் படைத்து வைத்துவிட்டுப் போய்விட்டான். வழக்கமாகப் படைக்கும் அந்தணனர் அவற்றை நீக்கிவிட்டுத் தன் சைவ உணவைப் படைத்தார். திண்ணனின் அன்பு மேலானது என்பதை அந்தணனுக்கு வெளிப்படுத்த இறைவன் விரும்பினார். சிவலிங்க்கதின் வலக்கண்ணில் குருதி ஒழுகச் செய்தார். திண்ணனின் மூலிகை மருத்துவம் பயன் தரவில்லை. தன் கண்களில் ஒன்றைப் பிடுங்கி அதன்மீது ஒட்டவைத்தான். ஒழுகிய குருதி நின்றுவிட்டது. பின் லிங்கத்தின் மற்றொரு அதேபோல் குறுதி. திண்ணன் தன் மறுகண்ணையும் பிடுங்கி அப்பினான். இறைவன் “கண்ணப்பா! என் கண் குருதி நின்றுவிட்டதைப் பார்” என்றார். கண்ணப்பன் கண் பெற்றான்."},{"question":"Мотивация (түрткү) бере турган сөздөр менен бөлүш !","answer":"Сен нааразы болуп, арызданган жашоо...Балким, азыр кимдир бирөөнүн арманы, кыялыдыр...Шүгүр кыл !"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Seán Ó Tuama. ","answer":"Scoláire, file agus drámadóir as Corcaigh ab ea Seán Ó Tuama (28 Eanáir 1926 - 14 Deireadh Fómhair 2006)."},{"question":"「巨人の星」「タイガーマスク」「空手バカ一代」など数々の名作を残した、今は亡き漫画原作者は誰でしょう？","answer":"梶原一騎です。"},{"question":"Ahoana ny fomba fanenana ny vatana? Vaha olana roa no azo isafidianana:Vaha olana 1: Misakafo ara-pahasalamana.Vaha olana 2: Ahena ny sakafo hanina.","answer":"Ny vaha olana voalohany no mahomby kokoa satria ny sakafo ara-pahasalamana dia manampy ny vatana hanala ireo tavy ratsy anatin'ny vatana."},{"question":"મામાનું ઘર કેટલે .... બાળગીત લખો.","answer":"મામાનું ઘર કેટલે દીવો બળે  એટલેદીવો મેં તો દીઠો  મામો લાગે મીઠોતાળી  વગાડે  છોકરાં  મામા   લાવે  ટોપરાંટોપરાં તો ભાવે નહિ મામા ખારેક લાવે નહિમામી  મારી   ભોળી   મીઠાઈ   લાવે   મોળીમોળી મીઠાઈ ભાવે નહિ રમકડાં તો લાવે નહિમામે  સામું  જોયું   મારું મનડું મોહ્યુંમામાનું ઘર કેટલે દીવો બળે  એટલે"},{"question":"When did Facebook first launch?","answer":"2004"},{"question":"Pierwszy telefon marki iPhone wszedł na rynek w 2011. roku. Prawda czy fałsz?","answer":"Powyższe zdanie to fałsz."},{"question":"自転車の車輪を支えるために中心から放射状に伸びている細い棒のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"スポークです。"},{"question":"将棋のコマは８種類、ではオセロのコマは何種類でしょう？","answer":"１種類です。"},{"question":"Fọláṣọdún Adébísí Shónúbi","answer":"Fọláṣọdún Adébísí Shónúbi (tí wọ́n bí lọ́jọ́ keje oṣù kẹta ọdún 1962) jẹ́ ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nigeria àti Gómìnà-fìdíhẹ Ilé-ìfowópamọ́-àgbà, the (Central Bank of Nigeria) tí Ààrẹ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà yàn lọ́jọ́ kẹwàá, oṣù Òkudù, ọdún 2023 láti rọ́pò Gómìnà-àná Ilé-ìfowópamọ́-àgbà, Godwin Emefiele tí wọn dá dúró lẹ́nu iṣẹ́ fún ìgbà díẹ̀ nítorí àwọn ẹsùn àwọn ìwà àjẹbánu kan."},{"question":"इस श्रेणी में ट्रिविया का एक उदाहरण दीजिए: संगीत","answer":"दी गई श्रेणी, \\"संगीत\\", में ट्रिविया का उदहारण यह है:एरियाना ग्रांडे ने कितनी स्टूडियो एल्बम रिलीज़ की हैं? 6"},{"question":"Unang sentensya: Si Michelle nikaon sa cafe niadtong Sabado.Ika duha nga sentensya: Nisuroy sa mall si Michelle niadtong Sabado.Ang duha ba ka sentensya nagkasinabot?","answer":"Dili. Wala nagkasinabot ang duha ka sentensya."},{"question":"Ajọ eleto idibo fẹẹ ṣafikun awọn ibudo idibo to wa nipinlẹ Ondo","answer":"Ajọ eleto idibo lorilẹ-ede yii ti kede ipinnu wọn lati ṣafikun si awọn ibudo idibo to wa nipinlẹ Ondo tẹlẹ.Alaboojuto fun ajọ naa nipinlẹ Ondo, Ambasadọ Rufus Akẹju, lo sọ eyi ninu ipade kan to ṣe pẹlu awọn tọrọ kan ni olu ileeṣẹ wọn to wa ni Alagbaka, niluu Akurẹ, lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ yii.O ni ibudo idibo tuntun bii ẹẹdẹgbẹrun ati okoo le mẹrin (924) ni wọn fẹẹ fi kun ẹgbẹrun mẹta o le mẹsan-an to ti wa nilẹ tẹlẹ, ti apapọ gbogbo ojuko idibo ti yoo wa nipinlẹ Ondo yoo si jẹ ẹgbẹrun mẹta ati oji le lẹẹẹdẹgbẹrun din meje (3,933)Akẹju ni ọkan-o-jọkan iwe ẹhonu lawọn araalu n kọ sawọn lati bii ọdun marundinlọgbọn sẹyin lori ẹsun pe awọn n fẹtọ awọn eeyan dun wọn lasiko ti eto idibo bá ń lọ lọwọ latari bi awọn ibudo idibo to yẹ ki wọn ti ṣe ojuṣe wọn ko ṣe si nitosi ibugbe wọn.O ni oun nigbagbọ pe afikun tuntun naa yoo fopin si gbogbo awuyewuye to maa n waye lori bi ero ṣe maa n pọ ju ohun eelo lọ lasiko atawọn oludibo ba n forukọ silẹ lati gba kaadi idibo.O ni iṣẹ tí n lọ labẹlẹ lori abajade iwadii ti ajọ eleto idibo ni ki awọn oṣiṣẹ rẹ kan lọọ ṣe lori igbesẹ naa bẹẹ lo fi da awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ondo loju pe gbogbo ibudo ibudo idibo tuntun naa ni yoo fara han nínu iwe ti wọn fẹẹ fi ṣe iforukọsilẹ awọn oludibo, eyi ti wọn fẹẹ bẹrẹ laipẹ."},{"question":"پوښتنه: که تاسو په سیالۍ کې یاست او تاسو په دوهم ځای کې یو کس تیر کړئ، تاسو اوس په کوم ځای کې یاست؟","answer":"ځواب: که تاسو یو کس په دویم ځای کې تېر کړئ، تاسو د هغه ځای نیسي، او تاسو اوس دویم ځای کې یاست."},{"question":"પોંગલ પર નિબંધ લખો.","answer":"પ્રસ્તાવના :-પોંગલનો અર્થ સંપૂર્ણ છે, આ દિવસે લોકોના ઘર સુખ અને સંપત્તિથી ભરાઈ જાય છે. પોંગલ એ ખેડૂતોનો તહેવાર છે. પોંગલ તહેવાર મુખ્યત્વે દક્ષિણ ભારતમાં ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. આ તહેવાર ચાર દિવસ સુધી ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. આ ચાર દિવસીય ઉત્સવ એ દેવતાઓને સમર્પિત છે જેઓ કૃષિ સાથે સંકળાયેલા છે.પોંગલ ઉત્સવના દિવસે ભગવાન સૂર્ય ભગવાનને ભોજન અર્પણ કરવા માટે જે પ્રસાદ બનાવવામાં આવે છે તેને પોંગલ કહેવામાં આવે છે, તેથી તેનું નામ પોંગલ પડ્યું. પોંગલનો તહેવાર તમિલનાડુમાં લણણીની ઉજવણી માટે ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. ખાસ કરીને તે એક ખેતીનો તહેવાર છે, તે જાન્યુઆરી મહિનાના મધ્યમાં ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. સારા પાકને કારણે લોકો આ તહેવારની ઉજવણી કરે છે. આમાં ચારેય દિવસોનું પોતપોતાનું મહત્વ છે.પોંગલનો ઈતિહાસ :-પોંગલ એ તમિલનાડુનો પ્રાચીન તહેવાર છે જે હરિયાળી અને સમૃદ્ધિને સમર્પિત છે.પોંગલ તહેવારના દિવસે ભગવાન સૂર્ય ભગવાનની પૂજા કરવામાં આવે છે અને અર્પણ કરવામાં આવે છે. ભગવાનને જે પ્રસાદ ચઢાવવામાં આવે છે તેને પોંગલ કહેવામાં આવે છે. આ કારણથી આ તહેવારનું નામ પોંગલ પડ્યું.પોંગલનો ઈતિહાસ 200 થી 300 એડી સુધીનો શોધી શકાય છે. જોકે પૌગલને દ્રવિડિયન લણણીના તહેવાર તરીકે ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. આ તહેવારનો ઉલ્લેખ સંસ્કૃતના પુરાણોમાં પણ જોવા મળે છે. પોંગલ તહેવાર સાથે કેટલીક પૌરાણિક કથાઓ જોડાયેલી છે. પોંગલ સાથે સંબંધિત બે વાર્તાઓ છે.એક દંતકથા અનુસાર, એકવાર ભગવાન શિવે તેના બળદને મનુષ્યોને એક સંદેશ આપવા માટે સ્વર્ગમાંથી પૃથ્વી પર જવા કહ્યું. ભગવાન શિવે કહ્યું કે તેણે દરરોજ તેલ સ્નાન કરવું જોઈએ અને મહિનામાં એકવાર ભોજન કરવું જોઈએ. પરંતુ બળદ એ ભગવાન શિવના આદેશથી વિપરીત લોકોને સંદેશો આપ્યો.બળદ એ લોકોને કહ્યું કે તેઓ એક દિવસ તેલથી સ્નાન કરે અને રોજ ભોજન કરે. બળદ ની આ ભૂલથી ભગવાન શિવ ખૂબ ગુસ્સે થયા. અને તેણે બળદને શાપ આપ્યો. બળદને પૃથ્વી પર કાયમ માટે રહેવા માટે કૈલાસમાંથી દેશનિકાલ કરવામાં આવ્યો હતો.તેઓએ ખેડૂતોને વધુ ખોરાકનું ઉત્પાદન કરવામાં મદદ કરવી પડશે. આ રીતે આ દિવસ પશુઓ સાથે સંબંધિત છે. તેવી જ રીતે, આ દિવસની બીજી દંતકથા છે જે ભગવાન કૃષ્ણ અને ભગવાન ઇન્દ્ર સાથે જોડાયેલી છે. જ્યારે ભગવાન કૃષ્ણ નાના હતા, ત્યારે તેમણે ભગવાન ઇન્દ્રને પાઠ ભણાવવાનું નક્કી કર્યું કારણ કે તેઓ દેવતાઓના રાજા બની ગયા હતા, તેથી તેમને ગર્વ હતો.ભગવાન શ્રી કૃષ્ણએ તેમના ગામના લોકોને કહ્યું કે ભગવાન ઈન્દ્રની પૂજા ન કરવા જણાવ્યું હતું. આ કારણે ભગવાન ઈન્દ્ર ખૂબ જ ગુસ્સે થયા. તેઓ વાદળો તોફાન કરે છે વાદળોને એકત્ર કરવા મોકલ્યા અને ત્રણ દિવસ સુધી સતત વરસાદ કર્યો. આ તોફાન સમગ્ર દ્વારકામાં તબાહી મચી ગઈ હતી.તે સમયે ભગવાન શ્રી કૃષ્ણએ તમામ લોકોની રક્ષા માટે ગોવર્ધન પર્વતને પોતાની નાની આંગળી પર ઉપાડ્યો હતો. તે સમયે ઈન્દ્રને પોતાની ભૂલનો અહેસાસ થયો અને તેને ભગવાન કૃષ્ણની શક્તિ સમજાઈ. ભગવાન શ્રી કૃષ્ણએ વિશ્વકર્માને દ્વારકામાં ફરી વસવાટ કરવા કહ્યું અને ગોવાળો તેમની ગાયો સાથે ફરીથી ખેતી કરવા લાગ્યા.હાર્વેસ્ટ ફેસ્ટિવલ :-પોંગલ એ લણણીનો તહેવાર છે જે જાન્યુઆરીના મધ્યમાં આવે છે. તમિલનાડુના લોકોનો આ મુખ્ય તહેવાર છે. ગ્રામીણ તમિલનાડુમાં મોસમ લોકો વ્યસ્ત બની જાય છે. પુરૂષો, મહિલાઓ અને બાળકો ખેતરમાં આવીને તમામ ખેતરોમાં પાક રોપશે.કારણ કે ભગવાનને ચોખા ચઢાવવામાં આવે છે, તે રસોડામાં, આંગણામાં અથવા ખુલ્લી જગ્યામાં પણ રાંધવામાં આવે છે, ભગવાનને જોવા માટે કે લોકોએ તેમને કેટલો ઉત્સાહ આપ્યો છે. જ્યાં ડાંગર ઉગે છે તે વિસ્તાર લીલા સમુદ્રના મોજા જેવો દેખાય છે. આ જોઈને ખેડૂતનું દિલ ખુશીથી ભરાઈ જાય છે. આવો નજારો તમિલનાડુના લોકોના મનને કમજોર કરૅ છે.પોંગલ કેવી રીતે ઉજવવામાં આવે છે?પોંગલનો તહેવાર એક દિવસ માટે નહીં પરંતુ ચાર દિવસ માટે ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. આ તહેવારને હિન્દુ ધર્મના વાર્ષિક તહેવારોમાંનો એક ગણવામાં આવે છે. તેનું મહત્વ એ હકીકતમાં રહેલું છે કે આ દિવસે લણણી માટે પુષ્કળ હવામાન માટે ભગવાનનો આભાર માનવામાં આવે છે.પોંગલ તમિલ શબ્દ પરથી આવ્યો છે જેનો અર્થ થાય છે ઉકાળો. આ ફેસ્ટિવલનું આયોજન જાન્યુઆરીથી ફેબ્રુઆરી વચ્ચે કરવામાં આવે છે. આ સિઝનમાં વિવિધ પ્રકારના અનાજનું ઉત્પાદન થાય છે જેમ કે ચોખા, શેરડી, હળદર વગેરે પરંતુ આ સિવાય તમિલનાડુમાં રસોઈ માટે જરૂરી એવા પાકની કાપણી કરવામાં આવે છે.તમિલ કેલેન્ડર મુજબ પોંગલ માટે જાન્યુઆરી મહિનાનો મધ્ય ભાગ વર્ષના સૌથી મહત્વપૂર્ણ તમિલનાડુનો આ તહેવાર 14-15 જાન્યુઆરીએ ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. આ તહેવાર માનવજાતને ઋતુચક્ર સાથે યોગ્ય રીતે સંતુષ્ટ કરવાનો પ્રસાદનો તહેવાર છે. પરંપરાગત રીતે, આ મહિનામાં ઘણા લગ્નો છે. આ પરંપરા તે લોકો માટે ખેતીનું આયોજન કરવા માટે છે જેઓ ખેતી સાથે સંબંધિત છે.પોંગલના ચાર દિવસ :-પોંગલ એ ચાર દિવસનો તહેવાર છે. પોંગલ તહેવારના આ ચાર દિવસ ખૂબ જ મહત્વપૂર્ણ છે. પહેલો દિવસ ભોગી પોંગલ, બીજો દિવસ સૂર્ય પોંગલ, ત્રીજો દિવસ મુથુ પોંગલ અને ચોથો દિવસ કનુમ પોંગલ છે.પોંગલનો પ્રથમ દિવસ ભોગી પોંગલ છે. આ દિવસે 2 લોકો પોતાના ઘરમાં માટીના વાસણો પર કુમકુમ અને સ્વસ્તિક લગાવે છે. આ દિવસે ઘરના દરેક ખૂણામાં સ્વચ્છતા કરવામાં આવે છે. પોંગલ તહેવારના પ્રથમ દિવસે ભગવાન ઇન્દ્રની પૂજા કરવામાં આવે છે કારણ કે ભગવાન ઇન્દ્રને વાદળોના શાસક કહેવામાં આવે છે અને તે વરસાદ લાવે છે.જો તમને સારો પાક જોઈતો હોય તો વરસાદ હોવો ખૂબ જ જરૂરી છે. પાકની પુષ્કળતા માટે ભગવાન ઈન્દ્રને શ્રદ્ધાંજલિ આપવામાં આવે છે. આ દિવસે અન્ય ધાર્મિક વિધિ મનાવવામાં આવે છે જેને ભોગી માંતાલુ તરીકે પણ ઓળખવામાં આવે છે. સારા પાકને કારણે ખેડૂતો આનંદથી ભગવાન ઈન્દ્રજીની પૂજા કરે છે અને તેમનો આભાર માને છે.ભગવાનને તેમના પર આશીર્વાદ આપવા માટે પૂજે છે જેથી તેમના ઘર અને દેશમાં સંપત્તિ અને સુખ સમૃદ્ધિ હોય. આ દિવસે ઘરના બેકાર ગાયના છાણ અને લાકડા વડે સામગ્રીને બાળવામાં આવે છે. આ અગ્નિની આસપાસ છોકરીઓ ભગવાન માટે નૃત્ય કરે છે અને ગીતો ગાય છે.પોંગલનો બીજો દિવસઃ પોંગલનો બીજો દિવસ સૂર્ય છે. સૂર્ય બીજા દિવસે, ઘરનો સૌથી મોટો સભ્ય સૂર્ય ભગવાનની અગ્નિનો ચાહક બને છે. આ દિવસે પૂજા કે કૃત્રિમ પૂજાનું કામ થાય છે અન્ય દૈવી પદાર્થો સાથે સૂર્ય ભગવાનને અર્પણ કરવામાં આવે છે.માટીના વાસણમાં ચોખા અને પાણી ઉમેરીને પોંગલ બનાવવામાં આવે છે. આ રીતે રાંધેલા ચોખાને પોંગલ કહેવામાં આવે છે. સૂર્ય પોંગલના દિવસે, લોકો પરંપરાગત વસ્ત્રો અને પ્રતીકો પહેરે છે. સૂર્ય પોંગલના દિવસે, લોકો કોલમ બનાવે છે, તે એક શુભ સંકેત છે.સવારે વહેલા સ્નાન કર્યા પછી સફેદ ચૂનાના પાવડર સાથે કોલમ ઘરે બનાવવામાં આવે છે. આ રીતે રાંધેલા ચોખાથી ભગવાન સૂર્યની પૂજા કરવામાં આવે છે. સૂર્ય ભગવાનને પ્રાર્થના કરવામાં આવે છે કે તેઓ હંમેશા તમારા પર તેમના આશીર્વાદ વરસાવે.આ દિવસે એક રસપ્રદ વિધિ પણ કરવામાં આવે છે જ્યાં પતિ-પત્ની પૂજા માટે ઉપયોગમાં લેવાતા વાસણો વહેંચે છે. ગામડાઓમાં પૌગલ ઉત્સવ સમાન ભક્તિભાવથી ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. ધાર્મિક વિધિના ભાગ રૂપે, વાસણની આસપાસ હળદરનો છોડ બાંધવામાં આવે છે જેમાં ચોખા ઉકાળવામાં આવે છે.પોંગલનો ત્રીજો દિવસ: મટ્ટુ પોંગલ એ પોંગલનો ત્રીજો દિવસ છે. પોંગલના દિવસે માતા ગાયની વિશેષ પૂજા-અર્ચના કરવામાં આવે છે. આ દિવસે ગાયને શણગારવામાં આવે છે, ગાયના ગળામાં ઘંટ બાંધવામાં આવે છે અને ફૂલોના હાર બાંધવામાં આવે છે, ત્યારબાદ ગાયની પૂજા કરવામાં આવે છે.ઢોરની ઘંટડીનો અવાજ ગ્રામજનોને આકર્ષે છે અને લોકો તેમના ઢોરને એકબીજાની વચ્ચે ચલાવે છે. ગાયને ખેડૂત માટે ખૂબ જ મહત્વપૂર્ણ માનવામાં આવે છે. તે ગાય છે જે ખેડૂતને દૂધ અને ખાતર આપે છે. આ દિવસે ગાયને પોંગલ ખવડાવવામાં આવે છે અને ગાય સિવાય અન્ય પ્રાણીઓનું પણ સન્માન કરવામાં આવે છે.કારણ કે પશુઓ દરેક ક્ષણે ખેડૂતને સાથ આપે છે. પશુઓ ખેડૂતને પાકને સિંચાઈથી લઈને પાક કાપવામાં મદદ કરે છે. પશુઓ ખેડૂતને તેના સુખ-દુઃખમાં સાથ આપે છે, તેથી જ હિંદુ ધર્મમાં પણ પ્રાણીઓની પૂજા કરવામાં આવે છે. મટ્ટુ પોંગલના દિવસે ગામડાઓમાં દરેક ખેડૂત પોતાની ગાય અને બળદની પૂજા કરે છે.મટ્ટુ પોંગલના દિવસનું બીજું મહત્વ છે. આ દિવસે તમામ મહિલાઓ પોતાના ભાઈઓના સારા જીવનની કામના કરે છે. આ દિવસે ઘરોમાં સ્વાદિષ્ટ મીઠાઈઓ બનાવવામાં આવે છે અને ભેટ તરીકે આપવામાં આવે છે.પોંગલનો ચોથો દિવસ: પોંગલનો ચોથો દિવસ કનુમ પોંગલ છે. આ દિવસે તમામ લોકો અને સભ્યો સાથે રહે છે અને સાથે મળીને ભોજન કરે છે. આ દિવસે હળદરના પાન ધોઈને ભોજન પીરસવામાં આવે છે અને ખાસ કરીને તેના પર મીઠાઈ, ચોખા, શેરડી, સોપારી પીરસવામાં આવે છે.આ દિવસે લોકો તેમના વડીલોના આશીર્વાદ લે છે અને તેમના નાનાને પ્રેમ અને ભેટ આપે છે. આ દિવસ ખૂબ જ આનંદ સાથે ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. આ દિવસે મહિલાઓ ચૂનાના પત્થર અને તેલથી તેમના ભાઈઓની આરતી કરે છે અને તેમના ઉજ્જવળ ભવિષ્યની કામના કરે છે.પોંગલના આકર્ષણો :-પોંગલ તહેવાર દક્ષિણ ભારતમાં ખૂબ જ ઉત્સાહ સાથે ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. આ દિવસે લોકો પોતાના ઘરને શણગારે છે. આ દિવસે બળદની લડાઈનું આયોજન કરવામાં આવે છે જે ખૂબ પ્રખ્યાત છે.રાત્રે, લોકો સમૂહ ભોજનનું આયોજન કરે છે અને એકબીજાને શુભેચ્છા પાઠવે છે. સમૃદ્ધ વર્ષ માટે શુભેચ્છાઓ. આ દિવસે લણણી અને જીવનમાં લોકો પ્રકાશ માટે ભગવાન સૂર્યનો આભાર વ્યક્ત કરે છે."},{"question":"ఈ ఆర్టికల్ ను సంగ్రహించండి:  ద్వారా. అసోసియేటెడ్ ప్రెస్ రిపోర్టర్. ప్రచురించినవారు: ఆగష్టు 4, 2013 మధ్యాహ్నం 14:41 గంటలకు EST... నవీకరించబడింది:. 2013 ఆగస్టు 4న మధ్యాహ్నం 14:48 గంటలకు EST. న్యూయార్క్, లాస్ ఏంజిల్స్, డల్లాస్ మరియు ఇతర నగరాల్లోని మూడు మిలియన్ల టైమ్ వార్నర్ కేబుల్ కస్టమర్లు ఆదివారం సిబిఎస్కు ప్రాప్యత లేకుండానే ఉన్నారు, అంటే వారు టైగర్ వుడ్స్ బ్రిడ్జ్స్టోన్ ఇన్విటేషనల్ గెలవడానికి చేసిన ప్రయత్నాన్ని కోల్పోవచ్చు. ఆయా మార్కెట్లలోని ప్రేక్షకుల కోసం కేబుల్ ప్రొవైడర్ శుక్రవారం సిబిఎస్ను నిలిపివేసింది, ఇతర ప్రసార సంస్థలకు చెల్లించే దానితో సరిపడని రీట్రాన్స్మిషన్ ఫీజులను నెట్వర్క్ డిమాండ్ చేస్తోందని చెప్పారు. ఇంతకు ముందెన్నడూ కేబుల్ ప్రొవైడర్ చేత తొలగించబడలేదని, AT&T, Cablevision, Comcast, DirecTV మరియు Verizon లతో సహా ఇతర ప్రొవైడర్లతో ఒప్పందాలను విజయవంతంగా చర్చించినట్లు CBS తెలిపింది. సిబిఎస్ బ్లాక్అవుట్: టైమ్ వార్నర్ కేబుల్ ప్రసార ఛార్జీలపై వివాదంలో పలు నగరాల్లో సిబిఎస్ను నిలిపివేసింది. టైమ్ వార్నర్ ప్రతినిధి మౌరీన్ హఫ్ ఆదివారం మాట్లాడుతూ 'సంభాషణలు కొనసాగుతున్నాయి' అని అన్నారు. సిబిఎస్ ప్రతినిధి చర్చల స్థితిపై వ్యాఖ్యానించడానికి నిరాకరించారు. న్యూ యార్క్ లోని రెండు కంపెనీలు తమ కేసులను ప్రజల ముందుకు తీసుకువెళ్లాయి, స్థానిక వార్తాపత్రికలలో పూర్తి పేజీ ముద్రణ ప్రకటనలతో. ఈ వారాంతంలో సిబిఎస్కు వచ్చిన టైమ్ వార్నర్ కేబుల్ కస్టమర్లు కూడా వైట్ స్క్రీన్ పై ఒక సందేశాన్ని అందుకున్నారు. 'సిబిఎస్ను ఉచితంగా ప్రసారం చేయడానికి యాంటెన్నాను ఉపయోగించడం' సహా అనేక మార్గాల ద్వారా తమ అభిమాన కార్యక్రమాలను చూడవచ్చని వీక్షకులకు సలహా ఇచ్చింది. సిబిఎస్ తన సిగ్నల్ ను యాంటెన్నా ఉన్న ఎవరికైనా ఉచితంగా ప్రసారం చేస్తున్నప్పటికీ, సిబిఎస్ వీక్షకులలో 85 శాతం మంది పే టీవీ ప్రొవైడర్ ద్వారా టీవీ చూస్తున్నారు. ప్రకటనల ఆదాయంలో మార్పులకు వ్యతిరేకంగా బఫర్గా రీట్రాన్స్మిషన్ ఫీజుల నుండి ఆదాయాన్ని సంపాదించడానికి సిబిఎస్ ప్రయత్నిస్తోంది. పే టీవీ చందాదారుల నుండి ఆదాయం సంపాదించడం నెట్వర్క్ వృద్ధి అవకాశాలకు కీలకం అని విశ్లేషకులు అంటున్నారు. ఇంతలో, టైమ్ వార్నర్, అధిక ఫీజుల డిమాండ్లకు అనుగుణంగా కస్టమర్ల కోసం బిల్లులు పెరగడానికి దారితీస్తుందని చెప్పారు. డైరెక్ట్ టివి తన పోటీదారుని కాపాడటానికి వచ్చింది, టైమ్ వార్నర్ 'అతిశయోక్తి ప్రోగ్రామింగ్ వ్యయ పెరుగుదలకు వ్యతిరేకంగా పోరాడటానికి' ప్రశంసలు తెలిపింది.","answer":"సిబిఎస్ బ్లాక్అవుట్ టైమ్ వార్నర్ కేబుల్ తరువాత మూడవ రోజు నెట్వర్క్ను కట్ చేసింది ఫీజు వివాదాల తరువాత. న్యూయార్క్, లాస్ ఏంజిల్స్ మరియు డల్లాస్ లోని వినియోగదారులు CBS ప్రోగ్రామింగ్ కు ప్రాప్యతను కోల్పోయారు. టైమ్ వార్నర్ ప్రతినిధి మాట్లాడుతూ 'చర్చలు కొనసాగుతున్నాయి' సిబిఎస్ యాంటెన్నా ఉన్న ఎవరైనా ఉచితంగా యాక్సెస్ చేయవచ్చు."},{"question":"O jakim wydarzeniu mówi ten tekst: Łucznictwo na Światowych Wojskowych Igrzyskach Sportowych 2015 – zawody, które odbywały się w południowokoreańskim Mungyeongu w dniach od 5 do 9 października 2015 roku podczas igrzysk wojskowych.","answer":"O Światowych Wojskowych Igrzyskach Sportowych 2015"},{"question":"لاندې برخې ته مراجعه وکړئ او بیا وروسته پوښتنې ته په ورته ژبه ځواب ورکړئ لکه څنګه چې د برخې سره:  پاساژ: په 1994 کې ، ګیتار لوبغاړو مارک مورټون او میټ کونر ، بیس لوبغاړی جان کمپبل او ډرمر کریس اډلر د برن دی پادری په نوم یو بینډ پیل کړ. د ډلې غړي یو بل د هغه کالج څخه پیژني چې دوی ټول پکې برخه اخیستې وه ، د ویرجینیا دولت پوهنتون ، په ریچمنډ ، ویرجینیا کې. مورټن او کونر د ډلې له پیل څخه سمدلاسه وروسته د ماسټرۍ درجې تعقیب او په ترتیب سره په نورو ډلو کې کار کولو لپاره ډله پریښوده. اډلر او کمبل د مورټن ځای ایب سپیئر ته واچاوه. د راتلونکو پنځو کلونو لپاره ، بینډ په ریچمنډ او شاوخوا ویرجینیا کې تمرین وکړ. په 1995 کې ، بینډ خپل ځان نومول شوی لومړی ډیمو خپور کړ. د ډیمو وروسته ، د Burn the Priest په ترتیب سره د شیطان اجنټانو او ZED سره دوه جلا EPs ثبت کړل. د ډیمو لومړیو دریو ډیمو وروسته ، د کاهن سوځول غږونکی رینډال بلیټ خپل قطار ته اضافه کړ.  پوښتنه: په کوم کال کې د Burn the Priest ډیمو خپره شوه؟","answer":"په 1995 کې"},{"question":"Mitovy hevitra sa mifanipa-kevitra sa tsy misy ifandraisany ireto fehezanteny roa ireto?Fehezanteny A: Miraikitra be ny lelako.Fehezanteny B: Tsy mahvita miteny tsara aho.","answer":"Mitovy hevitra ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"О ком идет речь: русский писатель, литературный критик, журналист, мемуарист, публицист. Муж Авдотьи Брянской.","answer":"Ива́н Ива́нович Пана́ев "},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"நம் நாட்டைப் பாரத தேசம் என்று சொல்வது ஆரிய ஆதிக்கத்தைக் குறிப்பதே தவிர வேறில்லை."},{"question":"வினா: ஒட்டகச்சிவிங்கிக்கு எத்தனை வயிறு உள்ளது?","answer":"விடை: 4"},{"question":"Wanne Sahabi ne ya kashe mahaifinsa a filin yakin  Badar","answer":" (a) Abu Ubaidah (b) Umar dan Khaddabi (c) Amru binAl As"},{"question":"Uthini umbuzo  onempendulo ethi: \\"AM-2201 (1-(5-fluoropentyl)-3-(1-naphthoyl) indole) ngumchiza wophando osebenza njenge-agonist epheleleyo enamandla kodwa engakhethiyo kwi-cannabinoid receptor.\\"? Umxholo wayo ngu-AM-2201.","answer":"\\"yintoni i-am 2201?\\""},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండి:నిర్జీవుల, సజీవుల పెరుగుదలలోని భేదాలను ఎలా గుర్తిస్తారు?","answer":"కింది విధంగా నిర్జీవుల, సజీవుల పెరుగుదలలోని భేదాలను గుర్తిస్తారు:1. సజీవులలో పెరుగుదల అనేది శరీరంలో జీవకణాల పెరుగుదల వలన జరుగుతుంది. వీటిలో పెరుగుదల అంతర్గతం. జంతువులలో పెరుగుదల పరిమితంగా ఉంటే మొక్కలలో పెరుగుదల అపరిమితంగా ఉంటుంది.2. నిర్జీవులలో మాత్రం పెరుగుదల అనేది బాహ్యంగా పదార్థం సమకూరడం వల్ల జరుగుతంది."},{"question":"اكمل الجملة التالية: وسيعود هنري (البالغ 46 عاما) إلى عالم التدريب بعد أن ترك منصبه مدربا مساعدا لمدرب","answer":"منتخب بلجيكا بعد مونديال قطر 2022."},{"question":"ગૂગલ મીટ મફત છે?","answer":"હા ગૂગલ મીટનો ઉપયોગ તમે મફત કરી શકો છો, વ્યક્તિગત રીતે મફત ઉપયોગ સરળતાથી કરી શકાશે, પણ તેમાં અમુક લિમિટેશન પણ આપેલી હોય છે.જો તમારે કોઈ જરૂરી ધંધાને લગતી, શિક્ષણને લગતી અથવા કોર્પોરેટ મિટિંગ કરવી હોય તો તમે પૈસા ખર્ચીને અલગથી પ્લાન પણ ખરીદી શકો છો જેમાં તમને ખૂબ જ સરસ અને આધુનિક ફીચર્સ આપવામાં આવે છે."},{"question":"రాజనీతిశాస్త్రాన్ని నిర్వచించి, ఆ శాస్త్ర పరిధిని వివరించండి.","answer":"పరిచయం: సాంఘిక శాస్త్రాలలో రాజనీతిశాస్త్రము ప్రధానమైనది. ప్రాచీన గ్రీకునగర రాజ్యాలైన ఏథెన్స్, స్పార్టా, గ్రీస్, రోమ్ లో క్రీ.పూ. 4వ శతాబ్దంలో ప్రారంభమైనది. ప్రముఖ గ్రీకు రాజనీతివేత్తలైన సోక్రటీస్, ప్లేటో, అరిస్టాటిల్ రాజనీతిని తత్త్వశాస్త్రము నుండి వేరుచేసి ప్రత్యేక అధ్యయన శాస్త్రముగా అభివృద్ధి చేసిరి. అరిస్టాటిల్ రాజనీతిశాస్త్రానికి ప్రత్యేక గుర్తింపు తెచ్చాడు. అందువలన ఇతను “మొట్టమొదటి రాజనీతి శాస్త్రవేత్త”గాను, “రాజనీతి “శాస్త్ర పితామహుడు”గా కీర్తింపబడినాడు. అరిస్టాటిల్ తన ప్రఖ్యాత గ్రంథమైన “పాలిటిక్స్”లో రాజ్యము, ప్రభుత్వము గురించి అధ్యయనము చేసే శాస్త్రము రాజనీతిశాస్త్రమని పేర్కొనినాడు.పద పరిణామము: “పాలిటిక్స్ అనే పదం “పోలిస్” మరియు “పొలిటికస్” అనే లాటిన్ పదాల నుండి గ్రహించడమైనది. వీటి అర్థం నగర రాజ్యం.రాజనీతిశాస్త్ర నిర్వచనాలు: రాజనీతి శాస్త్రజ్ఞులు రాజనీతిశాస్త్రాన్ని వివిధ రకాలుగా నిర్వచించినారు. వాటిని రెండు రకాలుగా వర్గీకరించవచ్చు.సాంప్రదాయ నిర్వచనాలుఆధునిక నిర్వచనాలు.1. సాంప్రదాయక నిర్వచనాలు: సాంప్రదాయకమైన నిర్వచనాలను మూడు ఉపవర్గాలుగా వర్గీకరించారు. వాటిని కింది విధంగా పేర్కొనవచ్చు.i) రాజ్యం గురించి అధ్యయనం చేసేదే రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం: రాజనీతి తత్వవేత్తలైన జె.డబ్ల్యు. గార్నర్, ఆర్.జి.గెటిల్, అప్పాదొరై మరియు ఇతరులు రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం రాజ్యాన్ని గురించి అధ్యయనం చేస్తుందని వివరించారు.జె.డబ్ల్యు. గార్నర్: “రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం రాజ్యంతో ఆరంభమై రాజ్యంతోనే అంతమవుతుంది”.ఆర్.జి.గెటిల్: “రాజనీతిశాస్త్రమంటే రాజ్యం గతంలో ఎలా ఉండేదో పరిశోధించి, వర్తమాన కాలంలో ఎలా ఉన్నదో విశ్లేషించి, భవిష్యత్ కాలంలో ఎలా ఉండాలి అనే అంశంపై జరిపే రాజకీయ, నైతిక చర్చల సారాంశం”.ii) ప్రభుత్వాన్ని గురించి అధ్యయనం చేసేదే రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం: రాజనీతి తత్వవేత్తలైన స్టీఫెన్ లీకాక్, జాన్ రిచర్డు సీలీ ఇతరులు రాజనీతి శాస్త్రం ప్రభుత్వాన్ని గురించి అధ్యయనం చేస్తుందని తెలిపారు.స్టీఫెన్ లీకాక్: “రాజనీతిశాస్త్రమంటే ప్రభుత్వం గురించి అధ్యయనం చేసే శాస్త్రం”.జాన్ రిచర్డు సీలీ: “ప్రభుత్వ దృగ్విషయాన్ని గురించి పరిశోధన జరిపే శాస్త్రమే రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం”.iii) రాజ్యం, ప్రభుత్వం గూర్చి అధ్యయనం చేసేది: రాజనీతితత్వవేత్తలైన పాలానెట్, ఆర్.ఎన్. గిల్ క్రిస్ట్, డిమాక్, ప్రొఫెసర్ కాట్లిన్ ఇతరులు రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం రాజ్యాన్ని మరియు ప్రభుత్వాన్ని గురించి అధ్యయనం చేసే శాస్త్రంగా తెలియజేసారు.“ప్రభుత్వాన్ని గురించి వివరిస్తుంది”:పాలానెట్: “రాజనీతిశాస్త్రమంటే రాజ్య మూలాధారాలు, ప్రభుత్వ సూత్రాల గురించి తెలియజేసే సామాజిక శాస్త్రంలోని ఒక విభాగం”.ఆర్.ఎన్.గిల్ క్రిస్ట్: ‘రాజ్యం, ప్రభుత్వ సూత్రాలను, అధ్యయనం చేసే శాస్త్రమే రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం’.కాట్లిన్: ‘ప్రభుత్వాంగాలు, వ్యక్తుల రాజకీయ కార్యకలాపాలను అధ్యయనం చేసే శాస్త్రమే రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం’.2. ఆధునిక నిర్వచనాలు:లాస్వెల్, కాప్లాన్: “రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం ఒక అనుభవాత్మక శాస్త్రంగా ఉంటూ అధికార రూపకల్పన, అధికారుల భాగస్వామ్యం గురించి అధ్యయనం చేస్తుంది”.డేవిడ్ ఈస్టన్: “రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం సమాజం కోసం విలువలను (వస్తువులను) అధికారయుతంగా పంపిణీ చేయడానికి సంబంధించి అధ్యయనం చేస్తుంది”.రాజనీతి శాస్త్రం-పరిధి: గత వంద సంవత్సరాలలో రాజనీతిశాస్త్ర పరిధి చాలా విస్తరించింది. ప్రస్తుతం ఉన్న ఆధునిక రాజ్యాల కార్యకలాపాలను వివరించే శాస్త్రముగా అభివృద్ధి చెందింది. వ్యక్తి స్వేచ్ఛను ఎలా కాపాడుకోవాలి, రాజ్యానికి, శాసనానికి ఎందుకు విధేయత చూపాలి అనే విషయాలను తెలియజేయును. వాస్తవానికి ప్రభుత్వ ప్రమేయం ప్రత్యక్షంగానో, పరోక్షంగానో లేని మానవ కార్యకలాపాలుండవు. రాజనీతిశాస్త్రము మానవుని ప్రవర్తనను అధ్యయనం చేస్తుంది. అందువలన ప్రవర్తనావాదులు “సర్వత్రా వ్యాపించిన రాజకీయాలు” అని అంటారు.రాజనీతిశాస్త్రములో చర్చించబడే విషయాలను ఈక్రింది విధంగా వివరించవచ్చును.i) సమాజం, రాజ్యాలతో మానవునికి గల సంబంధాలు అధ్యయనం: మానవుడు సంఘజీవి అని అరిస్టాటిల్ భావించాడు. మానవుడు తన ఆహారం, వస్త్రం, గృహం వంటి ప్రాథమిక అవసరాలను సమాజంలో తీర్చుకొంటాడు. రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం మానవుడికి, సమాజానికి మధ్య గల సంబంధాన్ని వివరిస్తుంది. అంతేకాకుండా సమాజం పుట్టుక, పరిణామం, ఉద్దేశ్యాలను కూడా అది తెలుపుతుంది. మానవుడు సమాజంలో ఏ విధంగా సర్దుబాటు చేసుకొని జీవిస్తాడు అనే అంశాన్ని పరిశీలిస్తుంది. ఈ సందర్భంలో రాజనీతిశాస్త్ర అధ్యయనం వ్యక్తికి, సమాజానికి ఎంతో ప్రాముఖ్యతగలదిగా ‘దిలాన్’ అనే పండితుడు భావించాడు. సమాజం పట్ల ఆధునిక మానవుడు సరైన దృక్పథాన్ని ఏర్పర్చుకోవాల్సిన అవసరం ఉందన్నాడు. సమాజంలో మానవుడు | మమేకం అయినప్పుడు మాత్రమే అది సాధ్యపడుతుందని వివరించారు.వ్యక్తులకు, రాజ్యానికి మధ్య సరియైన సంబంధాన్ని నెలకొల్పే ప్రధాన అంశాలపైనే రాజనీతిశాస్త్ర అధ్యయనం కేంద్రీకృతమవుతుంది. రాజ్యంలోని రాజకీయ సంస్థల ప్రాముఖ్యతను వివరించడం ద్వారా అనేక సంక్లిష్ట సమస్యల పరిష్కారానికి ఈ శాస్త్రం దోహదపడుతుంది. ఈ సందర్భంలో అది రాజ్యాధికార పరిమితులు, వ్యక్తి స్వాతంత్ర్యాల అవధులు వంటి అనేక విషయాలను చర్చిస్తుంది.ii) రాజ్య అధ్యయనం: పాలానెట్, బ్లంటి షిల్లీ, గార్నర్ లాంటి రాజనీతి శాస్త్రవేత్తలు రాజనీతిశాస్త్రాన్ని రాజ్యానికి సంబంధించిన అధ్యయన శాస్త్రంగా పరిగణించారు. వారి ప్రకారం, రాజ్యమనేది రాజకీయ సంస్థగా వారు భావించారు. రాజ్యం ప్రతి వ్యక్తికీ అవసరమైనది. రాజ్యానికి, పౌరులకు మధ్యగల సన్నిహిత సంబంధాన్ని రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం తెలుపుతుంది. అలాగే రాజ్య అవతరణ సిద్ధాంతాలను వివరిస్తుంది. అంతేకాకుండా రాజ్యం స్వభావం విధులు, వివిధ రాజ్యాధికార సిద్ధాంతాలను పేర్కొంటుంది. రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం గతంలో రాజ్య అవతరణ అభివృద్ధి గురించి, వర్తమానంలోనూ, భవిష్యత్తులోనూ రాజకీయ సంస్థ, రాజకీయ భావాలను వర్ణించి విశ్లేషించేందుకు దోహదపడుతుందని ఈ సందర్భంలో ఆర్.జి. గెటిల్ పేర్కొన్నాడు.i) వర్తమానంలో రాజ్యం పరిస్థితి ii) గతంలో రాజ్యపు ఉనికి iii) భవిష్యత్లో రాజ్యం ఎలా ఉండబోతుంది అనే మూడు విషయాల విశ్లేషణలు రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం పరిధిలో ఉంటాయి.iii) ప్రభుత్వ అధ్యయనం: రాజనీతిశాస్త్ర పరిధిలో ప్రభుత్వం గురించిన అంశాలు ఉంటాయి. స్టీఫెన్ లీకాక్, జాన్ రిచర్డ్ సీలీ లాంటి కొందరు రాజనీతిశాస్త్రవేత్తలు ఈ శాస్త్ర పరిధిని ప్రభుత్వ అధ్యయనానికి పరిమితం చేశారు. వారి ప్రకారం, ఈ శాస్త్రం ప్రభుత్వం గురించి అధ్యయనం చేస్తుంది. ప్రభుత్వమనేది రాజ్యపు ప్రతినిధి అని, ప్రభుత్వం లేకుండా రాజ్యం ఉండదని వారు భావించారు. ప్రభుత్వం ద్వారానే రాజ్య ఆశయాలు నెరవేరతాయి. రాజ్య అభీష్టాన్ని ప్రభుత్వం రూపొందించి, వ్యక్తీకరించి, అమలులో ఉంచుతుంది. కొంతమంది వ్యక్తులు లేదా వ్యక్తుల సముదాయం రాజ్యం తరపున అధికారికంగా ఆజ్ఞలను జారీచేస్తారు. వారినే ప్రభుత్వంగా పరిగణించడమైంది. రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం, ప్రభుత్వానికి గల అర్థం, నిర్మితి, రకాలు స్వభావం, కర్తవ్యాలను అధ్యయనం చేస్తుంది. అలాగే ప్రభుత్వ అంశాల మధ్య సంబంధాన్ని చర్చిస్తుంది. రాజ్యం, ప్రభుత్వాల మధ్య వ్యత్యాసాలను గుర్తిస్తుంది.iv) సంఘాలు, సంస్థల అధ్యయనం: వ్యక్తి జీవనాన్ని ప్రభావితం చేసే అనేక సంఘాలు, సంస్థలు ఉన్నాయి. ప్రతి వ్యక్తి రాజ్యంలోని భిన్న సంఘాలు, సంస్థలలో సభ్యుడిగా ఉంటాడు. రాజ్యం వ్యక్తుల రాజకీయ అవసరాలను తీర్చగా, సంఘాలు, సంస్థలనేవి వ్యక్తుల నైతిక, మత, సాంస్కృతిక, వైజ్ఞానిక, సాంకేతిక ప్రగతికి సంబంధించిన విషయాలపై సహాయంగా ఉంటాయి. అవి స్థానిక, జాతీయ, అంతర్జాతీయ స్థాయిలలో తమ కార్యక్రమాలను నిర్వహిస్తుంటాయి. వ్యక్తులు ఆ సంస్థలలో తమ ప్రయోజనాలు లేదా ఉద్దేశ్యాలకు అనుగుణంగా చేరి వ్యక్తిత్వ వికాసానికై కృషి చేస్తారు. పైన పేర్కొన్న సంఘాలు, సంస్థలు వ్యక్తుల సంపూర్ణ వికాసంలో కీలకపాత్ర పోషిస్తాయి. వ్యక్తులు, కుటుంబం, కులం, రాజకీయ పార్టీలు, మతం వంటి అనేక సంస్థలనుండి ప్రయోజనాలను పొందుతారు. రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం వివిధ సంస్థల నిర్మాణం, స్వభావం మరియు విధులను గురించి వివరిస్తుంది.v) హక్కులు, బాధ్యతల అధ్యయనం: రాజనీతిశాస్త్ర పరిధి, వ్యక్తుల హక్కులకు, బాధ్యతలకు సంబంధించిన అధ్యయనంగా ఉంది. ప్రజాస్వామ్య రాజ్యాలలోని పౌరులు జీవించే హక్కు, స్వాతంత్య్రపు హక్కు, ఆస్తిహక్కు కొన్ని హక్కులను అనుభవిస్తారు. ఈ సందర్భంలో రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం హక్కుల నిర్వచనం, వర్గీకరణ, వివిధ సిద్ధాంతాలను ప్రస్తావిస్తుంది. అలాగే ప్రాథమిక హక్కులకు సంబంధించిన రాజ్యాంగ అంశాలపై దృష్టిని సారిస్తుంది. రాజ్యం పట్ల పౌరులు కొన్ని బాధ్యతలు కలిగి ఉంటారు. అటువంటి బాధ్యతలలో పన్నుల చెల్లింపు, శాసన విధేయతలాంటివి ఉంటాయి. రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం, పౌరుల హక్కుల బాధ్యతల ప్రాముఖ్యతనువివరిస్తుంది.vi) జాతీయ – అంతర్జాతీయ అంశాల అధ్యయనం: రాజనీతిశాస్త్ర పరిధిలో 20వ శతాబ్ది ప్రారంభం నుంచి ప్రాముఖ్యత వహించిన అంతర్జాతీయ సంబంధాలనేవి చేర్చబడినాయి. ఈ శాస్త్రం వర్ధమాన జాతి రాజ్యాలతో పాటుగా అంతర్జాతీయ రాజకీయాలను కూడా చర్చిస్తుంది. ఆధునిక రాజ్యాలు ఇతర రాజ్యాలతో ప్రాదేశిక సమగ్రత, సార్వభౌమత్వం పరిరక్షణకు సంబంధించిన అంశాలను ఈ శాస్త్రం వివరిస్తుంది. ప్రచ్ఛన్న యుద్ధం, ప్రాబల్య సమతౌల్యం, నిరాయుధీకరణ, దౌత్యనీతి వంటి విషయాలను అధ్యయనం చేస్తుంది. అలాగే అంతర్జాతీయ రాజకీయాలు, అంతర్జాతీయ న్యాయం, అంతర్జాతీయ సంస్థలు వంటి అనేక అంశాలు ఈ శాస్త్ర అధ్యయనంలో ఉంటాయి.vii) శక్తి అధ్యయనం: 20వ శతాబ్ద కాలం నాటి ప్రవర్తనావాదులు రాజనీతిశాస్త్రాన్ని రాజకీయ శక్తి నిర్మాణం, దాని భాగస్వాములను గురించి అధ్యయనం చేసే శాస్త్రంగా భావించారు. ఈ శాస్త్రం శక్తి ఏ విధంగా దక్కించుకోబడి, వినియోగించబడుతుందనే విషయాన్ని వివరిస్తుందన్నారు. రాజకీయ సామాజికీకరణ రాజకీయ సంస్కృతి, రాజకీయ ప్రాతినిధ్యంలాంటి అనేక అంశాలు ఈ శాస్త్ర అధ్యయనంలో ఉన్నాయన్నారు. అంతేకాకుండా, రాజకీయ ప్రసరణ, ప్రయోజనాల వ్యక్తీకరణ, ప్రయోజనాల సమీకరణల వంటి లాంఛనప్రాయం కాని రాజకీయశక్తి దృక్కోణాలు కూడా ఈ శాస్త్ర అధ్యయనంలో భాగంగా ఉన్నాయన్నారు.viii) ప్రభుత్వ విధానాల అధ్యయనం: డేవిడ్ ఈస్టన్, ఆండర్సన్, ఛార్లెస్ లిండ్బామ్ లాంటి ఆధునిక రాజనీతిశాస్త్రవేత్తలు రాజనీతిశాస్త్రాన్ని విధానశాస్త్రమని వాదించారు. రాజనీతిశాస్త్రాన్ని ప్రభుత్వ విధాన రూపకల్పన, అమలు, మూల్యాంకనాలకు సంబంధించినదన్నారు. లాంఛనప్రాయమైన రాజకీయ నిర్మితులు, లాంఛనప్రాయంకాని రాజకీయ వర్గాల పాత్రను ఈ శాస్త్రం అధ్యయనం చేస్తుందన్నారు.ఒక రాజ్యం యొక్క ప్రభుత్వ విధానాన్ని అధ్యయనం చేసే సందర్భంలో అంతర్జాతీయ సంబంధాలపరంగా దౌత్యపరమైన, ఆర్థిక, సైనికపరమైన అంశాలకు శాస్త్రీయ వ్యూహాల రూపకల్పన కీలకపాత్రను పోషిస్తుంది."},{"question":"Ṣe àtúnkọ fún 'Adé na Olú' nípa lílo ọ̀rọ̀-arọ́pò-orúkọ dípò 'Olú'.","answer":"Adé nàn-án."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي شروط قبول العمل الصالح؟","answer":"الإجابة: الإيمان بالله وتوحيده ، والإخلاص، ومتابعة النبي فيه بأن يكون وفق ما جاء به"},{"question":"Ki ẹnikẹni tọwọ ba tẹ pe o ṣẹ sofin ijọba lori arun Korona maa mura ẹwọn oṣu mẹta- Ijọba Ondo","answer":"Ijọba ipinlẹ Ondo ti fofin de aisun tabi isọ-oru lasiko ayẹyẹ Keresimesi ati ọdun tuntun to n bọ lọna, gbogbo eto awọn ile ìjọsìn wọnyi ni wọn ni ko gbọdọ kọja aago mẹwaa alẹ titi tọrọ arun Korona to tun gbode bayii yoo fi kasẹ nilẹ.Bakan naa nijọba tun fi ọsẹ meji gbako kun ọjọ tawọn akẹkọọ ipinlẹ naa fẹẹ wọle fun saa eto ẹkọ tuntun.Iwọle awọn ọmọ ileewe ni wọn ti sun si ọjọ kejidinlogun, oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun to n bọ, dipo ọjọ kẹrin ti wọn kọkọ fi si.Alaga igbimọ to n ri si didena itankalẹ arun Korona nipinlẹ Ondo, Ọjọgbọn Olusẹgun Fatusin, sọ fawọn araalu l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, ni ọkan-o-jọkan ipade loun ti ṣe pẹlu awọn ti ọrọ kan lori ọna ti wọn fi le tete dena ajakalẹ arun naa ko too tun tan kalẹ kọja bo ṣe yẹ.Ọga agba fasiti Imọ Iṣegun to wa niluu Ondo ọhun ni ki i ṣe awọn ile-ijosin nikan lofin tuntun naa ba wi, gbogbo awọn ile-ijo, ile-ọti ati ibi igbafẹ ni wọn gbọdọ ti pa ni kete ti aago mẹwaa alẹ ba ti lu.O ni ki ẹnikẹni tọwọ ba tẹ pe o ṣẹ sofin ati ilana tijọba fi lelẹ lori ọrọ arun Korona maa mura lati fẹwọn oṣu mẹta jura tabi ki iru ẹni bẹẹ san ẹgbẹrun lọna ogun Naira gẹgẹ bii owo itanran."},{"question":"خارجی سیارے کی دریافتیں، خاص طور پر وہ جو ان کے میزبان ستاروں کے رہنے کے قابل زون میں ہیں، زمین سے باہر زندگی کے وجود کے لیے ضروری حالات کے بارے میں ہماری سمجھ کو کس طرح متاثر کرتی ہیں، اور ان نتائج سے ہماری کہکشاں کے اندر اور اس سے باہر ماورائے زمین کی زندگی کی تلاش کے لیے کیا اثرات مرتب ہوتے ہیں۔ ?","answer":"خارجی سیارے کی کھوج، خاص طور پر وہ لوگ جو قابل رہائش زون کے اندر واقع ہیں — جہاں حالات مائع پانی کے وجود کی اجازت دے سکتے ہیں — نے زمین سے باہر زندگی کے امکانات کے بارے میں ہماری سمجھ کو نمایاں طور پر متاثر کیا ہے۔ کیپلر اور ٹی ای ایس ایس جیسی خلائی دوربینوں کے مشاہدات نے ہزاروں ایکسپوپلینٹس کی نشاندہی کی ہے، جن میں سے کچھ زمین جیسی خصوصیات کو ظاہر کرتے ہیں۔ یہ معلومات ماہرین فلکیات اور ماہرین فلکیات کو سیاروں کے ماحول کے تنوع اور رہائش پذیر ہونے میں کردار ادا کرنے والے عوامل سے آگاہ کرتی ہے۔ جیمز ویب اسپیس ٹیلی اسکوپ جیسے آنے والے مشنوں کے ذریعہ ایکوپلینیٹری ماحول میں بائیو دستخطوں کے لئے جاری تلاش، ممکنہ طور پر قابل رہائش جہانوں کی نشاندہی کرنے اور اس پرانے سوال کا جواب دینے کے لئے ہماری جستجو کو آگے بڑھانے کا وعدہ رکھتی ہے کہ آیا کائنات میں کہیں اور زندگی موجود ہے۔"},{"question":"Refer to the passage below and then answer the question afterwards in the same language as the passage:Passage: There are no known official statistics of religions in North Korea. Officially, North Korea is an atheist state. Based on estimates from the late 1990s and the 2000s, North Korea is mostly irreligious, with the main religions being Korean shamanism and Chondoism. There are small communities of Buddhists and Christians. Chondoism is represented in politics by the Party of the Young Friends of the Heavenly Way, and is regarded by the government as Korea's \\"national religion\\" because of its identity as a minjung (popular) and \\"revolutionary anti-imperialist\\" movement.Question: What communities are there in North Korea?","answer":"There are small communities of Buddhists and Christians in North Korea, but the main religions are Korean shamanism and Chondoism."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഭൂമിയിലെ ഏറ്റവും വലിയ സമുദ്രം ഏതാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഭൂമിയിലെ ഏറ്റവും വലിയ സമുദ്രമാണ് പസഫിക് സമുദ്രം. ഏകദേശം 16,62,40,000 ച.കി.മീ. വിസ്തീർണ്ണമുള്ള ഈ സമുദ്രം ഭൂമിയിൽ മൊത്തം ജലത്തിന്റെ നാല്പത്തിയാറു ശതമാനം ഉൾക്കൊള്ളുന്നു. ഭൂഗോളത്തിന്റെ മൂന്നിലൊന്നു ഭാഗത്തോളം ഇത് വ്യാപിച്ചു കിടക്കുന്നു. മഹാസമുദ്രങ്ങളിൽ ഏറ്റവും ആഴമേറിയ സമുദ്രമാണ് പസഫിക് ( ശാന്തമഹാസമുദ്രം ). ഒരു ത്രികോണ ആകൃതിയാണ് ഈ സമുദ്രത്തിനുള്ളത്. വടക്കേയറ്റം ആർട്ടിക്കും, പടിഞ്ഞാറുഭാഗത്ത് ഏഷ്യ, ഓസ്ട്രേലിയ വൻ‌കരകളും കിഴക്കുഭാഗത്ത് വടക്കേ അമേരിക്ക, തെക്കേ അമേരിക്ക വൻ കരകളും, തെക്കു ഭാഗത്ത് അന്റാർട്ടിക്കയും സ്ഥിതിചെയ്യുന്നു. ശരാശരി 4500 മീറ്ററിലധികം ആഴം ഈ സമുദ്രത്തിനുണ്ട്."},{"question":" 2003 ஆம் ஆண்டு","answer":"ஈராக் மீதான கூட்டணி படையெடுப்பு மற்றும் சதாம் உசேனின் சுன்னி இசுலாம் அரபு அரசாங்கத்தை பாக்தாத்தில் இருந்து அகற்றியதில் இந்த மாகாணத்தின் மக்களின் இன அமைப்பானது ஒரு பெரிய பாத்திரம் வகித்தது. அந்த அரசாங்கமும் அதற்கு முந்தைய ஆட்சியாளர்கள் அனைவரும் சுன்னி அரேபியர்களாக இருந்தனர். மேலும் ஆட்சியாளர்கள் சியா மக்கள், குர்து மக்கள் மற்றும் ஈராக்கிய துர்க்மென் மக்கள் போன்ற பிற இன சிறுபான்மையினர் சுரண்டப்பட்டு சுன்னி அரபு நலன்களுக்கு ஆதரவாக இருந்தனர். இந்த நிலை 2003 முதல் வெகுவாக மாறியது, சுன்னி அரேபியர்கள் மாகாணம் முழுவதும் மிரட்டலுக்கு ஆளாகி வெளியேற்றத்திற்கு உள்ளாயினர்."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'hinggap bak langau, titik bak hujan'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud perkara yang terjadi dengan tiba-tiba (kemalangan dan sebagainya)"},{"question":"Күн тууралуу маалымат бер. ","answer":"Күн - сутканын жарык бөлүгү, Күн чыккандан батканга чейинки убакыт. Күндүн узактыгы ал жердин географиялык кеңдигине жана жыл мезгилине жараша болуп, күндүн жантайышына карата өзгөрөт.Күн - бул жер планетасына эн жакын жайгашкан жылдыз."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਜਿਸੁ ਧਨ ਕਉ ਚਾਰਿ ਕੁੰਟ ਉਠਿ ਧਾਵਹਿ ॥ਸੋ ਧਨੁ ਹਰਿ ਸੇਵਾ ਤੇ ਪਾਵਹਿ ॥ਜਿਸੁ ਸੁਖ ਕਉ ਨਿਤ ਬਾਛਹਿ ਮੀਤ ॥ਸੋ ਸੁਖੁ ਸਾਧੂ ਸੰਗਿ ਪਰੀਤਿ ॥ਜਿਸੁ ਸੋਭਾ ਕਉ ਕਰਹਿ ਭਲੀ ਕਰਨੀ ॥ਸਾ ਸੋਭਾ ਭਜੁ ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਸਰਨੀ ॥ਅਨਿਕ ਉਪਾਵੀ ਰੋਗੁ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ਰੋਗੁ ਮਿਟੈ ਹਰਿ ਅਵਖਧੁ ਲਾਇ ॥ਸਰਬ ਨਿਧਾਨ ਮਹਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਨਿਧਾਨੁ ॥ਜਪਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਦਰਗਹਿ ਪਰਵਾਨੁ ॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 288 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਮਿਤ੍ਰ!) ਜਿਸ ਧਨ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ (ਤੂੰ) ਚੌਹੀਂ ਪਾਸੀਂ ਉਠ ਦੌੜਦਾ ਹੈਂ ,ਉਹ ਧਨ ਤੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਤੋਂ ਲਏਂਗਾ ।ਹੇ ਮਿਤ੍ਰ! ਜਿਸ ਸੁਖ ਨੂੰ ਤੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਤਾਂਘਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਉਹ ਸੁਖ ਸੰਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆਰ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ (ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ) ।ਜਿਸ ਸੋਭਾ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ ਤੂੰ ਨੇਕ ਕਮਾਈ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਉਹ ਸੋਭਾ (ਖੱਟਣ ਲਈ) ਤੂੰ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੀ ਸਰਣ ਪਉ ।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਹਉਮੈ ਦਾ) ਰੋਗ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਹੀਲਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਦੂਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ।ਉਹ ਰੋਗ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਰੂਪੀ ਦਵਾਈ ਵਰਤਿਆਂ ਮਿਟ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਸਾਰੇ (ਦੁਨੀਆਵੀ) ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ (ਵਧੀਆ) ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਨਾਮ) ਜਪ, ਦਰਗਾਹ ਵਿਚ ਕਬੂਲ (ਹੋਵੇਂਗਾ) ।੨।\\""},{"question":"යුරෝපයේ ප්‍රබලම ආර්ථිකයට හිමිකම් කියන රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"යුරෝපයේ ප්‍රබලම ආර්ථිකයට හිමිකම් කියන රට ජර්මනිය වේ."},{"question":"When is World Children's Day?","answer":"World Children's Day is observed on November 20th each year. It was established by the United Nations in 1954 to promote international togetherness, awareness among children worldwide, and improving children's welfare. November 20th also marks the day on which the UN General Assembly adopted the Declaration of the Rights of the Child in 1959 and the Convention on the Rights of the Child in 1989."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk spaghetti bolognese sardin dengan cendawan? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah yang terperinci.","answer":"Bahan: 1 pek 500 gm spaghetti, 2 tin kecil sardin/mackerel dalam sos tomato, 1 pek 200 gm cendawan shitake atau cendawan butang, 1 tin besar tomato puree, 4 ulas bawang putih, 1 biji bawang besar, 1 sudu besar sos cili, 1 sudu kecil chilli flakes, 1 sudu kecil lada hitam, 1/2 sudu oregano kering, 2 sudu besar minyak masak, Gula dan garamCara penyediaan:1. Cencang bawang putih dan potong dadu bawang besar.2. Hiris nipis cendawan shitake.3. Tumbuk kasar lada hitam.Cara memasak spaghetti:1. Masak air dalam periuk besar.2. Bila air mendidih, masukkan satu sudu besar garam dan kemudian masukkan spaghetti. Kacau spaghetti supaya tidak melekat.3. Bila spaghetti lembut (sekitar 10 minit), angkat dan tuskan.4. Jangan buang kesemua air rebusan spaghetti. Simpan dua cawan untuk diguna kemudian.Cara memasak sos tomato sardin:1. Masukkan minyak, bawang besar, bawang putih ke dalam periuk dan tumis dengan api sederhanasehingga layu.2. Masukkan cendawan, chilli flakes dan tumis sehingga cendawan layu.3. Kemudian masukkan sardin bersama sosnya, hancurkan isi ikan dengan sudip.4. Masukkan tomato puri, lada hitam, oregano, sos cili, dua tin air dan satu cawan air rebusan spaghetti.Kacau sebati.5. Biarkan mereneh dengan api kecil, kacau sekali-sekala sehingga kuah pekat dan warna merah gelap.Masukkan gula dan garam jika perlu.6. Matikan api, angkat dan hidangkan."},{"question":"P vizesi nedir?","answer":"Amerika P vizesi, müzik, tiyatro gibi sanat faaliyetleri veya atletik müsabakalar için Amerika'ya gelen bireylerin başvurmak zorunda olduğu göçmen olmayan vize türüdür. Düzenlenecek faaliyetin ticari olup olmaması önemli değildir."},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહો માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:સાઠ વર્ષ પૂરાં થયે ઊજવાતો ઉત્સવ","answer":"ષષ્ઠિપૂર્તિ"},{"question":"Jawab soalan berikut: Ciri-ciri warganegara yang baik (rukun negara)?","answer":"Jawapan: Rukun Negara adalah konsep yang penting dalam pembentukan dan pemeliharaan keharmonisan sosial di Malaysia. Ciri-ciri warganegara yang baik (rukun negara) adalah taat pada undang-undang, memegang teguh nilai-nilai moral, bertanggung jawab, berkontribusi positif, menghormati hak asasi manusia, serta memperlihatkan sikap toleransi dan menerima perbedaan."},{"question":"கேள்வி : ஜப்பான் மீது வீசப்பட்ட முதல் அணுகுண்டு எது ?","answer":"பதில் : லிட்டில்பாய்"},{"question":"Awọn akẹkọọ Zamfara ni: Ṣoju wa ni wọn ṣe n bu yeepẹ sori irẹsi ti wọn se fun wa, wọn ni iyọ ni","answer":"“Oju oorun la wa, ko sẹni to reti pe iru nnkan bẹẹ le ṣẹlẹ, ojiji la kan bẹrẹ si i gburo ibọn tau, tau, ti ko si dawọ duro. Iro ibọn naa lo ji gbogbo wa, ẹru ba wa, awọn kan ni ka sa lọ, ṣugbọn a o mọ ibi ti a fẹẹ sa gba, awọn kan sa lọ sinu tọilẹẹti, olukaluku sa lọ, awa meji la ku ninu yara nla ti a n sun si. Bẹẹ ni iro ibọn ti wọn n yin n dun nita, ko dawọ duro rara. Awọn adigunjale la ro pe wọn de.”Bayii ni Farida Lawali, ọmọ ọdun mẹẹẹdogun, to jẹ ọkan lara awọn akẹkọọ tawọn janduku agbebọn ji gbe nileewe Government Girls Secondary School, to wa ni Jangebe, nipinlẹ Zamfara, ṣe royin bi iṣẹlẹ buruku naa ṣe ṣẹlẹ. Nnkan bii aago kan oru ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọjọ kẹrindinlọgbọn, oṣu keji, to kọja yii, lawọn agbebọn naa ṣakọlu sileewe awọn akẹkọọ-binrin naa, wọn ji ọọdunrun ati mẹtadinlogun gbe lara wọn, wọn si ko wọn wọgbo lọ.Farida ni niṣe lawọn agbebọn naa da ẹnu ibọn kọ ori wọn, ti wọn si paṣẹ pe ki awọn maa rin niṣo, wọn lawọn maa yinbọn pa ẹnikẹni to ba kọ lati ṣe bawọn ṣe wi.“Ẹsẹ la fi rin kuro niluu, titi ta a fi de inu igbo. A o riran, inu okunkun la n fẹsẹ rin gba ori okuta kọja, gbogbo wa la bu sẹkun, bi a ṣe n rin lọ la n wa ẹkun mu, ṣugbọn wọn bẹrẹ si i jan idi ibọn mọ wa pe ka dakẹ, nigba tawọn kan o tete dakẹ, wọn fi ibọn lu wọn, wọn la igi mọ awọn mi-in lori.“O ti rẹ awọn kan ninu wa tori ara wọn o ya tẹlẹ. Awọn agbebọn naa gbe awọn ti ko le rin daadaa ati awọn ti ara wọn o ya si apa wọn. Bẹẹ la n fẹsẹ kọ okuta ati ẹgun ati okun ninu igbo. Mi o ri iru e ri laye mi.”Akẹkọọ-binrin mi-in, Umma Abubakar, sọ pe, “Nigba ta a de inu igbo, oju kan naa ni wọn ko gbogbo wa si, ibẹ la si wa fun ọjọ mẹrin ta a lo lahaamọ wọn, gbangba ita nibẹ naa la n sun si. Ẹni to ba fẹẹ yagbẹ tabi tọ maa bọ si ẹgbẹ kan, agbebọn kan si maa duro ti i, ṣugbọn gbogbo eeyan maa ri ihooho ẹ.“Ninu ibẹru la n ṣe gbogbo nnkan, ninu ibẹru la n jẹun, la n yagbẹ, la n sun, tori a o mọ boya a tun le pada sile mọ, a o mọ boya a tun le ri awọn obi wa mọ. Awọn agbebọn naa ni awọn le pa gbogbo wa tinu ba bi awọn.’’Akẹkọọ-binrin mi-in, Hanainatu Abubakar sọ pe, “Awọn agbebọn naa fi wa ṣẹsin gidi, wọn pe wa lorukọ buruku, wọn bu wa, wọn si halẹ pe awọn maa pa wa danu ni. Ṣugbọn nigba to ya, wọn tun sọ pe ka gbadura fawọn ki awọn le di ọmọ Naijiria rere. Wọn lo wu awọn lati mọ ede Gẹẹsi i sọ, wọn ni ka maa kọ awọn, awọn fẹẹ gbọ oyinbo.“Nigba kan, awọn kan ti wọn duro ti wa sọ pe awọn maa fipa ba wa sun, ẹni ti ko ba si gba ninu wa, awọn maa yinbọn fun un. Ẹru ba mi gan-an, ṣugbọn olori wọn gbọ, o si kilọ fun wọn pe wọn o gbọdọ ṣe bẹẹ. Irẹsi ni wọn n se fun wa, irẹsi nikan, ko si ata ọbẹ tabi ororo. Ti wọn ba ti bu u fun wa, niṣoju wa ni wọn ṣe maa bu yeepẹ nilẹ, wọn a wọn ọn sori irẹsi naa, wọn aa ni ka maa jẹ ẹ, pe iyọ ni yeepẹ tawọn bu si i yẹn. Nigba ta a kọkọ debẹ, ọpọ ninu wa kọ lati jẹ ẹ, ṣugbọn nigba ti ebi pa wa, ti ko si si ounjẹ mi-in, niṣe la gba kamu, a n jẹ ẹ bẹẹ.”Hanainatu sọ fun Ajọ Akoroyinjọ ilẹ wa (NAN) pe bo tilẹ jẹ pe oru ni wọn waa ji awọn ko, oun ṣi ranti awọn ọna ti wọn mu awọn gba, oun si le da oju diẹ lara awọn agbebọn naa mọ toun ba ri wọn."},{"question":"Sanwo-Olu yan igbimọ ileeṣẹ to n ri si ọrọ ijọba ibilẹ tuntun","answer":"Nitori bi opin ṣe ti de ba asiko to yẹ ki awọn ọmọ igbimọ to n ri si ọrọ ijọba ibilẹ nipinlẹ Eko to wa nibẹ tẹlẹ lo, Gomina ipinlẹ Eko, Babajide Sanwo-Olu, ti yan awọn ọmọ igbimọ tuntun ti yoo maa mojuto ijọba ibilẹ naa bayii.Ninu atejade kan ti Olori awọn oṣiṣẹ nipinlẹ naa, Hakeem Muri-Okunọla fi sita lo ti sọ pe bi gomina ṣe fọwọ si awọn eeyan naa wa ni ibamu pelu ofin ti ipinlẹ Eko n lo, paapaa nigba to ṣe pe asiko awọn igbimọ to wa nibẹ ti tan. Beẹ lo ki wọn fun iṣẹ takuntakun ti wọn ṣe nigba ti wọn fi wa nipo.Atẹjade yii fi kun un pe ile igbimọ aṣofin nikan lo lẹtọọ lati fọwọ si awọn eeyan ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ yan ọhun, eyi ti wọn ni yiyan wọn da lori awọn iwe ẹri ti won ni, iwa wọn ati iriri ti wọn ti ni lori ọrọ ijọba ibilẹ.Alaga igbimọ naa ni Họnarebu Kamil Baiyewu. Awọn yooku ni Họnọrebu Taofeek Adaranijọ, Ahmed Seriki, Biọdun Ọrẹkọya ati Akeem Bamgbọla."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Oento any refa tsy foy sao ........................ \\" ","answer":"\\"  Oento any refa tsy foy sao hamoizako ny aiko. \\" "},{"question":"පැරණිතම පුරාවෘත්තය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ගිල්ගමේෂ්ගේ වීර කාව්‍යයගිල්ගමේෂ් වීර කාව්‍යය මෙසපොතේමියානු මිථ්‍යාවන්ගෙන් එකක් වන අතර එය බොහෝ විට ලෝකයේ දන්නා පැරණිතම සාහිත්‍ය කෘතිය ලෙස සැලකේ. "},{"question":"パリの女性をパリジェンヌというのに対して、パリの男性のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"パリジャンです。"},{"question":"trafalgar Square පිහිටා ඇති රට","answer":"එංගලන්තය"},{"question":"Who is the most recent person to achieve EGOT (Emmy, Grammy, Oscar, Tony) status?","answer":"Viola Davis, an American actress and producer, is the most recent person to achieve EGOT (Emmy, Grammy, Oscar, Tony) status. She is one of the few performers to have been awarded an Emmy, a Grammy, an Oscar, and a Tony. She is the sole African-American to achieve the Triple Crown of Acting as well as the third person to achieve both statuses. "},{"question":"ડાયમંડ કટિંગ અને પોલિશિંગ વિશે અમને વધુ કહો.","answer":"ડાયમંડ કટિંગ અને પોલિશિંગ એ એક જટિલ પ્રક્રિયા છે જે રફ હીરાને ચમકતા રત્નોમાં પરિવર્તિત કરે છે જેની આજે આપણે પ્રશંસા કરીએ છીએ. આ પ્રક્રિયાનો ઉદ્દભવ ગુજરાત, ભારતમાં થયો છે અને સદીઓથી ગુજરાતી કારીગરોની કુશળતા અને કારીગરી દ્વારા તેને પૂર્ણ કરવામાં આવી છે.રફ ડાયમંડથી રત્ન સુધીની જર્નીખરબચડા હીરા, જેમ જેમ તેઓ પૃથ્વી પરથી નીકળે છે, તે ઘણીવાર નિસ્તેજ અને નિરાધાર હોય છે, જે તેજસ્વી રત્નો સાથે થોડી સામ્યતા ધરાવે છે જે તેઓ આખરે બનશે. હીરાને કાપવાની અને પોલિશ કરવાની પ્રક્રિયામાં ઝીણવટભર્યા પગલાઓની શ્રેણીનો સમાવેશ થાય છે જે ધીમે ધીમે હીરાના આકાર, સ્પષ્ટતા અને તેજસ્વીતાને સુધારે છે.ક્લીવિંગ: ખરબચડી હીરાને તેના કુદરતી ક્લીવેજ પ્લેનને ઓળખવા માટે પ્રથમ તપાસવામાં આવે છે. આ વિમાનોની સાથે, હીરાને ક્લીવિંગ નાઈફ નામના વિશિષ્ટ સાધનનો ઉપયોગ કરીને નાના ટુકડાઓમાં વિભાજિત કરી શકાય છે. કટીંગ અને પોલિશિંગ માટે શ્રેષ્ઠ અભિગમ નક્કી કરવા માટે આ પ્રક્રિયા નિર્ણાયક છે.કરવત: કાપેલા હીરાને પછી ઇચ્છિત આકારમાં કાપવામાં આવે છે, સામાન્ય રીતે ગોળ અથવા અંડાકાર. આ હીરા-કોટેડ બ્લેડથી સજ્જ વિશિષ્ટ હીરાની આરીનો ઉપયોગ કરીને કરવામાં આવે છે જે અત્યંત સખત હીરાની સામગ્રીને કાપી શકે છે.બ્રુટીંગ:  હીરા બ્રુટીંગ નામની પ્રક્રિયામાંથી પસાર થાય છે, જેમાં તેમને રફ ડાયમંડ ગ્રિટ અથવા ડાયમંડ કોટેડ ગ્રાઇન્ડીંગ વ્હીલ્સ સામે ઘસવામાં આવે છે. આ પ્રારંભિક આકાર આપવાની પ્રક્રિયા અપૂર્ણતાને દૂર કરે છે અને હીરાના એકંદર સ્વરૂપને શુદ્ધ કરે છે.ગર્ડલ ગ્રાઇન્ડીંગ: હીરાની કમરપટ્ટી અથવા પથ્થરને ઘેરી લેતી પાતળી કિનારી એક સરળ અને સપ્રમાણ ધાર બનાવવા માટે ચોક્કસ રીતે ગ્રાઉન્ડ અને પોલિશ્ડ હોય છે. દાગીનામાં હીરાને સેટ કરવા માટે આ પગલું નિર્ણાયક છે.સામનો કરવો: પ્રક્રિયામાં સૌથી જટિલ અને માંગણી કરનાર પગલું એ ફેસિંગ છે. હીરાની સપાટી કાળજીપૂર્વક પાસાવાળી હોય છે, અથવા નાના, સપાટ વિમાનોની શ્રેણીમાં કાપવામાં આવે છે. આ પાસાઓના ચોક્કસ ખૂણા અને ગોઠવણી હીરાની તેજસ્વીતા અથવા પ્રકાશ અને ચમકને પ્રતિબિંબિત કરવાની તેની ક્ષમતા નક્કી કરે છે.પોલિશિંગ: એકવાર ફેસિંગ પૂર્ણ થઈ જાય, હીરાને પોલિશ કરવાના અંતિમ તબક્કામાંથી પસાર થાય છે. આમાં કોઈપણ બાકી રહેલા સ્ક્રેચ અને અપૂર્ણતાને દૂર કરવા માટે હીરાને ઝીણા હીરાના પાવડર સામે ઘસવામાં આવે છે, જેના પરિણામે અત્યંત પ્રતિબિંબીત સપાટી બને છે.ડાયમંડ કટિંગ અને પોલિશિંગમાં ગુજરાતી નિપુણતાહીરા કાપવાની અને પોલિશ કરવાની કળાને ગુજરાત, ભારતમાં સદીઓથી સન્માનિત કરવામાં આવી છે. ગુજરાતી કારીગરોને ભૂતકાળની પેઢીઓમાંથી કૌશલ્ય અને તકનીકો વારસામાં મળી છે અને આ હસ્તકલામાં તેમની નિપુણતાએ ગુજરાતને ડાયમંડ પ્રોસેસિંગ માટે વૈશ્વિક કેન્દ્ર બનાવ્યું છે.ગુજરાતી કારીગરો તેમના વિગતવાર ધ્યાન, નાજુક હીરાને ચોકસાઇ સાથે હેન્ડલ કરવાની તેમની ક્ષમતા અને હીરા કાપવા અને પોલિશ કરવાની તેમની ઊંડી સમજણ માટે જાણીતા છે. તેમની કુશળતા રફ હીરાને તેજસ્વી રત્નોમાં પરિવર્તિત કરવામાં નિમિત્ત બની છે જે વિશ્વભરમાં દાગીનાના ટુકડાને શણગારે છે.ડાયમંડ કટિંગ અને પોલિશિંગનું આર્થિક મહત્વડાયમંડ કટિંગ અને પોલિશિંગ એ ગુજરાતમાં નોંધપાત્ર આર્થિક પ્રેરક છે. આ ઉદ્યોગ કુશળ કારીગરોથી લઈને તકનીકી નિષ્ણાતો સુધી મોટી સંખ્યામાં લોકોને રોજગારી આપે છે. તે રાજ્ય માટે નોંધપાત્ર આવક પણ પેદા કરે છે અને ભારતના વૈશ્વિક વેપારમાં ફાળો આપે છે.ડાયમંડ પ્રોસેસિંગના અગ્રણી કેન્દ્ર તરીકે ગુજરાતની સ્થિતિએ આંતરરાષ્ટ્રીય ખેલાડીઓ પાસેથી રોકાણ આકર્ષ્યું છે, જેનાથી ઉદ્યોગની વૃદ્ધિ અને આર્થિક અસરમાં વધારો થયો છે. કાર્યક્ષમતા અને ગુણવત્તા સુધારવા માટે ઉદ્યોગ લેસર કટીંગ અને કોમ્પ્યુટરાઈઝ્ડ પોલીશીંગ મશીન જેવી નવી ટેકનોલોજી પણ અપનાવી રહ્યો છે.નિષ્કર્ષમાં, હીરાનું કટીંગ અને પોલિશિંગ એ એક નોંધપાત્ર હસ્તકલા છે જે ગુજરાતમાં સદીઓથી નિપુણ છે. ગુજરાતી કારીગરોએ રફ હીરાને ચમકતા રત્નોમાં રૂપાંતરિત કરવામાં મહત્ત્વની ભૂમિકા ભજવી છે જેને આપણે આજે યાદ કરીએ છીએ. તેમની કુશળતા અને સમર્પણએ ગુજરાતને હીરાની પ્રક્રિયા માટે વૈશ્વિક હબ બનાવ્યું છે, જે રાજ્યના અર્થતંત્ર અને સાંસ્કૃતિક વારસામાં નોંધપાત્ર યોગદાન આપે છે."},{"question":"Magaca Loo-Yaqaano Geedka Aanu Shimbiruhu Ku Dagan?","answer":"Geedka Loo-Yaqaano Baxar Saafka."},{"question":"Sheeg saxaabiyadii ugu horeesay ee dishay qof gaal ah?","answer":" Saxaabiyadii dishay qof gaal ah waa Safiya bintu Cabdi Mudalib (RC) oo eheed nabiga (NNKH) eedadiis."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa qofkii ugu horeeyey ee Islaamka u hijrooda?","answer":"Qofkii ugu horeeyey ee Islaamka u hijrooda waa Cusmaan Bin Cafaan Iyo Rukhiya bintu Muxammed Rc."},{"question":"Cual es la respuesta correcta para esta pregunta: ¿Qué libro de la saga Dragonlance es el más largo?","answer":"La respuesta correcta a esta pregunta es : Dragons of Summer Flame"},{"question":"《威尼斯商人》是誰的作品？","answer":"《威尼斯商人》 是莎士比亞早期的重要作品，是一部具有極大諷刺性的喜劇。"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"சமுதாய்ச் சீர்திருத்தத்தின் கடைசி எல்லை பொதுவுடைமை; அறிவின் உண்மையான கடைசி எல்லை நாத்திகம்."},{"question":"O que é Fitoenergética ou Fitoenergia? ","answer":"Fitoenergética ou Fitoenergia, de forma resumida, é utilizar o poder oculto das nossas queridas plantas para alcançar o equilíbrio espiritual e elevar a consciência. O que a fitoenergia busca é trazer à luz as verdadeiras causas de uma doença, por exemplo, tornando-se forte aliada à medicina convencional. Se você se interessa mais sobre o assunto, pesquise por Bruno Gimenes, o criador da técnica, e por bioeletrografia - que consiste em uma fotografia do campo energético do indivíduo. Não confunda, também, Fitoenergética com Fitoterapia. A fitoterapia utiliza os princípios químicos de uma planta para tratar o corpo físico, enquanto a fitoenegética, como anteriormente citado, utiliza o princípio energético da eva no campo sutil (o nosso emocional, mental e espiritual) do corpo humano, dos animais, do ambiente e das próprias plantas."},{"question":"متى أصبح الأمير عبدالله بن عبد العزيز وليا للعهد في المملكة السعودية؟","answer":"1982"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਰਾਗੁ ਗਉੜੀ ਬੈਰਾਗਣਿ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ੴ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ॥ਦਯ ਗੁਸਾਈ ਮੀਤੁਲਾ ਤੂੰ ਸੰਗਿ ਹਮਾਰੈ ਬਾਸੁ ਜੀਉ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਤੁਝ ਬਿਨੁ ਘਰੀ ਨ ਜੀਵਨਾ ਧ੍ਰਿਗੁ ਰਹਣਾ ਸੰਸਾਰਿ ॥ਜੀਅ ਪ੍ਰਾਣ ਸੁਖਦਾਤਿਆ ਨਿਮਖ ਨਿਮਖ ਬਲਿਹਾਰਿ ਜੀ ॥੧॥ਹਸਤ ਅਲੰਬਨੁ ਦੇਹੁ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਗਰਤਹੁ ਉਧਰੁ ਗੋਪਾਲ ॥ਮੋਹਿ ਨਿਰਗੁਨ ਮਤਿ ਥੋਰੀਆ ਤੂੰ ਸਦ ਹੀ ਦੀਨ ਦਇਆਲ ॥੨॥ਕਿਆ ਸੁਖ ਤੇਰੇ ਸੰਮਲਾ ਕਵਨ ਬਿਧੀ ਬੀਚਾਰ ॥ਸਰਣਿ ਸਮਾਈ ਦਾਸ ਹਿਤ ਊਚੇ ਅਗਮ ਅਪਾਰ ॥੩॥ਸਗਲ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਅਸਟ ਸਿਧਿ ਨਾਮ ਮਹਾ ਰਸ ਮਾਹਿ ॥ਸੁਪ੍ਰਸੰਨ ਭਏ ਕੇਸਵਾ ਸੇ ਜਨ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਹਿ ॥੪॥ਮਾਤ ਪਿਤਾ ਸੁਤ ਬੰਧਪੋ ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਾਣ ਅਧਾਰ ॥ਸਾਧਸੰਗਿ ਨਾਨਕੁ ਭਜੈ ਬਿਖੁ ਤਰਿਆ ਸੰਸਾਰੁ ॥੫॥੧॥੧੧੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 203 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਤਰਸ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ! ਹੇ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਦੇ ਖਸਮ! ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਮਿੱਤਰ ਹੈਂ, ਸਦਾ ਮੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਰਹੁ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਤੈਥੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਇਕ ਘੜੀ ਭਰ ਭੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਤੇ (ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ) ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿਣਾ ਫਿਟਕਾਰ-ਜੋਗ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਜਿੰਦ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ! ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਾਣ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ! ਹੇ ਸੁਖ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਮੈਂ ਤੈਥੋਂ ਨਿਮਖ ਨਿਮਖ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਹੱਥ ਦਾ ਸਹਾਰਾ ਦੇਹ । ਹੇ ਗੋਪਾਲ! ਮੈਨੂੰ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ) ਟੋਏ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਕੱਢ ਲੈ । ਗੁਣ-ਹੀਣ ਹਾਂ, ਮੇਰੀ ਮਤਿ ਹੋਛੀ ਹੈ । ਤੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਹੀ ਗਰੀਬਾਂ ਉਤੇ ਦਇਆ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈਂ ।੨।ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰੇ (ਦਿਤੇ ਹੋਏ) ਕੇਹੜੇ ਕੇਹੜੇ ਸੁਖ ਚੇਤੇ ਕਰਾਂ? ਮੈਂ ਕਿਹੜੇ ਕਿਹੜੇ ਤਰੀਕਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ (ਤੇਰੇ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ੇ ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦੀ) ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰਾਂ? (ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰੇ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਸੁਖ ਗਿਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ) ਹੇ ਉੱਚੇ! ਹੇ ਅਪਹੁੰਚ! ਹੇ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਹੇ ਸਰਨ ਆਏ ਦੀ ਸਹਾਇਤਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਹੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੇਵਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਤੂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਦਾਰਥ (ਜੋਗੀਆਂ ਦੀਆਂ) ਅੱਠੇ ਸਿੱਧੀਆਂ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਸ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਟ ਰਸ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਵਿਚ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹਨ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਉਤੇ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਲੰਮੇ ਕੇਸਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪ੍ਰਸੰਨ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਬੰਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੪।(ਹੇ ਦਯ! ਹੇ ਗੋਸਾਈਂ!) ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਾਣਾਂ ਦੇ ਆਸਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਮਾਂ, ਪਿਉ, ਪੁੱਤਰ, ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇਦਾਰ (ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਮੇਰਾ) ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਤੂੰ ਹੈਂ । (ਤੇਰਾ ਦਾਸ) ਨਾਨਕ (ਤੇਰੀ) ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ (ਤੇਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ) ਤੇਰਾ ਭਜਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਤੇਰਾ ਭਜਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ) ਜ਼ਹਰ-ਭਰੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਤੋਂ (ਸਹੀ-ਸਲਾਮਤਿ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਲੈ ਕੇ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੫।੧।੧੧੬।\\""},{"question":"کیا آپ فضیلت اخلاقیات کے ارسطو کے تصور کی وضاحت کر سکتے ہیں اور یہ کہ یہ دوسرے اخلاقی نظریات سے کیسے مختلف ہے؟","answer":"ارسطو کی فضیلت اخلاقیات اخلاقی طور پر اچھی زندگی گزارنے کی کلید کے طور پر نیک کردار کی خصوصیات کی نشوونما پر زور دیتی ہے۔ ان کا خیال تھا کہ ہمت، حکمت اور انصاف جیسی خوبیاں مشق اور عادت کے ذریعے پیدا کی جانی چاہئیں۔ دیگر اخلاقی نظریات کے برعکس، جیسا کہ افادیت پسندی یا ڈیونٹولوجی، فضیلت کی اخلاقیات مخصوص اصولوں یا نتائج کی بجائے کسی فرد کے اخلاقی کردار پر توجہ مرکوز کرتی ہے۔"},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Vốn xuất thân là một diễn viên hài nhưng những năm gần đây, Thành Trung lấn sang lĩnh vực MC và gặt hái được khá nhiều thành công. Với gương mặt và ngoại hình sáng sân khấu, cùng lối dẫn duyên dáng pha chút hài dí dỏm, MC Thành Trung nhận được nhiều lời mời dẫn dắt cho các chương trình nổi tiếng, trong đó phải nhắc tới show truyền hình thực tế về việc làm: \\"Cơ hội cho ai - Whose chance\\". Cũng trong chương trình này, nam MC cũng đã có những quan điểm thú vị và lồng ghép tài tình câu chuyện của mình với những chủ đề của chương trình để truyền tải những thông điệp ý nghĩa đến người chơi và quý khán giả. Trong một số phát sóng năm 2020 với chủ đề: Bạn nhận định như thế nào về quan điểm \\"30 tuổi chưa mua được nhà riêng là thất bại\\", nam MC Thành Trung đã ngẫu hứng kể câu chuyện của bản thân: \\"Có một sự thật là tôi chưa bao giờ nghĩ mình có năng khiếu về kinh doanh và cũng chẳng dám nghĩ là mua được nhà cho riêng mình. Nhưng tôi đã mua được nhà vào năm 27 tuổi. Đó là một ngôi nhà hơn 800 triệu ở trên phố cổ Hà Nội, ngay cạnh nhà ba mẹ tôi. Lúc đó, tôi chỉ có hơn 200 triệu đi làm và để dành được. Tôi cực kỳ ghét vay mượn nhưng lúc đó tôi liều lĩnh vay 600 triệu của ngân hàng, mượn sổ đỏ của bố mẹ. Đó là ngôi nhà đầu tiên của tôi năm 27 tuổi. Tôi chưa bao giờ đánh giá đấy là cột mốc thành công của một con người. Với tôi, thành công là hơn chính mình của ngày hôm qua. Và tôi tự nhận là mình thành công với chính mình\\". Ngoài câu chuyện mượn sổ đỏ của bố mẹ, vay ngân hàng để tậu nhà trên, ít ai biết rằng, trước khi trở thành một gương mặt sáng giá trong giới MC như hiện nay, Thành Trung cũng từng trải qua rất nhiều khó khăn của một người lao động tìm nghề, tìm hướng đi phù hợp. Đến cuối cùng, việc chuyển hướng làm MC là một con đường mà anh thấy phù hợp nhất với khả năng cũng như đam mê của mình và thành công đến hiện tại. MC Thành Trung tiết lộ bản thân chỉ mất khoảng 3 năm đã trả xong nợ ngân hàng. Dù vậy, việc nợ nần luôn là một áp lực không nhỏ, nhất là khi công việc và thu nhập không ổn định. Thế nhưng anh cũng cho rằng, việc có nợ nần là động lực để anh làm việc và phấn đấu. Đến nay, bên cạnh công việc làm MC, Thành Trung còn hoạt động kinh doanh. Cuộc sống của anh cũng đã sung túc hơn những năm mới vào nghề rất nhiều. Nam MC hiện đang sống cùng vợ là cựu tiếp viên hàng không Ngọc Hương và cặp song sinh trong một căn penthouse rộng 260m2 tại một khu chung cư cao cấp ở Hà Nội. Đây đồng thời là món quà mà nam MC dành tặng bạn đời khiến nhiều người vô cùng ngưỡng mộ. Nam MC không tiết lộ giá trị nhưng theo một nguồn tin, penthouse trị giá khoảng 18 tỷ đồng tính cả nội thất. Theo đó, penthouse này được thiết kế theo phong cách hiện đại, sang trọng. Nội thất nhập ngoại được tối giản giúp tổ ấm tiết kiệm thêm không gian, tạo cảm giác rộng rãi và thoáng đãng. Dưới đây là một vài hình ảnh về căn penthouse cao cấp của vợ chồng MC Thành Trung:","answer":"MC Thành Trung: Từng mượn sổ đỏ của bố mẹ đi thế chấp ngân hàng để tậu nhà 800 triệu ở Phố Cổ, nay sở hữu căn penthouse đáng giá gấp hàng chục lần"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو تعريف علم المقذوفات؟","answer":"الجواب: هو العلم الذي يهتم بشكل الحركة التي يُقذَف وفقها الجسم أو القذيفة عندما تكون قرب سطح الأرض، وعندما تتحرك في مسار منحنٍ ويخضع لتأثير الجاذبية فقط لا غير."},{"question":"இந்திய அறிவயற் கழகம் அமைதுள்ள நகரம்?","answer":"விடை: பெங்களூர்"},{"question":"नेपालको पुरानो नाम के हो ?","answer":"एकीकरण पछिको प्रारम्भिक दिनहरूमा, नेपाल \\"गोरखा राज्य\\" वा \\"गोरखा साम्राज्य\\" को रूपमा चिनिन्थ्यो।"},{"question":"\\"Na manomboka maizina ny androAleo hijanona eto ihanyEto anilanao eto aho mafanam-pitiaTaman-tsafosafoSambatsambatra anieIzay tiavinaoFantatrao ihany fa ...Tsy mba manana tianaToa anao anie ahoIanao ilay tiako hatrizay ka hatrizaoKa avelao hitiaAnao mandrakizayTena tiako ianaoAry ianao koa tia ahySadaikatra ahoNy hanambaraFa mahasaro-piaro ahyIanao sangin'olon-kafa inyMankarary ahySambatsambatra anieIzay tiavinaoFantatrao ihany fa ...Tsy mba manana tianaToa anao anie ahoIanao ilay tiako hatrizay ka hatrizaoKa avelao hitiaAnao mandrakizayTena tiako ianaoAry ianao koa tia ahy\\". Inona ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io dia fitiavana."},{"question":"Efa nanoratra tamin'ny solon'anarana ve i Marc Levy?","answer":"Manoratra amin'ny anarany manokana izy."},{"question":"ප රටේ පාලක පංතිය මහජන ධනය සූරා කෑහ.මෙහිදී පාලක පංතිය වෙනුවට පාලන පංතිය යෙදිය හැකිද?","answer":"නිවැරැදි වන්නේ පාලන පන්තියයි.පාලක යන්න යොදා ගැනීමට අවශ්‍ය නම් කළ යුත්තේ එය පාලකයෝ කිරීමයි.තවද පන්තිය අප්‍රාණවාචී පදයක් වන හෙයින් පාලන පන්තිය සූරා කෑවේය විය යුතුයි."},{"question":"Omeo ny tononkalo \\" Ny saka sy ny totozy \\" izay nosoratan'i Dox .","answer":"\\"Ny saka sy ny totozy \\" nosoratan'i Dox :\\" Indray mandeha ity saka honoNantsoin'izay totozy izayNdeha isika samy hatono Ka ho hita izay tsy mayNy totozy nialohaNototofana kitayAndraso andraso hoy izy alohaNihady lavaka izy zayAreheto amin'izayNisitrika izy fa tsy mayNoho ny afaka avy teoDia ny rehaka ho mahayFa ny saka kosa hono Nihady lavaka tsy hainy Tao izy dia voatono Ary tapitra ny ainy \\" ."},{"question":"Indro  misy fanehoan-kevitra:\\"Hainao fa tsy hangataka aminao ny hanova zavatra eny aminao izany mihitsy aho.\\"Maneho endrika fanavakavahana na ahitana teny mety hanafintohina ve io fanehoan-kevitra io?","answer":"Tsy maneho fanavakavahana ary tsy ahitana teny mety hanafintohina io fanehoan-kevitra io."},{"question":"Beri jawapan untuk soalan rumit ini: Apakah jenis tempat yang sama di Regency Road, Adelaide dan Klemzig, Australia Selatan?","answer":"bandar"},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"પ્રાણ થકી મને વૈષ્ણવ વ્હાલા\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"પ્રાણ થકી મને વૈષ્ણવ વ્હાલાહરનિશ એને ધાવું રે,તપ તીરથ વૈકુંઠ તજીને,મારા વૈષ્ણવ હોય ત્યાં જાવું રે ... પ્રાણ થકી\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"પ્રાણ થકી મને વૈષ્ણવ વ્હાલાહરનિશ એને ધાવું રે,તપ તીરથ વૈકુંઠ તજીને,મારા વૈષ્ણવ હોય ત્યાં જાવું રે ... પ્રાણ થકીઅંબરીષ મુજને અતિઘણા વ્હાલા,દુર્વાસાએ મન ભંગ કીધા,મેં મારું અભિમાન તજીને,દશવાર અવતાર લીધો રે ... પ્રાણ થકીગજ તજી વહારે તમે પાદે ધાયા,સેવકની સુધ લેવા,ઊંચનીચ કુલ હું નવ જાણું,મને ભજે સો મમ જેવા ... પ્રાણ થકીમારો બાંધ્યો મારો વૈષ્ણવ છોડાવે,વૈષ્ણવનો બાંધ્યો વૈષ્ણવ છૂટે,ક્ષેણું એક વૈષ્ણવ મુજને બાંધે,તો ફિર ઉત્તર નવ સુઝે ... પ્રાણ થકીબેઠો ગાવે ત્યાં ઉભો સાંભળું,ઉભા ગાવે ત્યાં નાચું,વૈષ્ણવ જનથી ક્ષેણું ન અળગો,માન નરસૈયા સાચું ... પ્રાણ થકી"},{"question":"નીચેના ગુજરાતી ઉખાણાં નો જવાબ આપો:વીસ વીસનાં ઉતારી લીધા શીશ,ના વહ્યું લોહી, ના ચઢી રીસ.","answer":"નખ"},{"question":"நீங்கள் எதிர்கொண்ட இயற்கை இடர் குறித்து விவரித்து எழுதுக.(மழை, வெள்ளம், புயல், வறட்சி)","answer":"மழை :தவறிப்பெய்த பருவமழையால் அறுவடைக்குத் தயாராய் இருந்த பயிர்கள் நீரில் நனைந்து நாசம் அடைந்தன. போக்குவரத்து பாதிப்புகளால் மக்கள் பல இன்னல்களுக்கு ஆளாயினர். மழைப் பொழிவின் காரணமாக மக்கள் பலர் வெளியே செல்ல முடியாததாலும். மின்சாரம் தடை செய்யப்பட்டதாலும் பல தொழில்கள் முடங்கின.புயல் :சென்னைக்குத் தென்கிழக்கே 260 கி.மீ தொலைவிலும், நாகைக்கு வடகிழக்கே 180 கி.மீ தொலைவிலும் மையம் கொண்டிருந்த கஜா புயல், மேற்கு தென் மேற்குத் திசையில் நகர்ந்து கடலூர் பாம்பன் இடையே நாகைக்கு அருகே மணிக்கு 111 கி.மீ வேகத்தில் கரையைக் கடந்தது. புயலானது கரையைக் கடந்த போதிலும் டெல்டா மற்றும் கரையோர பகுதி மக்களின் கவலை இன்னும் கடந்து போகவில்லை. ஏனெனில் விவசாயிகள், மீனவர்கள் ஆகியோரின் வாழ்வாதாரமே அழிந்தது.வெள்ளம்:கடந்த 2018 ஆம் ஆண்டு கேரளாவில் ஏற்பட்ட வெள்ளமானது அம்மாநிலத்தையே புரட்டிப் போட்டது. தென்மேற்கு பருவக்காற்றினால் ஏற்பட்ட மழைப்பொழிவே இதற்குக் காரணம். வெள்ளத்தினால் ஏற்பட்ட மண்சரிவில் சிக்கி பலர் உயிரிழந்தனர். இதில் கேரளாவில் உள்ள இடுக்கி, வயநாடு கோழிக்கோடு உட்பட 10 மாவட்டங்கள் பெரிதும் பாதிக்கப்பட்டன. மலைப்பாதையில் ஏற்பட்ட மண்சரிவினால் போக்குவரத்து பாதிக்கப்பட்டது.வறட்சி:இந்திய வானிலைத் துறையின் கூற்றுப்படி 10 சதவிதத்திற்கும் குறைவான மழைப்பொழிவு இருக்குமேயானால் அந்நாட்டை வறட்சியால் பாதிக்கப்பட்ட நாடு எனலாம். பற்றாக் குறையான மழைப் பொழிவே வறட்சிக்குக் காரணம் பருவகாலம் பொய்த்துப் போவதால் உருவாகும்.மழைப் பொழிவின்மை , பருவகால மாறுபாடுகள், காடுகள் அழிவு, சுற்றுச்சூழல் சீர்கேடு, அதிக அளவு ஆவியாதல், மோசமான நில மேலாண்மை , அதீத மேய்ச்சல், மண் அரிப்பு ஆகியன வறட்சி ஏற்பட முக்கியக் காரணங்களாகும்."},{"question":"ALLA MAY I","answer":"ALLA MAY I"},{"question":"Sheeg maxa lees-ku yiraahdaa dhirta iyo xayawaanka?","answer":"Waxa la isku yiraahdaa Noole."},{"question":"Inona avy ireto tombontsoa azo avy amin’ny fanatontoloana?","answer":"Ireto avy ny tombontsoa azo avy amin'ny fanatontoloana:-Malalaka ny fifampivarotana.-Mitobaka eny amin’ny tsena ny entana avy any ivelany.-Mihena ny vidin-javatra eny an-tsena noho ny hamaroany.-Tsy misy intsony ny fampifilafilana eo amin’ny firenena mpamokatra sy ny mpanjifa.-Afaka mifidy izay tiany ny mpanjifa.-Afaka manondrana entana any ivelany koa isika saingy tsy maintsy manaraka ireo fepetra takiana amin’izany.-Ahafahana mampivoatra ny haitao sy ny hairahan’ny firenenana."},{"question":"\\"Кудай урсун\\" деп кандай учурда айтышат?","answer":" 1. Актануу, чындык экендигине ишендирүү маанисиндеги каргануу. Кудай урсун! Мен өзүм көрдүм. Кудай урсун, тийген жокмун. Кудай урсун, барган жокмун. Ушу жакшылыгыңды унутсам, кудай урсун (Бердикеев) 2. Жемелөө, ачуулануу иретинде колдонулат. Сени кудай урсун! Ушундай да иш кыласыңбы? В.: Куран урсун! Ооз айыбымды тартайын, кагылайын жеңеке. Куран урсун! Буларды кой де (Сыдыкбеков). Кудай-теңир урсун! Кудай-теңир урсун, ошондогу мен көргөн кичинекей кагаз дал ушул болчу, – деп Ашырбек жанын сабайт (Акматов)"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Maxaa La Oran Jiray Ninkii Dilay Cumar Bin Khadaab?","answer":"Jawaab: Cumar Bin Khadaab Ninkii Dilay Waxa La Oran Jiray Abuu Lu’lu Al Majuuz."},{"question":"Apo irẹsi, ẹwa, maggi, iyọ ati garawa ororo lawọn to ji ọmọleewe ni Kaduna n beere fun","answer":"Ṣe wọn ni bi iya nla ba gbe ni ṣanlẹ, kekere a maa gori ẹni. Bẹẹ lọrọ ri fawọn obi ti wọn ji awọn ọmọ wọn gbe nipinlẹ Kaduna lasiko yii, wọn lawọn ajinigbe naa ti kan si wọn, wọn si ti beere pe ki wọn tete ṣeto lati ko ọpọ ounjẹ ṣọwọ sawọn, lati bọ awọn ọmọ wọn to wa lakata awọn.Bi wọn ṣe wi, lara nnkan tẹnu n jẹ ti wọn ni kawọn obi naa ko ṣọwọ ni apo irẹsi ilẹ okeere mẹwaa (10), ogun (20) apo irẹsi tiwa-n-tiwa ati ogun (20) apo ẹwa.Wọn tun beere fun paali maggi mẹwaa, kẹẹgi ororo mẹwaa ati baagi iyọ meji ko gbọdọ gbẹyin ninu ẹru ti wọn fẹẹ ko ranṣẹ si wọn ọhun.Wọn paṣẹ pe ayafi kawọn obi naa kọkọ ṣeto fun awọn nnkan tawọn beere fun yii, ki ajọsọ too le ṣẹlẹ lori owo itusilẹ tawọn maa gba ki wọn too le ri awọn ọmọ wọn pada laaye.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, oru ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Wẹsidee mọju Ọjọruu yii, lawọn apamọlẹkun agbebọn naa ya bo ọgba ileewe Bethel Baptist High School, to wa laduugbo Maraban Rido, nijọba ibilẹ Chikum, nipinlẹ Kaduna, ti wọn si ji awọn ọmọleewe mọkandinlọgọfa gbe.Titi di ba a ṣe n sọ yii, ko ti i sẹni to ri awọn ọmọleewe naa.Iṣẹlẹ yii wa lara ohun ti Gomina ipinlẹ Kaduna, Mallam Nasir El-Rufai, fi paṣẹ pe ki wọn ti awọn ileewe mẹtala kan nipinlẹ naa, o lawọn ileewe wọnyi wa lawọn ibi tawọn agbebọn naa ti le tete ṣakọlu si."},{"question":"Ireto misy fanambarana:\\"Manana saka mainty ho biby fiompy izy.\\" sy “Mivolontsôkôlà sy fotsy ny alikany, ary Max no anarany.”Mifanindra-teny ve ireo ?","answer":"Tsia, tsy mifanindra-teny ireo fanambarana ireo. Ny iray miresaka fananana saka fa ny iray kosa miresaka alika sy ny anarany."},{"question":"Zer da filosofia?","answer":"Filosofia pentsaeraren ikerketa bilatzen duen atala da"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗੁਰਾ ਇਕ ਦੇਹਿ ਬੁਝਾਈ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 2 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ! (ਤੇਰੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਅਰਦਾਸ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਕ ਸਮਝ ਦੇਹ ।\\""},{"question":"અહીં ગંગાસતી રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"ગુપત રસ આ જાણી લેજો\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"ગુપત રસ આ જાણી લેજો પાનબાઈ!જેથી જાણવું રહે નહિ કાંઈ,ઓઘ રે આનંદના કાયમ રહે,ને સેજે સંશય બધા મટી જાય ... ગુપત.\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"ગુપત રસ આ જાણી લેજો પાનબાઈ!જેથી જાણવું રહે નહિ કાંઈ,ઓઘ રે આનંદના કાયમ રહે,ને સેજે સંશય બધા મટી જાય ... ગુપત.શુરવીર થૈને સંગ્રામે ચડવું પાનબાઈ,માયલું મન ફરી ઊભું ન થાય;કેવળ ભક્તિને તમે એમ પામો પાનબાઈ,જેથી જનમ મરણ સહેજે મટી જાય ... ગુપત. પરપંચનાં તોડી નાખો પડલ પાનબાઈ,તો તો પચરંગી પાર જણાય;જથારથ પદને જાણ્યા પછી પાનબાઈ,ભાવ કભાવ મનમાં નહિ થાય ... ગુપત.મેદાનમાં હવે મામલો મચાવો પાનબાઈ,ભજન કરો ભરપૂર,ગંગા રે સતી એમ બોલિયાં રે,વરસાવો નિર્મળ નર ... ગુપત."},{"question":"පහළ ආමාශ ආන්ත්රයික පත්රිකාව යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"පහළ ආමාශ ආන්ත්රයික පත්රිකාව (GI), කුඩා අන්ත්රය සහ සියලුම මහා අන්ත්රය ඇතුළත් වේ.[30] අන්ත්රය අන්ත්රය හෝ බඩවැල් ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ. පහළ GI ආමාශයේ pyloric sphincter වලින් ආරම්භ වන අතර ගුද මාර්ගයෙන් අවසන් වේ. කුඩා අන්ත්රය duodenum, jejunum සහ ileum ලෙස බෙදී ඇත. cecum කුඩා හා විශාල අන්ත්රය අතර බෙදීම සලකුණු කරයි. මහා අන්ත්‍රයට ගුද මාර්ගය සහ ගුද මාර්ගය ඇතුළත් වේ."},{"question":"Iza no nitondra taorian’ny nialan’i Philbert TSIRANANA teo amin’ny fitondrana ?1- Didier RATSIRAKA2- Marc RAVALOMANANA3- Gabriel RAMANANTSOA","answer":"3- Gabriel RAMANANTSOA  izay miaramila jeneraly. Praiministra izy ary avy eo nitondra ny firenana ny volana Oktobra 1975 ka nisian’ny fitondrana tetezamita ara-miaramila."},{"question":"¿Quién fue el primer presidente de Colombia tras su independencia?","answer":"El primer presidente de Colombia fue Simón Bolívar; gobernó desde el 21 de septiembre de 1819 hasta su renuncia el 4 de mayo de 1830."},{"question":"O ex-presidente do Brasil, Jair Bolsonaro, foi condenado à quantos anos de inelegibilidade?","answer":"8 anos."},{"question":"Kí ni ẹṣin ọ̀rọ̀?","answer":"Òwe ni."},{"question":"１９９６年に発売され大ヒットし流行語にもなりました！２００４年にプラスとして復活した携帯おもちゃといえば？","answer":"たまごっちです。"},{"question":"Arkaanta islaamka waa imasa?","answer":"Arkaanta islaamka waa shan."},{"question":"Địa hình được nâng cao, sông ngòi trẻ lại là đặc điểm của giai đoạn nào ở nước Việt Nam","answer":"Địa hình được nâng cao, sông ngòi trẻ lại là đặc điểm của giai đoạn đất nước Việt Nam trải qua quá trình hình thành và phát triển trong bối cảnh địa chất. Đặc điểm này liên quan đến giai đoạn hình thành đất liền trong quá khứ địa chất, khi các quá trình núi lửa, động đất và động lực địa mạng diễn ra, dẫn đến sự nâng cao và tạo hình của đất liền.Địa hình được nâng cao, sông ngòi trẻ lại là đặc điểm của giai đoạn Tân kiến tạo ở nước Việt Nam.Tân kiến tạo là giai đoạn gần đây nhất trong việc hình thành lớp vỏ (thạch quyển) của Trái Đất. Giai đoạn này rất quan trọng vì nó sẽ hoàn thiện và chỉnh sửa địa mạo của Trái Đất."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਨਾਦੰ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਵੇਦੰ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਸਮਾਈ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 2 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\" ਨਾਮ ਤੇ ਗਿਆਨ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ)। ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ (ਇਹ ਪਰਤੀਤ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਉਹ ਹਰੀ ਸਭ ਥਾਈਂ ਵਿਆਪਕ ਹੈ।\\""},{"question":"أين يقع جبل النور ؟","answer":"جبل النور هو من أبرز معالم مكة، إذ يضم غار حراء وهو الغار الذي كان يتعبد به النبي محمد قبل البعثة، وفيه أيضاً نزل الوحي، يبلغ ارتفاع هذا الجبل 642 متراً وتبلغ مساحته حوالي 5250م²"},{"question":"வினா : வெற்றிடத்தின் வழியே செல்ல இயலாதது எது ?","answer":"விடை :  ஒலி"},{"question":"ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਨੇ ਟੈਟੂ ਬਣਵਾਇਆ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਹ ਸੂਈਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਡਰਦੀ ਸੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਹ ਵਿਦਰੋਹ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਹ ਵਿਦਰੋਹ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Ònye bụ Alexander Onye Ukwu? Alexander nke atọ nke Masedonia (Ancient Greek: <unk>λέξανδρος, romanized: Alexandros; 20/21 July 356 BC <unk> 10/11 June 323 BC), nke a na-akpọkarị Alexander Onye Ukwu, bụ eze nke alaeze Gris oge ochie nke Masedonia","answer":"Alexander nke atọ nke Masedonia, nke amaara dị ka Alexander Onye Ukwu, bụ eze nke alaeze Gris oge ochie nke Masedonia. Ọ nọchiri nna ya Philip nke abụọ n'ocheeze na 336 BC mgbe ọ dị afọ 20, ma nọrọ ọtụtụ n'ime afọ ọchịchị ya na-eduzi mkpọsa agha ogologo oge N'Western Asia N'Egypt. Mgbe ọ dị afọ iri atọ, o nweela alaeze kacha ukwuu e nwetụrụla, malite na Gris ruo n'ebe ugwu ọdịda anyanwụ India. E merighị ya n'agha, a na-ewerekwa ya n'ebe nile dị ka otu n'ime ndị ọchịagha kasị ukwuu na ndị kasị nwee ihe ịga nke ọma n'akụkọ ihe mere eme."},{"question":"ਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਕਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ? ਚਿੱਤਰ ਬਣਾ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਦਾ ਵਿਚਲਨ ਸਮਝਾਓ ।.","answer":"ਪਿਜ਼ਮ – ਕਿਸੇ ਪਾਰਦਰਸ਼ੀ ਮਾਧਿਅਮ ਦਾ ਉਹ ਭਾਗ ਜਿਹੜਾ ਕਿਸੇ ਕੋਣ ਤੇ ਝੁਕੇ ਹੋਏ ਦੋ ਸਮਤਲ ਸੜਾਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਥਿਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਕਹਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਦੇ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਸੜਾਵਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਅਪਵਰਤਨ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਅਪਵਰਤਕ ਸਤਹਿ ਆਖਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਕਾਰਲੇ ਕੋਣ ਨੂੰ ਅਪਵਰਤਨ ਕੋਣ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਦਾ ਵਿਚਲਨ – ਮੰਨ ਲਓ PQR ਕੱਚ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਕਾਟ (ਪਛੇਦ) ਹੈ । ਮੰਨ ਲਓ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਕਿਰਨ BC ਪਿਜ਼ਮ ਦੀ ਸਤਹਿ PR ਦੇ ਬਿੰਦੁ ਤੇ ਆਪਤਿਤ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਸਤਹਿ ਤੇ ਅਪਵਰਤਨ ਹੋਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਇਹ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਕਿਰਨ ਬਿੰਦੁ ਤੇ ਖਿੱਚੇ ਗਏ ਅਭਿਲੰਬ ਵੱਲ ਝੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ CD ਦਿਸ਼ਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਚਲੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਕਿਰਨ CD ਦੂਜੀ ਅਪਵਰਤਕ ਸਤਹਿ OR ਤੇ ਬਿੰਦ D ਤੇ ਖਿੱਚੇ ਗਏ ਅਭਿਲੰਬ ਤੋਂ ਪਰੇ ਹੱਟ ਕੇ DE ਦਿਸ਼ਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਿਜ਼ਮ ਤੋਂ ਨਿਰਗਮਨ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਲਈ ਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ BC ਦਿਸ਼ਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਉਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਕਿਰਨ ਨੂੰ DE ਦਿਸ਼ਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਚਲਿਤ ਕਰ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਦੀ ਦਿਸ਼ਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਈ ਵਿਚਲਨ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਅਪਾਤੀ ਕਿਰਨ BC ਨੂੰ ਅੱਗੇ ਵੱਲ ਨਿਰਗਮਨ ਕਿਰਨ DE ਨੂੰ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਵੱਲ ਵਧਾਉਣ ਨਾਲ ਇੱਕ ਦੂਜੇ ਨੂੰ ਬਿੰਦੁ G ਤੇ ਕੱਟਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੋਨਾਂ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਬਣਿਆ ∠FGD ਵਿਚਲਨ ਕੋਣ ਕਹਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਨੂੰ δ (ਡੇਲਟਾ) ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਿਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਵਿਚਲਨ ਕੋਣ ਦਾ ਮਾਨ ਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਦੇ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਦੇ(i) ਅਪਵਰਤਨ ਅੰਕ ਅਤੇ(ii) ਅਪਾਤੀ ਕਿਰਨ ਦੇ ਆਪਨ ਕੋਣ ‘ਤੇ ਨਿਰਭਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਜੇਕਰ ਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਤੇ ਡਿੱਗਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਕਿਰਨ ਦੇ ਆਪਨ ਕੋਣ ਦੇ ਮਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਵਧਾਉਂਦੇ ਜਾਈਏ ਤਾਂ ਵਿਚਲਨ ਕੋਣ δ (ਡੇਲਟਾ) ਦਾ ਮਾਨ ਘੱਟਦਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਆਪਨ ਕੋਣ ਲਈ ਵਿਚਲਨ ਕੋਣ ਨਿਊਨਤਮ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਨਿਊਨਤਮ ਵਿਚਲਨ ਕੋਣ ਨੂੰ ਅਲਪਤਮ ਵਿਚਲਨ ਕੋਣ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਜੇਕਰ ਕਿਸੇ ਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਦਾ ∠A ਅਤੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਰੰਗ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਨ ਲਈ ਅਲਪਮ ਵਿਚਲਨ ਕੋਣ ∠∂ m ਹੈ, ਤਾਂਪ੍ਰਿਜ਼ਮ ਦੇ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਦਾ ਅਪਵਰਤਕ ਅੰਕ (μ) = (sin(A+∂m)/2)/sin(A/2)"},{"question":"Apakah nama lagu kebangsaan negara Korea Selatan? ","answer":"Nama lagu kebangsaan negara Korea Selatan ialah Aegukga (애국가)"},{"question":"في أي قارة تقع سان مارينو؟","answer":"تقع سان مارينو في قارة أوروبا. سان مارينو أو رسميًا جمهورية سان مارينو أو جمهورية سان مارينو الأكثر صفاء هي دولة تقع في شبه الجزيرة الإيطالية على الجانب الشرقي من جبال الأبينيني وهي عبارة عن مكتنف تحيط به إيطاليا. تزيد مساحتها قليلًا عن 61 كم2 وبتعداد سكان يقدر بأكثر من 30,000. عاصمتها هي مدينة سان مارينو. تمتلك سان مارينو أقل تعداد سكان بين أعضاء مجلس أوروبا.سان مارينو هي أقدم دولة ذات سيادة وجمهورية دستورية في العالم، حيث أنها استمرار للمجتمع الرهباني الذي تأسس في 3 سبتمبر 301 على يد الحجار مارينوس من راب. تقول الأسطورة أن مارينوس غادر راب والتي كانت حينها مستعمرة رومانية باسم أربا في 257 عندما أصدر الإمبراطور المستقبلي ديوكلتيانوس مرسومًا بإعادة بناء أسوار مدينة ريميني، والتي كان قد دمرها القراصنة الليبورنيين.دستور سان مارينو الذي سن في عام 1600 هو أقدم دستور في العالم ما يزال ساري المفعول. يعتمد اقتصاد البلد أساسًا على التمويل والخدمات والصناعة والسياحة. تعد من أغنى البلدان في العالم من حيث الناتج المحلي الإجمالي (للفرد) مع أرقام مماثلة لبعض المناطق الإيطالية الأكثر نموًا مثل لومبارديا وترينتينو ألتو أديجي. تعد سان مارينو ذات اقتصاد مستقر للغاية مع واحد من أدنى معدلات البطالة في أوروبا ومن دون أي دين وطني وفائض في الميزانية."},{"question":"Wat is de overeenkomst tussen de nummers 11, 69 en 88? ","answer":"Je kan ze ook op de kop lezen."},{"question":"Про яку поетичну збірку йдеться мова? Під час арешту у Шевченка відібрали папери, зокрема книгу «Три літа» й під конвоєм відправили до Петербурга. На допитах у казематі Третього відділу імператорської канцелярії  поет не виказав нікого з членів товариства. Перебуваючи близько двох місяців за ґратами, Шевченко написав вірші, які згодом об'єднав у цикл «В казематі».","answer":"Цикл «В казематі»."},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Elias James Corey para a química?","answer":"Elias James Corey, também mencionado anteriormente, foi laureado com o Prêmio Nobel de Química em 1990 por suas contribuições significativas no desenvolvimento de conceitos e metodologias na síntese orgânica."},{"question":"नेपालमा ल्याप्सी खानेकुरा के हो ?","answer":"नेपाली होग प्लम भनेर पनि चिनिने लप्सी नेपालको मूल निवासी जंगली फल हो। अंडाकार आकारको यो फल पाक्दा हरियो पहेंलो रङको हुन्छ। \\"भिटामिन सी\\" को ठूलो स्रोतको रूपमा चिनिने ल्याप्सी कैंडी, टिटौरा, आचर, आदि जस्ता विभिन्न रूपहरूमा खपत गरिन्छ। यो स्थानीय डिपार्टमेन्ट स्टोरहरूमा सजिलै पाइन्छ वा विक्रेताहरूबाट किन्न सकिन्छ।"},{"question":"வினா:  காவேரியாற்றின் மிக நீளமான கிளை நதி எது?அ) அமராவதிஆ) பவானிஇ) ஹேமாவதிஈ) நொய்யல்","answer":"விடை: ஆ) பவானி.பவானி ஆறு, காவிரி ஆற்றின் முக்கிய துணை ஆறுகளில் ஒன்றாகும். இது சங்கநூலில் வானி எனக் குறிப்பிடப்படுகிறது. இது தமிழகத்தின் நீலகிரி மலைத்தொடரில் உள்ள குந்தா மலைப்பகுதியில் தென்மேற்கு மூலை முகட்டில் உருவாகிறது. மலை முகட்டிலிருந்து கீழிறங்கத் தொடங்கும் பகுதியில் மேல் பவானி அணை கட்டப்டுள்ளது. அங்கிருந்து தென்மேற்காக கேரள மாநிலத்தின் பாலக்காடு மாவட்டத்திலுள்ள அட்டப்பாடி பள்ளத்தாக்கில் பாய்ந்து அங்குள்ள முக்கலி என்னுமிடத்தில் கிழக்கு நோக்கி திரும்பி பாய்கிறது. "},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Trên trang cá nhân, Trương Mỹ Nhân xả kho bộ ảnh cùng con gái. Đây là lần đầu tiên người đẹp công khai việc sinh con đầu lòng trước công chúng khiến khán giả không khỏi bất ngờ. Trương Mỹ Nhân hạnh phúc chia sẻ: \\"Gửi con gái của mẹ! Chúc mừng sinh nhật tròn 2 tuổi của con, Bona. Hôm nay mẹ viết ra những dòng này vì mẹ biết với bản tính của mẹ thì chắc nơi đây là nơi lưu trữ tốt nhất. Mẹ mong những dòng tâm sự này sau khi con lớn lên có thể đọc được và xem là kỷ niệm thật ngọt ngào.   Trương Mỹ Nhân rất bất ngờ khi mình được bước vào hành trình làm mẹ đầy thiêng liêng. Bởi trước đó, cô bị đa nang buồng trứng, bác sĩ thông báo tỉ lệ có con là rất khó. Người đẹp nghẹn ngào: \\"Con được sinh ra bằng một tình yêu đẹp. Những ngày đầu con mới đến, mẹ đã rất bất ngờ. Lúc trước, bác sĩ nói mẹ bị đa nang buồng trứng nên rất khó có thai. Trước năm 25 tuổi, mẹ không dám nghĩ mình sẽ có con. Với mẹ, con như điều kỳ tích, là điều may mắn mà ông trời ưu ái dành cho mẹ. Dù mẹ vụng về, mẹ có nhiều lúc thật trẻ con nhưng được làm mẹ của Bona đã mang đến cho mẹ hạnh phúc quá lớn. Mẹ cám ơn Bona. Mẹ không hiểu tại sao ông trời có thể ban cho mẹ 1 em bé hiểu chuyện, ngoan ngoãn ngay từ khi còn nằm trong bụng mẹ. Lúc mang bầu con, mẹ chịu nhiều áp lực. Nhưng từ lúc con chào đời, con đã tiếp thêm cho mẹ sức mạnh. Con mạnh mẽ, ít khi khóc quấy, tình cảm và đặc biệt là lúc nào cho mẹ cảm giác mẹ là người đặc biệt nhất với con.   Bona ơi, con tuyệt vời như chòm sao Sư tử của con vậy đó. Từ bé, con đã luôn âu yếm mẹ, hôn mẹ, nắm lấy tay mẹ, nhìn vào gương mặt của mẹ để thể hiện cảm xúc. Nhiều khi mẹ nghĩ rằng không phải con mới 2 tuổi đâu, Bona à, mẹ ngốc quá phải không con. Bây giờ con thêm tuổi mới rồi, cũng đã dần bộc lộ tính cách và cái tôi của mình hơn. Mẹ yêu sao những lần đi đâu con cũng về cất dép ngăn nắp, những lần gặp người lớn là con ngoan ngoãn cúi đầu chào. Con lại còn biết cám ơn, xin lỗi và hờn dỗi nữa chứ. Con 2 tuổi rồi, đã biết chọn xem chương trình con thích, mặc bộ quần áo mà con yêu. Mẹ luôn tôn trọng những điều con chọn, con hãy chia sẻ cùng mẹ mọi điều con nhé.  Mẹ biết, khi mẹ viết những dòng này, sẽ có nhiều anh chị hỏi mẹ về con lắm. Nhưng con gái của mẹ quá là xinh xắn, đáng yêu mà, mẹ phải tự hào nói về con chứ. Mẹ đang rất hạnh phúc, khi được ở bên con. Và mẹ muốn cho cả thế giới biết rằng Bona của mẹ tuyệt vời đến thế nào\\". Trương Mỹ Nhân hạnh phúc khi thiên thần nhỏ xuất hiện trong cuộc đời mình, Bona là động lực lớn của cô lúc này. Thậm chí cô đánh đổi cả sự nghiệp để lựa chọn việc có con. Trương Mỹ Nhân kể: \\"Nếu quay lại những ngày mới mang thai con, mẹ vẫn sẽ chọn Bona. Mẹ thầm biết ơn bản thân vì đã quyết định đúng đắn. Mẹ có thể đi chậm 1 chút, có thể rơi vài nhịp trên con đường sự nghiệp nhưng mẹ không thể không có Bona. Nếu ngày đó mẹ không đủ mạnh mẽ thì thiên thần nhỏ của mẹ đã chẳng được nhìn thấy ánh mặt trời. Nếu ngày đó mẹ chọn sự nghiệp, mẹ sẽ không bao giờ biết được nụ cười của con ấm áp, rạng rỡ đến chừng nào. Nếu ngày đó mẹ chọn sự nghiệp, có thể mẹ sẽ bước nhanh hơn 1 chút nhưng chắc chắn rằng cả đời này mẹ sẽ ân hận, hối tiếc lắm.  Phải chi mẹ tính toán được nhiều hơn, sẵn sàng hơn trong việc chào đón con thì có thể con đã có nhiều điều tốt đẹp hơn. Mẹ xin lỗi Bona vì đôi khi mẹ vụng về, mẹ lúng túng, mẹ chưa làm 1 người mẹ thật tốt nhưng mẹ sẽ cố gắng nhiều hơn. Con giúp mẹ cảm thấy cuộc đời này đẹp quá, tích cực quá. Mẹ bây giờ sống có mục đích hơn, con cho mẹ trách nhiệm cùng niềm tin rằng chỉ cần có con bên cạnh, mẹ sẽ làm được mọi thứ. Không gì quý giá hơn được nhìn thấy con cười với mẹ mỗi ngày. Sinh nhật 2 tuổi rồi, Bona hãy mau ăn chóng lớn, khỏe mạnh và mãi đáng yêu nhé. Mẹ yêu con lắm, Bona của mẹ\\". Theo Thúy Ngọc (Saostar.vn)  https://saostar.vn/giai-tri/a-quan-the-face-2017-bat-ngo-cong-khai-con-dau-long-sau-thoi-gian-202207311422352681.html Trang Thông tin điện tử Docbao.vn Công ty Cổ phần Quang Minh Việt Nam Giấy phép thiết lập Trang thông tin điện tử tổng hợp trên Internet số 2372/GP-STTTT cấp ngày 29/8/2014. SĐT: 024. 666.40816 Địa chỉ: P604, Tầng 6, Tòa nhà Golden Field, Khu đô thị mới Mỹ Đình 1, phường Cầu Diễn, quận Nam Từ Liêm, Hà Nội Chịu trách nhiệm nội dung: Điều Thị Bích; ĐT: 0903.263.198; Email: docbao@kib.vn Đọc báo trực tuyến hiện tại chỉ sử dụng tên miền duy nhất là docbao.vn; độc giả lưu ý tránh nhầm lẫn. Chính sách bảo mật RSS","answer":"Á quân The Face 2017 bất ngờ công khai con đầu lòng sau thời gian giữ kín"},{"question":"Бет келип сайышпай, качып бериш, колдун арасына кире калуу кимдин адаты?а) Коңурбайдын б) Алоокенинв) Карыкандын г) Нескаранын","answer":"Бет келип сайышпай, качып бериш, колдун арасына кире калуу Коңурбайдын адаты. Туура жообу а) варианты."},{"question":"Inona no anarana iantsoana ny anabavin-drainao sy ianao?","answer":"Ny anarana iantsoana ny anabavin-draiko sy izaho dia nenitoa."},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Séworsi ?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Séworsi mu ngi tudd Tbilisi."},{"question":"வினா:தமிழில் ஓரெழுத்து ஒரு மொழிகளின் பெருக்கம் குறித்து இளங்குமரனார் கூறும் செய்திகளைத் தொகுத்து எழுதுக.","answer":"விடை:முன்னுரை:மொழி என்பதற்குச் சொல் என்பதும் ஒரு பொருள். மொழியை (சொல்லை) ஓர் எழுத்து மொழி, ஈரெழுத்து மொழி, இரண்டுக்கு மேற்பட்ட எழுத்துகள் உடைய மொழி என மூன்று வகையாக்குவர்.ஓரெழுத்து ஒரு மொழி:உயிர் வரிசையில் ஆறு எழுத்துகளும், ம வரிசையில் ஆறு எழுத்துகளும், த, ப, ந என்னும் வரிசைகளில் ஐந்து ஐந்து எழுத்துகளும், க, ச, வ என்னும் வரிசையில் நான்கு நான்கு எழுத்துகளும், ய வரிசையில் ஒன்றும் ஆக நாற்பது நெடில்கள் ஓரெழுத்து ஒரு மொழியாக வரும் என்றார் நன்னூலார். நொ, து என்னும் குறில்களையும் சேர்த்து நாற்பத்து இரண்டு என்றார்.பூ-யா சொற்கள்:பூ என்பது ஓரெழுத்து ஒரு மொழி. கா என்பதும் ஓரெழுத்து ஒரு மொழி. இவை இரண்டையும் இணைத்துப் பூங்கா எனக் கலைச்சொல் ஆக்கி வைத்துள்ளனர். யா என்பது வினா. யாது, யாவர், யாவன், யாங்கு, யாண்டு, யார், யாவை என்றெல்லாம் வினாவுவதற்கு முன் வந்து நிற்கும் எழுத்து ‘யா’ தானே!‘மா’ சொல்:மா என்பதும் ஓரெழுத்து ஒரு மொழிகளுள் ஒன்று. நாட்டிலுள்ள பெருமக்கள் பெரிதும் கூடும் அவையை மாநாடு என்கிறோம். பல குறு நிலங்களை உள்ளடக்கிய பெருநிலத்தை மாநிலம் என்கிறோம். மா என்பது விலங்கையும் குறிக்கும். அரிமா, பரிமா, நரிமா, வரிமா, கரிமா என்றெல்லாம் வந்து விலங்கினப் பெயராகி நிற்கின்றது.ஈ-காரச் சொல்:ஈ என்னும் பொதுப் பெயர் ஓயாது ஒலி செய்யும் ஒலிக்குறிப்பைக் காட்டி நிற்கிறது. மாட்டு ஈ, தேன் ஈ எனப் பகுத்து வழங்கும் வழக்கம் உள்ளது. ஈ என்பது ஈக என்னும் பொருளில் வழங்குதல் வெளிப்படை. ஈ என்று பல்லைக் காட்டாதே என்று அறிவுரை கூறுவதும் உண்டு .கால மாற்றத்தில் கரைந்தவை:இன்னொரு வகையாகவும் பார்க்கலாம். ஆன் என்பது ஆ ஆகியது; மான் என்பது மா ஆகியது; கோன் என்பது கோ ஆகியது; தேன் என்பது தே ஆகியது; பேய் என்பது பே ஆகியது இவையெல்லாம் கால வெள்ளத்தில் கரைந்து தேய்ந்தவை.ஏகாரச் சொல்:எட்டத்தில் போகிற ஒருவனை ஏய் என அழைத்தனர். ஏய் என்பது என்னோடு கூடு, பொருந்து, சேர் என்னும் பொருளை உடையது. ஏய் என்பது ஏ என வழக்கில் ஊன்றிவிட்டது. அம்பை ஏவு என்பர். ஏவுதல் என்பது ‘அம்புவிடுதல்’ ஏவும் அம்பு ‘ஏ’ என்றாகியது. அம்பு விரைந்து செல்வது போலச் சென்று உரிய கடமை புரிபவன் ஏவலன் எனப்பட்டான். அம்புவிடும் கலையை ஏகலை என்றது தமிழ். அதில் வல்லவனை ஏகலைவன் என்று பாராட்டியது.முடிவுரை:தமிழில் ஓரெழுத்து ஒரு மொழிச் சொற்களின் பெருக்கம் நம் மொழியின் பழமை, உயிரோட்டம், பெருவழக்கு என்பனவற்றைக் கையில் கனியாகக் காட்டும்."},{"question":"Qual foi o primeiro país a permitir o voto feminino?","answer":"A Nova Zelândia, em setembro de 1893."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Alouette III togs i tjänst för sent för att sättas in i","answer":"Algerietrevolten. I stället användes Alouette III till en början till huvudsakligen fredliga ändamål i Frankrike. Helikoptern demonstrerade sina utmärkta höghöjdsegenskaper i juni 1960 genom att landsätta sju personer på Mont Blanc, något som aldrig tidigare hade gjorts med helikopter."},{"question":"この質問に対する正解は何ですか？nニューイングランド・ペイトリオッツは2021年現在、スーパーボウルで6度優勝しているでしょうか？","answer":"質問に対する正しい答えは「イエス」だ。"},{"question":"በ17ኛ ምእት በቴሌስኮፕ የታገዘ የፀሓይ ምርምር ጀማሪ ማን ነበር?","answer":"ጋሊሌዮ"},{"question":"Maak de volgende zin af: De kardinalen hebben in een","answer":"erg kort conclaaf van één dag besloten dat de achtenzeventigjarige Duitse kardinaal Joseph Ratzinger de nieuwe paus wordt. Even voor 18:00 steeg er grijze rook op uit het Vaticaanse schoorsteentje − het was dus onduidelijk of het zwarte (wat zou betekenen dat de kardinalen nog eens hebben gestemd en er nog geen nieuwe paus is) of witte (wat zou betekenen dat er een nieuwe paus is verkozen) was − en enkele minuten later bleek het witte rook voor te stellen en te zijn. Dit werd iets na zes uur bevestigd doordat de klokken luidden, om 18:45 werd na de legendarische Latijnse woorden \\"Habemus papam\\" (Wij hebben een paus) de naam van kardinaal die de nieuwe paus is, uitgesproken."},{"question":"කළු විමුක්ති දේව ධර්මය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කළු විමුක්ති දේව ධර්මය යනු විශාල වශයෙන් මානවීය, එනම් දරි෿්‍රතාවයෙන් පෙළෙන අය වෙත කිතුණු දේව ධර්මය යොමු කිරීමට ගත් උත්සාහයක් වන අතර එය දකුණු අප්‍රිකානු දේව ධර්මයෙහි අංකුරයක්ය. කළු විමුක්ති දේව ධර්මය සාමාන්‍යයෙන් අප්‍රිකානුවන් වෙත අවධානය යොමු වන අතර, සමාජීය, දේශපාලන, ආර්ථික හෝ ආගමික අප්‍රිකානු-අමෙරිකානු අසාධාරණයෙන් හා වහල්කමින් මුදනාලද අය ලෙස සැබෑ ලෙස හෝ ප්‍රත්‍යක්‍ෂ වූවන්ය."},{"question":"नेपालमा चतमारी खानेकुरा के हो ?","answer":"चातमारी वा नेवारी पिज्जा अर्को परम्परागत खाजाका साथै लोकप्रिय नेपाली सडक खाना हो। दुई भागमा विभाजन गरी क्रेपको आधार चामलको पिठो प्रयोग गरेर बनाइन्छ भने टपिङमा म्यारिनेट गरिएको मासु, प्याज र मसलासहितको अण्डाको संयोजन हो। चतमारीले \\"नेवारी पिज्जा\\" को उपाधि विशुद्ध रूपमा हेरेको कारणले प्राप्त गरेको छ।"},{"question":"Ki sa ki se kesyon an nan: \\"Apre lanmò Harris a, Michael Gambon jwe ròl Dumbledore pou tout fim ki rete yo. \\"? Sijè a se Albus Dumbledore.","answer":"\\"ki moun ki jwe Dumbledore nan Harry Potter 6?\\""},{"question":"Sheeg asxaabigii bilaabay labada ragacadood ee qofka la dilaayo tukado?","answer":"Saxaabigii bilaabay tukashada labada rakcadod e qofka ladilaayo wuxu ahaa Qubeyd Bin Cadi RC"},{"question":"How did the banking sector's performance evolve, especially in light of the non-performing asset (NPA) crisis?","answer":"The banking sector faced challenges, notably the NPA crisis, where a significant portion of loans turned sour. The government initiated reforms, such as the Insolvency and Bankruptcy Code (IBC), to address this issue. The NPA crisis had implications for banks' health, credit availability, and overall economic stability."},{"question":"ప్రజాస్వామ్యాన్ని నిర్వచించండి.","answer":"మధ్యతరగతి ప్రభుత్వం వికృతరూపంగా మారి స్వార్థపరులచేత పరిపాలించబడే ప్రభుత్వమే ప్రజాస్వామ్యం లేదా మూకపాలన అని అరిస్టాటిల్ పేర్కొన్నాడు. స్టీఫెన్ లీకాక్ ప్రకారం ప్రజాస్వామ్య ప్రభుత్వంలో పాలకులు వయోజనులైన పౌరుల చేత ప్రత్యక్షంగానో లేదా పరోక్షంగానో ఎన్నుకోబడతారు. ప్రజాస్వామ్యంలో ప్రభుత్వానికి మెజారిటీ ప్రజల మద్దతు లభిస్తుంది."},{"question":"એનાટોમી એટલે શું?","answer":"એનાટોમી એ જીવવિજ્ ની શાખા છે જે સજીવની રચના અને તેમના ભાગોના અભ્યાસ સાથે સંબંધિત છે.એનાટોમી એ કુદરતી વિજ્ ની એક શાખા છે જે જીવંત વસ્તુઓની માળખાકીય સંસ્થા સાથે સંબંધિત છે.તે એક જૂનું વિજ્ છે, તેની શરૂઆત પ્રાગૈતિહાસિક સમયમાં છે.શરીરરચના સ્વાભાવિક રીતે વિકાસલક્ષી જીવવિજ્, એમ્બ્રોલોજી, તુલનાત્મક શરીરરચના, ઉત્ક્રાંતિ જીવવિજ્ અને ફાયલોજેની સાથે જોડાયેલી છે, કારણ કે આ તે પ્રક્રિયાઓ છે જેના દ્વારા એનાટોમી ઉત્પન્ન થાય છે, બંને તાત્કાલિક અને લાંબા ગાળાના ટાઇમસ્કેલ પર.એનાટોમી અને ફિઝિયોલોજી, જે સજીવો અને તેમના ભાગોની રચના અને કાર્યનો અનુક્રમે અભ્યાસ કરે છે, તે સંબંધિત શાખાઓની કુદરતી જોડી બનાવે છે, અને ઘણીવાર એક સાથે અભ્યાસ કરવામાં આવે છે.હ્યુમન એનાટોમી એ એક આવશ્યક મૂળભૂત વિજ્  છે જે દવામાં લાગુ પડે છે."},{"question":"Klasifikasikan kalimat berikut berdasarkan jenis sentimen (positif, negatif, atau netral) dan aspek sentimennya. Berikan jawaban beserta alasannya.Pernah dapat kerjaan desain di toko roti mulai jam 8 pagi, mengerjakan sampai jam 6 besok paginya baru pulang dari toko roti itu.Jawaban:","answer":"Kalimat tersebut secara harfiah, berdasarkan penggunaan kata-katanya dapat diklasifikasikan sebagai sentimen netral karena tidak mengandung kata-kata berkonotasi positif maupun negatif. Namun, apabila diberikan konteks eksternal tambahan berdasarkan norma dan hak pekerja, atapun setuju tidaknya penulis ulasan dengan aturan norma tersebut, maka kalimat netral tersebut dapat berubah ekspresi menjadi negatif.Aspek sentimennya adalah jam kerja. "},{"question":"Inona ny lokon\\"ny zavoka?","answer":"Ny lokon'ny zavoka dia mety miovaova arakaraka ny fahamatorana sy ny karazany. Amin'ny ankapobeny, maitso ny zavokà, saingy mety miovaova be ny aloky ny maitso. Ny zavokà tsy matotra dia matetika manana loko maitso mavana, saika mavomavo, fa ny zavokà efa masaka kosa dia maitso mavana kokoa. Misy karazany koa anefa ny zavokà izay saika mainty na volomparasy rehefa masaka.Marihina fa ny lokon’ny hoditry ny zavoka dia tsy hita taratra tsara foana ny fahamatorany. Mba hamaritana raha efa masaka ny zavokà iray, dia tsara kokoa ny manindry azy moramora. Ny zavokà efa masaka dia milefitra kely eo amin'ny ilay notsindriana, fa tsy ho malefaka loatra. Raha malemy be ny zavokà, dia mety efa masaka be na simba mihitsy aza."},{"question":"\\"Ny fiakaran'ny mponina sy ny nasionalisma dia nisy fiantraikany amin'ny tany politika eran-tany. Ny adihevitra momba ny fifindra-monina, ny fiandrianam-pirenena ary ny fiaraha-miasa iraisam-pirenena dia namorona ny fanapahan-kevitra politika. Ny fandanjalanjana ny tombontsoam-pirenena miaraka amin'ny fifandraisan-davitra manerantany dia lohahevitra lehibe amin'ny lahateny politika ankehitriny.\\"Inona no lohahevitra amin'io lahatsoratra io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitra amin' io lahatsoratra io  dia ny politika."},{"question":"Eeyan meje foju bale-ẹjọ lori ija awọn Musulumi ati Eleegun l’Oṣogbo","answer":"Olori ijọ Kamorudeen Society Central Mosque, Qosim Yunus, ati mẹta lara awọn ọmọ ijọ rẹ pẹlu awọn eleegun mẹta ni wọn ti n kawọ pọnyin rojọ ni kootu Majisreeti kan niluu Oṣogbo lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, lori wahala to waye laarin wọn laipẹ yii.Ẹsun ti agbẹjọro to wa lati ileeṣẹ eto idajọ nipinlẹ Ọṣun, Abiọdun Badiora, fi kan Yunus atawọn ọmọ ijọ rẹ; Salawu Jimoh, Alarape Sulaiman ati Raimi Saheed ni pe wọn huwa to le da omi alaafia agbegbe ru, didi ọlọpaa lọwọ lati ṣiṣẹ, didoju ija kọ eeyan ati didoju ija kọ inspẹkitọ ọlọpaa obinrin kan.Ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọjọ kẹtadinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹfa, ọdun yii, ni Badiora sọ pe wọn huwa naa ni adugbo Oluọdẹ Aranyin, Oṣogbo, ninu eyi ti aafa kan ti ku, ti awọn mẹrinla si fara pa yanna-yanna.Bakan naa ni Badiora fẹsun mẹrin kan Ifashọla Eṣuleke, Adeọṣun Kọla ati Idowu Abimbọla. O ni wọn ba dukia jẹ, wọn ba mọṣalaaṣi kan jẹ, bẹẹ ni wọn si ba mọto Toyota Camry kan to ni nọmba GGE 954 BV jẹ nibi iṣẹlẹ naa.Badiora sọ siwaju pe awọn ẹsun naa ni ijiya nla labẹ abala ikẹtalelọgọrin, igba o din mẹta, ọtalelọọọdunrun o din marun-un, okoolelẹẹẹdẹgbẹta o din mẹta ofin iwa ọdaran tipinlẹ Ọṣun n lo.Agbẹjọro awọn Musulumi, Kazeem Babatunde ati ti awọn eleegun, Abimbọla Ige, bẹbẹ fun beeli awọn olujẹjọ lọna irọrun pẹlu ileri pe wọn ko ni i sa fun igbẹjọ.Onidaajọ Asimiyu Adebayọ faaye silẹ fun beeli ọkọọkan awọn olujẹjọ pẹlu miliọnu kan naira ati oniduuro kọọkan ni iye kan naa. O ni awọn oniduuro ọhun gbọdọ ni ilẹ to jẹ tiwọn.Lẹyin naa lo sun igbẹjọ siwaju di ọjọ kẹtala, oṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun yii."},{"question":"ミロス・フォアマン監督の映画のタイトルにもなった、作曲家モーツァルトのミドルネームは何でしょう？","answer":"アマデウスです。"},{"question":"Bu paragrafın devamını yazın: Hersek'te bir isyan (1875-1878), Avrupa'daki Osmanlı kuvvetlerine karşı ayaklanmalara yol açtı. Karadağ ve Sırbistan 18 Haziran 1876'da Osmanlılara karşı savaş ilan ettiler. Nichola I'in kuzeni Osmanlıları Medun'da iki kere bozguna uğratmışdı. Zeta'daki Danilograd'da bir Karadağlı zafer ve Medun'un teslim edilmesi Karadağ-Osmanlı Savaşının","answer":"ilk yılını tamamladı. 13 Ocak 1878'de Nicholas I ve Ahmed Muhtar Paşa çatışmaların sona ermesi için ateşkes anlaşması yapıldı."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"belum tahu di masin garam\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat untuk peribahasa ini. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud belum ada pengalaman. Contohnya, dia masih muda, belum tahu di masin garam, biarkannya mengumpul pengalaman berkerja dulu."},{"question":"उखान वाक्यमा प्रयोग गर्नुहोस् :आफू नमरी स्वर्ग देखिदैन :","answer":"आफू नमरी स्वर्ग देखिँदैन भनेझै विदेश नगइकन त्यहाँको दुःख बुझ्न सकिदैन । "},{"question":"Оптикалык нурлануу","answer":"Оптикалык нурлануу - бул толкун узундугу 1 нмден 1 ммге чейинки диапазондогу электр-магниттик толкундар. Оптикалык нурланууга адамдын көзү кабыл алуучу көрүнгөн жарыктан башка инфракызыл жана ультракызгылт көк нурлануулар кирет. Оптикалык нурлануунун толкун касиети жарык дифракциясында, интерференциясында, уюлдануусунда (полярлануусунда) байкалат."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai dihentak alu luncung\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya, dikalahkan oleh orang yang tidak pandai atau yang lemah."},{"question":"Сынган кылыч романдагы 📚 Алымбек датка ким болгон?","answer":"Алымбек датка — Асан бий уулу, хандын вазири, парваначы, кийин Анжиан-Оштун беги, датка, саясий жана коомдук ишмер. Курманжан датканын күйөөсү. Адигиненин баргы уругунан. Кокондо жана Анжиянда бийлик чөйрөсүнө таасирдүү чыгаан инсан. Кокондо уюшулган кутумдан улам, чыгармада Чотон тарабынан башы алынат. Ал эми анын өлүмү боюнча тарыхый булактарда эки түрдүү көз караш бар. Кантсе да Кокон хандыгында саясий курмандыкка кабылган."},{"question":"كم ورد لفظ(كاهن)في القرآن الكريم؟","answer":"مرتان"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'memasukkan jarum halusnya'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud melakukan tipu daya secara halus untuk mencapai sesuatu maksud"},{"question":"هل عاصمة الإمارات هي أم القيوين؟","answer":"لا، عاصمة الإمارات العربية المتحدة هي أبوظبي."},{"question":"जगप्रसिद्ध लोणार सरोवर कोणत्या जिल्ह्यात आहे?","answer":"लोणार सरोवर हे महाराष्ट्रातील बुलढाणा जिल्ह्यात आहे"},{"question":"Tôi được nghe đề cập đến bốn trụ cột trong quản lý tài chính cá nhân của mỗi người gồm trả nợ, tiết kiệm, bảo hiểm và đầu tư. Nếu lần lượt thực hiện các bước kể trên và ưu tiên theo thứ tự, mỗi người sẽ có nền tảng tài chính cá nhân vững.Theo chuyên gia, kiến thức trên có đúng chưa? Tôi cần hiểu như thế nào về những trụ cột trong quản lý tài chính cá nhân?","answer":"Khi xây dựng một kế hoạch tài chính cá nhân, cần đảm bảo sự xuất hiện của năm khía cạnh sau: quản lý thu chi, tối ưu hóa dòng tiền, xây dựng một phương án vay và trả nợ tối ưu; xây dựng danh mục đầu tư phù hợp với khẩu vị rủi ro, mục tiêu đầu tư và nhu cầu tài chính, xây dựng các phương án bảo vệ tài chính khi có sự cố; các khía cạnh khác gồm thuế thu nhập cá nhân, quỹ hưu trí, bảo hiểm xã hội, thừa kế và hôn nhân.Do đó, bốn trụ cột mà bạn nhắc đến chỉ là những phần trong bức tranh tài chính cá nhân, không phải toàn diện và đầy đủ. Sau đây là năm khía cạnh của quản lý tài chính cá nhân.Quản lý thu chi và tối ưu hóa dòng tiềnCũng như việc xây một ngôi nhà, đây là cách tạo ra nền móng vững chắc. Bạn cần đảm bảo được dòng tiền vào (thu nhập) được tối ưu và dòng tiền ra (chi tiêu) được đảm bảo phù hợp, tránh lâm vào tình huống quá đà, thu không bù chi.Ở bước này, bạn có thể thực hiện theo nhiều phương pháp như \\"công thức 50-30-20\\" gồm 50% cho chi tiêu thiết yếu, 30% chi tiêu cho hưởng thụ, giải trí và 20% dành tiết kiệm, đầu tư. Tuy nhiên, công thức sẽ có sự thay đổi đối với các mức thu nhập khác nhau. Đối với việc quản lý thu và chi, tôi khuyên bạn tránh mắc phải các tình huống sau.Thứ nhất, chi tiền cho những mong muốn hơn cần thiết, chi tiêu mang tính cảm xúc, ham muốn nhất thời hơn là những khoản \\"không thể không chi\\". Bạn nên rà soát các hoạt động chi tiêu đảm bảo hợp lý, chính xác và cắt bỏ các khoản dư thừa.Thứ hai, chi cho ngắn hạn hơn dài hạn. Hãy nhớ, thói quen kỷ luật trong chi tiêu tạo ra sự bền vững trong tương lai, bạn không thể tạo ra quỹ hưu trí cho 30 năm về hưu bằng việc chi tiêu ngắn hạn, hoặc tiết kiệm ở mức quá thấp (<10% thu nhập). Hãy luôn dành ra một khoản chi tương lai dài hạn cho bản thân.Bên cạnh đó, ngoài việc đảm bảo rằng chi tiêu hợp lý, hãy đừng quên rằng bạn cần gia tăng các nguồn thu nhập cho bản thân thông qua học hỏi và phát triển các kỹ năng mới. Đa dạng hóa nguồn thu nhập giúp đảm bảo quản trị tốt rủi ro, đồng thời cũng giúp gia tăng tài sản bền vững. Mỗi kỹ năng bạn học được đều là một cơ hội gia tăng nguồn thu nhập, không ngừng học tập để có thể tạo ra nhiều dòng tiền.Cơ cấu lại các khoản vay và khoản nợTrả nợ là một vế mà bạn đã nhắc đến và tối ưu hóa khoản vay là vế còn lại. Nguyên tắc cần nhớ là nợ giảm dần, vay thông minh.Các khoản nợ luôn phải nằm trong khả năng trả từ thu nhập hàng tháng của bạn. Có hai loại nợ cần phân biệt: nợ dài hạn trên tài sản đầu tư (như vay mua nhà) hoặc nợ ngắn hạn trên tài sản tiêu hao (như vay mua điện thoại, laptop). Đối với loại nợ dài hạn trên tài sản đầu tư, số tiền trả hàng tháng chính là chi phí cho tiết kiệm và đầu tư, nên ở mức tối đa 30% thu nhập.Đối với loại nợ ngắn hạn trên tài sản tiêu hao, số tiền trả hàng tháng là chi phí hưởng thụ và giải trí, nên ở mức 10-15% thu nhập. Khi trả nợ có thể trả theo hai phương pháp, các khoản nhỏ trước hoặc các khoản lớn trước tùy hoàn cảnh của bạn.Thứ hai là tối ưu để có các khoản vay thông minh. Thay vì phải chịu các khoản lãi suất cao, nếu bạn dành thời gian tìm hiểu về điều kiện các khoản vay theo các tiêu chí khoản tiền có thể vay, lãi suất, lãi suất thả nổi, thời gian ưu đãi, điều kiện đi kèm như khuyến khích mua bảo hiểm, phí phạt trả trước hạn, bạn có thể có những khoản tiền dôi ra từ việc vay thông minh. Đó là một dòng tiền không nhỏ nếu gói vay của bạn lớn và dài hạn. Ví dụ, khách hàng A vay 12% mỗi năm tại ngân hàng B trong khi ngân hàng C có gói vay 10% mỗi năm. Nếu khách hàng A chọn ngân hàng C thay vì ngân hàng B, người này sẽ có khoản tiền dôi ra để chi tiêu những việc khác.Đầu tư thông minh và tối ưu hóa danh mục đầu tưTrong đầu tư, bạn không nên \\"dồn trứng vào một rổ\\" và phải biết phân bổ danh mục đầu tư để tối ưu hóa lợi nhuận và quản trị rủi ro. Nếu bạn không có nhiều thời gian và kinh nghiệm, hãy bắt đầu từ số vốn nhỏ, hoặc đều đặn tích sản một cách an toàn. Tìm đến các chuyên gia, cố vấn tài chính cũng là một cách với những người ít kinh nghiệm.Xây dựng các phương án dự phòng tài chínhĐây chính là chuẩn bị phương án cho các rủi ro không mong muốn. Bạn cần hiểu có hai dạng chính dẫn đến thất thoát tài chính hoặc mất đi hoàn toàn nguồn thu nhập.Thứ nhất, mất việc hoặc bị sa thải. Tình huống này đòi hỏi bạn chuyển đổi sang một công việc mới hoặc cần một khoảng thời gian thích nghi. Việc xây dựng một quỹ dự phòng cho trường hợp này, từ 3-6 tháng thu nhập, là cần thiết và nên làm.Thứ hai, có bất trắc xảy ra như tai nạn, ốm đau, bệnh hiểm nghèo hoặc thậm chí là mất sớm khi đang ở độ tuổi lao động. Những tình huống này hiện có nhiều phương án dự phòng nhưng cơ bản nhất là bảo hiểm y tế và bảo hiểm xã hội. Tuy vậy, với nhu cầu \\"ăn ngon, mặc đẹp\\" như hiện nay, việc cân nhắc sở hữu bảo hiểm nhân thọ hoặc bảo hiểm sức khỏe là việc nên làm. Tương tự các khoản đầu tư, bạn cần cẩn thận, kỹ càng và tìm các chuyên gia, cố vấn chất lượng vì thời gian bảo hiểm dài, đồng thời đây là dòng sản phẩm có tính chất phức tạp do bao gồm cả tích lũy và đầu tư."},{"question":"डॉक्टर कौन है? उस पेशे के बारे में बताएं|","answer":"प्रस्तावनाहमारे समाज में एक डॉक्टर का बहुत ही बड़ा महत्व है डॉक्टर हम सभी के बीमारियों को ठीक करते हैं इनके बिना किसी भी बीमारी का इलाज करना मुश्किल है।डॉक्टरडॉक्टर कई सालों की पढ़ाई करते हैं फिर उसके बाद उन्हें डॉक्टर की डिग्री मिल जाती है जिससे वह डॉक्टर बन जाते हैं और उसके बाद वह सभी व्यक्ति को अपने ज्ञान से उनकी बीमारी को अच्छी तरह से जान कर मरीज को अच्छी से अच्छी दवाई देते हैं जिससे मरीज जल्दी ठीक हो जाए।डॉक्टर हमेशा अपने मरीजों के इलाज के लिए हर समय तैयार रहता है और इनके मदद के लिए कंपाउंडर नर्स भी होते हैं जो कि मरीजों का ख्याल रखते हैं और डॉक्टर की मदद करते हैं।डॉक्टर हमेशा अपने साथ आपातकालीन के लिए कुछ दवाइयां और जरूरी सामान लिए रहते हैं जिससे आपातकालीन में मरीज का पहला इलाज हो सके।डॉक्टर हमेशा सफेद रंग का ड्रेस पहनते हैं और उनकी पहचान होती है।डॉक्टर कई प्रकार के होते हैं जैसे कि कुछ डॉक्टर दांतों का इलाज करते हैं जिन्हें डेंटिस्ट कहा जाता है और कुछ डॉक्टर गलों का इलाज करते हैं कुछ डॉक्टर हाथ का इलाज करते हैं, कुछ डॉक्टर दिमाग का इलाज करते हैं इसी प्रकार कई सारे डॉक्टर होते हैं जो विभिन्न विभिन्न अंगों का इलाज करते हैं।हाल ही में हुए कोरोना के महामारी में डॉक्टर का बहुत ही बड़ा योगदान रहा है सभी डॉक्टर अपने जान की परवाह किए बिना सभी को रोना से पीड़ित मरीजों का इलाज कर रहे थे बहुत से डॉक्टर कई दिनों तक सोए नहीं थे और लगातार सभी मरीजों का इलाज कर रहे थे।इसीलिए सभी भारत वासियों ने कोरोना के इस महामारी में कोरोना से लड़ने वाले सभी योद्धाओं के सम्मान के लिए और उनका उत्साह बढ़ाने के लिए दीए जलाएं गए।हमारे भारत में हर साल 1 जुलाई को डॉक्टर दिवस के रूप में मनाया जाता है।निष्कर्षडॉक्टर का एक मरीज के लिए बहुत ही बड़ा महत्व है या फिर यह कहे कि मरीज के लिए डॉक्टर एक भगवान होता है जिसके बिना मरीज को ठीक कर पाना मुश्किल है।डॉक्टर पर निबंध 10 लाइनमानव जीवन में एक डॉक्टर का बहुत ही बड़ा महत्व होता है।डॉक्टर बनने के लिए बहुत ज्यादा पढ़ाई करना होता है ।डॉक्टर मरीजों का इलाज करते हैं।हमारे देश में बहुत से अच्छे डॉक्टर है जो कि बिना पैसों के इलाज करते हैं।डॉक्टर कई प्रकार के होते हैं जैसे कि गले का डॉक्टर नाक नाक का डॉक्टर और दांत का डॉक्टर इत्यादि।कोरोना की महामारी में डॉक्टर का बहुत ही बड़ा योगदान था।डॉक्टर सफेद रंग का ड्रेस पहनते हैं।डॉक्टर ने मरीजों को बचाने की पूरी कोशिश करते हैं और उनके इलाज के लिए हमेशा तैयार रहते हैं।मरीजों का इलाज और डॉक्टर की मदद करने के लिए कंपाउंडर नर्स भी होते हैं।भारत में हर साल 1 जुलाई को डॉक्टर दिवस मनाया जाता है।"},{"question":"Lazao amin’ny fomba hafa ity fehezanteny ity :«Ny marina dia volamena latsaka am-bovoka»","answer":"Tsy maintsy ho fantatra ny marina na saroman’ny lainga sy fitaka."},{"question":"පරිගණක පද්ධතියක මතක උපාංග (Memory devices) යනු මොනවද ?","answer":"පරිගණකයේ දත්ත සහ උපදෙස් ගබඩා කරනු ලබන්නේ මතක උපාංග තුළයි. එමෙන්ම දත්ත සකසන තෙක් තාවකාලිකව ගබඩා කරන්නේ ද මතක තුලය. මෙම මතක ඒකක සෑදී ඇත්තේ මතක කෝෂ (memory cell) ගණනාවක එකතුවකිනි. මේ එක් එක් මතක කෝෂ සඳහා වෙන් වූ කෝෂ ලිපින(cell address) ඇත.මතක වර්ග,ප්‍රාථමික මතක – මධ්‍ය සැකසුම් ඒකකය සමඟ ඍජුවම සමිබන්ධ විය හැකි මතක වේ.වාරක මතකය (cache memory)නෂ්‍ය මතකයකි. සසම්භාවී පිවිසුම් මතකය හා මධ්‍ය සැකසුම් ඒකකය අතර අතරමැදියෙක් ලෙස ක්‍රියා කරයි. නිරන්තරයෙන් භාවිතා වන දත්ත තාවකාලිකව ගබඩා කර තබාගනී.සසම්භාවී පිවිසුම් මතකය (RAM)නෂ්‍ය මතකයකි. පරිගණකයේ ක්‍රියාත්මක වෙමින් පතින වැඩසටහන්වල දත්ත හා උපදෙස් තාවකාලිකව මතකයේ තබා ගනී. මේ නිසා පරිගණකයේ ප්‍රධාන මතකය ලෙස මෙය හදුන්වයි.පඨන මාත්‍ර මතකය (ROM)නෂ්‍ය නොවන මතකයකි .BIOS ලෙස හැඳින්වෙන පරිගණකය පණගැන්වීමට අවශ්‍ය මූලික වැඩසටහන් ඇතුළත් වේ.ද්වීතියික මතකයනශ්‍ය නොවන මතක වේ.පරිගණකයේ දත්ත ස්ථීරව ගබඩා කිරීමට භාවිතා වේ. මෙම මතකවල ඇති දත්ත ප්‍රථමයෙන් RAM වෙත පිවිස පසුව CPU වෙත ගමන් කරයි.මේවා ප්‍රධාන වර්ග තුනකි.චුම්භක මාධ්‍ය උපක්‍රම (Hard disk, Magnetic tape)ප්‍රකාශ මාධ්‍ය උපක්‍රම (CD, DVD)ඝන මාධ්‍ය උපක්‍රම ( Flash drive, SD card)"},{"question":"O que significa 'Decisão ou Despacho Designação de Audiência'?","answer":"'Decisão ou Despacho Designação de Audiência' é a decisão do juiz que agenda uma audiência para um determinado dia e hora, na qual as partes e testemunhas serão ouvidas."},{"question":"அழும் அதிசய சுவர் எந்த நாட்டில் உள்ளது ?","answer":"விடை : எருசேலம் நாட்டில்,மேற்குச் சுவர், அழுகைச் சுவர்/புலம்பற் சுவர் .எருசலேம் பழைய நகரில் கோவில் மலையின் மேற்கில் அமைந்துள்ளது."},{"question":"ある人が得意としていることを、他の人がとってかわってやってのけてしまうことを、「何を奪う」というでしょう？","answer":"お株"},{"question":"Que língua é falada no país Belize?","answer":"A língua oficial de Belize é o inglês. O inglês é amplamente falado e utilizado em todos os níveis de governo, na educação, nos negócios e na vida cotidiana em Belize. No entanto, é importante observar que Belize é um país multicultural e multilíngue, e outras línguas também são faladas na nação, incluindo o crioulo belizenho, o espanhol, o maia e várias línguas indígenas. O crioulo belizenho é uma língua crioula baseada no inglês que é amplamente falada pela população."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الجليل الذي كان أول من استل سيفًا في سبيل الله ؟","answer":"الجواب: الزبير بن العوام."},{"question":"لدينا المسألة الرياضاية التالية: 36 شجرة مزروعة في 9 صفوف؛ فكم عدد الأشجار في كل صف؟. قم بحلها.","answer":"بالتأكيد، يمكن حلها كالتالي: س = 63 قسمة 9 = 4 شجرة في كل صف."},{"question":"HTTP in software engineeringHTTP ကို ကွန်ပျူတာတွေအကြားက ဘာသာစကားလို့ ဘာကြောင့် တင်စားကြတာလဲ။ HTTP နဲ့ REST API တူသလား။ HTTP အကြောင်း အရိုးရှင်းဆုံး နားလည်သွားအောင် ပြောပြပါ","answer":"အင်တာနက် ကွန်ယက်ကြီးထဲမှာ ဖုန်း၊ ကွန်ပျူတာ စသဖြင့် မတူညီတဲ့ device တွေက ဘီလီယံနဲ့ချီပြီး ရှိကြပါတယ်။ ဒီ device တွေအကြား အချင်းချင်း ဆက်သွယ်ဖို့ တူညီတဲ့ language တခုခု ရှိမထားဘူးဆိုရင် ကွန်ယက်ကြီးက သူတလူ ငါတမင်းနဲ့ အမှိုက်ပုံကြီးတခုလို ဖြစ်နေပါလိမ့်မယ်။HTTP ကို ကျွန်တော်တို့ ဒီရည်ရွယ်ချက်နဲ့ ဖန်တီးခဲ့ကြတာပါ။ ကမ္ဘာရဲ့ ဒီဖက်ခြမ်းမှာရှိတဲ့ ဖုန်းကနေ တခါမှ မမြင်ဖူးတဲ့ ​မြောက်အမေရိကတိုက်က device တခုကို လှမ်းဆက်သွယ်တဲ့အခါ အချင်းချင်း နားလည်ကြဖို့ဆိုရင် ဘယ်လိုအချက်ပြမယ်၊ ဘယ်စကားလုံးက ဘာကိုဆိုလိုပါတယ် စသဖြင့် ကြိုဇာတ်တိုက်ထားရပါလိမ့်မယ်။ ဒါကိုပဲ protocol လို့ခေါ်တာဖြစ်တယ်။အချင်းချင်း တခါမှမမြင်ဖူးတဲ့ လူနှစ်ယောက် ရုပ်ရှင်ရုံရှေ့ ချိန်းထားကြတယ်လို့ မြင်ယောင်ကြည့်ပါ။ ငါအနီလေး ဝတ်လာခဲ့မယ်။ ငါ့ကိုတွေ့ရင် လက်ထောင်ပြလိုက်၊ ဒါဆို ငါ နင့်ဆီလျှောက်လာခဲ့မယ်လို့ ကြိုညှိထားတယ်လို့ ဆိုပါစို့။ ဒါက protocol ရဲ့သဘောဖြစ်တယ်။ device နှစ်ခုကို စက်ရုံတခုတည်းက ထုတ်ထားတာ ဖြစ်ဖို့ မလိုသလို သူတို့ချင်း ဆက်သွယ်နိုင်ဖို့ သီးသန့် ညှိနှိုင်းစရာလည်း မလိုပါဘူး။ ဒီလိုမျိုး device တိုင်းက နားလည်နိုင်အောင် ကြိုတင် သဘောတူထားတဲ့ protocol တွေထဲမှာမှ HTTP protocol ကတော့ နာမည်အကျော်ဆုံးနဲ့ အင်တာနက်ပေါ် နေရာအယူထားဆုံး protocol တခုဖြစ်တယ်။HTTP အကြောင်းပြောရင် client - server မော်ဒယ်အတွဲက မပါမဖြစ်ပါပဲ။ device တခုက HTTP protocol ကိုသုံးပြီး နောက်ထပ် device တခုကို ဆက်သွယ်တယ်လို့ ဆိုပါစို့။ စဆက်သွယ်တဲ့ device ကို client လို့ သမုတ်ကြပါတယ်။ မှတ်ထားရမှာက ကိုယ့်ဖက်က စဆက်သွယ်ချင်ရင် ဆက်သွယ်နိုင်ဖို့ လိုအပ်တာတွေကို ပြင်ဆင်ထားရပါမယ်။ ဆက်သွယ်ခံရတဲ့ device ကိုတော့ server လို့သတ်မှတ်ကြပါတယ်။ ဒီနေရာမှာလည်း ခုနကလိုပဲ ဆက်သွယ်ခံချင်ရင် ဆက်သွယ်ခံနိုင်အောင် ပြင်ဆင်ထားဖို့ လိုအပ်ပြန်ပါတယ်။HTTP ကမ္ဘာမှာ ကိုယ့်ဖက်က စဆက်သွယ်နိုင်ဖို့အတွက် device ပေါ်မှာ HTTP client ရှိထားဖို့ လိုအပ်ပါတယ်။ HTTP client က connection တည်ဆောက်တာနဲ့ စီမံခန့်ခွဲတာ၊ request တည်ဆောက်တာနဲ့ ပေးပို့တာ၊ response ကိုစောင့်ကြည့်ပေးတာ စသဖြင့် တာဝန်ယူပြီး Chrome, Safari, Firefox စတဲ့ Browser တွေက အတွေ့ရများဆုံး HTTP client တွေပဲဖြစ်တယ်။ ဒါတင်မကပဲ terminal ကနေ တိုက်ရိုက်သုံးနိုင်တဲ့ curl စတဲ့ CLI HTTP client တွေရှိသလို Android OS နဲ့အတူ ပါရှိတဲ့ Apache လို Client Library အနေနဲ့လည်း တွေ့ရနိုင်တယ်။HTTP server အကြောင်း မပြောခင်မှာ server ဆိုတဲ့ အသုံးအနှုန်းအကြောင်း အရင်နားလည်ထားစေချင်ပါတယ်။ software တခုလည်ပတ်ဖို့ လိုအပ်တဲ့ hardware ကို physical host လို့ခေါ်ပြီး အဲဒီ hardware ကို server လို့ခေါ်တယ်။ တခါ server ဆီရောက်လာမယ့် request တွေကို hardware ရဲ့ port တခုခုမှာ မပြတ်စောင့်ကြည့်နေနိုင်ဖို့ software တွေလိုအပ်ပြီး အဲဒီ software တွေကိုတော့ web server လို့ခေါ်ကြပါတယ်။ Apache နဲ့ Nginx တို့က နာမည်ကျော် web server software တွေပေါ့။ ဒါပေမယ့် အဲဒီ web server တွေက ကြားခံသက်သက်သာဖြစ်ပြီး request ကို ဖြည့်ဆည်းပေးနိုင်ဖို့ ရည်ရွယ်တဲ့ အစိတ်အပိုင်းတွေ မဟုတ်ပါဘူး။တကယ်တမ်း web server တွေဆီက request ကို လက်ခံပြီး စိစစ်ဖြည့်ဆည်းပေးနိုင်ဖို့အတွက်ကတော့ C++ Java PHP စတဲ့ programming language တွေနဲ့ server-side program တွေကိုတည်ဆောက်ရပါတယ်။ ဒီတော့ HTTP ကမ္ဘာမှာ server လို့ပြောရင် ကြားခံဖြစ်တဲ့ Web Server ကလည်း HTTP protocol ကိုနားလည်ဖို့ လိုအပ်သလို server program ကလည်း HTTP ကိုနားလည်ပြီး request တွေဖြည့်ဆည်းပေးနိုင်ဖို့ အရေးကြီးပါတယ်။ဒီတော့ HTTP protocol ကိုအသုံးပြုပြီး ဆက်သွယ်မှုတခု ပြုလုပ်ခဲ့ရင် ဒါကို request ပို့တယ်လို့ ခေါ်ဝေါ်ကြောင်း သိလောက်ရောပေါ့။ HTTP request တခုမှာ server ပေါ်က ဘယ် resource ကိုဆိုလိုကြောင်း ညွှန်းတဲ့ url နဲ့ အဲဒီ resource ကိုဘာလုပ်ချင်တယ်ဆိုတဲ့ HTTP verb (ဥပမာ GET, POST) တို့ပါဝင်ကြတယ်။ server ဖက်က ဒီ request ကို လက်ခံရရှိတဲ့အခါ စိစစ်ပြီး အကြောင်းပြန်လိုက်တာကို response ပြန်တယ်လို့ ခေါ်တယ်။အဲဒီ response မှာ တောင်းဆိုလာတဲ့ request က ပြီးမြောက်လား၊ ငြင်းခံရသလား ဒါမှမဟုတ်ပဲ နောက်တနေရာကို ထပ်တောင်းဆိုရမလား စသဖြင့် နားလည်စေမယ့် HTTP Status Code တခု ပါပါမယ်။ browser တွေမှာ မြင်နေရကျ 404 Not Found ဆိုတာ တောင်းဆိုလိုက်တဲ့ resource ကို server မှာရှာမတွေ့တဲ့အတွက် request မအောင်မြင်ပါလို့ အကြောင်းပြန်လိုက်တဲ့ သဘောပါပဲ။ ဒီတော့ request တခု အောင်မြင်သည်ဖြစ်စေ၊ အငြင်းခံရသည်ဖြစ်စေ server ဖက်က response ပြန်ကိုပြန်မှာဖြစ်လို့ request ရဲ့ အခြေအနေကို သိချင်ရင် status code ကိုသာ ဖတ်ရမှာဖြစ်တယ်။ရှေ့တခေါက်မှာ RESTful API တွေအကြောင်း ကျွန်တော်တို့ ပြောခဲ့ကြပါတယ်။ HTTP protocol ကို device တွေပေါ်က application program တွေကြား အချက်အလက် ဖလှယ်ဖို့အတွက် သုံးတာဖြစ်လို့ HTTP ကို application protocol လို့လည်း ရည်ညွှန်းကြပါတယ်။ဥပမာ Facebook Mobile App က /posts ဆိုတဲ့ url မှာ GET ဆိုတဲ့ HTTP verb အသုံးပြုပြီး Facebook Server ဆီက post တွေ လှမ်းတောင်းယူနိုင်တယ်။ ဒါပေမယ့် GET အစား DELETE နဲ့ကော post တွေ တောင်းယူနိုင်အောင် Facebook Server က ပြင်ထားပေးလို့ မရဘူးလားလို့ မေးရင် ရပါတယ်လို့ ဖြေရပါလိမ့်မယ်။ ဒါပေမယ့် အဲလို​လုပ်ချင်သလိုသာ လုပ်ကြမယ်ဆိုရင် အင်္ဂလိပ် စကားချင်း အတူတူ တမြို့မှာ အဓိပ္ပါယ်တမျိုး ဆိုသလို ဖြစ်တော့မှာပေါ့။ ဒါကြောင့် REST ရဲ့ အခြေခံ အိုင်ဒီယာက HTTP ကို ကမောက်ကမတွေ မလုပ်ကြပဲ စနစ်တကျ အသုံးပြုကြဖို့ ကြပ်မတ်ထိန်းသိမ်းထားဖို့ ဖြစ်တယ်။HTTP က application protocol သာဖြစ်တဲ့အတွက် သူ့မှာ program တွေကြား ဖလှယ်ကြတဲ့ အချက်အလက်တွေကို ဘယ်လိုဖော်ပြမယ်ဆိုတဲ့ သတ်မှတ်ချက်တွေတော့ မပါဝင်ပါဘူး။ ဖော်ပြဖို့အတွက် ရွေးချယ်စရာတွေထဲမှာ Json နဲ့ XML နှစ်ခုက လူသုံးအများဆုံးဖြစ်တယ်။ ဥပမာ Facebook Server အနေနဲ့ Facebook App ဆီက /posts အတွက် GET request ကိုလက်ခံရတဲ့အခါ response နဲ့အတူ post တွေ ပြန်ထည့်ပေးမှာဖြစ်တယ်။ ဒါပေမယ့် post တွေကို JSON နဲ့ပေးသလား။ XML နဲ့ပေးမှာလား ဆိုတာကတော့ ကိုယ့်လိုအပ်ချက်နဲ့ ကိုက်အောင် ရွေးချယ်နိုင်တာဖြစ်တဲ့အတွက် ဆန္ဒရှိရင် REST အစား HTTP နဲ့ XML ကိုပူးတွဲအသုံးချတဲ့ SOAP API တွေလည်း တည်ဆောက်နိုင်သေးတယ်။ဒီလောက်ဆိုရင် HTTP က အင်တာနက် ကွန်ယက်ကြီးရဲ့ Communication မှာ အရေးပါတဲ့ ထောက်တိုင်တခုဖြစ်တဲ့အကြောင်း ဆက်စပ်နားလည်သွားမယ်လို့ ယုံကြည်ပါတယ်။ ဒါပေမယ့် အင်တာနက်ကို ဒီထက် ပိုနားလည်စေချင်သေးလို့ ဒီအကြောင်းတွေ ထပ်ပြောကြပါမယ်။ ဒါကတော့ software engineering ရဲ့ HTTP အကြောင်း ဖြစ်ပါတယ်။မှတ်ချက်။   ။ CodeHub with Harry မှ Harry Yan ရဲ့ ၂၀၂၃၊ သြဂုတ်လမှ စာတပုဒ်မှ ကောက်နှုတ်ထားပါတယ်"},{"question":"බුදු දහමේ සඳහන්වන ආකාරයට , \\" සක්වළ \\" ට අයත්වන භූමිතල ( ලෝක ) ගණන කීයද ?","answer":"බුදු දහමේ සඳහන්වන ආකාරයට , \\" සක්වළ \\" ට අයත්වන භූමිතල ( ලෝක ) ගණන  31 යි"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Trực tiếp PMPL VN mùa Thu 2022 tuần 2 - ngày 5","answer":"Sau 4 ngày thi đấu của tuần 2 vòng Pro-League, nhà đương kim vô địch Box Gaming đang xây chắc ngôi đầu bảng xếp hạng với 241 điểm, sau khi mang về 114 mạng hạ gục, 127 điểm hạng cùng 4 WWCD. Xếp sau Box Gaming lần lượt là Eagle Esports (204 điểm), D'Xavier (177 điểm) và V Gaming (169 điểm). Theo thể thức thi đấu mới, ngày 5 tuần 2 của PMPL VN mùa Thu 2022 sẽ bổ sung 1 trận ở map Livik cho 12 đội dẫn đầu BXH tuần trong ngày Chủ nhật. Bên cạnh đó, sau khi kết thúc trận 4, khán giả cũng sẽ có cơ hội để thưởng thức những màn trình diễn tuyệt vời qua các siêu phẩm đến từ BlackPink và được trải nghiệm những nội dung liên quan thần tượng của mình tại các sự kiện in-game. "},{"question":"Otobanda hız sınırı yüzde kaç aşılabilir?","answer":"Azami hız limiti terimi de bu nedenle kullanılmaktadır. Azami hız limiti oluşabilecek hatalı tespitlerin de önüne geçilmesi adına hâlihazırda olan hız sınırlarına % 10'luk bir hata payı eklenmesiyle belirlenmektedir."},{"question":"ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨਰਿੰਦਰ ਮੋਦੀ ਅਤੇ ਆਰਐੱਸਐੱਸ ਮੁਖੀ ਮੋਹਨ ਭਾਗਵਤ।ਇਸ ਤਸਵੀਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਇੱਕ ਪਾਸੇ ਮੰਤਰ ਉਚਾਰਨ ਕਰਦੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ ਹਨ, ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨਰਿੰਦਰ ਮੋਦੀ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਖੱਬੇ ਹੱਥ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਸਵੈਮ ਸੇਵਕ ਸੰਘ ਦੇ ਮੁਖੀ ਮੋਹਨ ਭਾਗਵਤ ਬੈਠੇ ਦਿਖਾਈ ਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।ਭਾਰਤੀ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਇਹ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਮੌਕਾ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ ਜਦੋਂ ਸਰਕਾਰ, ਧਰਮ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਘ ਦੀ ਨੇੜਤਾ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਉਜਾਗਰ ਹੋਈ ਹੋਵੇ। ਸੰਘ ਦੇ ਦਹਾਕਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਮੌਕਾ ਕਿਸੇ ਸੁਨਹਿਰੇ ਪਲ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਣਾ।ਮੋਹਨ ਭਾਗਵਤ ਨੇ ਭੂਮੀ ਪੂਜਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਕਿਹਾ, ''ਅਨੰਦ ਦਾ ਪਲ ਹੈ। ਬਹੁਤ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਅਨੰਦ ਹੈ''। ''ਇੱਕ ਸੰਕਲਪ ਲਿਆ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਯਾਦ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਸਾਡੇ  ਸੰਘ ਸੰਚਾਲਕ ਬਾਲਾ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਦੇਵਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਕਦਮ ਅੱਗੇ ਵਧਾਉਣ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਇਹ ਯਾਦ ਦਵਾਈ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਵੀਹ-ਤੀਹ ਸਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨਾ ਪਵੇਗਾ। ਫਿਰ ਹੀ ਇਹ ਕੰਮ ਹੋ ਸਕੇਗਾ''।  ''ਵੀਹ-ਤੀਹ ਸਾਲ ਅਸੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਤੀਹਵੇਂ ਸਾਲ ਦੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਸੰਕਲਪ ਪੂਰਾ ਹੋਣ ਦਾ ਅਨੰਦ ਮਿਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।\\"ਮੋਹਨ ਭਾਗਵਤ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਨੌਂ ਮਿੰਟ ਲੰਬੇ ਭਾਸ਼ਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਕਿਹਾ ਉਸ ਤੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਗੱਲ ਤਾਂ ਸਪੱਸ਼ਟ ਹੈ- ਸੰਘ ਨੇ ਪੰਜ ਅਗਸਤ 2020 ਨੂੰ ਹੋਏ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਾਮ ਮੰਦਿਰ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਦਾ ਪੂਰਾ ਸਿਹਰਾ ਲੈਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ।ਤਾਕਤ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਪਹੁੰਚਿਆ ਸੰਘ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ। ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਸਵੈਮ ਸੇਵਕ ਉੱਪਰ ਕਿਤਾਬ- ਦਿ ਆਈਕੰਸ ਆਫ਼ ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਰਾਈਟ ਲਿਖਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸੀਨੀਅਰ ਪੱਤਰਕਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਲੇਖਕ ਨੀਲਾਂਜਨ ਮੁਖੋਪਾਧਿਆ ਮੰਨਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਸੰਘ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਸੰਘ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਵਾਨਗੀ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ।ਮੁਖੋਪਾਧਿਆ ਦੱਸਦੇ ਹਨ,\\"ਹਿੰਦੁਸਤਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੱਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਧਰਮ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਜੋ ਲਕੀਰਾਂ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾ ਤੋਂ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਧੁੰਦਲੀਆਂ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਜਾ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਲੇਕਿਨ ਇੰਨੀ ਧੁੰਦਲੀ ਕਦੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਈ। ਸੰਘ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਹੁਣ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਵਾਨਿਤ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਸਵੈਮ ਸੇਵਕ ਸੰਘ ਨੂੰ ਮੈਂ ਕਦੇ ਵੀ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਇੰਨਾ ਨੇੜੇ, ਉਹ ਵੀ ਅਧਿਕਾਰਿਤ ਰੂਪ ਤੋਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਹੈ। ਅਜਿਹੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਹਿੰਦੁਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਭਵਿੱਖ ਦੇ ਲਿਹਾਜ ਤੋਂ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਵੱਡੇ ਬਦਲਾਅ ਹੈ।\\"\\"ਪ੍ਰਤੀਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਕਰੀਏ ਤਾਂ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰਕ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਵਾਦ ਨੂੰ ਉਤਸ਼ਾਹਿਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਮੋਹਨ ਭਾਗਵਤ ਦੀ ਹਾਜ਼ਰੀ ਨਾਲ ਇਹ ਸਾਫ਼ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਸੰਘ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਮੰਦਰ ਲਹਿਰ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਉੱਪਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਹੱਕ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ।\\"ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਸਵਾਲ ਇਹ ਉਠਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਸਵੈਮ ਸੇਵਕ ਸੰਘ ਨੇ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸਿਆਸਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਕੱਦ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਹਾਸਲ ਕੀਤਾ?ਰਾਮ ਦੇ ਸਹਾਰੇ?ਕਿਸੇ ਭਾਈਚਾਰੇ ਦੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ, ਸਿਆਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਭਾਈਚਾਰਕ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਦਾ ਅਧਿਐਨ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਅਕਸਰ ਇਸ ਸਵਾਲ ਨਾਲ ਦੋ-ਚਾਰ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਲਹਿਰਾਂ, ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਸੰਸਥਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਆਪਕਤਾ ਦਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਨਾ ਕਿ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਸੰਸਥਾਵਾਂ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਲਹਿਰਾਂ ਉਭਰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਅਯੁੱਧਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਘ ਦੇ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਸਵਾਲ ਉਭਰ ਕੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਰਾਮ ਮੰਦਰ ਲਹਿਰ ਨੇ ਸੰਘ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਪਾਕਤਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਜਾਂ ਸੰਘ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਹਿਯੋਗੀ ਸੰਗਠਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਜ੍ਹਾ ਨਾਲ ਰਾਮ ਮੰਦਰ ਲਹਿਰ ਖੜ੍ਹੀ ਹੋਈ।ਸੀਨੀਅਰ ਪੱਤਰਕਾਰ ਸੁਨੀਤਾ ਏਰਾਨ ਮੰਦਰ ਉਸਾਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਆਰਐੱਸਐੱਸ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੀ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਗਿਣਦੇ ਹਨ।ਉਹ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ,\\" ਰਾਮ ਮੰਦਰ ਲਹਿਰ ਆਰਐੱਸਐੱਸ ਦੇ ਕਈ ਮੁੱਦਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਦਲਿਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਨਾਲ ਲਿਆਉਣ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਲਹਿਰ ਚਲਾਈ। ਦਲਿਤ ਭੋਜ ਕਰਾਏ। ਅਸ਼ੋਕ ਸਿੰਘਲ ਇੱਕ ਦਲਿਤ ਭੋਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੋਏ। ਅਜਿਹੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੇਰਾ ਖ਼ਿਆਲ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਆਰਐੱਸਐੱਸ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਲਹਿਰ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਹਿਮ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ।\\"\\"ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਸੰਘ ਨੇ ਗਊ ਹੱਤਿਆ ਦਾ ਮਸਲਾ ਵੀ  ਚੁੱਕਿਆ ਪਰ ਰਾਮ ਮੰਦਿਰ ਲਹਿਰ ਇੱਕ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਮੁੱਦਾ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਵੱਡੀ  ਗਿਣਤੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੋਕ ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੇ। ਵਜ੍ਹਾ ਰਾਮ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਵਾਨਗੀ ਵਿਆਪਕ ਸੀ।\\"ਰਾਮ ਨੇ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਵਿਆਪਕਤਾ?ਰਾਮ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਮਹਿਮਾ ਕੁਝ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਅਯੁੱਧਿਆ ਤੋਂ ਸੈਂਕੜੇ ਕਿੱਲੋਮੀਟਰ ਦੂਰ ਮਹਾਰਾਸ਼ਟਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿਆਸਤ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਾਲ ਠਾਕਰੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵੀ ਇਸ ਲਹਿਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।","answer":"ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਸਵੈਮ ਸੇਵਕ ਸੰਘ ਅਤੇ ਰਾਮ ਮੰਦਿਰ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ।"},{"question":"Тилекке каршы, эгемендүүлүктү алгандан бери Кыргызстандын бийлик башындатургандар акылсыз болуп чыкты. Керек болсо ХИПК аттуу аты суук уюмга киретургандай абалга кабылтып, балчыкка тыгып салышты. Он беш жылдын ичиндеалынган кредиттер, гуманитардык жардамдар 5 миллиард долларды чапчыйт. Булазыркы ички дүң продукциябыздан эки эсе көп каражат дегендикке жатат. Башкачаайтканда, 70 жылда чогултулган байлыгыбыздан да эки эсе көп жардам алыптырбыз.Ошончо жардам алганыбызга карабастан, экономикабыздын бели мертинип, азыр иткемингендей абалдабыз. Эгерде ХИПКке кире турган болсок, Африкадагы эң арттакалган, өз алдынчалыгына ээ боло албаган өлкөлөрдүн катарына киребиз.Автор текстте бийликке болгон мамилесин кандайча билдирген?(А) ишеними менен(Б) үмүтсүздүгү менен(В) байкагычтыгы менен(Г) маалымдоосу менен","answer":"Туура жооп - (Б)Тексттин автору “бийлик башында тургандар акылсыз болуп чыкты”, “Эгерде ХИПКкекире турган болсок, Африкадагы эң артта калган, өз алдынчалыгына ээ боло албаганөлкөлөрдүн катарына киребиз.” деген саптары аркылуу бийликке болгон мамилесинүмүтсүздүгү менен билдирди."},{"question":"கேள்வி: இந்தியாவின் மிகப் பெரிய நூலகமான தேசிய நூலகம் எங்கு அமைந்துள்ளது?கீழ் காணப்படும் நான்கு பதிலில் இருந்து சரியான பதிலை தேர்ந்து எடுக்கவும்:அ) கொல்கத்தாஆ) டெல்லிஇ) மும்பைஈ) பெங்களூர்","answer":"சரியான பதில்: அ) கொல்கத்தாவிளக்கம்: இந்திய தேசிய நூலகம் இந்தியாவின் மிகப்பெரிய நூலகம் ஆகும். இந்திய அரசின் சுற்றுலா மற்றும் பண்பாட்டுத் துறையால் பராமரிக்கப்படுகிறது. இந்நூலகம் கொல்கத்தாவில் முப்பது ஏக்கர் பரப்பளவில் அமைந்துள்ளது. தற்போது இருபத்தி இரண்டு இலட்சம் நூல்கள் இங்குள்ளன. இந்தியாவின் நான்கு சேகரிப்பு நூலகங்களில் இதுவும் ஒன்று. இந்தியாவைப் பற்றிய, இந்திய மொழிகளில் வெளியான அனைத்து நூல்களும் இங்குச் சேகரித்து வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. அனைத்து இந்திய மொழிகளில் மட்டுமன்றி, உலக மொழிகளில் எழுதப்பட்ட நூல்களும் இங்குள்ளன. இந்திய மொழிகளில் வங்காள மொழி, இந்தி, தமிழ் ஆகியன அதிக சேகரிப்புகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளன. உருசியம், அரபி, பிரெஞ்சு ஆகியன அதிக நூல்களைக் கொண்டுள்ள பிற நாட்டு மொழிகளாகும். இந்தியாவில் வெளியாகும் அனைத்து நாளிதழ்களும் இங்குச் சேகரிக்கப்படுகின்றன. தமிழின் அரிய சுவடிகளும் நூல்களும் இங்கு உள்ளன என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது. "},{"question":"Quelles monnaie est-ce qu'ils utilisent au Bénin ?","answer":"La monnaie officielle des pays formant l'Union économique et monétaire ouest-africaine (UEMOA) est le franc CFA. L'institut d'émission est la Banque centrale des États de l'Afrique de l'Ouest (BCEAO).Le franc CFA s'écrit en abrégé en FCFA ou F CFA, et son code ISO est XOF. Le taux de change du franc CFA était de 1 XOF (~0 € - cours du 29/09/2022) = 0,01 FRF ce qui donne une parité fixe avec l'euro de 1 € = 655,957 XOF (~1 € - cours du 29/09/2022) mais les banques et bureaux de change peuvent appliquer une commission sur la transaction.Sur chaque pièce et au recto des billets est représenté le logo de la BCEAO, un poisson-scie stylisé. Celui-ci représente une figurine en bronze employée anciennement par les Akan pour peser l'or.Les pays membres de la Communauté économique et monétaire de l'Afrique centrale utilisent un autre franc CFA dont le code est XAF."},{"question":"Cé hé Winston Churchill? ","answer":"Polaiteoir agus ceannaire cogaidh Sasanach ab ea Winston Spencer Churchill, (30 Samhain 1874 — 24 Eanáir 1965). Mac le státaire Sasanach eile Randolph Churchill, a bhí ann. Chaith sé tréimhse ina oifigeach airm san India, agus ghlac sé páirt i gCath Omdurman i gcoinne lucht leanúna an Mhahdaí sa tSúdáin freisin. Ina dhiaidh sin, ghlac sé páirt i Cogadh na mBórach. Ón mbliain 1900 anuas, bhí sé ina Fheisire don Pháirtí Choimeádach, ach thréig sé an páirtí sin ar mhaithe leis na Liobrálaigh sa bhliain 1904. "},{"question":"පහත ගීතයට තනු නිර්මාණය කලේ කවුද?රන් කෙන්දන් බැඳ අතැඟිලි එක්කළ ආදරයයි...පෙම් රැහැනෙන් බැඳසිතුම් වසඟ කළ ආදරයයි.....පෙම් රැහැනෙන් බැඳසිතුම් වසඟ කළ ආදරයයි.......කිරිලිය සේ දුර පියාසලාලාඅත්තටු රිදුණා පමණයිදෑල විදාහළ දෑත මගේඔබටත් ඔහුටත් උරුමයිහිරු සඳු එකවර දෙපස නැඟේකළුවර ඇයි විජිතයම මගේ....කණාටු සුළඟේ දුහුළු මලකි අදවල්මත් වී පාවෙන්නේඔබගෙන් දෝඔහුගෙන් දෝමා හෙට දින සමුගන්නේ.....","answer":"සංගීතය - සරත් දසනායක"},{"question":"కింది పరిచిత గద్యాలను చదవండి. ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నలకు సమాధానాలు రాయండి.“పెద్దాపురం ప్రభువులకు నజరు పెట్టుకుందామని తయారుచేశానది. గోల్కొండ నవాబుగారికి వట్టివేళ్ళ అత్తరు మిక్కిలి ప్రియం అని తెలిసి అదెంత శ్రద్ధగా తయారుచేశానో, పెద్దాపురం మహారాజులుంగారికి గులాబీ అత్తరు మిక్కిలి ప్రీతిపాత్రం అని తెలిసి అదీ అంతే శ్రద్ధగానూ తయారుచేశాను. ఆ సీసాలో ఉన్నది ఒక్కటే తులం – దీని నిమిత్తం కాశ్మీరం జాతి పువ్వులు వాడాను. ఢిల్లీ పరిసరాల్లో పారశీక జాతులే ఎక్కువ. కాశ్మీరజాతి చాలా అరుదుగా దొరుకుతుంది. అందుచేత, ఆ కాస్త అత్తరూ తయారు కావడానికి దాదాపుగా రెండేళ్ళు పట్టింది మహాప్రభూ” అని వివరించి చెప్పాడతను.ఇది విని అక్కడివారు; దాని విశిష్టతా, విలువ ఊహించుకుని చాలా ఆనందించారు; కాని “ఆశ్చర్యమా?”ప్రశ్నలు :1. ఎవరికి నజరు పెట్టుకుందామని తయారు చేశాడు?2. పెద్దాపురం మహారాజుకి ప్రీతిపాత్రం అయినది ఏది?3. గులాబీ అత్తరులో ఏ జాతి పువ్వులు వాడారు?4. ఢిల్లీ పరిసరాల్లో ఏ జాతులు ఎక్కువ?","answer":"1. ఎవరికి నజరు పెట్టుకుందామని తయారు చేశాడు?జవాబు:పెద్దాపురం ప్రభువులకు నజరు పెట్టుకుందామని తయారు చేశాడు.2. పెద్దాపురం మహారాజుకి ప్రీతిపాత్రం అయినది ఏది?జవాబు:పెద్దాపురం ప్రభువులకు గులాబీ అత్తరు ప్రీతి పాత్రమైనది.3. గులాబీ అత్తరులో ఏ జాతి పువ్వులు వాడారు?జవాబు:గులాబీ అత్తరులో కాశ్మీరుజాతి పువ్వులు వాడారు.4. ఢిల్లీ పరిసరాల్లో ఏ జాతులు ఎక్కువ?జవాబు:ఢిల్లీ పరిసరాల్లో పారశీక జాతులెక్కువ."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta goma sha-biyu a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 12"},{"question":"No anime Dragon Ball Z, quem é Majin Buu?","answer":"Majin Buu é uma entidade mágica que existe em várias formas ao longo da série, algumas das quais são extremamente destrutivas, enquanto outras são mais amigáveis."},{"question":"イスラム世界で赤十字マークの代わりとして使われている、白地に赤い三日月をかたどったマークのことを何というでしょう？","answer":"赤新月です。"},{"question":"الي ماذا يشير علم الأنثروبولوجي؟","answer":"هو علم دراسة الاجناس."},{"question":"Faizal menyimpan RM8 000 dalam akaun simpanan tetap untuk tempoh setengahtahun. Kadar faedah yang ditawarkan ialah 3.3% setahun. Hitung faedah yang diterimaoleh Faizal.","answer":"Faedah yang diterima oleh Faizal ialah RM8000 x 0.5 x 3.3% = RM132."},{"question":"Tai của mèo có bao nhiêu cơ?","answer":"Mèo có 32 cơ kiểm soát tai ngoài. Thính giác của mèo nhạy hơn nhiều so với người và chó. Mèo có thể di chuyển đôi tai của mình giống như đĩa radar, xác định chính xác nguồn phát, xoay chúng 180 độ theo hướng âm thanh nhanh hơn khoảng 10 lần so với những giống chó canh gác tốt nhất. "},{"question":"Cần Giuộc, địa danh trong tác phẩm Văn tế nghĩa sĩ Cần Giuộc hiện ở tỉnh nào?a. Tiền Giangb. Long Anc. Bến Tre","answer":"b. Long AnVăn tế là loại văn gắn với phong tục tang lễ, nhằm bày tỏ thương tiếc với người đã mất. Văn tế thường kể lại cuộc đời, công đức, phẩm hạnh của người đã khuất; bày tỏ nỗi đau thương của người sống trong phút vĩnh biệt. Âm hưởng chung của bài văn tế là bi thương, nhưng sắc thái biểu cảm ở mỗi bài có thể khác nhau.Văn tế nghĩa sĩ Cần Giuộc là bài văn tế do nhà thơ Nguyễn Đình Chiểu sáng tác để ca ngợi, thương tiếc gần 20 nghĩa sĩ đã hy sinh trong trận đánh quân Pháp tại Cần Giuộc (Long An) tháng 12/1861. Nghĩa quân đã giết được quan hai Pháp và một số lính thuộc địa, làm chủ đồn hai ngày rồi bị phản công và thất bại.Theo sách giáo khoa Văn học lớp 11 (tập 1, Nhà xuất bản Giáo dục Việt Nam), bài văn được Nguyễn Đình Chiểu viết theo yêu cầu của ông Đỗ Quang, tuần phủ Gia Định. Trong bối cảnh cuộc chiến đấu không cân sức những ngày đầu chống Pháp, sự hy sinh này có sức cổ vũ và khích lệ to lớn. Lần đầu tiên trong nền văn học dân tộc, người nông dân nghĩa sĩ chống ngoại xâm được dựng thành một tượng đài nghệ thuật bất hủ.Đoạn mở đầu của Văn tế nghĩa sĩ Cần Giuộc như sau:Hỡi ơi!Súng giặc đất rền; lòng dân trời tỏ.Mười năm công vỡ ruộng, chưa ắt còn danh nổi như phao; một trận nghĩa đánh Tây, tuy là mất tiếng vang như mõ.Trong thời kỳ bùng nổ cuộc kháng chiến chống Pháp ở Nam Kỳ, Nguyễn Đình Chiểu còn nhiều bài văn tế khác như: Văn tế Trương Định (1864), Văn tế nghĩa sĩ trận vong Lục tỉnh (1874)."},{"question":"Baca petikan di bawah dengan teliti, kemudian buat satu rumusan tentang faedah-faedah yang  diperoleh  daripada bidang bioteknologi di negara ini dan halangan-halangan yang dihadapi untuk menjayakan bidang tersebut.  Panjang  rumusan hendaklah tidak melebih 120 patah perkataan.Petikan:Selepas era teknologi maklumat dan komunikasi (ICT), dunia sekarang menumpukan perhatian pula kepada bidang bioteknologi. Bidang ini lebih menjurus dan menekankan aspek penyelidikan. Hal ini bertepatan dengan takrifan bioteknologi itu sendiri yang berasal daripada gabungan biologi dan teknologi yang bermaksud penggunaan sains untuk penghasilan bahan lain yang boleh dimanfaatkan bersama. Bidang ini mengaplikasikan ilmu pengetahuan demi kesejahteraan manusia.Dalam usaha memajukan sektor pertanian, semua pihak perlu melipatgandakan usaha bagi membuktikan sektor pertanian bukannya sektor ‘lembap’ yang sebelum ini sentiasa dikaitkan dengan kemiskinan. Kerajaan mahu menjadikan sektor pertanian maju dan dinamik serta mampu memberi nafas baru selari dengan perkembangan arus globalisasi. Aspirasi murni kerajaan ini terserlah dengan pelancaran Dasar Bioteknologi Negara (DBN). DBN memanfaatkan sumber kepelbagaian biologi di negara ini seperti flora dan fauna serta sumber lain seperti mikro dan organisma marin untuk penyelidikan. DBN memastikan rakyat mendapat faedah dengan wujudnya pelbagai bentuk aktiviti industri berasaskan bioteknologi.Bidang ini menjadi kunci pemacu kemajuan yang diperlukan untuk mengubah proses pertanian ke arah dimensi yang lebih moden, justeru meningkatkan imej sektor pertanian yang sekian lama dilihat sebagai sektor kelas kedua dibandingkan dengan sektor pembuatan dan automotif. Pendekatan baharu DBN juga membolehkan industri herba yang dikatakan bernilai RM50 bilion setahun akan terus berkembang. Pastinya penyelidikan bioteknologi bukan sekadar memproses Tongkat Ali dan Kacip Fatimah, tetapi juga mencakupi aspek penghasilan enzim dan makanan berfungsi serta penghasilan tumbuhan dan haiwan ternakan baka baharu. Penambahbaikan secara agresif oleh pihak kerajaan menerusi Kementerian Pertanian dan Industri Asas Tani akan memastikan bidang ini akan terus berkembang maju.Dalam aspek yang lain, menerusi bidang bioteknologi industri bahan buangan atau sisa industri dapat diberikan nilai tambah untuk menghasilkan produk baharu yang boleh dimanfaatkan. Bidang ini dianggap sebagai ilmu sains yang membawa kekayaan dan kemakmuran kepada manusia. Penyelidikan yang dilakukan dalam bidang ini tidak menggunakan unsur kimia untuk menghasilkan sesuatu penemuan, sebaliknya hanya menggunakan mikroorganisma, sel, dan molekul untuk tujuan tertentu.Tidak dapat dinafikan masa depan negara ini antara lain bergantung pada kejayaan bidang bioteknologi dan keberkesanan pelaksanaan DBN. Kita telah menyaksikan komitmen yang diberi oleh pihak kerajaan untuk menggapai kesejahteraan dan kemakmuran negara melalui bidang yang semakin penting ini. Justeru peluang untuk menikmati faedah daripada bidang bioteknologi ini tidak harus dilepaskan begitu sahaja.","answer":"Jawapan:Petikan membincangkan  manfaat yang diperoleh daripada pembangunan bioteknologi di negara kita           Antara  faedah pembangunan bioteknologi ialah  dapat dimanfaatkan untuk tujuan penyelidikan.  Seterusnya,  bidang ini menjadi kunci pemacu kemajuan yang diperlukan untuk mengubah proses pertanian ke arah dimensi yang lebih moden. Situasi ini dapat meningkatkan imej sektor pertanian yang selama ini dianggap sektor kelas kedua. Faedah selanjutnya ialah membolehkan industri herba di negara ini berkembang. Selain itu,aspek penghasilan enzim dan makanan turut  berfungsi  dengan adanya pembangunan bioteknologi. Selanjutnya , bahan buangan juga boleh dimanfaatkan untuk menghasilkan produk baharu .Halangan untuk  memajukan bidang bioteknologi ialah kos yang tinggi .  Selain itu, negara juga masih kekurangan tenaga pakar.Kesimpulannya, bidang bioteknologi harus diberikan perhatian oleh pengusaha industri agar sumber kepelbagaian biologi di negara ini dapat dimanfaatkan sepenuhnya."},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"கற்பு என்ற சொல், பெண் ஓர் அடிமை; சீவனற்ற ஒரு பொருள் என்று காட்டவே ஆகும்."},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Halako ireo zatovo ireo; maditra sy tsy mahay manaja izy rehetra.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Eny, kabary fankahalana ity fanambarana ity satria tsy ara-drariny no iantsoana ireo zatovo ho maditra sy tsy mahay manaja avokoa. "},{"question":"පහත මාතෘකා ව ඇති කතාව ලියා  දක්වන්න. (ඉඟිය: මෙය රසවාහිනීයේ එන කතාවකි)නාගාවගේ කථාව.","answer":"1. බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ ජීවත්ව වාසය කරන සමයෙහි ලඞ්කාවෙහි නාගදීපයෙහි දී චූලෝදර-මහෝදර යන මාමා බෑණලා අතර මැණික් පුටුවක් උදෙසා මහා යුද්ධයක් එළඹ සිටියේය. එකල්හි බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ බෝධියෙන් 5 වැනි අවුරුද්දෙහි දෙව්රම් වෙහෙරෙහි වැඩවාසය කරමින් අළුයම ලොව බලන්නේ ඔවුන් දැක අද මම එහි ගොස් කලහය සංසිඳවීම සුදුසු යයි සිතා බලන්නේ සමිද්ධි සුමන නම් දෙව් රජුන් දුටහ. මේ දෙව් රජ කවරෙක් ද? හේ මීට පෙර ජීවිතයෙහි නාගදීපයෙහි එක්තරා මිනිසෙක් වී. එකල්හි ගන්‍ධමාදන පර්වතයෙහි වසන එක් පසේබුදු කෙනෙක් පිඬු පිණිස හැසිර ඒ කිරිපලු නුග ගස ත බුණු තැන හිඳ බත්කිස කෙරෙති. හේ ඒ දැක එකෙණෙහිම සිත පහදවා පාත්‍ර‍ය සේදීමට කොළ කඩා දුන්නේය. හේ ඒ පින්කමෙන් එයින් චුතව දෙව්ලොව ඉපද අපගේ බුදුන් වහන්සේලාගේ කාලයෙහි දෙව්රම දොරටු කොටුවෙහි පසක කිරිපලු රුකක දේවතාවා වී උපන්නේය. භාග්‍යවතුන් වහන්සේ ඒ දෙව්රජුට කථාකොට මා සමග නාගදීපයට එන්නැයි කීහ. ඉක්බිති ඔහු විසින් තමන්ගේ භවනය වූ කිරිපලු ගස උදුරා භාග්‍යවතුන් වහන්සේගේ හිසට කුඩයක් මෙන් දරමින් යන මොහු සමග භාග්‍යවතුන් වහන්සේ නාගදීපයට වැඩිසේක.එහෙයින් මහා වංශයෙහි කියන ලදි.2. බක් මස කළුවර පක්‍ෂයෙහි පොහෝ දිනයෙහි උදයෙහි උතුම් පා සිවුරු ආදිය ගෙන, බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ කිරිපළු ගස රැගත් සුමන දෙවියා සමගම අහසින් පැමිණ නයින්ට අනුකම්පාව සඳහා නාගදීපයට වැඩි සේක.3. ඉක්බිති බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ මේ නාරජුන දෙදෙනාගේ සංග්‍රාමය මැද අහසෙහි හිඳ වැස්ස, සුළඟ, අඳුර ආදියෙන් බිය හා තැති ගැන්ම උපදවා එයින් ඉතා ඝන අඳුරු පටල පැන නැඟි සූර්යා සේ සවණක් රැසින් බබළමින් ආකාශයෙහි තමන් දක්වා ඔවුන් අස්වසා සියළුම බිය සංසිඳවීය. ඉක්බිති නාගයෝ සවණක් රසින් බබළන භාග්‍යවතුන් වහන්සේ දැක පහන් සිතින් ගත් ගත් ආයුධයන් හැර බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ දෙපා හිසින් වැන්දාහ. ඉක්බිති බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ ඔවුන්ට ධර්මය දේශනා කළ සේක. මහා වංශයෙහිම කියන ලදි.4. බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ ඔවුනට සමගි කරන ධර්මය දේශනා කළ සේක. ඒ දෙදෙනාම සතුටුව පුටුව බුදුපියාණන් වහන්සේට දුන්නාහුය.5. භූමියට වැඩම කළ බුදුරජාණෝ රතනාසනයෙහි වැඩ හුන් සේක. දිව්‍යමය ආහාර පානයෙන් නාගරාජයන් විසින් තර්පණය කරන ලදි.6. ජලයෙහි හා ගොඩ වාසය කරන නාගයෝ අසූ කෙළකි. බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ ඔවුන් සරණ ශීලයෙහි පිහිටවූ සේක.7. බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ ඒ කිරිපළු ගස ද මහාර්ග වූ ආසනයද නා රජුන්ට පූජා කරන්නට දුන් සේක.8. නාරජුනි, මගේ පාරිභෝගික චෛත්‍යයන්ට නමස්කාර කරව්. එය නාග රජුනි, ඔබට හිත සැප පිණිස වේ.9. මේ ආදී ක්‍ර‍මයෙන් ධර්ම දේශනා කොට ඔවුන් සමගි කරවා සමිද්ධි සුමන දෙවියන් කිරිපළු ගසක් සමග එහිම නවතා දෙව්රම් වෙහෙරටම ගිය සේක. ඉක්බිති නාගයෝ එහි සෑයක් හදා නිතර වඳිමින් පුදමින් වාසය කළාහු ය. ඉක්බිති බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ පිරිනිවන් පෑ කල්හි එහි මිනිස්සු සෑයක් කළාහුය. අද ද එය රාජායතන චෛත්‍ය නාමයෙන් ප්‍ර‍කට ය. මේ රාජායතන චෛත්‍යයාගේ උත්පත්තියයි.10. එක් කලෙක ලඞ්කාද්වීපයෙහි සැට නමක් පමණ භික්‍ෂූහු සමන්කුළු කැළණි ආදි මහා විහාරයන් වඳිමින් පුදමින් සැරිසරති. ඉක්බිති ඔවුහු නාගද්වීපයෙහි රාජායතන චෛත්‍යය වඳිනු කැමැතිව පිළිවෙලින් එහි ගොස් රාජායතන චෛත්‍යය වැඳ පුදා රැය පහන් වූ කල්හි උන්වහන්සේලා මනාව හැඳ පැළඳගෙන ගමට පිඬු පිණිස පිවිස මුළු ගමෙහම ඇවිද කිසිවක් නොලැබ සේදූ පාත්‍රයෙන්ම නික්මුණාය. එකල්හි එගමෙහි කහවණු සැටකට දාසියක වී එක ගෙදරක වාසය කරන්නා වූ නාගා නම් දැස්සක් කළයද රැගෙන දිය සඳහා යන්නී ගම්දොර ඒ භික්‍ෂූන් දැක ඔවුන්ගේ සමීපයට ගොස් වැඳ ආර්යවරුනි, භික්‍ෂාභාර ලැබුවාහුදැයි විචාළහ. උපාසිකාව තවම පෙර බත් කාලය යි කීවාහු ය. ඕ තොමෝ උන්වහන්සේලාට කිසිවක් නොලැබුණු බව දැනගෙන දොම්නස්ව කිනම් උපායකින් අද ආර්යන්ට දන් දෙම්දැයි සිතන්නී පෙර කහවණු හැට ණයට ගෙන පරකුලයක සේවය කරමි. දැන් මම රාත්‍රිකාල දාසියක්ව දන් දෙමියි සනිටුහන් කොට ගෙන භික්‍ෂූන් කරා පැමිණ උන්වහන්සේලාගේ ඉදිරිපස කළය තබා ස්වාමීනි, මේ කළය රන් පාදයක් වටී. මා එනතුරු මෙතැනින් ඉවත් නොවනු මැනවැයි කියා සක්මන් කොට ඒ ගෙදරටම ගොස් තවත් කහවණු සැටක් මට දෙන්නැයි කීවාය. හේ එය අසා පින්වතිය, තී පරකුලයෙහි දැස්සක්ව පරණ ණයෙන් නොමිදුණෙහි, එසේ වුවත් නැවතද වැඩියෙන් ධනය ගනී. මේ කිමෙක්ද? ධන ගැන නොසිතනු මැනව ස්වාමීනියි ඈ කීවාය. ඔබගේ ගෙදර රාත්‍රි සේවිකාවක්ව කර්මාන්ත කරමින් ණය ගෙවමි. කහවණු සැටක් මට දෙන්න. හේ යහපතැයි හසුනක් ලියා කහවණු දුන්නේය. ඉක්බිති ඇය එය රැගෙන මුළු මහත් ගමෙහි ම ඇවිද එක එක ගෙදරට එක එක කහවණුව බැගින් කහවණු හැටම දී බත් පිළියෙල කොට පාත්‍ර‍වලට බෙදා පිළිගන්නවා තමා විසින් කරන ලද වෑයම භික්‍ෂූන්ට මෙසේ කීවාය.11. ආර්යයන්ගේ ශ්‍රී පාදය වඳිමින් මෙය දන්වමි. එය හොඳින් ශ්‍ර‍වණය කරනු මැනවි. දුගී බවෙන් මා හා සම කෙනෙක් මේ මිහිපිට නොමැත.12. මම පළමු ණයට ගත් කහවණු ඇති නිසා ඉණ දාසියක් වීමි. පිස අනුභවයට සාල් නැළියක් වත් නොමැතිව භෝගයන් ගෙන් තොරව නෑයන් නැත්තියක්ව වසමි.13. අද දන් දුන්නී රාත්‍රි දාසී බවට පත්වීමෙනි. ආර්යවරු මවිසින් දෙන ලද දුප්පත් දානය වළඳත්වා!14. මේ ආදි ක්‍ර‍මයෙන් තමා විසින් කරන ලද සියල්ල කියා වැඳ කළයද රැගෙන ගියාය. භික්‍ෂූහු ඇගේ කථාව අසා අහෝ! පුදුමයි යන විස්මිත සිතින් බත් ගෙන මහානාම නම් විල සමීපයේ මුචලින්‍ද වනයට ඇතුල්ව සිටියාහු ය. ඉක්බිති ඔවුනතුරින් ප්‍ර‍ධාන භික්‍ෂූන් වහන්සේ ඇවැත්නි, යයි භික්‍ෂූන් අමතා ආයුෂ්මත්හු මැයගේ ශ්‍ර‍ද්ධාබීජයට කෙත ශුද්ධ කරත්වා! රාගීව හිඳ මේ දානය නොවළඳත්වායි කියා මෙසේ කීහ.15. එම්බා ඇවැත්නි, මෝ ස්ත්‍රීතොමෝ අපගේ මවක්, සොහොයුරියක්, නැන්දණියක්, යෙහෙළණියක්, නෑයෙක්, මිතුරියක් නොවන්නීය.16. මේ භික්‍ෂූහු ශීලවන්තයහ, ගුණවන්තයහ, මනාවූ ව්‍ර‍ත ඇත්තේයි. මොවුන් වහන්සේලාට දුන් සුළු දෙය තමාට ඵල ගෙන දේයයි.17. ඉතා දීනවූ දිළිඳු වූ ඕ තොමෝ අනුන්ගේ වැඩට තමා තමාම විකුණා අපට අද දන් දුන්නීය.18. ඒ උපාසිකාවට මහ ආනිසංස ඇතිවනු සඳහා ආත්මයන් පිරිසිදු කරමු. එයම කැමැත්තෙන් රාගීව, ආශ්‍ර‍වයන් දුරු නොකොට නොවළඳමු.19. මෙසේ කියා ඔවුහු මුචලින්‍ද වනයෙහි ඒ ඒ තැන හිඳිමින් විදසුන් වඩා සිවුපිළිසිඹියාපත් රහත් වූහ. ඉක්බිති උන්වහන්සේලා එම වනයෙහි දෙවියන් විසින් සාධුකාර පවත්වද්දී පැමිණ බත් අනුභව කළහ. ඉක්බිති ඇගේ ද භික්‍ෂූන් වහන්සේගේ ද ප්‍ර‍වෘත්තිය දැන දෙවියන්ගේ සාධුකාරය අසා රජුගේ සේසතෙහි අධිගෘහිත දෙව්දුව සතුටුව සාධුකාර දෙන්නී.20. මහා ශ්‍ර‍ද්ධා ඇති තැනැත්තිය, තී විසින් කරන ලද්දේ ඉතාම යහපත් ක්‍රියාවකි. දානය නමැති බීජය කෙත් වතට ගියේය. තිට යහපත් ලාභයක් විය.21. රජතුමා දෙව්දුවගේ සාධු නාදය අසා බොල දෙවතාවිය. කිමෙක් ද තී අපගේ දානය සඳහා ද සාධුකාර දුන්නීද, නැතහොත් කවර කෙනෙකුගේ දානයට සාධුකාර දුන්නී දැයි ඇසීය. තමුන්නාන්සේගේ දානය ගැන නොවේ. නාගාවගේ දන ගැනයි කීහ.22. යමෙක් සිඳුම් බිඳුම්වලින් පෙළා මහදන් පවත්වතියි ද, එවිට එය මහත් ඵල නොවෙයි.23. ආදරය පෙරදැරි නොකොට, ශ්‍ර‍ද්ධාවෙන් තොරව, නුවණින් නොසිතා කෙත් නොවන තැනකට යමෙක් දන්දේද එය මහත් ඵල නොවේ.24. දිළිඳු වූයේ නමුදු මහා ශ්‍ර‍ද්ධාවෙන් යුක්තවූයේ ආදර සහිතව පිරිසිදු සිතින් ඉතා සුලු දෙයක් හෝ දන් පිණිස දේද? එය හැම කල්හි අප්‍ර‍මාණ විපාක ගෙන දෙන්නේ ය.25. මේ ආදි විසින් මහත්ඵල බව වණා මහරජ, නාග දීපයෙහි නාගා නම් සැට කහවණුවක් ණයට ගත් ඉණ දාසියක වී භික්‍ෂූන්ට මෙසේ මෙසේ දන් දුන්නීය. භික්‍ෂූහු ද ඇගේ දානය නිසා රහත්වූහ. මම ඇයට සතුටුව සාධුකාර දුනිමියි සියල්ල විස්තර වශයෙන් කීයේය. රජතුමා එය අසා සතුටු වූයේ ණය දුන්නාට නියමයෙන් ණය දී ඇය දාසි බවෙන් මුදවා ඒ මුළු දිවයිනම උතුම් දායාද කොට ඇයට දී මහ සම්පත්ද දෙවීය. එතැන් පටන් ඒ දිවයින නාගදීපයයි ප්‍ර‍කට විය. ඇය එතැන් පටන් බොහෝ පින්කම් කොට දිවි කෙළවර දෙව්ලොව උපන්නීය.26. මෙසේ නුවණ ඇති ශ්‍ර‍ද්ධාවන්තයෝ තමන්ගේ ජීවිතය පවා අනුන්ට දාසකොට දී දන් පින් කොට මෙම ජාතියෙහි දිව්‍ය මනුෂ්‍යාදී බොහෝ දෙනාගේ ප්‍ර‍ශංසා ලැබ දිව්‍යලෝකයට යති. එනිසා දානය නම් කැමැති කැමැති දෑ දෙන කප් රුකක් සම ය. සත්‍වයන් විසින් මසුරු සතුරා විනාශ කොට දාන නැමැති මිත්‍ර‍යා භාජනය කරව්."},{"question":"\\" આનંદી કાગડો \\" વાર્તા લખો.","answer":"એક હતો કાગડો.કાગડો સ્વભાવે મોજીલો અને આનંદી. એને તો દરેક વાતમાં મજા આવે.એક વાર કોઈ કારણસર રાજા કાગડા પર ગુસ્સે થઈ ગયો. રાજાએ તો પોતાના માણસોને બોલાવી કહ્યું ; ‘જાઓ; આ કાગડાને ગામના કૂવાને કાંઠે ગારો છે તેમાં ફેંકી આવો.’ કાગડાને રાજાજીના હુકમ પ્રમાણે ગારામાં ફેંકી દેવામાં આવ્યો. કાગડાભાઈ તો ગારામાં પડ્યા પડ્યા આનંદથી ગાવા લાગ્યા :લપસણું કરતાં શીખીએ છીએ ભાઈલપસણું કરતાં શીખીએ છીએરાજા અને તેના માણસો નવાઈ પામ્યા કે લે આ કાગડો તો કેવો છે? ગારામાં આખા શરીરે કાદવ કીચડ ચોંટી જવા છતાં દુઃખી થવાને બદલે ખુશ કેમ થાય છે?રાજાને તો ક્રોધ ચડ્યો અને બીજો હુકમ કર્યો : ‘જાઓ; નાખો આ કાગડાને કૂવામાં. ભલે એ પાણીમાં ડૂબીને મરી જાય.’માણસોએ કાગડાને ઊંચકીને કૂવામાં ફેંકી દીધો. પણ કાગડાભાઈ તો કૂવામાં પડ્યા પડ્યા ગાવા લાગ્યા :કૂવામાં તરતાં શીખીએ છીએ ભાઈકુવામાં તરતાં શીખીએ છીએરાજા કહે : ‘હવે તો આ કાગડાને આથી વધારે શિક્ષા કરવી જોઈએ.’પછી તેણે તો કાગડાને કાંટાથી ભરેલાં એક પીંજરામાં નખાવી દીધો. પણ કાગડાભાઈ તો એના એ જ રહ્યા. વળી આનંદી સૂરમાં ગાવાનું શરૂ કર્યું :કૂંણા કાન વીંધાવીએ છીએ ભાઈકૂંણા કાન વીંધાવીએ છીએરાજા કહે : આ કાગડો તો ભાઈ ભારે જબરો છે! ગમે તે દુઃખમાં એને નાખો પણ તેને કોઈ દુઃખ થતું જ નથી. ચાલો એનાથી ઉલટું કરી જોઈએ. એને સુખ થાય એવા ઠેકાણે નાખીએ એટલે એ કદાચ દુઃખી થઈ જશે.પછી કાગડાભાઈને આંબાની ડાળે કોયલ ટહુકા કરતી હતી તેની બાજુમાં પાંજરે પૂરી મૂકાવ્યા. કાગડાભાઈને તો તે પણ સવળું પડ્યું. ખુશ થઈને ગાવા લાગ્યા :કોયલના ટહુકા સાંભળીએ છીએ ભાઈકોયલના ટહુકા સાંભળીએ છીએપછી તો રાજાએ તેને ખીર ખવડાવી જોઈ. કાગડો તો ગાય કેમીઠી ખીર ખાઈએ છીએ ભાઈમીઠી ખીર ખાઈએ છીએરાજાજીએ કાગડાને દુઃખી કરવા ઘણી કોશિશ કરી જોઈ પણ દુઃખી થાય તે બીજા. છેવટે થાકીને રાજાએ હુકમ કર્યો : ‘આ કાગડો કોઈ રીતે દુઃખી થાય તેમ લાગતું નથી. જાઓ, તેને છાપરા પર ફેંકી દો.’ છાપરાં પર બેઠા બેઠા કાગડાએ તો ગાયું કે :હવે અમે આઝાદ છીએ ભાઈહવે અમે આઝાદ છીએઅને કાગડો તો આનંદ કરતો કરતો ઊડીને પોતાના માળામાં પેશી ગયો. જેને દુઃખી ન થવું હોય તેને કોઈ પરાણે દુઃખી કરી શકે નહિ."},{"question":"धृतराष्ट्राची कन्या दुशाला हिचा विवाह कोणासोबत झाला होता?उत्तर -","answer":"जयद्रथ"},{"question":"அப்பா மற்றும் ஆசிரியரை வைத்து ஒரு கடி நகைச்சுவை சொல்லவும்.","answer":"அப்பா மற்றும் ஆசிரியரை வைத்து ஒரு கடி நகைச்சுவை:அப்பா: ஏன் ஐயா என் பையனை அடிச்சீங்க?ஆசிரியர்: ரெண்டு தண்டவாளம் இருக்கே எதுக்குன்னு கேட்டா, ஒண்ணு ஊருக்கு போக, இன்னொன்னு திரும்பி வரன்னு சொல்றான்ங்க."},{"question":"Isalin ang sumusunod na pahayag gamit lamang ang mga emoji:\\"Duwag ako sa aso, kaya tumakbo ako nang nakakita ako ng isa.\\"","answer":"🏃‍♂️🐕"},{"question":"ما هو عدد السور المدنية في القرآن؟\\t","answer":"عدد السور المدنية 29 سورة."},{"question":"చక్కని నీతులు చెప్పిన శతకకవుల గొప్పతనాన్ని వర్ణిస్తూ ఒక వ్యాసం రాయండి.","answer":"‘శతకం’ అంటే నూరు పద్యాల చిన్న గ్రంథం. శతక పద్యాలకు సామాన్యంగా చివర మకుటం ఉంటుంది. శతకాలలో సుమతీ శతకం, వేమన శతకం, భాస్కర శతకం, దాశరథీ శతకం, శ్రీకాళహస్తీశ్వర శతకం, కృష్ణ శతకం మొదలయిన శతకాలున్నాయి.శతకకవులు నీతిని, భక్తిని, వైరాగ్యాన్ని ప్రబోధిస్తూ గొప్ప శతకాలు రాశారు. వేమన శతకం, సుమతీ శతకాలలోని పద్యాలు రాని, తెలుగువాడుండడు. వేమన చెప్పిన “గంగిగోవుపాలు”, ‘ఉప్పు కప్పురంబు’, “తల్లిదండ్రి మీద దయలేని పుత్రుడు”, “నిక్కమైన మంచి నీలమొక్కటి చాలు” వంటి పద్యాలు, గొప్ప జ్ఞానాన్ని బోధిస్తాయి. ఇక సుమతీ శతకకారుడు బద్దెన చెప్పిన ‘కనకపు సింహాసనమున’, “తన కోపమె తన శత్రువు”, “ఎప్పుడు సంపద కలిగిన”, “వినదగు నెవ్వరు సెప్పిన” మొదలైన కంద పద్యాలు, జీవితం అంతా గుర్తుంచుకోదగినవి. కృష్ణ శతకం, దాశరథీ శతకం, శ్రీకాళహస్తీశ్వర శతకం భక్తిని ప్రబోధించి వైరాగ్యాన్ని కల్గిస్తాయి. శేషప్పకవి రచించిన నరసింహ శతకం కూడా భక్తినీ, నీతిని బోధిస్తుంది. కుమార కుమారీ శతకాలు బాలబాలికలకు చక్కని నీతులనూ, ధర్మాలనూ, కర్తవ్యాన్ని బోధిస్తాయి. ఏనుగు లక్ష్మణకవి భర్తృహరి సుభాషితాలను అనువదించి, మూడు గొప్ప శతకాలను తెలుగువారికి అందించాడు.మన తెలుగు శతకకర్తలు మన తెలుగువారికీ తెలుగుభాషకూ మహోన్నతమైన సేవచేసి ధన్యులయ్యారు."},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Carl Friedrich Gauss para a matemática?","answer":"Carl Friedrich Gauss, o \\"Príncipe dos Matemáticos\\", contribuiu para uma variedade de áreas, incluindo teoria dos números, geometria diferencial e estatística. Suas contribuições notáveis incluem o teorema fundamental da álgebra, a distribuição normal e a invenção do método dos mínimos quadrados na análise estatística."},{"question":"ऐतिहासिक काळात भारतावर पहिले आक्रमण कोणी केले ?","answer":"ऐतिहासिक काळात भारतावर पहिले आक्रमण राजा दारियसने केले."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca rasuulka NNKH hooyadii oo seddexan?","answer":"Waxa waaye Aamina Bintu Wahhaab Bin Cabdi Manaaf."},{"question":"sheeg bishii ayfurteen muslimiinta maka?","answer":"waa bisha ramadaan"},{"question":"Dandan ni ki Fayẹmi dupo aarẹ ni 2023 – APC Ekiti","answer":"Ẹgbẹ oṣelu All Progressives Congress (APC) tipinlẹ Ekiti ti ni dandan ni ki Gomina Kayọde Fayẹmi dupo aarẹ ilẹ Naijiria lọdun 2023, bi ko tilẹ wu u ko ṣe e.Alaga igbimọ fidi-hẹ ẹgbẹ naa, Ọnarebu Paul Ọmọtọṣọ, lo sọrọ yii niluu Ayede-Ekiti, nijọba ibilẹ Ọyẹ, lasiko ti oloye ẹgbẹ naa kan, Ọmọwe Oluṣẹgun Ọṣinkọlu, ṣayẹyẹ Keresi fun ẹgbẹrun kan ọmọ ẹgbẹ ọhun lẹkun idibo Ariwa Ekiti.Ọmọtọṣọ, ẹni ti Ọnarebu Ade Ajayi to jẹ Alukoro ẹgbẹ naa ṣoju fun, sọ pe bo tilẹ jẹ pe Fayẹmi ko ti i fifẹ han si ipo aarẹ, awọn yoo ri i daju o pe dupo naa dandan nitori iṣẹ nla to ti ṣe lagbo oṣelu.Ọmọtọṣọ ni, ‘‘Gbogbo ẹnu la le fi sọrọ pe APC ni yoo tun jawe olubori ninu ibo gomina ipinlẹ yii lọdun 2022, nitori awọn nnkan ribiribi ti Fayẹmi ti ṣe, a ko si fẹ ki ẹgbẹ rau-rau kan gbajọba ki wọn tun ba Ekiti jẹ.‘‘Lori ipo aarẹ ni 2023, asiko ti to ki aarẹ wa lati Ekiti. Idi niyi ta a fi n rọ gbogbo yin kẹ ẹ ṣatilẹyin fun Gomina Fayẹmi.‘‘Bo tilẹ jẹ pe Fayẹmi ko ti i sọ pe oun fẹẹ dupo, a maa wọ ọ sinu idije naa dandan ni nitori o kunju oṣuwọn, o ni ifarajin, bẹẹ lo jẹ oloootọ si APC.Bakan naa ni Ọmọtọṣọ gboriyin fun Ọsinkọlu to jẹ alaga ipolongo fun Buhari ati Oṣinbajo nipinlẹ Ekiti lasiko ibo ọdun 2019, ẹni to ni o duro ṣinṣin sinu ẹgbẹ, bo tilẹ jẹ pe igba meji lo padanu anfaani lati di sẹnetọ.Ninu ọrọ Ọṣinkọlu ti amugbalẹgbẹẹ ẹ, Ọgbẹni Ayọdeji Ọlọrunfẹmi, ṣoju fun, o bẹ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ naa lati sowọ pọ, ki wọn si ṣatilẹyin ti ko lẹgbẹ fun APC, eyi to pe ni ẹgbẹ gbogbo araalu."},{"question":"Iza no mpanjaka nitondra an'i Madagasikara ny taona 1810 hatramin'ny taona 1828?","answer":"I Radama I no mpanjaka an'i Madagasikara ny taona 1810 hatramin'ny taona 1828."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੪ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀਰਤਿ ਮਨਿ ਭਾਈ ਪਰਮ ਗਤਿ ਪਾਈ ਹਰਿ ਮਨਿ ਤਨਿ ਮੀਠ ਲਗਾਨ ਜੀਉ ॥ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਰਸੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਹਰਿ ਧਿਆਇਆ ਧੁਰਿ ਮਸਤਕਿ ਭਾਗ ਪੁਰਾਨ ਜੀਉ ॥ਧੁਰਿ ਮਸਤਕਿ ਭਾਗੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮਿ ਸੁਹਾਗੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੈ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਇਆ ॥ਮਸਤਕਿ ਮਣੀ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਬਹੁ ਪ੍ਰਗਟੀ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੈ ਹਰਿ ਸੋਹਾਇਆ ॥ਜੋਤੀ ਜੋਤਿ ਮਿਲੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਮਿਲਿ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਮਨੂਆ ਮਾਨ ਜੀਉ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀਰਤਿ ਮਨਿ ਭਾਈ ਪਰਮ ਗਤਿ ਪਾਈ ਹਰਿ ਮਨਿ ਤਨਿ ਮੀਠ ਲਗਾਨ ਜੀਉ ॥੧॥ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਜਸੁ ਗਾਇਆ ਪਰਮ ਪਦੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਤੇ ਊਤਮ ਜਨ ਪਰਧਾਨ ਜੀਉ ॥ਤਿਨੑ ਹਮ ਚਰਣ ਸਰੇਵਹ ਖਿਨੁ ਖਿਨੁ ਪਗ ਧੋਵਹ ਜਿਨ ਹਰਿ ਮੀਠ ਲਗਾਨ ਜੀਉ ॥ਹਰਿ ਮੀਠਾ ਲਾਇਆ ਪਰਮ ਸੁਖ ਪਾਇਆ ਮੁਖਿ ਭਾਗਾ ਰਤੀ ਚਾਰੇ ॥ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਹਰਿ ਗਾਇਆ ਹਰਿ ਹਾਰੁ ਉਰਿ ਪਾਇਆ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮਾ ਕੰਠਿ ਧਾਰੇ ॥ਸਭ ਏਕ ਦ੍ਰਿਸਟਿ ਸਮਤੁ ਕਰਿ ਦੇਖੈ ਸਭੁ ਆਤਮ ਰਾਮੁ ਪਛਾਨ ਜੀਉ ॥ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਜਸੁ ਗਾਇਆ ਪਰਮ ਪਦੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਤੇ ਊਤਮ ਜਨ ਪਰਧਾਨ ਜੀਉ ॥੨॥ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਮਨਿ ਭਾਈ ਹਰਿ ਰਸਨ ਰਸਾਈ ਵਿਚਿ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਹਰਿ ਰਸੁ ਹੋਇ ਜੀਉ ॥ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਆਰਾਧਿਆ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦਿ ਵਿਗਾਸਿਆ ਬੀਜਾ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਇ ਜੀਉ ॥ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਇ ਹਰਿ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਸੋਇ ਜਿਨਿ ਪੀਆ ਸੋ ਬਿਧਿ ਜਾਣੈ ॥ਧਨੁ ਧੰਨੁ ਗੁਰੂ ਪੂਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਲਗਿ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਪਛਾਣੈ ॥ਨਾਮੋ ਸੇਵਿ ਨਾਮੋ ਆਰਾਧੈ ਬਿਨੁ ਨਾਮੈ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਇ ਜੀਉ ॥ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਮਨਿ ਭਾਈ ਹਰਿ ਰਸਨ ਰਸਾਈ ਵਿਚਿ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਹਰਿ ਰਸੁ ਹੋਇ ਜੀਉ ॥੩॥ਹਰਿ ਦਇਆ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਧਾਰਹੁ ਪਾਖਣ ਹਮ ਤਾਰਹੁ ਕਢਿ ਲੇਵਹੁ ਸਬਦਿ ਸੁਭਾਇ ਜੀਉ ॥ਮੋਹ ਚੀਕੜਿ ਫਾਥੇ ਨਿਘਰਤ ਹਮ ਜਾਤੇ ਹਰਿ ਬਾਂਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪਕਰਾਇ ਜੀਉ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭਿ ਬਾਂਹ ਪਕਰਾਈ ਊਤਮ ਮਤਿ ਪਾਈ ਗੁਰ ਚਰਣੀ ਜਨੁ ਲਾਗਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪਿਆ ਆਰਾਧਿਆ ਮੁਖਿ ਮਸਤਕਿ ਭਾਗੁ ਸਭਾਗਾ ॥ਜਨ ਨਾਨਕ ਹਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਧਾਰੀ ਮਨਿ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਮੀਠਾ ਲਾਇ ਜੀਉ ॥ਹਰਿ ਦਇਆ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਧਾਰਹੁ ਪਾਖਣ ਹਮ ਤਾਰਹੁ ਕਢਿ ਲੇਵਹੁ ਸਬਦਿ ਸੁਭਾਇ ਜੀਉ ॥੪॥੫॥੧੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 446 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ) ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਪਿਆਰੀ ਲੱਗ ਗਈ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲਈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਲੱਗਣ ਲੱਗ ਪਿਆ । ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕੀਤਾ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸੁਆਦ ਚੱਖਿਆ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਉਤੇ ਧੁਰ ਦਰਗਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਲਿਖੇ ਹੋਏ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਭਾਗ ਜਾਗ ਪਏ । ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਉਤੇ ਧੁਰ ਦਰਗਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਲੇਖ ਉੱਘੜ ਪਿਆ, ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਖਸਮ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਲੱਭ ਲਿਆ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਹੀ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਉਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਦੀ ਮਣੀ ਚਮਕ ਉਠਦੀ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਜੋਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮਨ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਯਾਦ ਵਿਚ) ਗਿੱਝ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੱੁਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਪਿਆਰੀ ਲੱਗਣ ਲੱਗ ਪਈ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲਈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਲੱਗਣ ਲੱਗ ਪਿਆ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦਾ ਗੀਤ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਦਰਜਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਸ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਟ ਗਿਣੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਮਝੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ, ਅਸੀ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਅਸੀ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਪੈਰ ਧੋਂਦੇ ਹਾਂ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਲੱਗਾ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਿਆ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਉਤੇ ਚੰਗੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਮਣੀ ਚਮਕ ਪਈ ।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਹਾਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਂਭਦਾ ਹੈ ਆਪਣੇ ਗਲ ਵਿਚ ਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਸਾਰੀ ਲੁਕਾਈ ਨੂੰ ਇਕ (ਪਿਆਰ-) ਨਿਗਾਹ ਨਾਲ ਇਕੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਸਮਝ ਕੇ ਵੇਖਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਸਰਬ-ਵਿਆਪਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਪਛਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦਾ ਗੀਤ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਹ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਦਰਜਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਸ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਟ ਗਿਣੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਮਝੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਦੇ ਰਸ ਨਾਲ ਰਸੀ ਹੋਈ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆਰੀ ਲੱਗਦੀ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸੁਆਦ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੰੁਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜਿਉਂ ਜਿਉਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਆਰਾਧਦਾ ਹੈ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ (ਉਸ ਦਾ ਹਿਰਦਾ) ਖਿੜ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਤੇ ਭੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ । ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਤੇ ਭੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਜਲ ਪੀਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਇਹ ਨਾਮ-ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਪੀਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਦਸ਼ਾ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ (ਬਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ) ।ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਧੰਨਵਾਦ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਦਾ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਆਰਾਧਦਾ ਹੈ । ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਚੀਜ਼ ਪਿਆਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗਦੀ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਦੇ ਰਸ ਨਾਲ ਰਸੀ ਹੋਈ ਸਾਧ-ਸੰਗਤਿ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆਰੀ ਲੱਗਦੀ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸੁਆਦ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੰੁਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਹੇ ਹਰੀ! ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰ, ਸਾਨੂੰ ਕਠੋਰ-ਦਿਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘਾ ਲੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ ਸਾਨੂੰ (ਮੋਹ ਦੇ ਚਿੱਕੜ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਕੱਢ ਲੈ । ਹੇ ਹਰੀ! ਅਸੀ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ) ਮੋਹ ਦੇ ਚਿੱਕੜ ਵਿਚ ਫਸੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਾਂ, ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਲੋਂ ਅਸੀ ਡਿੱਗਦੇ ਜਾ ਰਹੇ ਹਾਂ, ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਸਾਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਬਾਂਹ ਫੜਾ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਬਾਂਹ ਫੜਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਟ ਮਤਿ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲਈ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਜਾ ਪਿਆ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਣ ਲੱਗ ਪਿਆ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਲੱਗ ਪਿਆ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਉਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਚੰਗਾ ਭਾਗ ਜਾਗ ਪਿਆ । ਹੇ ਦਾਸ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਆਖ—) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਮੇਹਰ ਕੀਤੀ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਲੱਗਣ ਲੱਗ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਹਰੀ! ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰ, ਸਾਨੂੰ ਕਠੋਰ-ਦਿਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘਾ ਲੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ, ਆਪਣੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ ਸਾਨੂੰ (ਮੋਹ ਦੇ ਚਿੱਕੜ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਕੱਢ ਲੈ ।੪।੫।੧੨।\\""},{"question":"Responde por favor la siguiente pregunta:¿Cuántas películas de Crepúsculo hay?","answer":"Hasta 2023 había un total de cinco películas de esta franquicia: Crepúsculo (2008), Luna Nueva (2009), Eclipse (2010), Amanecer - Parte 1 (2011) y Amanecer - Parte 2 (2012)."},{"question":"هل يمكنك توليد سؤال حول مسيرة الملح وإجابته 12 مارس عام 1930 بناءً على السياق التالي: كانت مسيرة الملح إحدى حملات اللا عنف احتجاجا على ضريبة الملح البريطانية في الهند البريطانية لتبدأ  مسيرة الملح إلى داندي  في 12 مارس عام 1930. كانت المسيرة أكبر تحد لسلطة الاحتلال البريطاني منذ حركة عدم التعاون والتي استمرت منذ 1920 حتى 1922، وإعلان الاستقلال من جانب المؤتمر الوطني الهندي في 31 ديسمبر 1929.","answer":"متى بدأت مسيرة الملح؟"},{"question":"Waa maxay lo ","answer":"Lo waxa wye xayawan lamasho hilibkisa la cuno "},{"question":" sheeg gobalka uu ku dhashay maxamed gacal xayow? ","answer":" Gobalka uu kudhashay maxamed gacal xayow gobalka banaadir. "},{"question":"No anime Pokémon, quem é Blue (ou Green, dependendo da versão)?","answer":"Blue (Green, no Japão) é outro protagonista dos jogos Pokémon e rival de Red. Ele é um treinador habilidoso e, dependendo da versão, desafia Red em sua jornada."},{"question":"Балага кандай сөздөрдү айтууга болбойт?","answer":"Мен сага токтот деп жатам!– Балага ушинтип айтууга болбойт. Эгер кыйкырып жиберген болсоңуз, кечирим сураңыз. Анткени бала өзүн эч нерсеге укуксуз сезип, таарынып калат. Ошол эле учурда басылуунун ордуна жаш балдар ыйлап, ого бетер чыргоолонуп, чоңоюп калгандары үн катпастан кетип калышат. Түнт боло башташат. Кыскасы, жогорудагы одоно сөз каалаган жыйынтыкка жетишиңизге түк жардам бербейт. "},{"question":" சாதாரண சளிக்கு காரணம்?","answer":"200 க்கும் மேற்பட்ட வைரஸ்கள் சளியை ஏற்படுத்தும், ஆனால் ரைனோவைரஸ்கள் மிகவும் பொதுவான வகை."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"_ no nanoratra ny tantara 'The Stranger'.\\"","answer":"Valiny: Albert Camus no nanoratra ny tantara 'The Stranger'."},{"question":"A seguinte frase faz sentido? \\"The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time é jogado no Nintendo GameCube\\". Opções: - Sim. - Não. Explique o processo de raciocínio passo a passo:","answer":"The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time foi desenvolvido para o Nintendo 64. Portanto, a resposta final é não."},{"question":"Escreva uma conversa entre duas crianças imaginando uma aventura espacial.","answer":"Criança 1: \\"Vamos viajar para as estrelas numa nave espacial!\\"Criança 2: \\"Sim! Vamos visitar planetas e encontrar alienígenas simpáticos.\\"Criança 1: \\"E teremos jetpacks para explorar a lua!\\"Criança 2: \\"Incrível! Vai ser épico!\\""},{"question":"Berikan penerangan ringkas untuk Universiti Teknologi MARA (UiTM) dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 120 perkataan. ","answer":"Universiti Teknologi MARA (UiTM) merupakan sebuah Universiti Awam di Malaysia yang berpusat di Shah Alam. Ditubuhkan pada tahun 1956 sebagai Dewan Latehan RIDA yang terletak di Petaling Jaya, UiTM membuka pintu kepada lebih kurang 50 pelajar dengan fokus untuk membantu orang Melayu di luar bandar. Sejak itu, UiTM sehingga kini telah berkembang menjadi Institusi Pendidikan Tinggi Terbesar di Malaysia dengan infrastruktur fizikal, organisasi kakitangan dan pelajar.Universiti ini terdiri daripada satu kampus utama, 13 kampus negeri berautonomi dan 35 kampus yang berada di seluruh Malaysia. Dengan 18,725 staf akademik dan bukan akademik, UiTM menawarkan 514 program dari peringkat asas sehingga peringkat pascasarjana. Pengajaran di UiTM dijalankan sepenuhnya dalam bahasa Inggeris."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਃ ੪ ॥ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਮਹਿ ਹਰਿ ਉਸਤਤਿ ਹੈ ਸੰਗਿ ਸਾਧੂ ਮਿਲੇ ਪਿਆਰਿਆ ॥ਓਇ ਪੁਰਖ ਪ੍ਰਾਣੀ ਧੰਨਿ ਜਨ ਹਹਿ ਉਪਦੇਸੁ ਕਰਹਿ ਪਰਉਪਕਾਰਿਆ ॥ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਦ੍ਰਿੜਾਵਹਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਸੁਣਾਵਹਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੇ ਜਗੁ ਨਿਸਤਾਰਿਆ ॥ਗੁਰ ਵੇਖਣ ਕਉ ਸਭੁ ਕੋਈ ਲੋਚੈ ਨਵ ਖੰਡ ਜਗਤਿ ਨਮਸਕਾਰਿਆ ॥ਤੁਧੁ ਆਪੇ ਆਪੁ ਰਖਿਆ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਵਿਚਿ ਗੁਰੁ ਆਪੇ ਤੁਧੁ ਸਵਾਰਿਆ ॥ਤੂ ਆਪੇ ਪੂਜਹਿ ਪੂਜ ਕਰਾਵਹਿ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਕਉ ਸਿਰਜਣਹਾਰਿਆ ॥ਕੋਈ ਵਿਛੁੜਿ ਜਾਇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸਹੁ ਤਿਸੁ ਕਾਲਾ ਮੁਹੁ ਜਮਿ ਮਾਰਿਆ ॥ਤਿਸੁ ਅਗੈ ਪਿਛੈ ਢੋਈ ਨਾਹੀ ਗੁਰਸਿਖੀ ਮਨਿ ਵੀਚਾਰਿਆ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੋ ਮਿਲੇ ਸੇਈ ਜਨ ਉਬਰੇ ਜਿਨ ਹਿਰਦੈ ਨਾਮੁ ਸਮਾਰਿਆ ॥ਜਨ ਨਾਨਕ ਕੇ ਗੁਰਸਿਖ ਪੁਤਹਹੁ ਹਰਿ ਜਪਿਅਹੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਿਸਤਾਰਿਆ ॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 311 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਸਤਸੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਓਥੇ) ਪਿਆਰੇ (ਗੁਰਸਿੱਖ, ਸੰਤ ਜਨ) ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਮੁਬਾਰਿਕ ਹਨ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਪਰਉਪਕਾਰ ਲਈ ਉਹ (ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭੀ) ਉਪਦੇਸ਼ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ,ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਸਿਦਕ ਬੰਨ੍ਹਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਸੁਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਤਾਰਦੇ ਹਨ, (ਇਹ ਸਾਰੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਵਡਭਾਗੀ ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਦੇ ਹਨ) ।(ਇਹ ਬਰਕਤਾਂ ਸੁਣ ਕੇ) ਹਰੇਕ ਜੀਵ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕਰਨ ਨੂੰ ਤਾਂਘਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਨਵਾਂ ਖੰਡਾਂ (ਦੇ ਜੀਵ) ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਸਿਰ ਨਿਵਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਆਪ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਵਿਚ ਲੁਕਾ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੈਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ ਤੇ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ) ਵਡਿਆਈ ਕਰਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਕੋਲੋਂ ਵਿੱਛੜ ਜਾਏ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮੂੰਹ ਕਾਲਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਜਮਰਾਜ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਰ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ, (ਭਾਵ, ਉਹ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਤਾਂ ਮੁਕਾਲਖ ਖੱਟਦਾ ਹੈ, ਦੂਜੇ ਮੌਤ ਆਦਿਕ ਦਾ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਸਹਿਮ ਪਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ) ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਨਾ ਇਸ ਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ ਤੇ ਨਾ ਹੀ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ ਕਿਤੇ ਭੀ ਆਸਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ—ਸਭ ਗੁਰਸਿੱਖਾਂ ਨੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਇਹ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ ।ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਜਾ ਮਿਲਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ (ਸੰਸਾਰ ਸਾਗਰ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਹ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਭਾਲਦੇ ਹਨ (ਇਸ ਲਈ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ) ਦਾਸ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇ ਸਿੱਖ ਪੁੱਤਰੋ! ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪੋ, (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਸੰਸਾਰ ਤੋਂ) ਪਾਰ ਉਤਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।\\""},{"question":"Apakah punca kematian Yasmin Ahmad?","answer":"Beliau jatuh pengsan akibat strok dalam satu perbentangan dengan Siti Nurhaliza dan suaminya Khalid Muhammad Jiwa untuk TV3. Beliau dihantar ke hospital dan doktor menjalankan pembedahan untuk menstabilkan keadaan beliau yang kritikal. Namun, beliau tidak sedarkan diri dan akhirnya meningkal dunia pada 25 Julai 2009."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Götschl har vunnit nio VM-medaljer varav tre guld. I komination 1997, störtlopp 1999","answer":"och i lagtävlingen 2007."},{"question":"Title: ప్రశాంత్ భూషణ్ కేసు: తీర్పుపై పునఃపరిశీలించాలని సీజేఐని కోరుతూ 122 మంది న్యాయ విద్యార్థుల బహిరంగ లేక","answer":"ప్రశాంత్ భూషణ్సుప్రీంకోర్టు ప్రధాన న్యాయమూర్తి, ఇతర మాజీ ప్రధాన న్యాయమూర్తులపై ట్విట్టర్‌లో వివాదాస్పద వ్యాఖ్యలు చేశారంటూ సీనియర్ న్యాయవాది ప్రశాంత్ భూషణ్‌పై ఉన్న కోర్టు ధిక్కరణ కేసులో తుది తీర్పును రేపు ప్రకటించనున్నారు. ఈ నేపథ్యంలో లాయర్ ప్రశాంత్ భూషణ్ దోషి కాదంటూ అనేకమంది ఆయనకు మద్దతు తెలుపుతున్నారు. దేశవ్యాప్తంగా 122 మంది న్యాయ విద్యార్థులు చీఫ్ జస్టిస్ బాబ్డేకు, ఇతర న్యాయమూర్తులకు భావోద్వేగపూరితమైన లేఖ రాశారు.\\"న్యాయవ్యవస్థ, ప్రజల విశ్వాసాన్ని పునరుద్ధరించడం ద్వారా విమర్శలకు బదులు చెప్పాలి. తన పనితీరును మెరుగుపరుచుకోవడం ద్వారా విమర్శలకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వాలి. అంతేగానీ న్యాయవ్యవస్థపై విశ్వాసంతో, ప్రేమతో, అందరికీ న్యాయం జరగాలనే సదుద్దేశంతో అదే వ్యవస్థకు చెందిన వ్యక్తి ప్రశ్నలు సంధించినప్పుడు దాన్ని కోర్టు ధిక్కరణగా తీర్పునివ్వరాదు\\" అంటూ ఆ లేఖలో పేర్కొన్నారు.\\"పాదర్శకత, జవాబుదారీతనం, పర్యావరణ పరిరక్షణ, మానవ హక్కులు, అవినీతిలాంటి అనేక అంశాలపై ఎన్నో ఏళ్లుగా లాయర్ ప్రశాంత్ భూషణ్ కోర్టులో పోరాడుతుండడం మేం చూశాం. దేశ నిర్మాణం, దేశ ప్రజల సౌభ్రాతృత్వాన్ని పెంపొందించడంలో ఆయన కృషిని న్యాయవాద బృందం ఎప్పుడూ గుర్తుంచుకుంటుంది.\\" ఆయన చేసిన రెండు ట్వీట్లు కూడా నోరు లేని, అట్టడుగు వర్గాల వేదనను ప్రతిబింబిస్తున్నాయని, అవి కోర్టు గౌరవాన్ని భంగపరిచేవిగా లేవని ఆ లేఖలో పేర్కొన్నారు.ఇంతకీ ఏమిటీ కేసు\\"గులాబీలు కాకుండా ముళ్లు గెలిచే చోట మౌనంగా ఉండడం అసాధ్యం. అలాంటి సందర్భాలలో న్యాయం కోసం పోరాటం చేయడం ఎంత అవసరమో నాకు అర్థమైంది\\" అని మాజీ న్యాయమూర్తి జస్టిస్ వీకే అయ్యర్ వ్యాఖ్యలను ఆ లేఖలో ఉదహరించారు.ప్రజాస్వామ్యంలో ఒక న్యాయమూర్తిని నిష్పాక్షికంగా విమర్శించడం నేరం కాదు సరి కదా ఒక అవసరమైన హక్కుగా గుర్తించాలి అంటూ లేఖలో పేర్కొన్నారు.రేపు సోమవారం ఈ కేసులో లాయర్ ప్రశాంత్ భూషణ్‌కు విధించబోయే శిక్ష వివరాలను జస్టిస్ అరుణ్ మిశ్రా నాయకత్వంలో ధర్మాసనం ప్రకటించనుంది.ఈ కేసు విషయంలో ప్రశాంత్ భూషణ్ క్షమాపణలు కోరితే శిక్ష తగ్గిస్తామని చెబుతూ తప్పు చేసినప్పుడు క్షమాపణలు కోరడంలో ఎలాంటి తప్పూ లేదు అని గతంలో జస్టిస్ అరుణ మిశ్రా తెలిపారు.ఈ కేసు విచారణలో ప్రశాంత్ భూషణ్ తరుపు న్యాయవాది రాజీవ ధావన్ తన వాదన వినిపిస్తూ..సీనియర్ లాయర్ ప్రశాంత్ భూషణ్‌కు న్యాయవ్యవస్థపై అపారమైన గౌరవం ఉందని, కానీ గత నలుగురు ప్రధాన న్యాయమూర్తుల విధానంపై అతనికి..."},{"question":"Apakah air ","answer":"Air Atas."},{"question":"Gece nasıl daha iyi fotoğraf çekilir?","answer":"Hareketsiz bir gece fotoğrafı çekeceksek ISO değerini en düşükte tutup (örnek; 50 – 80 veya 100) uzun pozlama yaparak temiz bir fotoğraf elde edebiliriz. Hareketli bir gece fotoğrafı çekeceksek en açık diyaframda ve yüksek ISO'lar da çalışmamız gerekir."},{"question":"وجدت هذا السؤال: متى عقدت الجمعية البرلمانية لمجلس أوروبا دورتها الأولى؟ في موقع ثقافي ، ماهي الإجابة؟","answer":"الإجابة على السؤال هي 1949."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ॥ਪਉਣੁ ਉਪਾਇ ਧਰੀ ਸਭ ਧਰਤੀ ਜਲ ਅਗਨੀ ਕਾ ਬੰਧੁ ਕੀਆ ॥ਅੰਧੁਲੈ ਦਹਸਿਰਿ ਮੂੰਡੁ ਕਟਾਇਆ ਰਾਵਣੁ ਮਾਰਿ ਕਿਆ ਵਡਾ ਭਇਆ ॥੧॥ਕਿਆ ਉਪਮਾ ਤੇਰੀ ਆਖੀ ਜਾਇ ॥ਤੂੰ ਸਰਬੇ ਪੂਰਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਜੀਅ ਉਪਾਇ ਜੁਗਤਿ ਹਥਿ ਕੀਨੀ ਕਾਲੀ ਨਥਿ ਕਿਆ ਵਡਾ ਭਇਆ ॥ਕਿਸੁ ਤੂੰ ਪੁਰਖੁ ਜੋਰੂ ਕਉਣ ਕਹੀਐ ਸਰਬ ਨਿਰੰਤਰਿ ਰਵਿ ਰਹਿਆ ॥੨॥ਨਾਲਿ ਕੁਟੰਬੁ ਸਾਥਿ ਵਰਦਾਤਾ ਬ੍ਰਹਮਾ ਭਾਲਣ ਸ੍ਰਿਸਟਿ ਗਇਆ ॥ਆਗੈ ਅੰਤੁ ਨ ਪਾਇਓ ਤਾ ਕਾ ਕੰਸੁ ਛੇਦਿ ਕਿਆ ਵਡਾ ਭਇਆ ॥੩॥ਰਤਨ ਉਪਾਇ ਧਰੇ ਖੀਰੁ ਮਥਿਆ ਹੋਰਿ ਭਖਲਾਏ ਜਿ ਅਸੀ ਕੀਆ ॥ਕਹੈ ਨਾਨਕੁ ਛਪੈ ਕਿਉ ਛਪਿਆ ਏਕੀ ਏਕੀ ਵੰਡਿ ਦੀਆ ॥੪॥੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 350 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ ਹਵਾ ਬਣਾਈ, ਸਾਰੀ ਧਰਤੀ ਸਾਜੀ, ਪਾਣੀ ਅੱਗ ਦਾ ਮੇਲ ਕੀਤਾ (ਭਾਵ, ਇਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਤੱਤ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਜਗਤ-ਰਚਨਾ ਕੀਤੀ ।ਰਚਨਹਾਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਇਕ ਅਸਚਰਜ ਲੀਲਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਤੋਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਵੱਡੀਆਂ ਤਾਕਤਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਭੁੱਲ ਕੇ ਨਿਰਾ ਰਾਵਣ ਦੇ ਮਾਰਨ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਸਮਝਣੀ ਭੁੱਲ ਹੈ) । ਅਕਲ ਦੇ ਅੰਨ੍ਹੇ ਰਾਵਣ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਮੌਤ (ਮੂਰਖਪਣ ਵਿਚ) ਸਹੇੜੀ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਨਿਰਾ ਉਸ ਮੂਰਖ) ਰਾਵਣ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਰ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਵੱਡਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ!) ਤੇਰੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਬਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ  ਤੂੰ ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਆਪਕ ਹੈਂ, ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੈਂ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ!) ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਸਭਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਜੀਵਨ-ਜੁਗਤ ਤੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਹੱਥ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਖੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ, (ਸਭ ਨੂੰ ਨੱਥਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ) ਨਿਰਾ ਕਾਲੀ-ਨਾਗ ਨੂੰ ਨੱਥ ਕੇ ਤੂੰ ਵੱਡਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ।ਨਾਹ ਤੂੰ ਕਿਸੇ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਦਾ ਖਸਮ ਹੈਂ, ਨਾਹ ਕੋਈ ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਤੇਰੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਹੈ, ਤੂੰ ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਇੱਕ-ਰਸ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੈਂ ।੨।(ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਜੇਹੜਾ) ਬ੍ਰਹਮਾ ਕੌਲ ਦੀ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਜੰਮਿਆ ਸੀ, ਵਿਸ਼ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਹਮਾਇਤੀ ਸੀ, ਉਹ ਬ੍ਰਹਮਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਕੁਦਰਤ ਦਾ ਅੰਤ ਲੱਭਣ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਗਿਆ, (ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਭਟਕਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ) ਪਰ ਅੰਤ ਨ ਲੱਭ ਸਕਿਆ । (ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਕੁਦਰਤ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈ) ਨਿਰਾ ਕੰਸ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਰ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਕਿਤਨਾ ਕੁ ਵੱਡਾ ਬਣ ਗਿਆ? (ਇਹ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਸਾਧਾਰਨ ਜਿਹੀ ਗੱਲ ਹੈ) ।੩।(ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਦੇਵਤਿਆਂ ਤੇ ਦੈਂਤਾਂ ਨੇ ਰਲ ਕੇ) ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਰਿੜਕਿਆ ਤੇ (ਉਸ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਚੌਦਾਂ ਰਤਨ ਕੱਢੇ, (ਵੰਡਣ ਵੇਲੇ ਉਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਧੜੇ) ਗੁੱਸੇ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਆ ਕੇ ਆਖਣ ਲੱਗੇ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਰਤਨ ਅਸਾਂ ਕੱਢੇ ਹਨ ਅਸਾਂ ਕੱਢੇ ਹਨ (ਆਪਣੇ ਵਲੋਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਬਿਆਨ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ ਮੋਹਣੀ ਅਵਤਾਰ ਧਾਰ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਰਤਨ) ਇਕ ਇਕ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਵੰਡ ਦਿੱਤੇ, (ਪਰ) ਨਾਨਕ ਆਖਦਾ ਹੈ (ਕਿ ਨਿਰੇ ਇਹ ਰਤਨ ਵੰਡਣ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਕੇਹੜੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਬਣ ਗਈ, ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਵਡਿਆਈਆਂ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਰਚੀ ਕੁਦਰਤਿ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਥਾਂ ਥਾਂ ਦਿੱਸ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ) ਉਹ ਭਾਵੇਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਕੁਦਰਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਲੁਕਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਲੁਕਿਆ ਰਹਿ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ (ਪ੍ਰਤੱਖ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਕੁਦਰਤਿ ਦੱਸ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਬਹੁਤ ਤਾਕਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈ) ।੪।੭।\\""},{"question":"දසය යන්නෙන් කුමන ඉලක්කමක් හැදින්වේද?","answer":" දසය = 10"},{"question":"Olóri Ẹbi, Baba Bùkátà","answer":"Olóri Ẹbi jẹ àkọ́bi ọkùnrin ni idilé.  Bi àkọ́bi bá kú, ọkùnrin ti ó bá tẹ̀le yio bọ si ipò.  Iṣẹ́ olóri ẹbi ni lati kó ẹbi jọ fún ilọsiwájú ẹbi, nipa pi pari ijà, ijoko àgbà ni ibi igbéyàwó, ìsìnkú, pi pin ogún, ìsọmọ-lórúkọ, ọdún ìbílẹ̀ àti ayẹyẹ yoku.Ni ayé òde òni, wọn ti fi owó dipò ipò àgbà, nitori ki wọn tó pe olóri ẹbi ti ó wà ni ìtòsí, wọn yio pe ẹni ti ó ni owó ninú ẹbi ti ó wà ni òkèrè pàtàki ti ó bá wà ni Èkó àti àwọn ilú nla miran tàbi Ilú-Òyinbó/Òkè-Òkun. Ai ṣe ojúṣe Ìjọba nipa ipèsè ilé-iwòsàn ti ó péye, Ilé-iwé, omi mimu àti ohun amáyédẹrùn yoku jẹ ki iṣẹ́ pọ fún olóri ẹbi.Gẹ́gẹ́ bi ọ̀rọ̀ Yorùbá ti ó sọ wi pé “Olóri Ẹbi, Baba Bùkátà”, iṣẹ́ nla ni lati jẹ Olóri Ẹbi, ó gba ọgbọ́n, òye àti ìnáwó lati kó ẹbi jọ."},{"question":"１９６８年の「白い鮫のいる島」でデビューした、本名を井上優美子という漫画家で、代表作にそばかすなんて気にしない「キャンディキャンディ」があるのは誰でしょう？","answer":"いがらしゆみこ"},{"question":"ശനിയാഴ്ചയ്ക്ക് ശേഷം ഏത് ദിവസമാണ് വരുന്നത്?","answer":"ശനിയാഴ്ച കഴിഞ്ഞാൽ ഞായറാഴ്ചയാണ്"},{"question":"لدينا السؤال التالي: ما إسم آخر غزوة قادها الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم ؟ ، أجب عليه بطريقة مختصرة.","answer":"حسناً، الإجابة هي غزوة تبوك."},{"question":" Sheeg dagaalkii Khandaq magaca kale ee loo yaqaanno?.","answer":"Dagaalka Khandaq magaca kale ee loo-yaqaanno waa Axzaab."},{"question":"Gịnị bụ emumme Lagos Black Heritage?","answer":"Lagos Black Heritage Festival (LBHF) bụ emume a na-eme kwa afọ na Legọs nke gụnyekwara emume Lagos Carnival. Emumme a bụ mmemme omenala na akụkọ ihe mere eme nke ezubere iji gosipụta ịba ụba na ụdị dị iche iche nke ihe nketa Africa. LBHF na-eji mmemme dị iche iche eme mmemme dị ka egwu ọdịnala na nke oge a, ihe nkiri, egwu, eserese, na ngosi foto n'etiti ndị ọzọ"},{"question":"料理のときに使う計量スプーンで、大さじ１杯といったら通常何ccでしょう？","answer":"15cc"},{"question":"ਵਾਰਾਂ ਭਾਈ ਗੁਰਦਾਸ : ਵਾਰ ੧ ਪਉੜੀ ੧੫ ਪੰ. ੧ਜੁਗਾਂ ਬਾਬਤ ਪ੍ਰਚਲਿਤ ਖਯਾਲਜੁਗਿ ਜੁਗਿ ਮੇਰੁ ਸਰੀਰ ਕਾ ਬਾਸਨਾ ਬਧਾ ਆਵੇ ਜਾਵੈ।ਫਿਰਿ ਫਿਰਿ ਫੇਰਿ ਵਟਾਈਐ ਗਿਆਨੀ ਹੋਇ ਮਰਮੁ ਕਉ ਪਾਵੈ।ਸਤਿਜੁਗ ਦੂਜਾ ਭਰਮੁ ਕਰਿ ਤ੍ਰੇਤੇ ਵਿਚਿ ਜੋਨੀ ਫਿਰ ਆਵੈ।ਤ੍ਰੇਤੇ ਕਰਮਾ ਬਾਂਧਤੇ ਦੁਆਪਰਿ ਫਿਰਿ ਅਵਤਾਰ ਕਰਾਵੈ।ਦੁਆਪਰਿ ਮਮਤਾ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਹਉਮੈ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਗਰਬਿ ਗਲਾਵੈ।ਤ੍ਰਿਹੁ ਜੁਗਾ ਕੇ ਕਰਮ ਕਰਿ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਸੰਸਾ ਨ ਚੁਕਾਵੈ।ਫਿਰਿ ਕਲਿਜੁਗ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਦੇਹਿ ਧਰਿ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਫੇਰ ਫਸਾਵੈ।ਅਉਸਰੁ ਚੁਕਾ ਹਥ ਨ ਆਵੈ ॥੧੫॥","answer":"ਆਦਿ ਕਾਲ ਤੋਂ, ਅਪੂਰਣ ਇੱਛਾਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਬੰਧਨ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ, ਜੀਵ ਆਵਾਗਵਣ ਭੋਗਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਵਾਰ-ਵਾਰ, ਸਰੀਰ ਬਦਲਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਇਸ ਤਬਦੀਲੀ ਦਾ ਭੇਤ ਗਿਆਨਵਾਨ ਬਣ ਕੇ ਸਮਝਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ।ਸਤਿਯੁਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਵੈਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੀਨ ਹੋ ਕੇ, ਜੀਵ ਨੇ ਤ੍ਰੇਤਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਵੇਸ਼ ਕੀਤਾ।ਤ੍ਰੇਤੇ ਵਿਚ ਕਰਮ-ਬੰਧਨ ਵਿਚ ਫਸ ਜਾਣਾਉਹ ਦਵਾਪਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਰਗੜਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ।ਤਿੰਨਾਂ ਜੁਗਾਂ ਦੇ ਕਰਤੱਵ ਦੀ ਪਾਲਣਾ ਕਰਨ ਨਾਲ ਵੀ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦਾ ਡਰ ਦੂਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ।ਜੀਵ ਕਲਿਯੁਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੁਨਰ ਜਨਮ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਲਝ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਗੁਆਚਿਆ ਮੌਕਾ ਮੁੜ ਕੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦਾ।"},{"question":"miatanisa   kitan'ny baolina kitra brezilianina ?","answer":"i Ronaldinho,Ronaldo  dia anisan'ny kitan'ny baolina kitra brezilianina"},{"question":"Коомдук унааларда өзүн-өзү алып жүрүү эрежелери... ","answer":"Коомдук унаада башка бирөөлөр жол кире төлөбөй же бирөөгө орун бербей же отура албай талашып- тартышып кетишсе, ага кийгилишпей эле койгонуңуз дурус. Мында, өзүңүздүн ички терс сапатыңызды көрсөтүп алышыңыз ыктымал."},{"question":"தேன் + நீர் = ?பனி + பாறை = ?பூ + மாலை = ?இடி + ஆப்பம் = ?","answer":"தேநீர்பனிப்பாறைபூமாலைஇடியாப்பம்"},{"question":"De qual categoria é essa pergunta: Quem dirigiu o primeiro filme baseado na série de livros do Jogos Vorazes?.","answer":"Livros"},{"question":"Allwell Adémọ́lá","answer":"Allwell Adémọ́lá tí wọ́n bí ní Ọjọ́ Ọjọ́ Kẹ̀sán-án oṣù kẹjọ ọdún 1983 jẹ́ gbajúmọ̀ òṣèrébìnrin, olùdarí, oǹkọ̀tàn, akọrin àti olóòtú sinimá àgbéléwò ọmọ bíbí ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn lórílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó jẹ́ ọmọ-ọmọbìnrin adájọ́-àgbà jùlọ àkọ́kọ́ ní Nàìjíríà, Adájọ́-Àgbà, Olóògbé Adétòkunbọ̀ Adémọ́láÓ kàwé gbàwé ẹ̀rí ní ifáfitì ìjọba àpapọ̀ tó gúnwà sí Ilé-Ifẹ̀, OAU. Allwell bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ sinimá àgbéléwò láti èwe ṣùgbọ́n ní ọdún 2008 ni ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní gbajúmọ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí òṣèré sinimá àgbéléwò. Láti ìgbà náà, ó ti kópa nínú ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ sinimá àgbéléwò, lára àwọn sinimá-àgbéléwò tó gbé ìràwọ̀ rẹ̀ síta ni; Láródó Ọjọ́, Etí kẹta, Ọmọ Ẹ̀mí, You. Or I, Ayé Kejì."},{"question":"\\"தமிழ் பல்கலைக்கழகம்\\" எங்கு  அமைந்துள்ளது?A. கோயம்புத்தூர்B. சென்னைC. தஞ்சாவூர்D. மதுரை","answer":"தமிழ்ப் பல்கலைக்கழகம் என்பது தஞ்சாவூரில் உள்ள தமிழ்நாட்டுப் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களுள் ஒன்றாகும். இது 1981, செப்டம்பர் 15ஆம் நாள் உருவாக்கப்பட்டது. தஞ்சாவூரில் தஞ்சாவூர்-திருச்சிராப்பள்ளி சாலையில் 972.7 ஏக்கர் நிலப்பரப்பில் இப்பல்கலைக்கழகம் அமைந்துள்ளது. தமிழ் மொழி, தமிழர் பண்பாடு போன்றவற்றின் முதன்மையான உயர் ஆய்வை நோக்கமாகக் கொண்டது இப்பல்கலைக்கழகம்.தமிழ்ப் பல்கலைக்கழகம் தஞ்சைக்கு வந்த கதை:தமிழ்ப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் வரலாற்றில் மதுரையில் நடந்த உலகத் தமிழ் மாநாடு, அப்போதைய முதல்வர் எம்ஜிஆரின் முன்னெடுப்பு, முதல் துணைவேந்தரான வ.அய்.சுப்பிரமணியத்தின் தொலைநோக்கு ஆகியவற்றுடன் அன்றைய மன்னார்குடி சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர் மு.அம்பிகாபதி சட்டமன்றத்தில் விடுத்த கோரிக்கையும் நினைவுகூரப்பட வேண்டியது. இது ஏன் இப்போது நினைவுகூரப்பட வேண்டியதாகிறது என்றால், சமீபத்தில் காலமாகிவிட்ட அம்பிகாபதி, மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகளில் உள்ளூர் ஆளுமைகளுக்கான உதாரணர்களில் ஒருவர். ஒரு பெரிய பொதுக் காரியம் நடக்க பெரிய மக்கள் தலைவர்கள், ஆட்சியைக் கையில் வைத்திருப்பவர்கள் மட்டும் அல்ல; உள்ளூர் மக்கள் பிரதிநிதிகளும்கூட எப்படிப் பங்காற்றுகிறார்கள் என்பது அவர் வழியே பேசப்பட வேண்டியதாகிறது.மதுரையில் 1901-ல் தொடங்கப்பட்ட தமிழ்ச் சங்கத்தையடுத்து தஞ்சையிலும் ஒரு தமிழ்ச் சங்கம் தொடங்கப்பட்டது. ஆனால், அது தொடர்ந்து செயல்படவில்லை. அதை ஈடுசெய்யும்விதமாக, நீதிக் கட்சித் தலைவர்களில் ஒருவரான தமிழவேள் உமாமகேசுவரனார் 1911-ல் கரந்தை தமிழ்ச் சங்கத்தைத் தொடங்கினார். 1922-ல் தமிழுக்கென்று தனிப் பல்கலைக்கழகம் வேண்டும் என்று கோரிக்கையையும் அவர் விடுத்தார். சைவ சமாஜங்களைத் தொடங்குவதற்கு அவரைத் துணைக்கு அழைத்துக்கொண்ட தமிழறிஞர்கள், இந்த விஷயத்தில் ஆர்வம் காட்டவில்லை. அவரைச் சமாதானப்படுத்தி அந்தக் கோரிக்கையைக் கைவிடவும் நிர்ப்பந்தித்தனர்.தனித்தமிழ் இயக்கத்தின் மூலவர் யார், உற்சவர் யார் என்று இன்றும் தொடரும் விவாதங்களில் தேரோடுவதற்கு வடம்பிடித்த தமிழவேளையும் கரந்தைக் கவியரசையும் நாட்டாரையும் யாருமே பேசுவதில்லை என்பது வியப்பிற்குரியதல்ல. தஞ்சையில் இருபதுகளில் உமாமகேசுவரனார் முன்னெடுத்த தமிழ்ப் பல்கலைக்கழகக் கோரிக்கை எண்பதுகளில்தான் நிறைவேறுகிறது. இந்திய கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சியின் சார்பில் அன்றைய ஒருங்கிணைந்த தஞ்சை மாவட்டத்தில் மன்னார்குடி சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினராக இருந்த மு.அம்பிகாபதியால் அந்த அரை நூற்றாண்டுக் கனவு நனவானது. 1981 நிதிநிலை அறிக்கையில், தமிழ்ப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்துக்கான அறிவிப்பு வெளியிடப்பட்டது. அதன் மீது நடந்த விவாதத்தில், சோவியத் பயணத்தின்போது தான் கண்ட ரஷ்ய மொழிக்கான சிறப்புப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் செயல்பாடுகளைச் சட்டமன்றத்தில் விளக்கிப் பேசினார் அம்பிகாபதி. தமிழறிஞர் வ.சுப.மாணிக்கம் தலைமையில் வல்லுநர் குழு அமைக்கவும் காரணமாக இருந்தார். சங்கம் வளர்த்த மதுரையில் தமிழ்ப் பல்கலைக்கழகம் அமைக்கலாம் என்று விவாதிக்கப்பட்டபோது, அங்கு ஏற்கெனவே காமராஜரின் பெயரில் பல்கலைக்கழகம் இருப்பதைச் சுட்டிக்காட்டிய அம்பிகாபதி, கம்பன் பிறந்த சோழ நாட்டிலேயே பல்கலைக்கழகம் அமைக்க வேண்டும் என்று உறுதியாக நின்று அதில் வெற்றியும்பெற்றார். தமிழுக்கான உயராய்வு மையம் என்ற வ.அய்.சுப்பிரமணியத்தின் கனவு இன்று உயர் நீதிமன்றப் படியேறிக்கொண்டிருக்கிறது என்பது தனியாய் விவரிக்கப்பட வேண்டிய துயரக் கதை.ஒரு சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர் தான் சார்ந்த தொகுதியின் பிரச்சினைகளுக்காகச் சட்டமன்றத்தில் குரல் கொடுப்பவர் என்பதைத் தாண்டி மாநிலத்தின் முக்கியப் பிரச்சினைகளிலும் அவரால் எவ்வாறெல்லாம் பங்காற்ற முடியும் என்பதற்கு ஜூலை 17-ல் மரணமடைந்த மன்னை மு.அம்பிகாபதி ஒரு சிறந்த உதாரணர். திராவிட இயக்கத்திலிருந்து தனது அரசியல் பயணத்தைத் தொடங்கியதால் இயல்பாகவே கலை இலக்கியச் செயல்பாடுகளில் அவருக்குத் தீவிர ஈடுபாடு இருந்தது. பொதுவுடைமை இயக்கத்தில் இணைந்து பணியாற்றிய அவர் ப.ஜீவானந்தத்தின் வழியைப் பின்தொடர்ந்தவர். கம்பன், இளங்கோ, பாரதி ஆகியோரை ஆர்வத்துடன் பயின்று மக்களிடம் அவர்களைக் கொண்டுசேர்த்தார். விவசாயிகள் சங்கச் செயல்பாடுகளுக்கு நடுவே மன்னை கம்பன் கழகத்தின் தலைவராகவும் அவர் பொறுப்புவகித்தார்.தமிழ்நாட்டில் மிதிவண்டியில் இருவர் செல்ல அனுமதி இல்லாத காலமும் ஒன்று இருந்தது; மீறிச் சென்றால் வழியில் போலீஸார் பிடித்து அபராதம் விதிப்பார்கள். அம்பிகாபதிதான் சட்டமன்றத்தில் இதை விவாதம் ஆக்கி முடிவுக்குக் கொண்டுவந்தார். விசேஷம் அதுவல்ல; மிதிவண்டியில் இருவர் செல்ல கம்பனைத் துணைக்கு அழைத்தார் அம்பிகாபதி. தொழிலாளர் நலனை முன்னிறுத்தி அவர் பல்வேறு கோரிக்கைகளை முன்வைத்திருக்கிறார். ‘கல்கி’, ‘சுதேசமித்திரன்’ பத்திரிகை அலுவலகங்களில் நடந்த தொழிலாளர் நலப் பிரச்சினைகளையும்கூட சட்டமன்றத்தில் கவனப்படுத்தியிருக்கிறார். அண்ணாவின் ஆட்சிக் காலத்தில் எதிர்க்கட்சித் தலைவராக இருந்த பி.ஜி.கருத்திருமனின் மறைவுக்கு இரங்கல் உரையாற்றியபோது கருத்திருமனின் கம்பராமாயண ஈடுபாட்டைச் சொல்லி, கம்பன் வரிகளை மேற்கோள் காட்டியிருக்கிறார். வழக்கறிஞர்களின் உண்ணாவிரதப் போராட்டத்தைப் பற்றி பேசியபோது ‘தேரா மன்னா’ எனத் தொடங்கும் சிலம்பின் வரிகளைச் சொல்லி இடித்துரைக்கவும் செய்திருக்கிறார்.மு.அம்பிகாபதியின் சட்டமன்ற உரைகளில் ஒரு பகுதி மட்டும் நூலாக வெளிவந்திருக்கிறது. இலக்கிய மேற்கோள்களால் மட்டும் இந்த சட்டமன்ற உரைகள் முக்கியத்துவம் பெறவில்லை. உள்ளாட்சியில் பெண்களுக்கான இடஒதுக்கீடு, 500 குடும்ப அட்டைகளுக்கு ஒரு பொது விநியோகக் கடை, சிறைச்சாலைச் சீர்திருத்தம், சட்டமன்ற நிகழ்ச்சிகளின் நேரடி ஒளிபரப்பு, மாநில சுயாட்சி, படித்த இளைஞர்களுக்கு வேலையில்லாக் கால நிவாரணம், சீரான மின்கட்டணம் என்று அம்பிகாபதியின் உரைகள் இப்போதும் பொருத்தமாக இருக்கின்றன. மிக முக்கியமாக அந்நாட்களில் அரசியலர்கள் உள்ளூர் அளவில் தங்களை நிலைநிறுத்திக்கொண்டாலும் வாசிப்புக்கு எவ்வளவு முக்கியத்துவம் அளித்திருக்கிறார்கள் என்பதை இந்த உரைகள் சொல்கின்றன. ‘ஆங்கிலத்தில் மட்டும் ‘தி இந்து’ வந்துகொண்டிருந்த காலம் போய் தமிழிலும் வரத் தொடங்கியது ஒரு வாசகனாக எனக்குக் கிடைத்த பெரிய சந்தோஷம்’ என்று ஒரு விழாவில் சொன்ன அம்பிகாபதி, காலையில் நடுப்பக்கக் கட்டுரைகளைப் படித்துவிட்டு சென்னையிலுள்ள நல்லகண்ணு தொடங்கி குமரியிலுள்ள கொடிக்கால் ஷேக் அப்துல்லா வரையிலான தன் காலத்துக்கு அரசியலர்களுடன் விவாதிப்பதை ஒரு வழக்கமாகக் கொண்டிருந்தவர். கடைசி நாட்கள் வரை வாசிப்பதை நிறுத்தவில்லை அவர். ‘அரசியலர்கள் எப்போதும் மாணவர்கள்தான்; வாழ்நாள் முழுவதும் அவர்கள் படித்துக்கொண்டே இருக்க வேண்டும்’ என்று சொல்வாராம் அம்பிகாபதி. எழுத்தின் மீதான இந்த மதிப்பும், நேசமும்தான் தமிழ்ப் பல்கலைக்கழக வரலாற்றுக்கு ஒரு சிறு பங்கை தானும் அளிப்பதற்கான உத்வேகத்தை அவருக்கு அளித்திருக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Wat voor belangrijke gebeurtenis beschrijft de volgende tekst: Het gematigde klimaat van de stad maakte dat het een populaire vakantiebestemming was voor Franse kolonisten in Algerije. De Fransen hebben veel in de stad geïnvesteerd en gaven haar een mondainere sfeer. Anders dan Algiers was de stad weinig betrokken bij de onafhankelijkheidsstrijd halverwege de jaren 1950.","answer":"Het gaat over Tlemcen tijdens de onafhankelijkheidsstrijd. Waar ze niet veel aan deelnamen."},{"question":"هات اجابة للسؤال ده: \\"عندما تحب المرأة\\" هى أول أغنية منفردة للمغني آر. كيلي من ألبوم الاستوديو الحداشر و اللى كان بعنوان أيه؟","answer":"الاجابة هى: كان بعنوان \\"رسالة حب\\"."},{"question":"Iza no tany efitra mafana indrindra eran-tany?","answer":"Ny Sahara no efitra mafana indrindra eran-tany."},{"question":"برای بیان ویژگی‌های مواد از چه عباراتی استفاده می‌شود؟","answer":"از عبارت ها و واژه هایی مانند سخت یا نرم، چکش خوار یا شکننده، انعطاف‌پذیر یا انعطاف ناپذیر ، جاذب آب یا ضد آب، شفاف یا کدر، دارای خاصیت آهن ربایی یا بدون خاصیت آهن ربایی و ... استفاده می‌شود."},{"question":"Papara hesabı silinirse ne olur?","answer":"Papara hesap silme işlemiZira Papara Card'larınız Papara hesabınıza bağlı olduğundan, hesabınızı kapatmanız durumunda tüm Papara Card'larınız da iptal edilir. Öte yandan hesabınızı kapatmadan önce tüm bakiyeni çekmeniz, harcamanız ya da başka bir hesaba göndermeniz, kısacası bakiyenizi sıfırladığınız gerekiyor."},{"question":"Izwi ripi rechiGerman rinoreva hondo yemheni yakashandiswa muWW2?","answer":"Izwi rechiGerman rekuti \\"Blitzkrieg\\" rinonyatso tsanangura kukurumidza-kukurumidza uye kurongeka kwemauto zano rakashandiswa muHondo Yenyika II. Zvaisanganisira kurwiswa nekukurumidza uye kwakakura kuti tikunde nekukurumidza."},{"question":"'దయగల గుండె గలవారే ఆశకు దూరమౌతారు' దీని మీద అభిప్రాయం ఏమిటి? వివరించండి.","answer":"కొంతమందికి దయగల గుండె ఉంటుంది. వారు ప్రక్క వారికి కష్టం వస్తే, చూచి సహించలేరు. అవసరమైతే ప్రక్కవారి కోసం వారు తమ ప్రాణాలైన ఇవ్వడానికి సిద్ధమౌతారు. వారికి వారి ప్రాణాల మీద కూడా ఆశ ఉండదు. ఇతరులకు అవసరమయితే తమ రక్తాన్ని, అవయవాలను సైతం దానం చేస్తారు. తమ మూత్రపిండాల్నీ, నేత్రాలనూ దానం చేస్తారు. దయాహృదయం లేనివారు దానం చేయలేరు."},{"question":"Ada seorang buta, dia jalan-jalan tiba-tiba ada lubang depan dia, dia boleh elak, kenapa dia boleh elak?","answer":"Sebab buta sebelah"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Tháng 7, thị trường xe hơi Việt Nam chào đón hai mẫu SUV 7 chỗ mới Ford Everest, Isuzu mu-X. Cặp xe sang nhà Audi là A8L và xe điện e-tron GT. Range Rover thế hệ mới diện kiến các đại gia Việt. Cặp đôi nhà Nissan là mẫu bán tải Navara và sedan Almera. Ford Everest thế hệ mới Mẫu SUV chủ bài của hãng xe Mỹ ra mắt khách Việt với 4 phiên bản, giá từ 1,099-1,452 tỷ đồng. Ở thế hệ mới, Everest tăng giá từ 40-52 triệu so với thế hệ cũ. Mẫu SUV 7 chỗ thiết kế mới từ trong ra ngoài, thêm công nghệ. Ngoại hình nam tính hơn thế hệ cũ. Nội thất phong cách mới ở bảng điều khiển trung tâm và táp-lô. Everest cạnh tranh với những đối thủ như Toyota Fortuner, Mitsubishi Pajero Sport. Audi ra mắt A8L mới A8L phiên bản mới nhập khẩu Đức ra mắt ngày 9/7. Mẫu sedan cao cấp nhất của Audi bán ra 3 phiên bản, gồm Classic 5 chỗ (bản tiêu chuẩn) giá dưới 6 tỷ đồng, và hai bản cao cấp hơn là Plus 5 chỗ và Premium 4 chỗ giá trên 6 tỷ đồng. A8L cạnh tranh với những đối thủ như Mercedes S-class và BMW series 7. Nissan Navara động cơ mới Navara 2022 thay đổi động cơ 2.5 hút khí tự nhiên bằng động cơ tăng áp kép 2.3 và đạt chuẩn khí thải Euro 5. Động cơ mới lắp cho hai bản cao nhất, gồm Navara 4WD giá 945 triệu đồng và Navara Pro4X gía 970 triệu đồng, cả hai đều dẫn động 2 cầu. Mức giá này tăng lần lượt 50 và 25 triệu so với trước. Trong khi các bản một cầu chưa có hàng và hãng chưa thông tin về những nâng cấp mới. Hai bản hiện hành Navara một cầu tiêu chuẩn và cao cấp giá lần lượt 748 triệu và 845 triệu đồng. Sau bản nâng cấp của mẫu bán tải Nissan, phân khúc này sắp có sự xuất hiện của Isuzu D-Max 2022 chuẩn khí thải Euro5 và Ford Ranger thế hệ mới. Audi ra mắt e-tron GT quattro.","answer":"Mẫu xe điện thể thao đầu tiên của Audi chào thị trường Việt Nam. e-tron GT quattro nhập Đức, giá từ 5,2 triệu đồng, cạnh tranh với đối thủ đồng hương Porsche Taycan. Mẫu xe điện thể thao của Audi bán ra hai phiên bản, gồm quattro và RS. Đối thủ Taycan có 7 lựa chọn phiên bản, giá từ 4,7-9,5 tỷ đồng. Nissan giới thiệu Almera 2022 Almera phiên bản mới nâng cấp động cơ, bổ sung tính năng như điều hòa nóng, đèn pha tự động và ghế da trên bản cao nhất. Mẫu sedan của Nissan nhập khẩu Thái Lan và bán ra hai phiên bản, CVT tiêu chuẩn giá 539 triệu và CVT cao cấp giá 595 triệu đồng. Giá tăng nhẹ so với bản cũ. Ngoài bản CVT, Almera còn có bản số sàn MT giá 469 triệu đồng. Almera thuộc phân khúc sedan cỡ B, nơi có những cái tên đáng gờm như Toyota Vios, Hyundai Accent hay Honda City. Isuzu mu-X mới ra mắt Mẫu SUV 7 chỗ nhà Isuzu nhập khẩu Thái Lan. Xe thiết kế mới mong tăng thêm sức cạnh tranh với các đối thủ đáng gờm, như Toyota Fortuner, Mitsubishi Pajero Sport, Ford Everest. mu-X bán ra với 4 phiên bản, trong đó 3 bản như thế hệ tiền nhiệm: B7 4x2 MT, B7 Plus 4x2 AT, Prestige 4x2 AT. Riêng bản mu-X Premium 4x4 AT cao cấp nhất lần đầu tiên xuất hiện. Giá từ 900 triệu đến 1,19 tỷ đồng. Ranger Rover 2022 chào thị trường Việt Nam Range Rover thế hệ mới thay đổi với thiết kế \\"phẳng\\" hơn. Xe ngập tràn các công nghệ đi kèm và nội thất cao cấp đi cùng giá bán hàng chục tỷ đồng. Xe bán ra với 4 phiên bản, gồm SWB P360 Autobiography giá từ 11,19 tỷ đồng, LWB P360 Autobiography từ 11,389 tỷ đồng, LWB P360 Autobiography (7 chỗ) từ 11,409 tỷ đồng, LWB P530 SV từ 23,859 tỷ đồng. Với tầm giá từ 11,2 tỷ đồng, Range Rover cạnh tranh với Mercedes-Maybach GLS từ 12,5 tỷ đồng. Còn phiên bản Range Rover SV từ hơn 23 tỷ đồng là một lựa chọn khác bên cạnh Bentley Bentayga, từ 19,5 tỷ đồng. Minh Vũ"},{"question":"జస్, జంగేరి పదవృత్తాంతాలను వివరించండి.","answer":"కొంతమంది రాజనీతిజ్ఞుల ప్రకారం ‘చట్టం’ అనే పదం లాటిన్ భాషలోని ‘జస్’, ‘జంగేరి’ అనే రెండు పదాల నుండి ఉద్భవించింది. లాటిన్ భాషలో ఈ రెండు పదాలకు ‘బంధం’ అనే అర్థం ఉంది. సాధారణంగా చట్టం అనేది రాజకీయ సార్వభౌమాధికారిచే వ్యక్తుల బాహ్య ప్రవర్తనను నియంత్రించేందుకై రూపొందించబడిన నియమావళి అని పేర్కొనవచ్చు."},{"question":"Inona ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Mifampihantsy\\"?","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Mifampihantsy\\" dia \\"Mifandrangitra\\"."},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:પોતાનાં વખાણ પોતે જ કરવાં તે ","answer":"આત્મશ્લાઘા "},{"question":"Talaabada labaad ee loo baahan yahay.","answer":"waa in la raacanidaamka daaweynta xaaladda aad ka u daran eenafaqodarada (TFP) sida hoos ku xusa ."},{"question":"问题：冰块的用途有哪些？","answer":"回答：冰块常用于降低温度、制冷食物和饮料，以及在冷敷时使用。"},{"question":"Iru ki waa leleyii, ileetura ni Teslim wa tawọn adigunjale fi yinbọn pa a n’Ibadan","answer":"Awọn adigunjale tun da kun ipenija eto aabo ti ipinlẹ Ọyọ n koju lọwọ bayii pẹlu bi wọn ṣe yinbọn pa ọkunrin alafẹ igboro Ibadan kan to n jẹ Teslim Akinpẹlu.Ileetura kan ti wọn n pe ni Town Hotel, laduugbo Iyaganku, n’Ibadan, lawọn adigunjale ẹlẹni mẹrin ọhun ti fibọn ja awọn eeyan lole owo ati dukia wọn mi-in lọjọ Àbámẹ́ta, Satide, to kọja.Otẹẹli yìí ni Teslim atawọn ọrẹ ẹ ti lọọ ṣe faaji to fi ba iku ojiji pade ni nnkan bíi aago mẹwaa alẹ ọjọ naa.Awọn adigunjale yii ti n fi otẹẹli ọhún silẹ ki Teslim toun naa fẹẹ kuro nileetu náà lati maa pada sile ẹ ni nnkan bíi aago mẹwaa alẹ too pade wọn. Gẹgẹ b’ALAROYE ṣe gbọ, ọkunrin alafẹ yii ko mọ pe awọn adigunjale náà ṣì wa nitosi. Nibi to ti n ba ẹnikan sọrọ lọwọ lori ẹrọ ibanisọrọ lawọn jagunlabi ti yinbọn fun un.Agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ CSP Olugbenga Fadeyi, fidi ẹ mulẹ pe. O ni, “Awọn òṣìkà eeyan yii dibọn bíi ẹni to fẹẹ gba yara ninu iteetura naa titi ti wọn fi wọle sí awọn alejo to gba yara nileetura naa lara ni.O ni yara ti wọn n ṣe oku lọ́jọ̀ sí nileewosan kan nigboro Ibadan ni wọn gbe oloogbe naa lọ ko too di pe wọn sinkú ẹ̀ nilana Musulumi."},{"question":"ముగ్గురు పిల్లల ఒంటరి తల్లి మైనా.. ఈ కఠినమైన పనులను చేస్తున్నారు. ఆమె పనులే కాదు.. ఆమె జీవితం కూడా చాలా కఠినంగా ఉంది. భర్త చనిపోయాక మైనా ఈ వృత్తిలోకి వచ్చారు.తన తండ్రి వద్ద నేర్చుకున్న పనే ప్రస్తుతం ఆమెకు జీవనాధారం అయ్యింది. ఈ వృత్తిలో ఆమె ఎన్నో సవాళ్లు ఎదుర్కొన్నారు. ఎన్నో అవహేళనలను చవిచూశారు.మహిళలకు ఏ పనీ కష్టం కాదని ఆమె విశ్వాసం. జీవితంలో కష్టాలకు ఎదురొడ్డి పోరాడుతున్నారు. ఆమె జీవన పోరాటం ఆమె మాటల్లోనే...‘మహిళలకు ఏదీ కష్టం కాదు..’మా నాన్న ఈ పని చేసేవారు. అలా నేను కూడా టైర్లు రిపేరు చేయడం నేర్చుకున్నాను. పెళ్లయ్యాక అత్తగారింటికి వెళ్లాను. నాకు ముగ్గురు ఆడపిల్లలు పుట్టారు. నా భర్త చనిపోయినపుడు నేను గర్భవతిని.ఈ పనిలో.. దాదాపు 30 ఏళ్లు గడిచిపోయాయి. టైర్లు రిపేరు చేస్తాను, వాటికి గ్రీజ్ రాస్తాను. ఈమధ్యనే కార్ల సర్వీస్ సెంటర్ కూడా ప్రారంభించాను. ఈ పని చేస్తూ, కార్ వాష్ కూడా చేస్తాను.నా భర్త చనిపోయినపుడు పిల్లలు చాలా చిన్నవాళ్లు. ఒకరికి ఐదేళ్లు, మరొకరికి నాలుగేళ్లు, చిన్నదానికి మూడేళ్లు. నా తోడబుట్టినవాళ్లు కూడా చిన్నవారే. అందర్నీ నేనే చదివించాను. ఒకవైపు ఈ పని చేస్తూ, మరోవైపు గరిష్ఠంగా మరో 4000 అక్షరాలతో కథనాన్ని కొనసాగించండి:","answer":"వాళ్ల బాగోగులన్నీ చూశాను. నా ఆరోగ్యం దెబ్బతింది. జీవితంలో ఎన్నో సమస్యలు ఎదుర్కొన్నాను.అప్పట్లో ఇది వన్ వే రోడ్డు. ఒకేఒక షాపు ఉండేది. చుట్టూ ఈ మార్కెట్ ఉండేది కాదు. పగలు, రాత్రి తేడా లేకుండా, పని చేసేదాన్ని. పని చేసేటపుడు ప్యాంట్, షర్ట్ వేసుకుంటాను.మొదట్లో మా అమ్మతో కలిసి ఉండేదాన్ని. ఆమెతో గొడవలయ్యాయి. నా పిల్లలను తీసుకుని బయటకు వచ్చేసి, ఇక్కడే ఇల్లు ఏర్పాటుచేసుకున్నా. తినడానికి ఏమీలేక, చాలా సార్లు అటుకులు తినేదాన్ని.నా పిల్లల్ని మాత్రమే తీసుకుని, కట్టుబట్టలతో బయటకు వచ్చేసి, కొన్ని బోర్డులతో ఇల్లు కట్టుకున్నాను.చుట్టుపక్కలవాళ్లకు నన్ను చూస్తే కుళ్లు. 'ఒక స్త్రీ ఇంత సంపాదిస్తోందా..? టైర్లు రిపేరు చేస్తుంది, గ్రీజింగ్ కూడా చేస్తుంది, ఈ పనులన్నీ మాకు రావే..' అని వారి బాధ.ఒక స్త్రీ సంపాదిస్తుంటే చుట్టూ ఉన్నవారు ఓర్వలేరు. ఆమె ఎదుగుదలకు అడ్డుపడుతూ ఎన్నో అవమానాలకు గురి చేస్తారు. 'అరే.. ఓ మహిళ అయ్యుండీ ఎంతో కష్టపడుతోంది.. కనీసం సాయం చేద్దాం' అనుకోరు. ఈ పని చాలా కష్టం. వెన్నెముక దగ్గర నొప్పి పుడుతుంది. అయినా రోజంతా పని చేస్తూనే ఉంటాను. నొప్పి మరీ ఎక్కువుంటే కాసేపు పడుకుంటాను. మళ్లీ లేచి పని చేస్తా.మా షాపుకు వచ్చేవాళ్లలో 80 శాతం మంది మంచివాళ్లుంటే, 20 శాతం మంది చెడ్డవాళ్లుంటారు. అలాంటివారిని వెంటనే వెళ్లిపోమని చెబుతాను. వారిని తరమడానికి ఒక్కోసారి తిట్టడం, చేతలతో బెదిరించడం చేస్తుంటాను.టైరు రిపేరు చేసినందుకు వంద రూపాయలు తీసుకుంటాను. పది టైర్లు వస్తే, రోజుకు వెయ్యి రూపాయలు వస్తుంది. ఈ కాలంలో ఆ సంపాదన ఏపాటిది?"},{"question":"Mitovy hevitra ve ireto fehezanteny roa manaraka ireto?1 . \\"Nianatra nandritra ny alina izy ka nahomby tamin'ny fanadinana izy.\\"2. \\"Taorian'ny fianarana ora maro tamin'ny fiharetan-tory dia nahomby izy tamin'ny fanadinany\\"","answer":"Eny, mitovy hevitra ny fehezanteny roa."},{"question":"Lengkapi kalimat berikut:  Murad II menandatangani suatu perjanjian selama sepuluh tahun dan turun takhta untuk mendukung putranya Mehmed II. Ketika perdamaian rusak tahun berikutnya, Murad kembali ke Balkan dan memenangkan","answer":"Pertempuran Varna pada bulan November 1444."},{"question":"次の段落にマッチするタイトルをつけてください： 今月6日、兵庫県豊岡市の海岸の近くで、いつもは深い海で生活している大きなダイオウイカがいるのが見つかりました。体の長さが2.5mぐらいあって、長い足をゆっくり動かして泳いでいました。ダイビングの仕事をしている夫婦が海に入って、ダイオウイカをビデオに撮りました。30分ぐらいして、イカは離れていきました。妻は「一緒に泳いで撮りました。触ることができるぐらい近くにダイオウイカがいて感動しましたが、目がとても大きくて怖かったです」と話しました。専門家は「生まれて1年から2年ぐらいの大人のダイオウイカだと思います。泳いでいるところを撮るのは珍しいです」と話しています。","answer":"兵庫県の海　ダイオウイカと一緒に泳いでビデオに撮った"},{"question":"Write a continuation for this paragraph - বাংলাদেশের স্বাধীনতা","answer":"১৯৭১ খ্রিষ্টাব্দের ২৫ মার্চ সেনাবাহিনীর আক্রমণের পর পাকিস্তানের দুই অংশের মধ্যে সমস্যা নিষ্পত্তির সর্বশেষ প্রচেষ্টাও ব্যর্থ হয়ে যায়। সেই রাতে শুরু হওয়া গণহত্যার প্রেক্ষিতে শেখ মুজিবুর রহমান ২৬ মার্চ প্রথম প্রহরে প্রচারিত এক বেতার ভাষণে আনুষ্ঠানিকভাবে বাংলাদেশের স্বাধীনতা ঘোষণা করেন।"},{"question":"\\"ඕං බලහං මේ ඇබිංදං එකීගෙ මූණත් පිපිහළු වෙලා\\"\\"පිපිහළු වෙලා\\" යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"පිපිහළුව යනු පැරැන්නන් මන්දපෝෂණ තත්වයට හැදින්වූ නමකි.පණු අමාරු එකල බහුලව පැවති අතර ඉන් ඇතිවන තත්වය පිපිහළුවයි.ඊට ප්‍රතිකාර ලෙස ඇහැල දලු මැල්ලුම එකල ආහාරයට ගත් අතර ඉන් බඩ විරේකයක් ලැබේ"},{"question":"Ułóż pytanie do następującej odpowiedzi. Obwód Ziemii wynosi 40 075 km.","answer":"Oto pytanie do powyższej odpowiedzi. \\"Jaki jest obwód Ziemii?\\""},{"question":"Кыргызстандын белгилүү 👨‍⚕️ хирург Мамбет Мамакеев эне жөнүндө айткан сөзү кайсы?","answer":"Мамбет Мамакеев эне жөнүндө айткан сөздөрү мындай.\\"Мен 95 жашта болсомда апамды күндө эстеймин. Кыйынчылык же кубаныч ийгилик болсо мени аркамда энем колдоп турат.Эне сүтүнөн кутулайын деп жакшы аракет жасадым. Үй салып бердим, мал жандык алып бердим кийим кече. Бирок өзүм карыздар сеземин. Аткара албагандай сеземин\\"."},{"question":"问题：三星手机的电池寿命如何？","answer":"答案：三星手机的电池寿命取决于具体型号和使用情况，采用节能技术以延长续航时间。"},{"question":"Sentence 1: Tide ndiro dambarefu rechitanhatu raDeodato, rakabudiswa muna 1970 paA & M Records uye rakarongedzwa naAntônio Carlos Jobim. Sentence 2: Tide ndiro dambarefu rechitanhatu raAntônio Carlos Jobim, rakaburitswa paA'M Records muna 1970 uye rakarongedzwa naDeodato. Mubvunzo: Mutsara wokutanga nomutsara wechipiri unoreva chinhu chimwe chete here? Hungu kana kuti Aiwa?","answer":"Aiwa"},{"question":"රේඩියෝ සිලෝන් ප්‍රචාරණ වේදිකාවක් බවට පත් වූයේ කෙසේද?","answer":"රේඩියෝ සිලෝන් ප්‍රධාන වෙළඳනාම සඳහා ජිංගල් පටිගත කර ඒවා සමස්ත ආසියානු සේවයේ විකාශනය කරමින් බලවත් වෙළඳ ප්‍රචාරණ වේදිකාවක් බවට පත් විය. Lux සබන් සිට Coca-Cola දක්වා කැපී පෙනෙන සන්නාමයන් රේඩියෝ සිලෝන් විසින් විකාශනය කරන ලදී."},{"question":"من أكثر الأنبياء ذكراً بالقرآن ؟","answer":"الإجابة: موسى عليه السلام وذكر 236 مرة"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਹਭੇ ਥੋਕ ਵਿਸਾਰਿ ਹਿਕੋ ਖਿਆਲੁ ਕਰਿ ॥ਝੂਠਾ ਲਾਹਿ ਗੁਮਾਨੁ ਮਨੁ ਤਨੁ ਅਰਪਿ ਧਰਿ ॥੧॥ਆਠ ਪਹਰ ਸਾਲਾਹਿ ਸਿਰਜਨਹਾਰ ਤੂੰ ॥ਜੀਵਾਂ ਤੇਰੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਹੁ ਮੂੰ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸੋਈ ਕੰਮੁ ਕਮਾਇ ਜਿਤੁ ਮੁਖੁ ਉਜਲਾ ॥ਸੋਈ ਲਗੈ ਸਚਿ ਜਿਸੁ ਤੂੰ ਦੇਹਿ ਅਲਾ ॥੨॥ਜੋ ਨ ਢਹੰਦੋ ਮੂਲਿ ਸੋ ਘਰੁ ਰਾਸਿ ਕਰਿ ॥ਹਿਕੋ ਚਿਤਿ ਵਸਾਇ ਕਦੇ ਨ ਜਾਇ ਮਰਿ ॥੩॥ਤਿਨੑਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਰਾਮੁ ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਭਾਣਿਆ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦਿ ਅਕਥੁ ਨਾਨਕਿ ਵਖਾਣਿਆ ॥੪॥੫॥੧੦੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 397 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਸਾਰੇ (ਸੰਸਾਰਕ) ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ (ਦਾ ਮੋਹ) ਭੁਲਾ ਕੇ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਇਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਧਿਆਨ ਧਰ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੀਆਂ ਮਲਕੀਅਤਾਂ ਦਾ) ਝੂਠਾ ਮਾਣ (ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਦੇ, ਆਪਣਾ ਮਨ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਅੱਗੇ) ਭੇਟਾ ਕਰ ਦੇ, ਆਪਣਾ ਹਿਰਦਾ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਭੇਟਾ ਕਰ ਦੇ ।੧।ਹੇ ਸਿਰਜਣਹਾਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਅੱਠੇ ਪਹਰ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕੇ (ਤੇਰੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰ ਕੇ) ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੰੁਦਾ ਹੈ ਮੇਰੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰ ਮੈਨੂੰ (ਤੇਰੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ) ਦਾਤਿ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਏ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਉਹੀ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਿਆ ਕਰ ਜਿਸ ਕੰਮ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਲੋਕ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ) ਤੇਰਾ ਮੂੰਹ ਰੋਸ਼ਨ ਰਹੇ । (ਪਰ,) ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੇਰੇ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜੁੜਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਇਹ ਦਾਤਿ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ ।੨।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! (ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੀ ਉਸਾਰੀ ਵਾਲੇ) ਉਸ (ਹਿਰਦੇ-) ਘਰ ਨੂੰ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਬਣਾ ਜੋ ਫਿਰ ਕਦੇ ਭੀ ਢਹਿ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ।  ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਇਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਿੱਤ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾਈ ਰੱਖ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਕਦੇ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਰਦਾ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਚੰਗੇ ਲੱਗ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਲੱਗਣ ਲੱਗ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ(ਪਰ, ਇਹ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮੇਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ), ਨਾਨਕ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਾਲਕ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਨੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ।੪।੫।੧੦੭।\\""},{"question":"කරත්ත කවියක් සඳහා උදාහරණය​ක් දෙන්න.","answer":"කරත්ත කවියක් සඳහා උදාහරණය​ක් පහත දැක්වේ.දුප්පත් කමට ගොන් බැඳගෙන දක්කනවාකන්නත් නැතුව රෑ දාවල් වෙහෙසෙනවාගොන්ඩත් නොයෙක් වද දී-ලා ගෙනියනවාදැන්පත් දුකට දෙවියෝ පිහිටක් වෙනවා"},{"question":"“Spam ve ity mailaka ity?\\"“Nisy simba ny kaontinao! Kitiho eto mba hahazoana antoka izany.”","answer":"Eny, spam ity mailaka ity. Na dia toa matotra aza ilay hafatra, dia mampiasa tetika fampitahorana hamitahana ny mpampiasa amin'ny fitsidihana rohy tsy azo antoka."},{"question":"Nitori jibiti miliọnu rẹpẹtẹ ti wọn lu, ogoji ọdun ni tọkọ-tiyawo yii yoo lo lewọn","answer":"Ẹwọn ogoji ọdún nile-ẹjọ sọ tọkọ-tiyawo kan, Ẹbiesuwa Abayọmi Frederick ati iyawo iyawo ẹ, Tinuọla Idayat Oyeginlẹ, sí nitori iwa jibiti wọn.Onídàájọ Joyce Abdulmalik ti ile-ẹjọ gíga ijọba apapọ to wa ni Ring Road, n’Ibadan, lo gbe idajọ ọ̀hún kalẹ lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii.Àjọ to n gbogun ti jibiti owo ati iwa magomago nilẹ yii, ìyẹn Economic and Financial Crimes Commission, EFCC, ẹkun Ibadan, lo gbe wọn lọ sí kootu fún ẹsun jibiti owo nla, wọn ni wọn lu obinrin oniṣowo kan to n jẹ Dunni Ọlatẹru-Ọlagbẹgi ni jibiti owo to le ni mílíọ̀nù mẹtalelaaadọta Naira (N53,713,260).ALAROYE gbọ pe ọgbọn ẹtan lawọn tọkọ-tiyawo yii fi lu iya oniyaa ni jibiti, wọn lo nilo owo nla lati gba ẹ̀mí ẹ̀ là lọwọ iku ojiji ni, owo ọ̀hùn lawọn yóò sì fi ra awọn eroja lati ré iku ojiji to n rọ dìrọ̀dìrọ̀ lori ẹ̀ danu.Gẹgẹ bí Ọgbẹni Wilson Uwujaren ti i ṣe Alukoro ajọ EFCC se sọ ninu atẹjade to fi ṣọwọ́ sawọn oniroyin n’Ibadan, ninu oṣù karun-un ọdún 2013 lAbilekọ Dunni kọ pade awọn onijibiti naa ninu ọkọ tasin to wọ̀ nigboro Ibadan.Ohun ti wọn fi wọle sí i lara lọrọ nipa owo dọ́là rẹpẹtẹ kan ti wọn sọ pe ọkan ninu awọn gbé sí ẹyin buutu ọkọ̀ naa, awọn sí nilo alagbara to le ba oògùn ara owo naa jẹ nitori owo ọ̀hún kò tí ì ṣe é ná pẹlu bo ṣe jẹ pe awọn ẹ̀mí òkùnkùn pọ ninu ẹ̀ dọ́ba.Eyi to mu aba wa ninu wọn pe oun ni agbara ti yóò mu awọn ẹmi okunkun kuro lara owo, naa lo ríran èké sí Abilékọ Dunni, pe iku n rọ̀ dẹ̀dẹ̀ lori ẹ̀, bi ko ba sì fẹẹ ku, afi ko wa owo nla wa lati fi gbẹ̀mí ẹ̀ là.Ni gbogbo asiko yii, mílíọ̀nù mẹsan-an lowo ti Dunni ni nileefowopamọ, gbogbo ẹ̀ lo fi ranṣẹ sí Idayat ti i ṣe obinrin ninu àwọn onijibiti naa.Síbẹ̀síbẹ̀, wọn kò fi iya yii lọrun silẹ, afigba to ta gbogbo eyi to nilaari ninu awọn dukia ẹ̀, tó sì kó gbogbo owo to pa lori wọn fún àwọn onijibiti wọnyi. Ìyẹn ni gbogbo owo to padanu sọwọ wọn fi lè láàádọ́ta mílíọ̀nù Naira.Nigba ti ko sí dukia kankan fún ìyá oníṣòwò yii lójú ẹ̀ ṣẹṣẹ waa la pe jibiti lọkọ atiyawo naa lù oun. N lo ba mu ẹjọ awọn abatẹnijẹ tọ àjọ EFCC n’Ibadan lọ.Ẹsun mẹrin ọtọọtọ lajọ EFCC fi kan wọn ni kootu. Kò sì sí èyí tí wọn mórí bọ́ ninu awọn esun naa láì jẹ̀bi. Iṣiro ẹwọn ọdun mẹwaa nile-ẹjó fi ijiya ẹsun kọọkan ṣe. Ìyẹn lo ṣe jẹ pe sẹria ẹwọn ogoji (40) ọdún ladajọ da fún ẹni kọọkan wọn.Ìyẹn nikan kọ, ileetura kan to n jẹ Victoria East Park Hotel and Suit ni Fredrick fi owo jibiti ọ̀hún kọ sigboro Ibadan, Onídàájọ Abdulmalik si ti pàṣẹ pé kí wọn lu ileetura ọhún ta ni gbanjo, ki wọn da owo to fọgbón jibiti gba lọwọ Abilékọ Dunni pada fún ùn. Eyi to ba ṣẹ́kù ninu ẹ, ki wọn san an sinu aṣunwọn ijọba apapọ orileede yii."},{"question":"බංග්ලාදේශයේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"බංග්ලාදේශයේ අගනුවර ඩකා ය."},{"question":"Talaabada 2-aad:","answer":"Waydii in ay jirto ama ilmaha lagu arkayHadii ay jirto xaalad xun oo lagu arkayilamaha .Heerkulka jirka ilmaha ama neefsigailmahaMiisaanka ilmaha, wareega cabirkagacanta ilmaha iyo bararKuna samey ilmaha tijaabada cuntaqaadashada. Talaabada sadexaad:Waa in aad qaadaa tilaabo ( ficil) adiga o kusaleenaya wixii aad aragtay markii aad ilamahaku sameenaysay indha-indhayta iyo daba galida,Balse gudbi hadii aad ku aragto mid kamid ah xaladahaanXaalada ilmaha oo ka sii dareysaIlmaha hadii aad ku arato cunto qadashao la’an ka dib markii aad ka tijaabisay  Hadii ilmaha bararku ku nsii kordhaayoMiisaanka ilmaha oo ka sii daraya (laba booqasho oo isku xigta)Hadiise aynan jirin wax loo gudbiyoilmaha waa in aad sii wadaa lasocoshadiisa todobaad laha ahayd eeadeega barnaamijka sida: In loo dhameys tiro dawadii looqoondeeyayRaashiinkii uu ku jiray lawska ( pulmpy nut)In la siiyo balnkii todobaadka danbe Iyo in wixii warbixina lagu qorokaarka.Hadiise ilmuhu ka maqan yahay guriga waqtiga booqashada waxaa u sheegtaa shaqaalahamutadawacnimada u shaqeeya caafimaadka bulshada(VCHWs), in uu boqdo gurigawarbixintan u keen shaqaalahaas fidintacaafimaadka jooga halkaas. Waa in bukaanka la bixiyaa ama lagasaaraa barnaamijka hadii uu buuxiyoshuruudaha soo socda. A)Hadii ilmaha la soo seexinayay u bararsanaa, waa in hadii laga waayo wax barar ah mudo laba todobaad ah ama laba booqasho (14) waa la fasaxaya ilmahaas.B)Hadiise ilmuhu una lahyn wax barar ahmarkii la soo jiifinaayo waa in la saaraa (discharge) marka u buuxiyo miisaankiilaga rabaa.C)Hadiise ilmuhu ku guuldareysto in uu buuxiyo shuruudaha lagu saari lahaamudo ka badan laba bilood waa in loogudbiyaa goobta barnaamijka ee nafaqodarada.D)Markasta oo aad ilmaha ku jira barnaamijkan fasaxaysid waa in aadeegtaa shuruudahan soo socda:I.In hooyadu ilmaha wadatay la barayhabka quudinta iyo daryeelka ilmaha.II.In hooyadu heshay shahaadadii lagusharfayay, u dhameystirka daawada ilmaha.In ilmaha la diwaan galiyay waqtiga bixitaankiisa iyo xaaladiisa in ilmaha ladiwaan galiyay waqtiga bixitaan iyo xaaladiisa."},{"question":"السؤال: في الحرب العالمية الثانية ، ما هي معدات المشروبات التي يتم توفيرها في دبابات القتال البريطانية؟","answer":"الإجابة: شاي"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"anjing mengulangi bangkai\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud laki-laki yang mengulangi perbuatan yang tidak senonoh (perempuan jahat dan lain-lain)"},{"question":" Quais esportes passaram a ser considerados olímpicos a partir dos Jogos Olímpicos de Tóquio?","answer":"Skate, surfe, karatê, escalada esportiva e beisebol/softbol."}]`),I={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:M},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:S,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},B={class:"search-container"},x={class:"card-container"},O=["disabled"],H={key:0},P={key:1};function D(e,a,s,m,t,r){const k=b("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",B,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),c(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=u=>t.searchQuery=u),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[y,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",x,[(i(!0),o(p,null,w(r.filteredPoems,(u,d)=>(i(),f(k,{key:d,poem:u},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),r.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...u)=>r.loadMore&&r.loadMore(...u))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",P,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",H,"See more"))],8,O)):v("",!0)])}const L=g(I,[["render",D],["__scopeId","data-v-e552e71e"]]),F=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/8.md","filePath":"chatai/8.md"}'),E={name:"chatai/8.md"},R=Object.assign(E,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[j(L)]))}});export{F as __pageData,R as default};
